<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 36—</num>
<heading>POSTAL RATES, CLASSES, AND SERVICES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PROVISIONS RELATING TO MARKET-DOMINANT PRODUCTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3621.</num>
<heading> Applicability; definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subchapter shall apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> first-class mail letters and sealed parcels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> first-class mail cards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> periodicals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> standard mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> single-piece parcel post;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> media mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> bound printed matter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> library mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> special services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> single-piece international mail,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">subject to any changes the Postal Regulatory Commission may make under section 3642.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Mail matter referred to in subsection (a) shall, for purposes of this subchapter, be considered to have the meaning given to such mail matter under the mail classification schedule.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3622.</num>
<heading> Modern rate regulation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority Generally</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall, within 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, by regulation establish (and may from time to time thereafter by regulation revise) a modern system for regulating rates and classes for market-dominant products.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Such system shall be designed to achieve the following objectives, each of which shall be applied in conjunction with the others:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To maximize incentives to reduce costs and increase efficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To create predictability and stability in rates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To maintain high quality service standards established under section 3691.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To allow the Postal Service pricing flexibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To assure adequate revenues, including retained earnings, to maintain financial stability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To reduce the administrative burden and increase the transparency of the ratemaking process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To enhance mail security and deter terrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To establish and maintain a just and reasonable schedule for rates and classifications, however the objective under this paragraph shall not be construed to prohibit the Postal Service from making changes of unequal magnitude within, between, or among classes of mail.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> To allocate the total institutional costs of the Postal Service appropriately between market-dominant and competitive products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In establishing or revising such system, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall take into account—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the value of the mail service actually provided each class or type of mail service to both the sender and the recipient, including but not limited to the collection, mode of transportation, and priority of delivery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the requirement that each class of mail or type of mail service bear the direct and indirect postal costs attributable to each class or type of mail service through reliably identified causal relationships plus that portion of all other costs of the Postal Service reasonably assignable to such class or type;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the effect of rate increases upon the general public, business mail users, and enterprises in the private sector of the economy engaged in the delivery of mail matter other than letters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the available alternative means of sending and receiving letters and other mail matter at reasonable costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the degree of preparation of mail for delivery into the postal system performed by the mailer and its effect upon reducing costs to the Postal Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> simplicity of structure for the entire schedule and simple, identifiable relationships between the rates or fees charged the various classes of mail for postal services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the importance of pricing flexibility to encourage increased mail volume and operational efficiency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the relative value to the people of the kinds of mail matter entered into the postal system and the desirability and justification for special classifications and services of mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the importance of providing classifications with extremely high degrees of reliability and speed of delivery and of providing those that do not require high degrees of reliability and speed of delivery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> the desirability of special classifications for both postal users and the Postal Service in accordance with the policies of this title, including agreements between the Postal Service and postal users, when available on public and reasonable terms to similarly situated mailers, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> improve the net financial position of the Postal Service through reducing Postal Service costs or increasing the overall contribution to the institutional costs of the Postal Service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enhance the performance of mail preparation, processing, transportation, or other functions; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> do not cause unreasonable harm to the marketplace.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the educational, cultural, scientific, and informational value to the recipient of mail matter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the need for the Postal Service to increase its efficiency and reduce its costs, including infrastructure costs, to help maintain high quality, affordable postal services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the value to the Postal Service and postal users of promoting intelligent mail and of secure, sender-identified mail; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the policies of this title as well as such other factors as the Commission determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The system for regulating rates and classes for market-dominant products shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> include an annual limitation on the percentage changes in rates to be set by the Postal Regulatory Commission that will be equal to the change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers unadjusted for seasonal variation over the most recent available 12-month period preceding the date the Postal Service files notice of its intention to increase rates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish a schedule whereby rates, when necessary and appropriate, would change at regular intervals by predictable amounts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 45 days before the implementation of any adjustment in rates under this section, including adjustments made under subsection (c)(10)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> require the Postal Service to provide public notice of the adjustment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide an opportunity for review by the Postal Regulatory Commission;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provide for the Postal Regulatory Commission to notify the Postal Service of any noncompliance of the adjustment with the limitation under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> require the Postal Service to respond to the notice provided under clause (iii) and describe the actions to be taken to comply with the limitation under subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> establish procedures whereby the Postal Service may adjust rates not in excess of the annual limitations under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> notwithstanding any limitation set under subparagraphs (A) and (C), and provided there is not sufficient unused rate authority under paragraph (2)(C), establish procedures whereby rates may be adjusted on an expedited basis due to either extraordinary or exceptional circumstances, provided that the Commission determines, after notice and opportunity for a public hearing and comment, and within 90 days after any request by the Postal Service, that such adjustment is reasonable and equitable and necessary to enable the Postal Service, under best practices of honest, efficient, and economical management, to maintain and continue the development of postal services of the kind and quality adapted to the needs of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Classes of mail</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under subparagraph (C), the annual limitations under paragraph (1)(A) shall apply to a class of mail, as defined in the Domestic Mail Classification Schedule as in effect on the date of enactment of the Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rounding of rates and fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall preclude the Postal Service from rounding rates and fees to the nearest whole integer, if the effect of such rounding does not cause the overall rate increase for any class to exceed the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of unused rate authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subparagraph, the term “unused rate adjustment authority” means the difference between—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the maximum amount of a rate adjustment that the Postal Service is authorized to make in any year subject to the annual limitation under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of the rate adjustment the Postal Service actually makes in that year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to clause (iii), the Postal Service may use any unused rate adjustment authority for any of the 5 years following the year such authority occurred.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In exercising the authority under clause (ii) in any year, the Postal Service—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> may use unused rate adjustment authority from more than 1 year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> may use any part of the unused rate adjustment authority from any year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> shall use the unused rate adjustment authority from the earliest year such authority first occurred and then each following year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> for any class or service, may not exceed the annual limitation under paragraph (1) by more than 2 percentage points.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Ten years after the date of enactment of the Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act and as appropriate thereafter, the Commission shall review the system for regulating rates and classes for market-dominant products established under this section to determine if the system is achieving the objectives in subsection (b), taking into account the factors in subsection (c). If the Commission determines, after notice and opportunity for public comment, that the system is not achieving the objectives in subsection (b), taking into account the factors in subsection (c), the Commission may, by regulation, make such modification or adopt such alternative system for regulating rates and classes for market-dominant products as necessary to achieve the objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Workshare Discounts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “workshare discount” refers to rate discounts provided to mailers for the presorting, prebarcoding, handling, or transportation of mail, as further defined by the Postal Regulatory Commission under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall ensure that such discounts do not exceed the cost that the Postal Service avoids as a result of workshare activity, unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the discount is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> associated with a new postal service, a change to an existing postal service, or with a new work share initiative related to an existing postal service; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> necessary to induce mailer behavior that furthers the economically efficient operation of the Postal Service and the portion of the discount in excess of the cost that the Postal Service avoids as a result of the workshare activity will be phased out over a limited period of time;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the amount of the discount above costs avoided—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is necessary to mitigate rate shock; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> will be phased out over time;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the discount is provided in connection with subclasses of mail consisting exclusively of mail matter of educational, cultural, scientific, or informational value; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> reduction or elimination of the discount would impede the efficient operation of the Postal Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this subsection shall require that a work share discount be reduced or eliminated if the reduction or elimination of the discount would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> lead to a loss of volume in the affected category or subclass of mail and reduce the aggregate contribution to the institutional costs of the Postal Service from the category or subclass subject to the discount below what it otherwise would have been if the discount had not been reduced or eliminated; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> result in a further increase in the rates paid by mailers not able to take advantage of the discount.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever the Postal Service establishes a workshare discount rate, the Postal Service shall, at the time it publishes the workshare discount rate, submit to the Postal Regulatory Commission a detailed report that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> explains the Postal Service’s reasons for establishing the rate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sets forth the data, economic analyses, and other information relied on by the Postal Service to justify the rate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> certifies that the discount will not adversely affect rates or services provided to users of postal services who do not take advantage of the discount rate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transition Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this section, rates and classes for market-dominant products shall remain subject to modification in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and section 407, as such provisions were last in effect before the date of enactment of this section. Proceedings initiated to consider a request for a recommended decision filed by the Postal Service during that 1-year period shall be completed in accordance with subchapter II of chapter 36 of this title and implementing regulations, as in effect before the date of enactment of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 3623 to 3625.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3205</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3626.</num>
<heading> Reduced rates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, rates of postage for a class of mail or kind of mailer under former section 4358, 4452(b), 4452(c), 4554(b), or 4554(c) of this title shall be established in accordance with section 3622.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this subsection, the term “regular-rate category” means any class of mail or kind of mailer, other than a class or kind referred to in section 2401(c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Rates of postage for a class of mail or kind of mailer under former section 4358(a) through (c) of this title shall be established so that postage on each mailing of such mail reflects its preferred status as compared to the postage for the most closely corresponding regular-rate category mailing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as specified in subparagraph (B), rates of postage for a class of mail or kind of mailer under former section 4358 (d) or (e) of this title shall be established so that postage on each mailing of such mail shall be as nearly as practicable 5 percent lower than the postage for a corresponding regular-rate category mailing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> With respect to the postage for the advertising pound portion of any mail matter under former section 4358 (d) or (e) of this title, the 5-percent discount specified in subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the advertising portion exceeds 10 percent of the publication involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The rates for any advertising under former <ref>section 4358(f) of this title</ref> shall be equal to 75 percent of the rates for advertising contained in the most closely corresponding regular-rate category of mail.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The rates for mail matter under former sections 4452 (b) and (c) of this title shall be established as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The estimated average revenue per piece to be received by the Postal Service from each subclass of mail under former sections 4452 (b) and (c) of this title shall be equal, as nearly as practicable, to 60 percent of the estimated average revenue per piece to be received from the most closely corresponding regular-rate subclass of mail.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraph (A), the estimated average revenue per piece of each regular-rate subclass shall be calculated on the basis of expected volumes and mix of mail for such subclass at current rates in the test year of the proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Rate differentials within each subclass of mail matter under former sections 4452 (b) and (c) shall reflect the policies of this title, including the factors set forth in <ref>section 3622(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The rates for mail matter under former sections 4554 (b) and (c) of this title shall be established so that postage on each mailing of such mail shall be as nearly as practicable 5 percent lower than the postage for a corresponding regular-rate mailing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this title, the term “periodical publications”, as used in former <ref>section 4351 of this title</ref>, includes (A) any catalog or other course listing, including mail announcements of legal texts which are part of post-bar admission education issued by any institution of higher education or by a nonprofit organization engaged in continuing legal education; and (B) any looseleaf page or report (including any index, instruction for filing, table, or sectional identifier which is an integral part of such report) which is designed as part of a looseleaf reporting service concerning developments in the law or public policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any material described in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall qualify to be entered and mailed as second class mail in accordance with the applicable provisions of former section 4352 through former <ref>section 4357 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given it by section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, and includes a nonprofit organization that coordinates a network of college-level courses that is sponsored primarily by nonprofit educational institutions for an older adult constituency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In the administration of this section, one conservation publication published by an agency of a State which is responsible for management and conservation of the fish or wildlife resources of such State shall be considered a publication of a qualified nonprofit organization which qualifies for rates of postage under former <ref>section 4358(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For purposes of this title, the term “agricultural”, as used in former sections 4358(j)(2), 4452(d), and 4554(b)(1)(B) of this title, includes the art or science of cultivating land, harvesting crops or marine resources, or raising of livestock.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the administration of this section, and for purposes of former sections 4358(j)(2), 4452(d), and 4554(b)(1)(B) of this title, agricultural organizations or associations shall include any organization or association which collects and disseminates information or materials relating to agricultural pursuits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the administration of this section, the rates for third-class mail matter mailed by a qualified political committee shall be the rates currently in effect under former <ref>section 4452 of this title</ref> for third-class mail matter mailed by a qualified nonprofit organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “qualified political committee” means a national or State committee of a political party, the Republican and Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committees, the Democratic National Congressional Committee, and the National Republican Congressional Committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “national committee” means the organization which, by virtue of the bylaws of a political party, is responsible for the day-to-day operation of such political party at the national level; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “State committee” means the organization which, by virtue of the bylaws of a political party, is responsible for the day-to-day operation of such political party at the State level.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In the administration of this chapter, the rates for mail under former <ref>section 4358(g) of this title</ref> shall be established without regard to either the provisions of such former section 4358(g) or the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the administration of this section, the rates for mail under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of former <ref>section 4358 of this title</ref> shall not apply to an issue of a publication if the number of copies of such issue distributed within the county of publication is less than the number equal to the sum of 50 percent of the total paid circulation of such issue plus one.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to an issue of a publication if the total paid circulation of such issue is less than 10,000 copies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section and former section 4358(a) through (c) of this title, those copies of an issue of a publication entered within the county in which it is published, but distributed outside such county on postal carrier routes originating in the county of publication, shall be treated as if they were distributed within the county of publication.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of an issue of a publication, any number of copies of which are mailed at the rates of postage for a class of mail or kind of mailer under former section 4358(a) through (c) of this title, any copies of such issue which are distributed outside the county of publication (excluding any copies subject to paragraph (3)) shall be subject to rates of postage provided for under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The rates of postage applicable to mail under this paragraph shall be established in accordance with section 3622.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> This paragraph shall not apply with respect to an issue of a publication unless the total paid circulation of such issue outside the county of publication (not counting recipients of copies subject to paragraph (3)) is less than 5,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> In the administration of this section, the number of copies of a subscription publication mailed to nonsubscribers during a calendar year at rates under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of former <ref>section 4358 of this title</ref> may not exceed 50 percent of the number of copies of such publication mailed at such rates to subscribers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(i)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title VII, § 704(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1269</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the administration of this section, the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title shall not apply to mail which advertises, promotes, offers, or, for a fee or consideration, recommends, describes, or announces the availability of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any credit, debit, or charge card, or similar financial instrument or account, provided by or through an arrangement with any person or organization not authorized to mail at the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any insurance policy, unless the organization which promotes the purchase of such policy is authorized to mail at the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title, the policy is designed for and primarily promoted to the members, donors, supporters, or beneficiaries of the organization, and the coverage provided by the policy is not generally otherwise commercially available;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any travel arrangement, unless the organization which promotes the arrangement is authorized to mail at the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title, the travel contributes substantially (aside from the cultivation of members, donors, or supporters, or the acquisition of income or funds) to one or more of the purposes which constitutes the basis for the organization’s authorization to mail at such rates, and the arrangement is designed for and primarily promoted to the members, donors, supporters, or beneficiaries of the organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> any product or service (other than any to which subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) relates), if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the sale of such product or the providing of such service is not substantially related (aside from the need, on the part of the organization promoting such product or service, for income or funds or the use it makes of the profits derived) to the exercise or performance by the organization of one or more of the purposes constituting the basis for the organization’s authorization to mail at such rates; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the mail matter involved is part of a cooperative mailing (as defined under regulations of the Postal Service) with any person or organization not authorized to mail at the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that—</continuation>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any determination under clause (i) that a product or service is not substantially related to a particular purpose shall be made under regulations which shall be prescribed by the Postal Service and which shall be consistent with standards established by the Internal Revenue Service and the courts with respect to subsections (a) and (c) of section 513 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> clause (i) shall not apply if the product involved is a periodical publication described in subsection (m)(2) (including a subscription to receive any such publication); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> clause (i) shall not apply to space advertising in mail matter that otherwise qualifies for rates under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title, and satisfies the content requirements established by the Postal Service for periodical publications: <i>Provided</i>, That such changes in law shall take effect immediately and shall stay in effect hereafter unless the Congress enacts legislation on this matter prior to <date date="1995-10-01">October 1, 1995</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Matter shall not be excluded from being mail at the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title, by an organization authorized to mail at those rates solely because—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such matter contains, but is not primarily devoted to, acknowledgements of organizations or individuals who have made donations to the authorized organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such matter contains, but is not primarily devoted to, references to and a response card or other instructions for making inquiries concerning services or benefits available as a result of membership in the authorized organization: <i>Provided</i>, That advertising, promotional, or application materials specifically concerning such services or benefits are not included.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Upon request, an organization authorized to mail at the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title shall furnish evidence to the Postal Service concerning the eligibility of any of its mail matter or mailings to be sent at those rates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall establish procedures to carry out this paragraph, including procedures for mailer certification of compliance with the conditions specified in paragraph (1)(D) or subsection (m), as applicable, and verification of such compliance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No person or organization shall mail, or cause to be mailed by contractual agreement or otherwise, at the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title, any matter to which those rates do not apply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Postal Service may assess a postage deficiency in the amount of the unpaid postage against any person or organization which violates paragraph (1) of this subsection. This assessment shall be deemed the final decision of the Postal Service, unless the party against whom the deficiency is assessed appeals it in writing within thirty days to the postmaster of the office where the mailing was entered. Such an appeal shall be considered by an official designated by the Postal Service, other than the postmaster of the office where the mailing was entered, who shall issue a decision as soon as practicable. This decision shall be deemed final unless the party against whom the deficiency was assessed appeals it in writing within thirty days to a further reviewing official designated by the Postal Service, who shall issue the final decision on the matter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall maintain procedures for the prompt collection of postage deficiencies arising from the violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection, and may in its discretion, follow the issuance of a final decision regarding a deficiency under paragraph (2) of this subsection deduct the amount of that deficiency incurred during the previous 12 months from any postage accounts or other monies of the violator in its possession.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<content> In the administration of this section, the term “advertising”, as used in former <ref>section 4358(j)(2) of this title</ref>, does not include the publisher’s own advertising in a publication published by the official highway or development agency of a State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the administration of this section, the rates for mail under former section 4452(b) or 4452(c) of this title shall not apply to mail consisting of products, unless such products—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> were received by the organization as gifts or contributions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are low cost articles (as defined by section 513(h)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a periodical publication of a qualified nonprofit organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<content> In the administration of this section, matter that satisfies the circulation standards for requester publications shall not be excluded from being mailed at the rates for mail under former section 4358 solely because such matter is designed primarily for free circulation or for circulation at nominal rates, or fails to meet the requirements of former section 4354(a)(5).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 762</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–328, § 1</ref>, <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–421, § 11</ref>, <date date="1976-09-24">Sept. 24, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–593, § 11(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XV</ref>, §§ 15102(b)(1), (c), 15104, 15105, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 330</ref>, 331; <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6003(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1933</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title II</ref>, §§ 1(a), 3, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1397</ref>, 1399; <ref>Pub. L. 102–141, title II</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 842</ref>, 843; <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title VII</ref>, §§ 704(a)(1), (3)(A), 705(a)–(c), 708(e), <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1267</ref>, 1269, 1271, 1273; <ref>Pub. L. 103–329, title VI, § 639</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2432</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–255, § 2</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–384</ref>, §§ 1(b)–(e), 2(b), <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1460–1462</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1003</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–108, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2022-04-06">Apr. 6, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3627.</num>
<heading> Adjusting free rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If Congress fails to appropriate an amount authorized under <ref>section 2401(c) of this title</ref> for any class of mail sent free of postage under section 3217 or 3403–3406 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> the rate for that class may be adjusted in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter so that the increased revenues received from the users of such class will equal the amount for that class that the Congress was to appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 763</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–593, § 11(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–410, title II, § 201(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-28">Aug. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–31, § 8(h)(3)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-20">May 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 86</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title VII, § 704(a)(3)(B)(i)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1269</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(g)(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3628.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3205</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3629.</num>
<heading> Reduced rates for voter registration purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Postal Service shall make available to a State or local voting registration official the rate for any class of mail that is available to a qualified nonprofit organization under section 3626 for the purpose of making a mailing that the official certifies is required or authorized by the National Voter Registration Act of 1993.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–31, § 8(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-20">May 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 86</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PROVISIONS RELATING TO COMPETITIVE PRODUCTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3631.</num>
<heading> Applicability; definitions and updates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subchapter shall apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> priority mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expedited mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> bulk parcel post;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> bulk international mail; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> mailgrams;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">subject to subsection (d) and any changes the Postal Regulatory Commission may make under section 3642.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this subchapter, the term “costs attributable”, as used with respect to a product, means the direct and indirect postal costs attributable to such product through reliably identified causal relationships.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Mail matter referred to in subsection (a) shall, for purposes of this subchapter, be considered to have the meaning given to such mail matter under the mail classification schedule.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3632.</num>
<heading> Action of the Governors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Establish Rates and Classes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Governors, with the concurrence of a majority of all of the Governors then holding office, shall establish rates and classes for products in the competitive category of mail in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter and regulations promulgated under section 3633.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Rates and classes shall be established in writing, complete with a statement of explanation and justification, and the date as of which each such rate or class takes effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rates or classes of general applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of rates or classes of general applicability in the Nation as a whole or in any substantial region of the Nation, the Governors shall cause each rate and class decision under this section and the record of the Governors’ proceedings in connection with such decision to be published in the Federal Register at least 30 days before the effective date of any new rates or classes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rates or classes not of general applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of rates or classes not of general applicability in the Nation as a whole or in any substantial region of the Nation, the Governors shall cause each rate and class decision under this section and the record of the proceedings in connection with such decision to be filed with the Postal Regulatory Commission by such date before the effective date of any new rates or classes as the Governors consider appropriate, but in no case less than 15 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As part of the regulations required under section 3633, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall establish criteria for determining when a rate or class established under this subchapter is or is not of general applicability in the Nation as a whole or in any substantial region of the Nation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transition Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Until regulations under section 3633 first take effect, rates and classes for competitive products shall remain subject to modification in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and section 407, as such provisions were as last in effect before the date of enactment of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3633.</num>
<heading> Provisions applicable to rates for competitive products</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall, within 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, promulgate (and may from time to time thereafter revise) regulations to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prohibit the subsidization of competitive products by market-dominant products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that each competitive product covers its costs attributable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure that all competitive products collectively cover what the Commission determines to be an appropriate share of the institutional costs of the Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Minimum Contribution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Five years after the date of enactment of this section, and every 5 years thereafter, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall conduct a review to determine whether the institutional costs contribution requirement under subsection (a)(3) should be retained in its current form, modified, or eliminated. In making its determination, the Commission shall consider all relevant circumstances, including the prevailing competitive conditions in the market, and the degree to which any costs are uniquely or disproportionately associated with any competitive products.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3634.</num>
<heading> Assumed Federal income tax on competitive products income</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “assumed Federal income tax on competitive products income” means the net income tax that would be imposed by chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 on the Postal Service’s assumed taxable income from competitive products for the year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “assumed taxable income from competitive products”, with respect to a year, refers to the amount representing what would be the taxable income of a corporation under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for the year, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the only activities of such corporation were the activities of the Postal Service allocable under section 2011(h) to competitive products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the only assets held by such corporation were the assets of the Postal Service allocable under section 2011(h) to such activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Computation and Transfer Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Service shall, for each year beginning with the year in which occurs the deadline for the Postal Service’s first report to the Postal Regulatory Commission under section 3652(a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> compute its assumed Federal income tax on competitive products income for such year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfer from the Competitive Products Fund to the Postal Service Fund the amount of that assumed tax.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline for Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any transfer required to be made under this section for a year shall be due on or before the January 15th next occurring after the close of such year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3226</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PROVISIONS RELATING TO EXPERIMENTAL AND NEW PRODUCTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3641.</num>
<heading> Market tests of experimental products</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service may conduct market tests of experimental products in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provisions waived</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A product shall not, while it is being tested under this section, be subject to the requirements of sections 3622, 3633, or 3642, or regulations promulgated under those sections.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A product may not be tested under this section unless it satisfies each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Significantly different product</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The product is, from the viewpoint of the mail users, significantly different from all products offered by the Postal Service within the 2-year period preceding the start of the test.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Market disruption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The introduction or continued offering of the product will not create an unfair or otherwise inappropriate competitive advantage for the Postal Service or any mailer, particularly in regard to small business concerns (as defined under subsection (h)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Correct categorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service identifies the product, for the purpose of a test under this section, as either market-dominant or competitive, consistent with the criteria under section 3642(b)(1). Costs and revenues attributable to a product identified as competitive shall be included in any determination under section 3633(3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> (relating to provisions applicable to competitive products collectively). Any test that solely affects products currently classified as competitive, or which provides services ancillary to only competitive products, shall be presumed to be in the competitive product category without regard to whether a similar ancillary product exists for market-dominant products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At least 30 days before initiating a market test under this section, the Postal Service shall file with the Postal Regulatory Commission and publish in the Federal Register a notice—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> setting out the basis for the Postal Service’s determination that the market test is covered by this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describing the nature and scope of the market test.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safeguards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For a competitive experimental product, the provisions of section 504(g) shall be available with respect to any information required to be filed under paragraph (1) to the same extent and in the same manner as in the case of any matter described in section 504(g)(1). Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be considered to permit or require the publication of any information as to which confidential treatment is accorded under the preceding sentence (subject to the same exception as set forth in section 504(g)(3)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duration.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A market test of a product under this section may be conducted over a period of not to exceed 24 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If necessary in order to determine the feasibility or desirability of a product being tested under this section, the Postal Regulatory Commission may, upon written application of the Postal Service (filed not later than 60 days before the date as of which the testing of such product would otherwise be scheduled to terminate under paragraph (1)), extend the testing of such product for not to exceed an additional 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Dollar-Amount Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A product may only be tested under this section if the total revenues that are anticipated, or in fact received, by the Postal Service from such product do not exceed $10,000,000 in any year, subject to paragraph (2) and subsection (g). In carrying out the preceding sentence, the Postal Regulatory Commission may limit the amount of revenues the Postal Service may obtain from any particular geographic market as necessary to prevent market disruption (as defined under subsection (b)(2)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Regulatory Commission may, upon written application of the Postal Service, exempt the market test from the limit in paragraph (1) if the total revenues that are anticipated, or in fact received, by the Postal Service from such product do not exceed $50,000,000 in any year, subject to subsection (g). In reviewing an application under this paragraph, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall approve such application if it determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the product is likely to benefit the public and meet an expected demand;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the product is likely to contribute to the financial stability of the Postal Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the product is not likely to result in unfair or otherwise inappropriate competition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cancellation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Postal Regulatory Commission at any time determines that a market test under this section fails, with respect to any particular product, to meet 1 or more of the requirements of this section, it may order the cancellation of the test involved or take such other action as it considers appropriate. A determination under this subsection shall be made in accordance with such procedures as the Commission shall by regulation prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adjustment for Inflation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of each year following the year in which occurs the deadline for the Postal Service’s first report to the Postal Regulatory Commission under section 3652(a), each dollar amount contained in this section shall be adjusted by the change in the Consumer Price Index for such year (as determined under regulations of the Commission).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of a Small Business Concern</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The criteria used in defining small business concerns or otherwise categorizing business concerns as small business concerns shall, for purposes of this section, be established by the Postal Regulatory Commission in conformance with the requirements of section 3 of the Small Business Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Market tests under this subchapter may be conducted in any year beginning with the first year in which occurs the deadline for the Postal Service’s first report to the Postal Regulatory Commission under section 3652(a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 763</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–421, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-24">Sept. 24, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1306</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3642.</num>
<heading> New products and transfers of products between the market-dominant and competitive categories of mail</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon request of the Postal Service or users of the mails, or upon its own initiative, the Postal Regulatory Commission may change the list of market-dominant products under section 3621 and the list of competitive products under section 3631 by adding new products to the lists, removing products from the lists, or transferring products between the lists.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>All determinations by the Postal Regulatory Commission under subsection (a) shall be made in accordance with the following criteria:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The market-dominant category of products shall consist of each product in the sale of which the Postal Service exercises sufficient market power that it can effectively set the price of such product substantially above costs, raise prices significantly, decrease quality, or decrease output, without risk of losing a significant level of business to other firms offering similar products. The competitive category of products shall consist of all other products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of products covered by postal monopoly</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A product covered by the postal monopoly shall not be subject to transfer under this section from the market-dominant category of mail. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “product covered by the postal monopoly” means any product the conveyance or transmission of which is reserved to the United States under <ref>section 1696 of title 18</ref>, subject to the same exception as set forth in the last sentence of section 409(e)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In making any decision under this section, due regard shall be given to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the availability and nature of enterprises in the private sector engaged in the delivery of the product involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the views of those who use the product involved on the appropriateness of the proposed action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the likely impact of the proposed action on small business concerns (within the meaning of section 3641(h)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers of Subclasses and Other Subordinate Units Allowable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this title shall be considered to prevent transfers under this section from being made by reason of the fact that they would involve only some (but not all) of the subclasses or other subordinate units of the class of mail or type of postal service involved (without regard to satisfaction of minimum quantity requirements standing alone).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification and Publication Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service shall, whenever it requests to add a product or transfer a product to a different category, file with the Postal Regulatory Commission and publish in the Federal Register a notice setting out the basis for its determination that the product satisfies the criteria under subsection (b) and, in the case of a request to add a product or transfer a product to the competitive category of mail, that the product meets the regulations promulgated by the Postal Regulatory Commission under section 3633. The provisions of section 504(g) shall be available with respect to any information required to be filed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall, whenever it changes the list of products in the market-dominant or competitive category of mail, prescribe new lists of products. The revised lists shall indicate how and when any previous lists (including the lists under sections 3621 and 3631) are superseded, and shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in section 3641, no product that involves the physical delivery of letters, printed matter, or packages may be offered by the Postal Service unless it has been assigned to the market-dominant or competitive category of mail (as appropriate) either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under this subchapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by or under any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title VII, § 704(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1268</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>REPORTING REQUIREMENTS AND RELATED PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3651.</num>
<heading> Annual reports by the Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall submit an annual report to the President and the Congress concerning the operations of the Commission under this title, including the extent to which regulations are achieving the objectives under sections 3622 and 3633, respectively.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the information required under subsection (a), each report under this section shall also include, with respect to the period covered by such report, an estimate of the costs incurred by the Postal Service in providing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> postal services to areas of the Nation where, in the judgment of the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Postal Service either would not provide services at all or would not provide such services in accordance with the requirements of this title if the Postal Service were not required to provide prompt, reliable, and efficient services to patrons in all areas and all communities, including as required under the first sentence of section 101(b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> free or reduced rates for postal services as required by this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other public services or activities which, in the judgment of the Postal Regulatory Commission, would not otherwise have been provided by the Postal Service but for the requirements of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basis for estimates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall detail the basis for its estimates and the statutory requirements giving rise to the costs identified in each report under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information From Postal Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service shall provide the Postal Regulatory Commission with such information as may, in the judgment of the Commission, be necessary in order for the Commission to prepare its reports under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3211</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3652.</num>
<heading> Annual reports to the Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Costs, Revenues, Rates, and Service</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Postal Service shall, no later than 90 days after the end of each year, prepare and submit to the Postal Regulatory Commission a report (together with such nonpublic annex to the report as the Commission may require under subsection (e))—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which shall analyze costs, revenues, rates, and quality of service, using such methodologies as the Commission shall by regulation prescribe, and in sufficient detail to demonstrate that all products during such year complied with all applicable requirements of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> which shall, for each market-dominant product provided in such year, provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> product information, including mail volumes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> measures of the quality of service afforded by the Postal Service in connection with such product, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the level of service (described in terms of speed of delivery and reliability) provided; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the degree of customer satisfaction with the service provided.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Inspector General shall regularly audit the data collection systems and procedures utilized in collecting information and preparing such report (including any annex thereto and the information required under subsection (b)). The results of any such audit shall be submitted to the Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Relating to Workshare Discounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Service shall include, in each report under subsection (a), the following information with respect to each market-dominant product for which a workshare discount was in effect during the period covered by such report:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The per-item cost avoided by the Postal Service by virtue of such discount.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The percentage of such per-item cost avoided that the per-item workshare discount represents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The per-item contribution made to institutional costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Market Tests</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out subsections (a) and (b) with respect to experimental products offered through market tests under section 3641 in a year, the Postal Service shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> report data on the costs, revenues, and quality of service by market test, which may be reported in summary form; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> report such data as the Postal Regulatory Commission requires.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supporting Matter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall have access, in accordance with such regulations as the Commission shall prescribe, to the working papers and any other supporting matter of the Postal Service and the Inspector General in connection with any information submitted under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Content and Form of Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall, by regulation, prescribe the content and form of the public reports (and any nonpublic annex and supporting matter relating to the report) to be provided by the Postal Service under this section. In carrying out this subsection, the Commission shall give due consideration to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing the public with timely, adequate information to assess the lawfulness of rates charged;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> avoiding unnecessary or unwarranted administrative effort and expense on the part of the Postal Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> protecting the confidentiality of commercially sensitive information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revised requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commission may, on its own motion or on request of an interested party, initiate proceedings (to be conducted in accordance with regulations that the Commission shall prescribe) to improve the quality, accuracy, or completeness of Postal Service data required by the Commission under this subsection whenever it shall appear that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the attribution of costs or revenues to products has become significantly inaccurate or can be significantly improved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the quality of service data has become significantly inaccurate or can be significantly improved; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such revisions are, in the judgment of the Commission, otherwise necessitated by the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Confidential Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Postal Service determines that any document or portion of a document, or other matter, which it provides to the Postal Regulatory Commission in a nonpublic annex under this section or under subsection (d) contains information which is described in <ref>section 410(c) of this title</ref>, or exempt from public disclosure under <ref>section 552(b) of title 5</ref>, the Postal Service shall, at the time of providing such matter to the Commission, notify the Commission of its determination, in writing, and describe with particularity the documents (or portions of documents) or other matter for which confidentiality is sought and the reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any information or other matter described in paragraph (1) to which the Commission gains access under this section shall be subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 504(g) in the same way as if the Commission had received notification with respect to such matter under section 504(g)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Service shall submit to the Postal Regulatory Commission, together with any other submission that the Postal Service is required to make under this section in a year, copies of its then most recent—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> comprehensive statement under section 2401(e);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> performance plan under section 2803; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> program performance reports under section 2804.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3211</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3653.</num>
<heading> Annual determination of compliance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opportunity for Public Comment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After receiving the reports required under section 3652 for any year, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall promptly provide an opportunity for comment on such reports by users of the mails, affected parties, and an officer of the Commission who shall be required to represent the interests of the general public.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Compliance or Noncompliance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 90 days after receiving the submissions required under section 3652 with respect to a year, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall make a written determination as to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether any rates or fees in effect during such year (for products individually or collectively) were not in compliance with applicable provisions of this chapter (or regulations promulgated thereunder); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether any service standards in effect during such year were not met.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If, with respect to a year, no instance of noncompliance is found under this subsection to have occurred in such year, the written determination shall be to that effect.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Noncompliance With Regard to Rates or Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, for a year, a timely written determination of noncompliance is made under subsection (b), the Postal Regulatory Commission shall take appropriate action in accordance with subsections (c) and (e) of section 3662 (as if a complaint averring such noncompliance had been duly filed and found under such section to be justified).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Performance Goals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall also evaluate annually whether the Postal Service has met the goals established under sections 2803 and 2804, and may provide recommendations to the Postal Service related to the protection or promotion of public policy objectives set out in this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rebuttable Presumption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A timely written determination described in the last sentence of subsection (b) shall, for purposes of any proceeding under section 3662, create a rebuttable presumption of compliance by the Postal Service (with regard to the matters described under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b)) during the year to which such determination relates.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3654.</num>
<heading> Additional financial reporting</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional Financial Reporting.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Service shall file with the Postal Regulatory Commission beginning with the first full fiscal year following the effective date of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> within 40 days after the end of each fiscal quarter, a quarterly report containing the information required by the Securities and Exchange Commission to be included in quarterly reports under sections 13 and 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78m</ref>, 78<i>o</i>(d)) on Form 10–Q, as such Form (or any successor form) may be revised from time to time;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> within 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, an annual report containing the information required by the Securities and Exchange Commission to be included in annual reports under such sections on Form 10–K, as such Form (or any successor form) may be revised from time to time; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> periodic reports within the time frame and containing the information prescribed in Form 8–K of the Securities and Exchange Commission, as such Form (or any successor form) may be revised from time to time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Registrant defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of defining the reports required by paragraph (1), the Postal Service shall be deemed to be the “registrant” described in the Securities and Exchange Commission Forms, and references contained in such Forms to Securities and Exchange Commission regulations are incorporated herein by reference, as amended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Internal control report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of defining the reports required by paragraph (1)(B), the Postal Service shall comply with the rules prescribed by the Securities and Exchange Commission implementing section 404 of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 7262</ref>), beginning with the annual report for fiscal year 2010.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Financial reporting.—</inline>
</heading>
<chapeau>
<inline class="small-caps"> </inline>
<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">1</ref>
</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The reports required by subsection (a)(1)(B) shall include, with respect to the Postal Service’s pension and post-retirement health obligations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the funded status of the Postal Service’s pension and postretirement health obligations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> components of the net change in the fund balances and obligations and the nature and cause of any significant changes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> components of net periodic costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> cost methods and assumptions underlying the relevant actuarial valuations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the effect of a one-percentage point increase in the assumed health care cost trend rate for each future year on the service and interest costs components of net periodic postretirement health cost and the accumulated obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> actual contributions to and payments from the funds for the years presented and the estimated future contributions and payments for each of the following 5 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the composition of plan assets reflected in the fund balances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the assumed rate of return on fund balances and the actual rates of return for the years presented.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall provide the data listed under paragraph (1) to the Postal Service not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Beginning with reports for the fiscal year 2010, for purposes of the reports required under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1), the Postal Service shall include segment reporting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall determine the appropriate segment reporting under subparagraph (A) after consultation with the Postal Regulatory Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of the reports required by subsection (a)(1)(B), the Postal Service shall obtain an opinion from an independent auditor on whether the information listed in subsection (b) is fairly stated in all material respects, either in relation to the basic financial statements as a whole or on a stand-alone basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supporting Matter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall have access to the audit documentation and any other supporting matter of the Postal Service and its independent auditor in connection with any information submitted under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revised Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Regulatory Commission may, on its own motion or on request of an interested party, initiate proceedings (to be conducted in accordance with regulations that the Commission shall prescribe) to improve the quality, accuracy, or completeness of Postal Service data required under this section whenever it shall appear that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the data have become significantly inaccurate or can be significantly improved; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> those revisions are, in the judgment of the Commission, otherwise necessitated by the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Confidential Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Postal Service determines that any document or portion of a document, or other matter, which it provides to the Postal Regulatory Commission in a nonpublic annex under this section or pursuant to subsection (d) contains information which is described in <ref>section 410(c) of this title</ref>, or exempt from public disclosure under <ref>section 552(b) of title 5</ref>, the Postal Service shall, at the time of providing such matter to the Commission, notify the Commission of its determination, in writing, and describe with particularity the documents (or portions of documents) or other matter for which confidentiality is sought and the reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any information or other matter described in paragraph (1) to which the Commission gains access under this section shall be subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 504(g) in the same way as if the Commission had received notification with respect to such matter under section 504(g)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>POSTAL SERVICES, COMPLAINTS, AND JUDICIAL REVIEW</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3661.</num>
<heading> Postal services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall develop and promote adequate and efficient postal services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When the Postal Service determines that there should be a change in the nature of postal services which will generally affect service on a nationwide or substantially nationwide basis, it shall submit a proposal, within a reasonable time prior to the effective date of such proposal, to the Postal Regulatory Commission requesting an advisory opinion on the change.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Commission shall not issue its opinion on any proposal until an opportunity for hearing on the record under sections 556 and 557 of title 5 has been accorded to the Postal Service, users of the mail, and an officer of the Commission who shall be required to represent the interests of the general public. The opinion shall be in writing and shall include a certification by each Commissioner agreeing with the opinion that in his judgment the opinion conforms to the policies established under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3662.</num>
<heading> Rate and service complaints</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any interested person (including an officer of the Postal Regulatory Commission representing the interests of the general public) who believes the Postal Service is not operating in conformance with the requirements of the provisions of sections 101(d), 401(2), 403(c), 404a, or 601, or this chapter (or regulations promulgated under any of those provisions) may lodge a complaint with the Postal Regulatory Commission in such form and manner as the Commission may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prompt Response Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Regulatory Commission shall, within 90 days after receiving a complaint under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> upon a finding that such complaint raises material issues of fact or law, begin proceedings on such complaint; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> issue an order dismissing the complaint; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to any action taken under subparagraph (A)(i) or (ii), issue a written statement setting forth the bases of its determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of complaints not timely acted on</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of section 3663, any complaint under subsection (a) on which the Commission fails to act in the time and manner required by paragraph (1) shall be treated in the same way as if it had been dismissed pursuant to an order issued by the Commission on the last day allowable for the issuance of such order under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action Required if Complaint Found To Be Justified</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Postal Regulatory Commission finds the complaint to be justified, it shall order that the Postal Service take such action as the Commission considers appropriate in order to achieve compliance with the applicable requirements and to remedy the effects of any noncompliance (such as ordering unlawful rates to be adjusted to lawful levels, ordering the cancellation of market tests, ordering the Postal Service to discontinue providing loss-making products, or requiring the Postal Service to make up for revenue shortfalls in competitive products).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Order Fines in Cases of Deliberate Noncompliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition, in cases of deliberate noncompliance by the Postal Service with the requirements of this title, the Postal Regulatory Commission may order, based on the nature, circumstances, extent, and seriousness of the noncompliance, a fine (in the amount specified by the Commission in its order) for each incidence of noncompliance. Fines resulting from the provision of competitive products shall be paid from the Competitive Products Fund established in section 2011. All receipts from fines imposed under this subsection shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3663.</num>
<heading> Appellate review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person, including the Postal Service, adversely affected or aggrieved by a final order or decision of the Postal Regulatory Commission may, within 30 days after such order or decision becomes final, institute proceedings for review thereof by filing a petition in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia. The court shall review the order or decision in accordance with <ref>section 706 of title 5</ref>, and chapter 158 and <ref>section 2112 of title 28</ref>, on the basis of the record before the Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3664.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The several district courts have jurisdiction specifically to enforce, and to enjoin and restrain the Postal Service from violating, any order issued by the Postal Regulatory Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3681.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No mailer may be reimbursed for any amount paid under any rate or fee which, after such payment, is determined to have been unlawful after proceedings in accordance with the provisions of sections 3662 through 3664 of this title, or is superseded by a lower rate or fee established under subchapter II of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3682.</num>
<heading> Size and weight limits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Postal Service may establish size and weight limitations for mail matter in the market-dominant category of mail consistent with regulations the Postal Regulatory Commission may prescribe under section 3622. The Postal Service may establish size and weight limitations for mail matter in the competitive category of mail consistent with its authority under section 3632.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1331(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–242, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 300</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3683.</num>
<heading> Uniform rates for books; films; other materials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the rates of postage established for mail matter enumerated in former <ref>section 4554 of this title</ref> shall be uniform for such mail of the same weight, and shall not vary with the distance transported.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The rates of postage under former <ref>section 4554(b)(1) of this title</ref> shall not be effective except with respect to mailings which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> constitute materials specified in former <ref>section 4554(b)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> are sent between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an institution, organization, or association listed in subparagraph (A) or (B) of such former section 4554(b)(1) and any other such institution, organization, or association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an institution, organization, or association referred to in subparagraph (A) and any individual (other than an individual having a financial interest in the sale, promotion, or distribution of the materials involved);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an institution, organization, or association referred to in subparagraph (A) and a qualified nonprofit organization (as defined in former <ref>section 4452(d) of this title</ref>) that is not such an institution, organization, or association; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an institution, organization, or association referred to in subparagraph (A) and a publisher, if such institution, organization, or association has placed an order to purchase such materials for delivery to such institution, organization, or association.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–421, § 12</ref>, <date date="1976-09-24">Sept. 24, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1312</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title VII, § 706(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3684.</num>
<heading> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 3627 of this title</ref>, no provision of this chapter shall be construed to give authority to the Governors to make any change in any provision of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–410, title II, § 201(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-28">Aug. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3685.</num>
<heading> Filing of information relating to periodical publications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each owner of a publication having periodical publication mail privileges shall furnish to the Postal Service at least once a year, and shall publish in such publication once a year, information in such form and detail and at such time as the Postal Service may require with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the identity of the editor, managing editor, publishers, and owners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the identity of the corporation and stockholders thereof, if the publication is owned by a corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the identity of known bondholders, mortgagees, and other security holders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent and nature of the circulation of the publication, including, but not limited to, the number of copies distributed, the methods of distribution, and the extent to which such circulation is paid in whole or in part; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> such other information as the Postal Service may deem necessary to determine whether the publication meets the standards for periodical publication mail privileges.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Postal Service shall not require the names of persons owning less than 1 percent of the total amount of stocks, bonds, mortgages, or other securities.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each publication having such mail privileges shall furnish to the Postal Service information in such form and detail, and at such times, as the Postal Service requires to determine whether the publication continues to qualify for such privileges.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall make appropriate rules and regulations to carry out the purposes of this section, including provision for suspension or revocation of periodical publication mail privileges for failure to furnish the required information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3686.</num>
<heading> Bonus authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service may establish 1 or more programs to provide bonuses or other rewards to officers and employees of the Postal Service in senior executive or equivalent positions to achieve the objectives of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Total Compensation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under any such program, the Postal Service may award a bonus or other reward in excess of the limitation set forth in the last sentence of section 1003(a), if such program has been approved under paragraph (2). Any such award or bonus may not cause the total compensation of such officer or employee to exceed the total annual compensation payable to the Vice President under <ref>section 104 of title 3</ref> as of the end of the calendar year in which the bonus or award is paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval process</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Postal Service wishes to have the authority, under any program described in subsection (a), to award bonuses or other rewards in excess of the limitation set forth in the last sentence of section 1003(a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Postal Service shall make an appropriate request to the Board of Governors of the Postal Service in such form and manner as the Board requires; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Board of Governors shall approve any such request if the Board certifies, for the annual appraisal period involved, that the performance appraisal system for affected officers and employees of the Postal Service (as designed and applied) makes meaningful distinctions based on relative performance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revocation authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Board of Governors of the Postal Service finds that a performance appraisal system previously approved under paragraph (2)(B) does not (as designed and applied) make meaningful distinctions based on relative performance, the Board may revoke or suspend the authority of the Postal Service to continue a program approved under paragraph (2) until such time as appropriate corrective measures have, in the judgment of the Board, been taken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions for Critical Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board of Governors may allow up to 12 officers or employees of the Postal Service in critical senior executive or equivalent positions to receive total compensation in an amount not to exceed 120 percent of the total annual compensation payable to the Vice President under <ref>section 104 of title 3</ref> as of the end of the calendar year in which such payment is received. For each exception made under this subsection, the Board shall provide written notification to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Congress within 30 days after the payment is made setting forth the name of the officer or employee involved, the critical nature of his or her duties and responsibilities, and the basis for determining that such payment is warranted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information for Inclusion in Comprehensive Statement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Included in its comprehensive statement under section 2401(e) for any period shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name of each person receiving a bonus or other payment during such period which would not have been allowable but for the provisions of subsection (b) or (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of the bonus or other payment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount by which the limitation set forth in the last sentence of section 1003(a) was exceeded as a result of such bonus or other payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board of Governors may prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3236</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>MODERN SERVICE STANDARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3691.</num>
<heading> Establishment of modern service standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority Generally</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Postal Service shall, in consultation with the Postal Regulatory Commission, by regulation establish (and may from time to time thereafter by regulation revise) a set of service standards for market-dominant products.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Objectives.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Such standards shall be designed to achieve the following objectives:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To enhance the value of postal services to both senders and recipients.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To preserve regular and effective access to postal services in all communities, including those in rural areas or where post offices are not self-sustaining.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To reasonably assure Postal Service customers delivery reliability, speed and frequency consistent with reasonable rates and best business practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To provide a system of objective external performance measurements for each market-dominant product as a basis for measurement of Postal Service performance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading> Implementation of performance measurements.—</heading>
<content>With respect to paragraph (1)(D), with the approval of the Postal Regulatory Commission an internal measurement system may be implemented instead of an external measurement system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In establishing or revising such standards, the Postal Service shall take into account—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the actual level of service that Postal Service customers receive under any service guidelines previously established by the Postal Service or service standards established under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the degree of customer satisfaction with Postal Service performance in the acceptance, processing and delivery of mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the needs of Postal Service customers, including those with physical impairments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> mail volume and revenues projected for future years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the projected growth in the number of addresses the Postal Service will be required to serve in future years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the current and projected future cost of serving Postal Service customers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the effect of changes in technology, demographics, and population distribution on the efficient and reliable operation of the postal delivery system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the policies of this title and such other factors as the Postal Service determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The regulations promulgated pursuant to this section (and any revisions thereto), and any violations thereof, shall be subject to review upon complaint under sections 3662 and 3663.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3692.</num>
<heading> Performance targets and transparency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Targets</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each year, to ensure that mail service for postal customers meets the service standards for market-dominant products, established under section 3691, the Postal Service shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than 60 days after the beginning of the fiscal year in which they will apply, establish and provide to the Postal Regulatory Commission reasonable targets for performance for each product; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide the previous fiscal year’s performance targets in its Annual Compliance Report to the Postal Regulatory Commission for evaluation of compliance for each product.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Postal Regulatory Commission Determination of Certain Performance Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 90 days after first receiving the performance targets under subsection (a)(1), the Postal Regulatory Commission shall provide to the Postal Service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> requirements for the Postal Service to publish nationwide, regional, and local delivery area performance information in accordance with subsection (c)(2) that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are consistent with the organizational structure of the delivery network of the Postal Service (including at the District and Area organizational levels, or the functional equivalents, and, to the extent practicable, at the U.S. ZIP Code Area level);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reflect the most granular geographic level of performance information appropriate for the Postal Service to publish; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> includes time period segments for the published geographic levels to satisfy the publishing requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (C) of subsection (c)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recommendations for any modifications to the Postal Service’s measurement systems necessary to measure and publish the performance information under subsection (c)(2) that the Postal Regulatory Commission deems relevant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Public Performance Dashboard.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service shall develop and maintain a publicly available Website with an interactive web-tool that provides performance information for market-dominant products that is updated on a weekly basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The performance information provided for a market-dominant product on the Website shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the type of market-dominant product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> performance information for different geographic areas, consistent with subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> performance information for different time periods, including annual, quarterly, monthly, and weekly segments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> comparisons of performance information for market-dominant products to performance information for previous time periods to facilitate identification of performance trends; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the performance targets then in effect, and the performance targets for the previous fiscal year, as established under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comprehensibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Website shall include plain language descriptions of the elements required under paragraph (2) and information on the collection process, measurement methodology, completeness, accuracy, and validity of the performance information provided on the Website.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Address search functionality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Website shall include functionality to enable a user to search for performance information by street address, ZIP Code, or post office box.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Format</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Service shall make the performance information provided on the Website available—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in a manner that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> presents the information required under paragraph (2) on an interactive dashboard;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is searchable and may be sorted and filtered by the elements described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent practicable, enables any person or entity to download in bulk—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such performance information; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the results of a search by the elements described in paragraph (2);</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under an “open license” which has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3502 of title 44</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as an “open Government data asset” and in a “machine-readable” format which have the meaning given those terms in <ref>section 3502 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service shall regularly consult with the Postal Regulatory Commission on appropriate features and information to be included on the Website.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public input</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Service shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> solicit public input on the design and implementation of the Website; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintain a public feedback tool to ensure each feature of, and the information on, the Website is usable and understandable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service shall implement and make available to the public (and make any subsequent changes in accordance with subsection (b)) the Website not later than 60 days from the date on which the Postal Service receives the requirements and recommendations from the Postal Regulatory Commission under subsection (b), and shall continuously update such information on the Website as required by subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A link and plain language description of the Website shall be made available on any webpage where performance targets and measurements established under subsection (a)(1) are made available to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service, the Postmaster General, or the Board, as applicable, shall reference the dashboard described in paragraph (5)(A)(i) in the Annual Performance Plan under section 2803, the Annual Performance Report under section 2804, and the Annual Report under section 2402.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “performance information” means the objective external performance measurements established under section 3691(b)(1)(D).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Website</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Website” means the website described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–108, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-04-06">Apr. 6, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1144</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>