<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>POSTAL POLICY AND DEFINITIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Postal policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The United States Postal Service shall be operated as a basic and fundamental service provided to the people by the Government of the United States, authorized by the Constitution, created by Act of Congress, and supported by the people. The Postal Service shall have as its basic function the obligation to provide postal services to bind the Nation together through the personal, educational, literary, and business correspondence of the people. It shall provide prompt, reliable, and efficient services to patrons in all areas and shall render postal services to all communities. The costs of establishing and maintaining the Postal Service shall not be apportioned to impair the overall value of such service to the people.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall maintain an integrated network for the delivery of market-dominant and competitive products (as defined in chapter 36 of this title). Delivery shall occur at least six days a week, except during weeks that include a Federal holiday, in emergency situations, such as natural disasters, or in geographic areas where the Postal Service has established a policy of delivering mail fewer than six days a week as of the date of enactment of the Postal Service Reform Act of 2022. The Postal Service shall provide a maximum degree of effective and regular postal services to rural areas, communities, and small towns where post offices are not self-sustaining. No small post office shall be closed solely for operating at a deficit, it being the specific intent of the Congress that effective postal services be insured to residents of both urban and rural communities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As an employer, the Postal Service shall achieve and maintain compensation for its officers and employees comparable to the rates and types of compensation paid in the private sector of the economy of the United States. It shall place particular emphasis upon opportunities for career advancements of all officers and employees and the achievement of worthwhile and satisfying careers in the service of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Postal rates shall be established to apportion the costs of all postal operations to all users of the mail on a fair and equitable basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> In determining all policies for postal services, the Postal Service shall give the highest consideration to the requirement for the most expeditious collection, transportation, and delivery of important letter mail.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In selecting modes of transportation, the Postal Service shall give highest consideration to the prompt, economical, consistent, and reliable delivery of all mail in a manner that increases operational efficiency and reduces complexity. Modern methods of transporting mail by containerization and programs designed to achieve cost-effective overnight transportation to the destination of important letter mail to all parts of the Nation shall also be a primary goal of postal operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> In planning and building new postal facilities, the Postal Service shall emphasize the need for facilities and equipment designed to create desirable working conditions for its officers and employees, a maximum degree of convenience for efficient postal services, proper access to existing and future air and surface transportation facilities, and control of costs to the Postal Service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–405, § 2(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–108, title II</ref>, §§ 202(a), 208, <date date="2022-04-06">Apr. 6, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1146</ref>, 1151.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this title—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Postal Service” means the United States Postal Service established by <ref>section 201 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Board of Governors”, and “Board”, unless the context otherwise requires, mean the Board of Governors established under <ref>section 202 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Governors” means the 9 members of the Board of Governors appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, under <ref>section 202(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Inspector General” means the Inspector General appointed under <ref>section 202(e) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “postal service” refers to the delivery of letters, printed matter, or mailable packages, including acceptance, collection, sorting, transportation, or other functions ancillary thereto;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “product” means a postal service with a distinct cost or market characteristic for which a rate or rates are, or may reasonably be, applied;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “rates”, as used with respect to products, includes fees for postal services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “market-dominant product” or “product in the market-dominant category of mail” means a product subject to subchapter I of chapter 36;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “competitive product” or “product in the competitive category of mail” means a product subject to subchapter II of chapter 36; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “year”, as used in chapter 36 (other than subchapters I and VI thereof), means a fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 662(a)(2)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–379; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>