<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 28—</num>
<heading>STRATEGIC PLANNING AND PERFORMANCE MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2801.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “outcome measure” refers to an assessment of the results of a program activity compared to its intended purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “output measure” refers to the tabulation, calculation, or recording of activity or effort and can be expressed in a quantitative or qualitative manner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “performance goal” means a target level of performance expressed as a tangible, measurable objective, against which actual achievement shall be compared, including a goal expressed as a quantitative standard, value, or rate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “performance indicator” refers to a particular value or characteristic used to measure output or outcome;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “program activity” means a specific activity related to the mission of the Postal Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “program evaluation” means an assessment, through objective measurement and systematic analysis, of the manner and extent to which Postal Service programs achieve intended objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–62, § 7</ref>, <date date="1993-08-03">Aug. 3, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2802.</num>
<heading> Strategic plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> No later than <date date="1997-09-30">September 30, 1997</date>, the Postal Service shall submit to the President and the Congress a strategic plan for its program activities. Such plan shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a comprehensive mission statement covering the major functions and operations of the Postal Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> general goals and objectives, including outcome-related goals and objectives, for the major functions and operations of the Postal Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of how the goals and objectives are to be achieved, including a description of the operational processes, skills and technology, and the human, capital, information, and other resources required to meet those goals and objectives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a description of how the performance goals included in the plan required under section 2803 shall be related to the general goals and objectives in the strategic plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an identification of those key factors external to the Postal Service and beyond its control that could significantly affect the achievement of the general goals and objectives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a description of the program evaluations used in establishing or revising general goals and objectives, with a schedule for future program evaluations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The strategic plan shall cover a period of not less than five years forward from the fiscal year in which it is submitted, and shall be updated and revised at least every three years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The performance plan required under section 2803 shall be consistent with the Postal Service’s strategic plan. A performance plan may not be submitted for a fiscal year not covered by a current strategic plan under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When developing a strategic plan, the Postal Service shall solicit and consider the views and suggestions of those entities potentially affected by or interested in such a plan, and shall advise the Congress of the contents of the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–62, § 7</ref>, <date date="1993-08-03">Aug. 3, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2803.</num>
<heading> Performance plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Postal Service shall prepare an annual performance plan covering each program activity set forth in the Postal Service budget, which shall be included in the comprehensive statement presented under <ref>section 2401(e) of this title</ref>. Such plan shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish performance goals to define the level of performance to be achieved by a program activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> express such goals in an objective, quantifiable, and measurable form unless an alternative form is used under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> briefly describe the operational processes, skills and technology, and the human, capital, information, or other resources required to meet the performance goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish performance indicators to be used in measuring or assessing the relevant outputs, service levels, and outcomes of each program activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide a basis for comparing actual program results with the established performance goals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> describe the means to be used to verify and validate measured values.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If the Postal Service determines that it is not feasible to express the performance goals for a particular program activity in an objective, quantifiable, and measurable form, the Postal Service may use an alternative form. Such alternative form shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> include separate descriptive statements of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a minimally effective program, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a successful program,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">with sufficient precision and in such terms that would allow for an accurate, independent determination of whether the program activity’s performance meets the criteria of either description; or</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> state why it is infeasible or impractical to express a performance goal in any form for the program activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In preparing a comprehensive and informative plan under this section, the Postal Service may aggregate, disaggregate, or consolidate program activities, except that any aggregation or consolidation may not omit or minimize the significance of any program activity constituting a major function or operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Postal Service may prepare a non-public annex to its plan covering program activities or parts of program activities relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the avoidance of interference with criminal prosecution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> matters otherwise exempt from public disclosure under <ref>section 410(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–62, § 7</ref>, <date date="1993-08-03">Aug. 3, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 293</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2804.</num>
<heading> Program performance reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall prepare a report on program performance for each fiscal year, which shall be included in the annual comprehensive statement presented under <ref>section 2401(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The program performance report shall set forth the performance indicators established in the Postal Service performance plan, along with the actual program performance achieved compared with the performance goals expressed in the plan for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If performance goals are specified by descriptive statements of a minimally effective program activity and a successful program activity, the results of such program shall be described in relationship to those categories, including whether the performance failed to meet the criteria of either category.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The report for fiscal year 2000 shall include actual results for the preceding fiscal year, the report for fiscal year 2001 shall include actual results for the two preceding fiscal years, and the report for fiscal year 2002 and all subsequent reports shall include actual results for the three preceding fiscal years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Each report shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review the success of achieving the performance goals of the fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> evaluate the performance plan for the current fiscal year relative to the performance achieved towards the performance goals in the fiscal year covered by the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> explain and describe, where a performance goal has not been met (including when a program activity’s performance is determined not to have met the criteria of a successful program activity under section 2803(b)(2))—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> why the goal was not met;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> those plans and schedules for achieving the established performance goal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if the performance goal is impractical or infeasible, why that is the case and what action is recommended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> include the summary findings of those program evaluations completed during the fiscal year covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–62, § 7</ref>, <date date="1993-08-03">Aug. 3, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 294</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2805.</num>
<heading> Inherently Governmental functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The functions and activities of this chapter shall be considered to be inherently Governmental functions. The drafting of strategic plans, performance plans, and program performance reports under this section shall be performed only by employees of the Postal Service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–62, § 7</ref>, <date date="1993-08-03">Aug. 3, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>