<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32—</num>
<heading>PENALTY AND FRANKED MAIL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3201.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “penalty mail” means official mail, other than franked mail, which is authorized by law to be transmitted in the mail without prepayment of postage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “penalty cover” means envelopes, wrappers, labels, or cards used to transmit penalty mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “frank” means the autographic or facsimile signature of persons authorized by sections 3210–3216 and 3218 of this title to transmit matter through the mail without prepayment of postage or other indicia contemplated by sections 733 and 907 of title 44;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “franked mail” means mail which is transmitted in the mail under a frank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “Members of Congress” includes Senators, Representatives, Delegates, and Resident Commissioners; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “missing child” has the meaning provided by section 403(1) of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 751</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–87, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-09">Aug. 9, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3202.</num>
<heading> Penalty mail</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the limitations imposed by sections 3204 and 3207 of this title, there may be transmitted as penalty mail—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> official mail of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> officers of the Government of the United States other than Members of Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Smithsonian Institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Pan American Union;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Pan American Sanitary Bureau; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the United States Employment Service and the system of employment offices operated by it in conformity with the provisions of sections 49–49c, 49d, 49e–49k of title 29, and all State employment systems which receive funds appropriated under authority of those sections.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> mail relating to naturalization to be sent to the Immigration and Naturalization Service by clerks of courts addressed to the Department of Justice or the Immigration and Naturalization Service, or any official thereof; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> mail relating to a collection of statistics, survey, or census authorized by title 13 and addressed to the Department of Commerce or a bureau or agency thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A department or officer authorized to use penalty covers may enclose them with return address to any person from or through whom official information is desired. The penalty cover may be used only to transmit the official information and endorsements relating thereto.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to officers who receive a fixed allowance as compensation for their services including expenses of postage.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 751</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–553, § 105(e)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title VII, § 708(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7404(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7404(b)(2)(B), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2008.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3203.</num>
<heading> Endorsements on penalty covers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, penalty covers shall bear, over the words “Official Business” an endorsement showing the name of the department, bureau, or office from which, or officer from whom, it is transmitted. The penalty for the unlawful use of all penalty covers shall be printed thereon.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall prescribe the endorsement to be placed on covers mailed under clauses (1)(E), (2), and (3) of <ref>section 3202(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 752</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3204.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on use of penalty mail</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise provided in this section or <ref>section 3220(a) of this title</ref>, an officer, executive department, or independent establishment of the Government of the United States may not mail, as penalty mail, any article or document unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a request therefor has been previously received by the department or establishment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> its mailings is required by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) of this section does not prohibit the mailing, as penalty mail, by an officer, executive department, or independent agency of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enclosures reasonably related to the subject matter of official correspondence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> informational releases relating to the census of the United States and authorized by title 13;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> matter concerning the sale of Government securities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> forms, blanks, and copies of statutes, rules, regulations, instructions, administrative orders, and interpretations necessary in the administration of the department or establishment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> agricultural bulletins;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> lists of public documents offered for sale by the Superintendent of Documents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> announcements of the publication of maps, atlases, and statistical and other reports offered for sale by the Federal Power Commission as authorized by <ref>section 825k of title 16</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> articles or documents to educational institutions or public libraries, or to Federal, State, or other public authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–87, § 1(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-09">Aug. 9, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3205.</num>
<heading> Accounting for penalty covers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Executive departments and agencies, independent establishments of the Government of the United States, and organizations and persons authorized by law to use penalty mail, shall account for all penalty covers through the Postal Service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3206.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement for penalty mail service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, executive departments and agencies, independent establishments of the Government of the United States, and Government corporations concerned, shall transfer to the Postal Service as postal revenue out of any appropriations or funds available to them, as a necessary expense of the appropriations or funds and of the activities concerned, the equivalent amount of postage due, as determined by the Postal Service, for matter sent in the mails by or to them as penalty mail under authority of <ref>section 3202 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Department of Agriculture shall transfer to the Postal Service as postal revenues out of any appropriations made to it for that purpose the equivalent amount of postage, as determined by the Postal Service, for penalty mailings under clauses (1)(F) and (4) of <ref>section 3202(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Department of State shall transfer to the Postal Service as postal revenues out of any appropriations made to it for that purpose the equivalent amount of postage, as determined by the Postal Service, for penalty mailings under clause (1)(C) and (D) of <ref>section 3202(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 753</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 9</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–553, § 105(e)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2599</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3207.</num>
<heading> Limit of weight of penalty mail; postage on overweight matter</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Penalty mail is restricted to articles not in excess of the weight and size prescribed for that class of mail receiving high priority in handling and delivery, except—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> stamped paper and supplies sold or used by the Postal Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> books and documents published or circulated by order of Congress when mailed by the Superintendent of Documents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A penalty mail article which is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> over 4 pounds in weight;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not in excess of the weight and size prescribed for mail matter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> otherwise mailable;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is mailable at rates for that class of mail entitled to the lowest priority in handling and delivery, even though it may include written matter and may be sealed.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3208.</num>
<heading> Shipment by most economical means</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Shipments of official matter other than franked mail shall be sent by the most economical means of transportation practicable. The Postal Service may refuse to accept official matter for shipment by mail when in its judgment it may be shipped by other means at less expense, or it may provide for its transportation by freight or express whenever a saving to the Government of the United States will result therefrom without detriment to the public service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3209.</num>
<heading> Executive departments to supply information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Persons and governmental organizations authorized to use penalty mail shall supply all information requested by the Postal Service necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter as soon as practicable after request therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3210.</num>
<heading> Franked mail transmitted by the Vice President, Members of Congress, and congressional officials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It is the policy of the Congress that the privilege of sending mail as franked mail shall be established under this section in order to assist and expedite the conduct of the official business, activities, and duties of the Congress of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> It is the intent of the Congress that such official business, activities, and duties cover all matters which directly or indirectly pertain to the legislative process or to any congressional representative functions generally, or to the functioning, working, or operating of the Congress and the performance of official duties in connection therewith, and shall include, but not be limited to, the conveying of information to the public, and the requesting of the views of the public, or the views and information of other authority of government, as a guide or a means of assistance in the performance of those functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> It is the intent of the Congress that mail matter which is frankable specifically includes, but is not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> mail matter to any person and to all agencies and officials of Federal, State, and local governments regarding programs, decisions, and other related matters of public concern or public service, including any matter relating to actions of a past or current Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the usual and customary congressional newsletter or press release which may deal with such matters as the impact of laws and decisions on State and local governments and individual citizens; reports on public and official actions taken by Members of Congress; and discussions of proposed or pending legislation or governmental actions and the positions of the Members of Congress on, and arguments for or against, such matters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the usual and customary congressional questionnaire seeking public opinion on any law, pending or proposed legislation, public issue, or subject;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> mail matter dispatched by a Member of Congress between his Washington office and any congressional district offices, or between his district offices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> mail matter directed by one Member of Congress to another Member of Congress or to representatives of the legislative bodies of State and local governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> mail matter expressing congratulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> mail matter, including general mass mailings, which consists of Federal laws, Federal regulations, other Federal publications, publications purchased with Federal funds, or publications containing items of general information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> mail matter which consists of voter registration or election information or assistance prepared and mailed in a nonpartisan manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> mail matter which constitutes or includes a biography or autobiography of any Member of, or Member-elect to, Congress or any biographical or autobiographical material concerning such Member or Member-elect or the spouse or other members of the family of such Member or Member-elect, and which is so mailed as a part of a Federal publication, in response to a specific request therefor, or which relates to the Member’s or Member-elect’s official and representational duties, and is not included for publicity purposes in a newsletter or other general mass mailing of the Member or Member-elect under the franking privilege.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> It is the intent of the Congress that the franking privilege under this section shall not permit, and may not be used for, the transmission through the mails as franked mail, of matter which in its nature is purely personal to the sender or to any other person and is unrelated to the official business, activities, and duties of the public officials covered by subsection (b)(1) of this section, except that nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prohibit the use of the franking privilege for the transmission of matter which is purely personal to a recipient who is a constituent of a Member of Congress and which is related to the official business, activities, and duties of the Member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> It is the intent of the Congress that a Member of or Member-elect to Congress may not mail as franked mail—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> mail matter which constitutes or includes any article, account, sketch, narration, or other text laudatory and complimentary of any Member of, or Member-elect to, Congress on a purely personal or political basis rather than on the basis of performance of official duties as a Member or on the basis of activities as a Member-elect;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> mail matter which constitutes or includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> greetings from the spouse or other members of the family of such Member or Member-elect unless it is a brief reference in otherwise frankable mail;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reports of how or when such Member or Member-elect, or the spouse or any other member of the family of such Member or Member-elect, spends time other than in the performance of, or in connection with, the legislative, representative, and other official functions of such Member or the activities of such Member-elect as a Member-elect; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any card expressing holiday greetings from such Member or Member-elect; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> mail matter which specifically solicits political support for the sender or any other person or any political party, or a vote or financial assistance for any candidate for any public office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The House Communications Standards Commission and the Select Committee on Standards and Conduct of the Senate shall prescribe for their respective Houses such rules and regulations and shall take such other action, as the Commission or Committee considers necessary and proper for the Members and Members-elect to conform to the provisions of this clause and applicable rules and regulations. Such rules and regulations shall include, but not be limited to, provisions prescribing the time within which such mailings shall be mailed at or delivered to any postal facility to attain compliance with this clause and the time when such mailings shall be deemed to have been so mailed or delivered and such compliance attained.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> It is the intent of Congress that a Member of, or Member-elect to, Congress may not mail any mass mailing as franked mail—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if the mass mailing is postmarked fewer than 60 days immediately before the date of any primary election or general election (whether regular, special, or runoff) in which the Member is a candidate for reelection; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a Member of, or Member-elect to, the House who is a candidate for any other public office, if the mass mailing—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is prepared for delivery within any portion of the jurisdiction of or the area covered by the public office which is outside the area constituting the congressional district from which the Member or Member-elect was elected; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is postmarked fewer than 60 days immediately before the date of any primary election or general election (whether regular, special, or runoff) in which the Member or Member-elect is a candidate for any other public office.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any mass mailing which is mailed by the chairman of any organization referred to in the last sentence of <ref>section 3215 of this title</ref> which relates to the normal and regular business of the organization may be mailed without regard to the provisions of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> No Member of the Senate may mail any mass mailing as franked mail if such mass mailing is postmarked fewer than 60 days immediately before the date of any primary election or general election (whether regular, special, or runoff) for any national, State or local office in which such Member is a candidate for election.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate and the House Communications Standards Commission shall prescribe for their respective Houses rules and regulations, and shall take other action as the Committee or the Commission considers necessary and proper for Members and Members-elect to comply with the provisions of this paragraph and applicable rules and regulations, and in the case of the Commission, to waive this paragraph in the case of mailings sent in response to or to address threats to life safety. The rules and regulations shall include provisions prescribing the time within which mailings shall be mailed at or delivered to any postal facility and the time when the mailings shall be deemed to have been mailed or delivered to comply with the provisions of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section, the term “mass mailing” means, with respect to a session of Congress, any mailing of newsletters or other pieces of mail with substantially identical content (whether such mail is deposited singly or in bulk, or at the same time or different times), totaling more than 500 pieces in that session, except that such term does not include any mailing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of matter in direct response to a communication from a person to whom the matter is mailed;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> from a Member of Congress to other Members of Congress, or to Federal, State, or local government officials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> of a news release to the communications media; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> providing information exclusively on competitions which are officially sanctioned by the House of Representatives or Senate, nominations to military service academies, official employment listings for positions in the House of Representatives (including listings for positions in the Wounded Warrior Program or the Gold Star Family Fellowship Program), or natural disasters or other threats to public health and life safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (C) if mail matter is of a type which is not customarily postmarked, the date on which such matter would have been postmarked if it were of a type customarily postmarked shall apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> A Member of the House of Representatives may not send any mass mailing outside the congressional district from which the Member was elected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Vice President, each Member of or Member-elect to Congress, the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, each of the elected officers of the House of Representatives (other than a Member of the House), the Legislative Counsels of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Law Revision Counsel of the House of Representatives, and the Senate Legal Counsel, may send, as franked mail, matter relating to their official business, activities, and duties, as intended by Congress to be mailable as franked mail under subsection (a)(2) and (3) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a vacancy occurs in the Office of the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, an elected officer of the House of Representatives (other than a Member of the House), the Legislative Counsel of the House of Representatives or the Senate, the Law Revision Counsel of the House of Representatives, or the Senate Legal Counsel, any authorized person may exercise the franking privilege in the officer’s name during the period of the vacancy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Vice President, each Member of Congress, the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, and each of the elected officers of the House (other than a Member of the House), during the 90-day period immediately following the date on which they leave office, may send, as franked mail, matter on official business relating to the closing of their respective offices. The House Communications Standards Commission and the Select Committee on Standards and Conduct of the Senate shall prescribe for their respective Houses such rules and regulations, and shall take such other action as the Commission or Committee considers necessary and proper, to carry out the provisions of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Franked mail may be in any form appropriate for mail matter, including, but not limited to, correspondence, newsletters, questionnaires, recordings, facsimiles, reprints, and reproductions. Franked mail shall not include matter which is intended by Congress to be nonmailable as franked mail under subsection (a)(4) and (5) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A Member of Congress may mail franked mail with a simplified form of address for delivery within that area constituting the congressional district or State from which the Member was elected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A Member-elect to the Congress may mail franked mail with a simplified form of address for delivery within that area constituting the congressional district or the State from which he was elected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A Delegate, Delegate-elect, Resident Commissioner, or Resident Commissioner-elect to the House of Representatives may mail franked mail with a simplified form of address for delivery within the area from which he was elected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any franked mail which is mailed under this subsection shall be mailed at the equivalent rate of postage which assures that the mail will be sent by the most economical means practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Senate Committee on Rules and Administration and the House Communications Standards Commission shall prescribe for their respective Houses rules and regulations governing any franked mail which is mailed under this subsection and shall by regulation limit the number of such mailings allowed under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any Member of, or Member-elect to, the House of Representatives entitled to make any mailing as franked mail under this subsection shall, before making any mailing, submit a sample or description of the mail matter involved to the House Communications Standards Commission for an advisory opinion as to whether the proposed mailing is in compliance with the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Senate Select Committee on Ethics may require any Member of, or Member-elect to, the Senate entitled to make any mailings as franked mail under this subsection to submit a sample or description of the mail matter to the Committee for an advisory opinion as to whether the proposed mailing is in compliance with the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Franked mail mailed with a simplified form of address under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be prepared as directed by the Postal Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may be delivered to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> each box holder or family on a rural or star route;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each post office box holder; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> each stop or box on a city carrier route.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this subsection, a congressional district includes, in the case of a Representative at Large or Representative at Large-elect, the State from which he was elected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The frankability of mail matter shall be determined under the provisions of this section by the type and content of the mail sent, or to be sent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Any mass mailing which otherwise would be permitted to be mailed as franked mail under this section shall not be so mailed unless the cost of preparing and printing the mail matter is paid exclusively from funds appropriated by Congress, except that an otherwise frankable mass mailing may contain, as an enclosure or supplement, any public service material which is purely instructional or informational in nature, and which in content is frank­able under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal, State, or local law, or any regulation thereunder, the equivalent amount of postage determined under <ref>section 3216 of this title</ref> on franked mail mailed under the frank of the Vice President or a Member of Congress, and the cost of preparing or printing such frankable matter for such mailing under the frank, shall not be considered as a contribution to, or an expenditure by, the Vice President or a Member of Congress for the purpose of determining any limitation on expenditures or contributions with respect to any such official, imposed by any Federal, State, or local law or regulation, in connection with any campaign of such official for election to any Federal office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–51, § 101</ref>, <date date="1971-07-09">July 9, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–177</ref>, <date date="1975-12-23">Dec. 23, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1032</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–521, title VII, § 714(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-26">Oct. 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–69</ref>, §§ 1–3(a), 4, <date date="1981-10-26">Oct. 26, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1041–1043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–263, § 1(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1982-09-24">Sept. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title III, § 318</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1067</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title III</ref>, §§ 311(h)(1), 316, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2283; <ref>Pub. L. 102–392, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(g)(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3262</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. B, title IX, § 19006(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 116(b)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, (e)(1)–(5)(A), (6), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1637</ref>, 1640, 1641.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3211.</num>
<heading> Public documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Vice President, Members of Congress, the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, each of the elected officers of the House of Representatives (other than a Member of the House) during the 90-day period immediately following the expiration of their respective terms of office, may send and receive as franked mail all public documents printed by order of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–69, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-26">Oct. 26, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1043</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3212.</num>
<heading> Congressional Record under frank of Members of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Members of Congress may send the Congressional Record as franked mail.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Members of Congress may send, as franked mail, any part of, or a reprint of any part of, the Congressional Record, including speeches or reports contained therein, if such matter is mailable as franked mail under <ref>section 3210 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 3</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3213.</num>
<heading> Seeds and reports from Department of Agriculture</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Seeds and agricultural reports emanating from the Department of Agriculture may be mailed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as penalty mail by the Secretary of Agriculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during the 90-day period immediately following the expiration of their terms of office, as franked mail by Members of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–69, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-26">Oct. 26, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1043</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3214.</num>
<heading> Mailing privilege of former President; surviving spouse of former President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A former President and the surviving spouse of a former President may send nonpolitical mail within the United States and its territories and possessions as franked mail. Such mail of a former President and of the surviving spouse of a former President marked “Postage and Fees Paid” in the manner prescribed by the Postal Service shall be accepted by the Postal Service for transmission in the international mails.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title IV, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–61, title IV, § 409(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-10-10">Oct. 10, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1299</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3215.</num>
<heading> Lending or permitting use of frank unlawful</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person entitled to use a frank may not lend it or permit its use by any committee, organization, or association, or permit its use by any person for the benefit or use of any committee, organization, or association. This section does not apply to any standing, select, special, or joint committee, or subcommittee thereof, or commission, of the Senate, House of Representatives, or Congress, composed of Members of Congress, or to the Democratic caucus or the Republican conference of the House of Representatives or of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 10</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3216.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement for franked mailings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The equivalent of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> postage on, and fees and charges in connection with, mail matter sent through the mails—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under the franking privilege (other than under <ref>section 3219 of this title</ref>), by the Vice President, Members of and Members-elect to Congress, the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, each of the elected officers of the House of Representatives (other than a Member of the House), the Legislative Counsels of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Law Revision Counsel of the House of Representatives, and the Senate Legal Counsel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by the survivors of a Member of Congress under <ref>section 3218 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> those portions of fees and charges to be paid for handling and delivery by the Postal Service of Mailgrams considered as franked mail under <ref>section 3219 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be paid by appropriations for the official mail costs of the Senate and the House of Representatives for that purpose and then paid to the Postal Service as postal revenue. Except as to Mailgrams and except as provided by sections 733 and 907 of title 44, envelopes, wrappers, cards, or labels used to transmit franked mail shall bear, in the upper right-hand corner, the sender’s signature, or a fac­simile thereof.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Postage on, and fees and charges in connection with, mail matter sent through the mails under <ref>section 3214 of this title</ref> shall be paid each fiscal year, out of any appropriation made for that purpose, to the Postal Service as postal revenue in an amount equivalent to the postage, fees, and charges which would otherwise be payable on, or in connection with, such mail matter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Payment under subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be deemed payment for all matter mailed under the frank and for all fees and charges due the Postal Service in connection therewith.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Money collected for matter improperly mailed under the franking privilege shall be deposited as miscellaneous receipts in the general fund of the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than two weeks after the last day of each quarter of the fiscal year, or as soon as practicable thereafter, the Postmaster General shall send to the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, the House Communications Standards Commission, the Secretary of the Senate, and the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration a report which shall contain a tabulation of the estimated number of pieces and costs of franked mail, as defined in <ref>section 3201 of this title</ref>, in each mail classification sent through the mail for that quarter and for the preceding quarters in the fiscal year, together with separate tabulations of the number of pieces and costs of such mail sent by the House and by the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Two weeks after the close of the second quarter of the fiscal year, or as soon as practicable thereafter, the Postmaster General shall send to the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, the House Communications Standards Commission, the Committee on House Oversight, the Secretary of the Senate, and the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, a statement of the costs of postage on, and fees and charges in connection with, mail matter sent through the mails as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection for the preceding two quarters together with an estimate of such costs for the balance of the fiscal year. As soon as practicable after receipt of this statement, the House Communications Standards Commission, the Committee on House Oversight, and the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration shall consider promulgating such regulations for their respective Houses as may be necessary to ensure that total postage costs, as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, will not exceed the amounts available for the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–51, § 101</ref>, <date date="1971-07-09">July 9, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 7</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–255, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-03-27">Mar. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 52</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–521, title VII, § 714(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-26">Oct. 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–69, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-26">Oct. 26, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–263, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-24">Sept. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title III</ref>, §§ 316(b), formerly § 316(c), 317, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1067</ref>, renumbered § 316(b), <ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title III, § 311(h)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–90, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 466</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1748</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 116(b)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3217.</num>
<heading> Correspondence of members of diplomatic corps and consuls of countries of Postal Union of Americas and Spain</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Correspondence of the members of the diplomatic corps of the countries of the Postal Union of the Americas and Spain stationed in the United States may be reciprocally transmitted in the domestic mails free of postage, and be entitled to free registration without right to indemnity in case of loss. The same privilege is accorded consuls and vice consuls when they are discharging the function of consuls of countries stationed in the United States, for official correspondence among themselves, and with the Government of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3218.</num>
<heading> Franked mail for survivors of Members of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the death of a Member of Congress during his term of office, the surviving spouse of such Member (or, if there is no surviving spouse, a member of the immediate family of the Member designated by the Secretary of the Senate or the Clerk of the House of Representatives, as appropriate, in accordance with rules and procedures established by the Secretary or the Clerk) may send, for a period not to exceed 180 days after his death, as franked mail, nonpolitical correspondence relating to the death of the Member.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 755</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 11</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 746</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–69, § 6(b)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1981-10-26">Oct. 26, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1043</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3219.</num>
<heading> Mailgrams</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any Mailgram sent by the Vice President, a Member of or Member-elect to Congress, the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, an elected officer of the House of Representatives (other than a Member of the House), the Legislative Counsel of the House of Representatives or the Senate, the Law Revision Counsel of the House of Representatives, or the Senate Legal Counsel, and then delivered by the Postal Service, shall be considered as franked mail, subject to <ref>section 3216(a)(2) of this title</ref>, if such Mailgram contains matter of the kind authorized to be sent by that official as franked mail under <ref>section 3210 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 746</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–521, title VII, § 714(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-26">Oct. 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–263, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-24">Sept. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3220.</num>
<heading> Use of official mail in the location and recovery of missing children</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, after consultation with appropriate public and private agencies, shall prescribe general guidelines under which penalty mail may be used to assist in the location and recovery of missing children. The guidelines shall provide information relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the form and manner in which materials and information relating to missing children (such as biographical data and pictures, sketches, or other likenesses) may be included in penalty mail;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appropriate sources from which such materials and information may be obtained;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the procedures by which such materials and information may be obtained; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other matter which the Office considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each executive department and independent establishment of the Government of the United States shall prescribe regulations under which penalty mail sent by such department or establishment may be used in conformance with the guidelines prescribed under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Senate Committee on Rules and Administration and the House Communications Standards Commission shall prescribe for their respective Houses rules and regulations, and shall take such other action as the Committee or Commission considers necessary and proper, in order that purposes similar to those of subsection (a) may, in the discretion of the congressional official or office concerned, be carried out by the use of franked mail sent by such official or office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section, “Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention” and “Office” each means the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention within the Department of Justice, as established by section 201 of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–87, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-09">Aug. 9, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 116(b)(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>