<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29—</num>
<heading>PROPERTY MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2901.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Excess property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “excess property” means any postal property that the Postal Service determines is not required to meet the needs or responsibilities of the Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Postal property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “postal property” means any property owned or leased by the Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Underutilized property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “underutilized property” means a portion or the entirety of any real property that is postal property, including any improvements, that is used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> irregularly or intermittently by the Postal Service for program purposes of the Postal Service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for program purposes that can be satisfied only with a portion of the property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2902.</num>
<heading> Property management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Postal Service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall maintain adequate inventory controls and accountability systems for postal property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall develop current and future workforce projections so as to have the capacity to assess the needs of the Postal Service workforce regarding the use of property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> may develop a 5-year management template that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishes goals and policies that will lead to the reduction of excess property and underutilized property in the inventory of the Postal Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adopts workplace practices, configurations, and management techniques that can achieve increased levels of productivity and decrease the need for real property assets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assesses leased space to identify space that is not fully used or occupied;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> develops recommendations on how to address excess capacity at Postal Service facilities without negatively impacting mail delivery; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> develops recommendations on ensuring the security of mail processing operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> if the Postal Service develops a template under paragraph (3) shall, as part of that template and on a regular basis—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct an inventory of postal property that is real property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> publish a report that covers each property identified under subparagraph (A), similar to the USPS Owned Facilities Report and the USPS Leased Facilities Report, that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the date on which the Postal Service first occupied the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the size of the property in square footage and acreage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the geographical location of the property, including an address and description;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the extent to which the property is being utilized;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the actual annual operating costs associated with the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the total cost of capital expenditures associated with the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the number of postal employees, contractor employees, and functions housed at the property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the mission of the Postal Service is dependent on the property; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> the estimated amount of capital expenditures projected to maintain and operate the property over each of the next 5 years after the date of enactment of this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in subsection (a)(4)(B) shall be construed to require the Postal Service to obtain an appraisal of postal property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–318, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2903.</num>
<heading> Use of funds from sale of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event that the Postal Service permanently ceases operations, any funds derived from the sale of any real property owned by the Postal Service shall be used to pay any outstanding liability with respect to the salaries and expenses of any Postal Service employee. The balance of any remaining funds shall be deposited into the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund established under <ref>section 8909a of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–108, title I, § 102(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-04-06">Apr. 6, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>