<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 4—</num>
<heading>GENERAL AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 401.</num>
<heading> General powers of the Postal Service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of section 404a, the Postal Service shall have the following general powers:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to sue and be sued in its official name;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to adopt, amend, and repeal such rules and regulations, not inconsistent with this title, as may be necessary in the execution of its functions under this title and such other functions as may be assigned to the Postal Service under any provisions of law outside of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to enter into and perform contracts, execute instruments, and determine the character of, and necessity for, its expenditures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to determine and keep its own system of accounts and the forms and contents of its contracts and other business documents, except as otherwise provided in this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to acquire, in any lawful manner, such personal or real property, or any interest therein, as it deems necessary or convenient in the transaction of its business; to hold, maintain, sell, lease, or otherwise dispose of such property or any interest therein; and to provide services in connection therewith and charges therefor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to construct, operate, lease, and maintain buildings, facilities, equipment, and other improvements on any property owned or controlled by it, including, without limitation, any property or interest therein transferred to it under <ref>section 2002 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to accept gifts or donations of services or property, real or personal, as it deems, necessary or convenient in the transaction of its business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to settle and compromise claims by or against it;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to exercise, in the name of the United States, the right of eminent domain for the furtherance of its official purposes; and to have the priority of the United States with respect to the payment of debts out of bankrupt, insolvent, and decedents’ estates; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to have all other powers incidental, necessary, or appropriate to the carrying on of its functions or the exercise of its specific powers.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title IV, § 403(b)(1)</ref>, title V, § 504, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3227</ref>, 3235.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 402.</num>
<heading> Delegation of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for those powers, duties, or obligations specifically vested in the Governors, as distinguished from the Board of Governors, the Board may delegate the authority vested in it to the Postmaster General under such terms, conditions, and limitations, including the power of redelegation, as it deems desirable. The Board may establish such committees of the Board, and delegate such powers to any committee, as the Board determines appropriate to carry out its functions and duties. Delegations to the Postmaster General or committees shall be consistent with other provisions of this title, shall not relieve the Board of full responsibility for the carrying out of its duties and functions, and shall be revocable by the Governors in their exclusive judgment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 723</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 403.</num>
<heading> General duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall plan, develop, promote, and provide adequate and efficient postal services at fair and reasonable rates and fees. The Postal Service shall receive, transmit, and deliver throughout the United States, its territories and possessions, and, pursuant to arrangements entered into under sections 406 and 411 of this title, throughout the world, written and printed matter, parcels, and like materials and provide such other services incidental thereto as it finds appropriate to its functions and in the public interest. The Postal Service shall serve as nearly as practicable the entire population of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be the responsibility of the Postal Service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to maintain an efficient system of collection, sorting, and delivery of the mail nationwide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide types of mail service to meet the needs of different categories of mail and mail users; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to establish and maintain postal facilities of such character and in such locations, that postal patrons throughout the Nation will, consistent with reasonable economies of postal operations, have ready access to essential postal services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In providing services and in establishing classifications, rates, and fees under this title, the Postal Service shall not, except as specifically authorized in this title, make any undue or unreasonable discrimination among users of the mails, nor shall it grant any undue or unreasonable preferences to any such user.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1331(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 404.</num>
<heading> Specific powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the provisions of section 404a, but otherwise without limitation of the generality of its powers, the Postal Service shall have the following specific powers, among others:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide for the collection, handling, transportation, delivery, forwarding, returning, and holding of mail, and for the disposition of undeliverable mail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to prescribe, in accordance with this title, the amount of postage and the manner in which it is to be paid;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to determine the need for post offices, postal and training facilities and equipment, and to provide such offices, facilities, and equipment as it determines are needed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to provide and sell postage stamps and other stamped paper, cards, and envelopes and to provide such other evidences of payment of postage and fees as may be necessary or desirable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide philatelic services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to investigate postal offenses and civil matters relating to the Postal Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to offer and pay rewards for information and services in connection with violation of the postal laws, and, unless a different disposal is expressly prescribed, to pay one-half of all penalties and forfeitures imposed for violations of law affecting the Postal Service, its revenues, or property, to the person informing for the same, and to pay the other one-half into the Postal Service Fund; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to authorize the issuance of a substitute check for a lost, stolen, or destroyed check of the Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided, the Governors are authorized to establish reasonable and equitable classes of mail and reasonable and equitable rates of postage and fees for postal services in accordance with the provisions of chapter 36. Postal rates and fees shall be reasonable and equitable and sufficient to enable the Postal Service, under best practices of honest, efficient, and economical management, to maintain and continue the development of postal services of the kind and quality adapted to the needs of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall maintain one or more classes of mail for the transmission of letters sealed against inspection. The rate for each such class shall be uniform throughout the United States, its territories, and possessions. One such class shall provide for the most expeditious handling and transportation afforded mail matter by the Postal Service. No letter of such a class of domestic origin shall be opened except under authority of a search warrant authorized by law, or by an officer or employee of the Postal Service for the sole purpose of determining an address at which the letter can be delivered, or pursuant to the authorization of the addressee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Postal Service, prior to making a determination under subsection (a)(3) of this section as to the necessity for the closing or consolidation of any post office, shall provide adequate notice of its intention to close or consolidate such post office at least 60 days prior to the proposed date of such closing or consolidation to persons served by such post office to ensure that such persons will have an opportunity to present their views.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Postal Service, in making a determination whether or not to close or consolidate a post office—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the effect of such closing or consolidation on the community served by such post office;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the effect of such closing or consolidation on employees of the Postal Service employed at such office;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> whether such closing or consolidation is consistent with the policy of the Government, as stated in <ref>section 101(b) of this title</ref>, that the Postal Service shall provide a maximum degree of effective and regular postal services to rural areas, communities, and small towns where post offices are not self-sustaining;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the economic savings to the Postal Service resulting from such closing or consolidation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> such other factors as the Postal Service determines are necessary; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not consider compliance with any provision of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any determination of the Postal Service to close or consolidate a post office shall be in writing and shall include the findings of the Postal Service with respect to the considerations required to be made under paragraph (2) of this subsection. Such determination and findings shall be made available to persons served by such post office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall take no action to close or consolidate a post office until 60 days after its written determination is made available to persons served by such post office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> A determination of the Postal Service to close or consolidate any post office may be appealed by any person served by such office to the Postal Regulatory Commission within 30 days after such determination is made available to such person under paragraph (3). The Commission shall review such determination on the basis of the record before the Postal Service in the making of such determination. The Commission shall make a determination based upon such review no later than 120 days after receiving any appeal under this paragraph. The Commission shall set aside any determination, findings, and conclusions found to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with the law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> without observance of procedure required by law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> unsupported by substantial evidence on the record.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Commission may affirm the determination of the Postal Service or order that the entire matter be returned for further consideration, but the Commission may not modify the determination of the Postal Service. The Commission may suspend the effectiveness of the determination of the Postal Service until the final disposition of the appeal. The provisions of section 556, section 557, and chapter 7 of title 5 shall not apply to any review carried out by the Commission under this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (5), any appeal received by the Commission shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if sent to the Commission through the mails, be considered to have been received on the date of the Postal Service postmark on the envelope or other cover in which such appeal is mailed; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if otherwise lawfully delivered to the Commission, be considered to have been received on the date determined based on any appropriate documentation or other indicia (as determined under regulations of the Commission).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “nonpostal service” means any service that is not a postal service defined under section 102(5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be considered to permit or require that the Postal Service provide any nonpostal service, except that the Postal Service may provide nonpostal services which were offered as of <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>, as provided under this subsection, or any nonpostal products or services authorized by chapter 37.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall review each nonpostal service offered by the Postal Service on the date of enactment of that Act and determine whether that nonpostal service shall continue, taking into account—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the public need for the service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the ability of the private sector to meet the public need for the service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any nonpostal service not determined to be continued by the Postal Regulatory Commission under paragraph (3) shall terminate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If the Postal Regulatory Commission authorizes the Postal Service to continue a nonpostal service under this subsection, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall designate whether the service shall be regulated under this title as a market dominant product, a competitive product, or an experimental product.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–421, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-24">Sept. 24, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1310</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–241, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-09-28">Sept. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, title IV, § 403(b)(2), title VI, § 604(a), title X, §§ 1006(a), 1010(e), <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3200</ref>, 3227, 3241, 3258, 3261; <ref>Pub. L. 117–108, title I, § 103(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-04-06">Apr. 6, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1144</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 404a.</num>
<heading> Specific limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as specifically authorized by law, the Postal Service may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish any rule or regulation (including any standard) the effect of which is to preclude competition or establish the terms of competition unless the Postal Service demonstrates that the regulation does not create an unfair competitive advantage for itself or any entity funded (in whole or in part) by the Postal Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compel the disclosure, transfer, or licensing of intellectual property to any third party (such as patents, copyrights, trademarks, trade secrets, and proprietary information); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> obtain information from a person that provides (or seeks to provide) any product, and then offer any postal service that uses or is based in whole or in part on such information, without the consent of the person providing that information, unless substantially the same information is obtained (or obtainable) from an independent source or is otherwise obtained (or obtainable).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Postal Regulatory Commission shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any party (including an officer of the Commission representing the interests of the general public) who believes that the Postal Service has violated this section may bring a complaint in accordance with section 3662.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3226</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 405.</num>
<heading> Printing of illustrations of United States postage stamps</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When requested by the Postal Service, the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall print, as a public document for sale by the Superintendent of Documents, illustrations in black and white or in color of postage stamps of the United States, together with such descriptive, historical, and philatelic information with regard to the stamps as the Postal Service deems suitable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 505 of title 44</ref>, stereotype or electrotype plates, or duplicates thereof, used in the publications authorized to be printed by this section may not be sold or otherwise disposed of.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 406.</num>
<heading> Postal services at Armed Forces installations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Postal Service may establish branch post offices at camps, posts, bases, or stations of the Armed Forces and at defense or other strategic installations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretaries of Defense and Transportation shall make arrangements with the Postal Service to perform postal services through personnel designated by them at or through branch post offices established under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall authorize the use of a post office established under subsection (a) in a location outside the United States by citizens of the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are employed by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> perform functions in support of the Armed Forces of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if the Secretary makes a written determination that such use is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the best interests of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> otherwise authorized by applicable host nation law or agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No funds may be obligated or expended to establish, maintain, or expand a post office established under subsection (a) for the purpose of use described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title X, § 1056</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1806(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 407.</num>
<heading> International postal arrangements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to promote and encourage communications between peoples by efficient operation of international postal services and other international delivery services for cultural, social, and economic purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote and encourage unrestricted and undistorted competition in the provision of international postal services and other international delivery services, except where provision of such services by private companies may be prohibited by law of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to promote and encourage a clear distinction between governmental and operational responsibilities with respect to the provision of international postal services and other international delivery services by the Government of the United States and by intergovernmental organizations of which the United States is a member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to participate in multilateral and bilateral agreements with other countries to accomplish these objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State shall be responsible for formulation, coordination, and oversight of foreign policy related to international postal services and other international delivery services and shall have the power to conclude postal treaties, conventions, and amendments related to international postal services and other international delivery services, except that the Secretary may not conclude any treaty, convention, or other international agreement (including those regulating international postal services) if such treaty, convention, or agreement would, with respect to any competitive product, grant an undue or unreasonable preference to the Postal Service, a private provider of international postal or delivery services, or any other person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out the responsibilities specified in paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall exercise primary authority for the conduct of foreign policy with respect to international postal services and international delivery services, including the determination of United States positions and the conduct of United States participation in negotiations with foreign governments and international bodies. In exercising this authority, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall coordinate with other agencies as appropriate, and in particular, shall give full consideration to the authority vested by law or Executive order in the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Transportation, and the Office of the United States Trade Representative in this area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall maintain continuing liaison with other executive branch agencies concerned with postal and delivery services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall maintain continuing liaison with the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> shall maintain appropriate liaison with both representatives of the Postal Service and representatives of users and private providers of international postal services and other international delivery services to keep informed of their interests and problems, and to provide such assistance as may be needed to ensure that matters of concern are promptly considered by the Department of State or (if applicable, and to the extent practicable) other executive branch agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> shall assist in arranging meetings of such public sector advisory groups as may be established to advise the Department of State and other executive branch agencies in connection with international postal services and international delivery services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State shall establish an advisory committee (within the meaning of chapter 10 of title 5) to perform such functions as the Secretary considers appropriate in connection with carrying out subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Before concluding any treaty, convention, or amendment that establishes a rate or classification for a product subject to subchapter I of chapter 36, the Secretary of State shall request the Postal Regulatory Commission to submit its views on whether such rate or classification is consistent with the standards and criteria established by the Commission under section 3622.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that each treaty, convention, or amendment concluded under subsection (b) is consistent with the views submitted by the Commission pursuant to paragraph (1), except if, or to the extent, the Secretary determines, in writing, that it is not in the foreign policy or national security interest of the United States to ensure consistency with the Commission’s views. Such written determination shall be provided to the Commission together with a full explanation of the reasons thereof, provided that the Secretary may designate which portions of the determination or explanation shall be kept confidential for reasons of foreign policy or national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section shall be considered to prevent the Postal Service from entering into such commercial or operational contracts related to providing international postal services and other international delivery services as it deems appropriate, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any such contract made with an agency of a foreign government (whether under authority of this subsection or otherwise) shall be solely contractual in nature and may not purport to be international law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a copy of each such contract between the Postal Service and an agency of a foreign government shall be transmitted to the Secretary of State and the Postal Regulatory Commission not later than the effective date of such contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “private company” means a private company substantially owned or controlled by persons who are citizens of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> With respect to shipments of international mail that are competitive products within the meaning of section 3631 that are exported or imported by the Postal Service, the Customs Service and other appropriate Federal agencies shall apply the customs laws of the United States and all other laws relating to the importation or exportation of such shipments in the same manner to both shipments by the Postal Service and similar shipments by private companies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In exercising the authority under subsection (b) to conclude new postal treaties and conventions related to international postal services and to renegotiate such treaties and conventions, the Secretary of State shall, to the maximum extent practicable, take such measures as are within the Secretary’s control to encourage the governments of other countries to make available to the Postal Service and private companies a range of nondiscriminatory customs procedures that will fully meet the needs of all types of American shippers. The Secretary of State shall consult with the United States Trade Representative and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in carrying out this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The provisions of this subsection shall take effect 6 months after the date of enactment of this subsection or such earlier date as the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security may determine in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(h) [title VI, § 633(a)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–480</ref>, 2681–523; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3229</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(226)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 408.</num>
<heading> International money-order exchanges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Postal Service may make arrangements with other governments, with which postal conventions are or may be concluded, for the exchange of sums of money by means of postal orders. It shall fix limitations on the amount which may be so exchanged and the rates of exchange.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 409.</num>
<heading> Suits by and against the Postal Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this title, the United States district courts shall have original but not exclusive jurisdiction over all actions brought by or against the Postal Service. Any action brought in a State court to which the Postal Service is a party may be removed to the appropriate United States district court under the provisions of chapter 89 of title 28.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Unless otherwise provided in this title, the provisions of title 28 relating to service of process, venue, and limitations of time for bringing action in suits in which the United States, its officers, or employees are parties, and the rules of procedure adopted under title 28 for suits in which the United States, its officers, or employees are parties, shall apply in like manner to suits in which the Postal Service, its officers, or employees are parties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The provisions of chapter 171 and all other provisions of title 28 relating to tort claims shall apply to tort claims arising out of activities of the Postal Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of the provisions of law cited in paragraphs (2)(A) and (2)(B), respectively, the Postal Service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be considered to be a “person”, as used in the provisions of law involved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not be immune under any other doctrine of sovereign immunity from suit in Federal court by any person for any violation of any of those provisions of law by any officer or employee of the Postal Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection applies with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1946-07-05">July 5, 1946</date> (commonly referred to as the “Trademark Act of 1946” (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1051</ref> and following)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provisions of section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent that the Postal Service, or other Federal agency acting on behalf of or in concert with the Postal Service, engages in conduct with respect to any product which is not reserved to the United States under <ref>section 1696 of title 18</ref>, the Postal Service or other Federal agency (as the case may be)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not be immune under any doctrine of sovereign immunity from suit in Federal court by any person for any violation of Federal law by such agency or any officer or employee thereof; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> shall be considered to be a person (as defined in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act) for purposes of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the antitrust laws (as defined in such subsection); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of the preceding sentence, any private carriage of mail allowable by virtue of section 601 shall not be considered a service reserved to the United States under <ref>section 1696 of title 18</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No damages, interest on damages, costs or attorney’s fees may be recovered, and no criminal liability may be imposed, under the antitrust laws (as so defined) from any officer or employee of the Postal Service, or other Federal agency acting on behalf of or in concert with the Postal Service, acting in an official capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection shall not apply with respect to conduct occurring before the date of enactment of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each building constructed or altered by the Postal Service shall be constructed or altered, to the maximum extent feasible as determined by the Postal Service, in compliance with 1 of the nationally recognized model building codes and with other applicable nationally recognized codes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each building constructed or altered by the Postal Service shall be constructed or altered only after consideration of all requirements (other than procedural requirements) of zoning laws, land use laws, and applicable environmental laws of a State or subdivision of a State which would apply to the building if it were not a building constructed or altered by an establishment of the Government of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of meeting the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) with respect to a building, the Postal Service shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in preparing plans for the building, consult with appropriate officials of the State or political subdivision, or both, in which the building will be located;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon request, submit such plans in a timely manner to such officials for review by such officials for a reasonable period of time not exceeding 30 days; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> permit inspection by such officials during construction or alteration of the building, in accordance with the customary schedule of inspections for construction or alteration of buildings in the locality, if such officials provide to the Postal Service—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a copy of such schedule before construction of the building is begun; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reasonable notice of their intention to conduct any inspection before conducting such inspection.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Nothing in this subsection shall impose an obligation on any State or political subdivision to take any action under the preceding sentence, nor shall anything in this subsection require the Postal Service or any of its contractors to pay for any action taken by a State or political subdivision to carry out this subsection (including reviewing plans, carrying out on-site inspections, issuing building permits, and making recommendations).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Appropriate officials of a State or a political subdivision of a State may make recommendations to the Postal Service concerning measures necessary to meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2). Such officials may also make recommendations to the Postal Service concerning measures which should be taken in the construction or alteration of the building to take into account local conditions. The Postal Service shall give due consideration to any such recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In addition to consulting with local and State officials under paragraph (3), the Postal Service shall establish procedures for soliciting, assessing, and incorporating local community input on real property and land use decisions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, legal representation may not be furnished by the Department of Justice to the Postal Service in any action, suit, or proceeding arising, in whole or in part, under any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subsection (d) or (e) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subsection (f) or (g) of section 504 (relating to administrative subpoenas by the Postal Regulatory Commission).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Section 3663 (relating to appellate review).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Postal Service may, by contract or otherwise, employ attorneys to obtain any legal representation that it is precluded from obtaining from the Department of Justice under this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In any circumstance not covered by paragraph (1), the Department of Justice shall, under section 411, furnish the Postal Service such legal representation as it may require, except that, with the prior consent of the Attorney General, the Postal Service may, in any such circumstance, employ attorneys by contract or otherwise to conduct litigation brought by or against the Postal Service or its officers or employees in matters affecting the Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In any action, suit, or proceeding in a court of the United States arising in whole or in part under any of the provisions of law referred to in subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (1), and to which the Commission is not otherwise a party, the Commission shall be permitted to appear as a party on its own motion and as of right.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Department of Justice shall, under such terms and conditions as the Commission and the Attorney General shall consider appropriate, furnish the Commission such legal representation as it may require in connection with any such action, suit, or proceeding, except that, with the prior consent of the Attorney General, the Commission may employ attorneys by contract or otherwise for that purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> A judgment against the Government of the United States arising out of activities of the Postal Service shall be paid by the Postal Service out of any funds available to the Postal Service, subject to the restriction specified in section 2011(g).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(k)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 410.</num>
<heading> Application of other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided by subsection (b) of this section, and except as otherwise provided in this title or insofar as such laws remain in force as rules or regulations of the Postal Service, no Federal law dealing with public or Federal contracts, property, works, officers, employees, budgets, or funds, including the provisions of chapters 5 and 7 of title 5, shall apply to the exercise of the powers of the Postal Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The following provisions shall apply to the Postal Service:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 552 (public information), section 552a (records about individuals), section 552b (open meetings), section 3102 (employment of personal assistants for blind, deaf, or otherwise handicapped employees), section 3110 (restrictions on employment of relatives), section 3333 and chapters 72 (antidiscrimination; right to petition Congress) and 73 (suitability, security, and conduct of employees), section 5520 (withholding city income or employment taxes), and section 5532 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref> (dual pay) of title 5, except that no regulation issued under such chapters or section shall apply to the Postal Service unless expressly made applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all provisions of title 18 dealing with the Postal Service, the mails, and officers or employees of the Government of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content><ref>section 107 of title 20</ref> (known as the Randolph-Sheppard Act, relating to vending machines operated by the blind);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the following provisions of title 40:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sections 3114–3116, 3118, 3131, 3133, and 3141–3147; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> chapters 37 and 173;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> chapters 65 and 67 of title 41;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> sections 2000d, 2000d–1—2000d–4 of title 42 (title VI, the Civil Rights Act of 1964);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> section 19 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 668</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the provisions of the Act of <date date="1968-08-12">August 12, 1968</date> (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4151–415</ref>6);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> chapter 39 of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> chapter 4 of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content><ref>section 5520a of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (b)(1) of this section shall not require the disclosure of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name or address, past or present, of any postal patron;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information of a commercial nature, including trade secrets, whether or not obtained from a person outside the Postal Service, which under good business practice would not be publicly disclosed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> information prepared for use in connection with the negotiation of collective-bargaining agreements under chapter 12 of this title or minutes of, or notes kept during, negotiating sessions conducted under such chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> information prepared for use in connection with proceedings under chapter 36 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the reports and memoranda of consultants or independent contractors except to the extent that they would be required to be disclosed if prepared within the Postal Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> investigatory files, whether or not considered closed, compiled for law enforcement purposes except to the extent available by law to a party other than the Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A lease agreement by the Postal Service for rent of net interior space in excess of 6,500 square feet in any building or facility, or part of a building or facility, to be occupied for purposes of the Postal Service shall include a provision that all laborers and mechanics employed in the construction, modification, alteration, repair, painting, decoration, or other improvement of the building or space covered by the agreement, or improvement at the site of such building or facility, shall be paid wages at not less than those prevailing for similar work in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor under <ref>section 3142 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority and functions of the Secretary of Labor with respect to labor standards enforcement under Reorganization Plan numbered 14 of 1950 (title 5, appendix), and regulations for contractors and subcontractors under <ref>section 3145 of title 40</ref>, shall apply to the work under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraph (2) of this subsection shall not be construed to give the Secretary of Labor authority to direct the cancellation of the lease agreement referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–656, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-01-08">Jan. 8, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1955</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–340, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-07-10">July 10, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–82, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–409, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-13">Sept. 13, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–541, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, title VII, § 703(c)(4), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1146</ref>, 1217; <ref>Pub. L. 96–523, § 1(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3040</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–496, § 2(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–504, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-18">Oct. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–82, title II, § 202(g)(6)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 9(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–123, title VII, § 708(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 662(f)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–382; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(k)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 4(j)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(k)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3850</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(63)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 411.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with other Government agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Executive agencies within the meaning of <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref> and the Government Publishing Office are authorized to furnish property, both real and personal, and personal and nonpersonal services to the Postal Service, and the Postal Service is authorized to furnish property and services to them. The furnishing of property and services under this section shall be under such terms and conditions, including reimbursability within the limitations of chapter 37, as the Postal Service and the head of the agency concerned shall deem appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–108, title I, § 103(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-04-06">Apr. 6, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1144</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 412.</num>
<heading> Nondisclosure of lists of names and addresses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as specifically provided by subsection (b) or other law, no officer or employee of the Postal Service shall make available to the public by any means or for any purpose any mailing or other list of names or addresses (past or present) of postal patrons or other persons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Postal Service shall provide to the Secretary of Commerce for use by the Bureau of the Census such address information, address-related information, and point of postal delivery information, including postal delivery codes, as may be determined by the Secretary to be appropriate for any census or survey being conducted by the Bureau of the Census. The provision of such information under this subsection shall be in accordance with such mutually agreeable terms and conditions, including reimbursability, as the Postal Service and the Secretary of Commerce shall deem appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–430, § 4</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 413.</num>
<heading> Postal services at diplomatic posts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Postal Service and the Department of State may enter into 1 or more agreements for field testing to ascertain the feasibility of providing postal services through personnel provided by the Department of State at branch post offices established by the Postal Service in United States diplomatic missions at locations abroad for which branch post offices are not established under section 406.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> To the extent that the Postal Service and the Department of State conclude it to be feasible and in the public interest, the Postal Service may establish branch post offices at United States diplomatic missions in locations abroad for which branch post offices are not established under section 406, and the Department of State may enter into an agreement with the Postal Service to perform postal services at such branch post offices through personnel designated by the Department of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Department of State shall reimburse the Postal Service for any amounts, determined by the Postal Service, equal to the additional costs incurred by the Postal Service, including transportation costs, incurred by the Postal Service in the performance of its obligations under any agreement entered into under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Each agreement entered into under this section shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provisions under which the Department of State shall make any reimbursements required under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provisions authorizing the Postal Service to terminate the agreement, and the services provided thereunder, in the event that the Department of State does not comply with the provisions under paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other provisions which may be necessary, including provisions relating to the closing of a post office under this section if necessary because a post office under section 406 is established in the same location.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–524, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-06">Nov. 6, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 414.</num>
<heading> Special postage stamps</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In order to afford the public a convenient way to contribute to funding for breast cancer research, the Postal Service shall establish a special rate of postage for first-class mail under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The rate of postage established under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be equal to the regular first-class rate of postage, plus a differential of not less than 15 percent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be set by the Governors in accordance with such procedures as the Governors shall by regulation prescribe (in lieu of the procedures under chapter 36); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be offered as an alternative to the regular first-class rate of postage.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The use of the special rate of postage established under this section shall be voluntary on the part of postal patrons. The special rate of postage of an individual stamp under this section shall be an amount that is evenly divisible by 5.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Of the amounts becoming available for breast cancer research pursuant to this section, the Postal Service shall pay—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 70 percent to the National Institutes of Health; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the remainder to the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Payments under this paragraph to an agency shall be made under such arrangements as the Postal Service shall by mutual agreement with such agency establish in order to carry out the purposes of this section, except that, under those arrangements, payments to such agency shall be made at least twice a year. An agency that receives amounts from the Postal Service under this paragraph shall use the amounts for breast cancer research.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, the term “amounts becoming available for breast cancer research pursuant to this section” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the total amounts received by the Postal Service that it would not have received but for the enactment of this section, reduced by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an amount sufficient to cover reasonable costs incurred by the Postal Service in carrying out this section, including those attributable to the printing, sale, and distribution of stamps under this section,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">as determined by the Postal Service under regulations that it shall prescribe.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> It is the sense of the Congress that nothing in this section should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> directly or indirectly cause a net decrease in total funds received by the National Institutes of Health, the Department of Defense, or any other agency of the Government (or any component or program thereof) below the level that would otherwise have been received but for the enactment of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> affect regular first-class rates of postage or any other regular rates of postage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Special postage stamps under this section shall be made available to the public beginning on such date as the Postal Service shall by regulation prescribe, but in no event later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> The Postmaster General shall include in each report rendered under section 2402 with respect to any period during any portion of which this section is in effect information concerning the operation of this section, except that, at a minimum, each shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the total amount described in subsection (c)(2)(A) which was received by the Postal Service during the period covered by such report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of the amount under paragraph (1), how much (in the aggregate and by category) was required for the purposes described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> For purposes of section 416 (including any regulation prescribed under subsection (e)(1)(C) of that section), the special postage stamp issued under this section shall not apply to any limitation relating to whether more than 1 semipostal may be offered for sale at the same time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> This section shall cease to be effective after <date date="2027-12-31">December 31, 2027</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–41, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-13">Aug. 13, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1119</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–253, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-07-28">July 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–67, title VI, § 650(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 556</ref>, 557; <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. F, title V, § 541</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–100, § 1</ref>, <date date="2005-11-11">Nov. 11, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–150, § 1</ref>, <date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1820</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–80, § 1</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–99</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="2015-12-11">Dec. 11, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2201</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1737</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 415.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on restriction or elimination of services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Postal Service may not restrict, eliminate, or adversely affect any service provided by the Postal Service as a result of the payment of any penalty imposed under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–241, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-09-28">Sept. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 416.</num>
<heading> Authority to issue semipostals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “semipostal” means a postage stamp which is issued and sold by the Postal Service, at a premium, in order to help provide funding for a cause described in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “agency” means an Executive agency within the meaning of <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discretionary Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postal Service is hereby authorized to issue and sell semipostals under this section in order to advance such causes as the Postal Service considers to be in the national public interest and appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate of Postage</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The rate of postage on a semipostal issued under this section shall be established by the Governors, in accordance with such procedures as they shall by regulation prescribe (in lieu of the procedures under chapter 36), except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the rate established for a semipostal under this section shall be equal to the rate of postage that would otherwise regularly apply, plus a differential of not less than 15 percent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no regular rates of postage or fees for postal services under chapter 36 shall be any different from what they otherwise would have been if this section had not been enacted.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The use of any semipostal issued under this section shall be voluntary on the part of postal patrons. The special rate of postage of an individual stamp under this section shall be an amount that is evenly divisible by 5.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Amounts Becoming Available.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amounts becoming available from the sale of a semipostal under this section shall be transferred to the appropriate agency or agencies under such arrangements as the Postal Service shall by mutual agreement with each such agency establish.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification of appropriate causes and agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Decisions concerning the identification of appropriate causes and agencies to receive amounts becoming available from the sale of a semipostal under this section shall be made in accordance with applicable regulations under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Determination of amounts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amounts becoming available from the sale of a semipostal under this section shall be determined in a manner similar to that provided for under section 414(c)(2) (as in effect on <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Regulations under subsection (e) shall specifically address how the costs incurred by the Postal Service in carrying out this section shall be computed, recovered, and kept to a minimum.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other funding not to be affected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts which have or may become available from the sale of a semipostal under this section shall not be taken into account in any decision relating to the level of appropriations or other Federal funding to be furnished to an agency in any year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recovery of costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before transferring to an agency in accordance with paragraph (1) any amounts becoming available from the sale of a semipostal over any period, the Postal Service shall ensure that it has recovered the full costs incurred by the Postal Service in connection with such semipostal through the end of such period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Postal Service shall prescribe any regulations necessary to carry out this section, including provisions relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which office or other authority within the Postal Service shall be responsible for making the decisions described in subsection (d)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> what criteria and procedures shall be applied in making those decisions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> what limitations shall apply, if any, relating to the issuance of semipostals (such as whether more than one semipostal may be offered for sale at the same time).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and comment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before any regulation is issued under this section, a copy of the proposed regulation shall be published in the Federal Register, and an opportunity shall be provided for interested parties to present written and, where practicable, oral comment. All regulations necessary to carry out this section shall be issued not later than 30 days before the date on which semipostals are first made available to the public under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Postmaster General shall include in each report rendered under section 2402, with respect to any period during any portion of which this section is in effect, information concerning the operation of any program established under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specific requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If any semipostal ceases to be offered during the period covered by such a report, the information contained in that report shall also include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the commencement and termination dates for the sale of such semipostal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total amount that became available from the sale of such semipostal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> of that total amount, how much was applied toward administrative costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For each year before the year in which a semipostal ceases to be offered, any report under this subsection shall include, with respect to that semipostal (for the year covered by such report), the information described in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall cease to be effective at the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date on which semipostals are first made available to the public under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–253, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-07-28">July 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 634</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–67, title VI, § 652(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 557</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–117, div. B, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2002-01-10">Jan. 10, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>