<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 22—</num>
<heading>EMPLOYEE POLYGRAPH PROTECTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2001.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “commerce” has the meaning provided by <ref>section 203(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “employer” includes any person acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation to an employee or prospective employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lie detector</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “lie detector” includes a polygraph, deceptograph, voice stress analyzer, psychological stress evaluator, or any other similar device (whether mechanical or electrical) that is used, or the results of which are used, for the purpose of rendering a diagnostic opinion regarding the honesty or dishonesty of an individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Polygraph</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “polygraph” means an instrument that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> records continuously, visually, permanently, and simultaneously changes in cardiovascular, respiratory, and electrodermal patterns as minimum instrumentation standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is used, or the results of which are used, for the purpose of rendering a diagnostic opinion regarding the honesty or dishonesty of an individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 646</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2002.</num>
<heading> Prohibitions on lie detector use</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in sections 2006 and 2007 of this title, it shall be unlawful for any employer engaged in or affecting commerce or in the production of goods for commerce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> directly or indirectly, to require, request, suggest, or cause any employee or prospective employee to take or submit to any lie detector test;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to use, accept, refer to, or inquire concerning the results of any lie detector test of any employee or prospective employee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to discharge, discipline, discriminate against in any manner, or deny employment or promotion to, or threaten to take any such action against—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any employee or prospective employee who refuses, declines, or fails to take or submit to any lie detector test, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any employee or prospective employee on the basis of the results of any lie detector test; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> to discharge, discipline, discriminate against in any manner, or deny employment or promotion to, or threaten to take any such action against, any employee or prospective employee because—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such employee or prospective employee has filed any complaint or instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding under or related to this chapter,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such employee or prospective employee has testified or is about to testify in any such proceeding, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> of the exercise by such employee or prospective employee, on behalf of such employee or another person, of any right afforded by this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 646</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2003.</num>
<heading> Notice of protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare, have printed, and distribute a notice setting forth excerpts from, or summaries of, the pertinent provisions of this chapter. Each employer shall post and maintain such notice in conspicuous places on its premises where notices to employees and applicants to employment are customarily posted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 647</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2004.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cooperate with regional, State, local, and other agencies, and cooperate with and furnish technical assistance to employers, labor organizations, and employment agencies to aid in effectuating the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make investigations and inspections and require the keeping of records necessary or appropriate for the administration of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpoena authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of any hearing or investigation under this chapter, the Secretary shall have the authority contained in sections 49 and 50 of title 15.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 647</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2005.</num>
<heading> Enforcement provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), any employer who violates any provision of this chapter may be assessed a civil penalty of not more than $10,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In determining the amount of any penalty under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall take into account the previous record of the person in terms of compliance with this chapter and the gravity of the violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any civil penalty assessed under this subsection shall be collected in the same manner as is required by subsections (b) through (e) of <ref>section 1853 of this title</ref> with respect to civil penalties assessed under subsection (a) of such section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Injunctive actions by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may bring an action under this section to restrain violations of this chapter. The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary in any litigation brought under this chapter. In any action brought under this section, the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, to issue temporary or permanent restraining orders and injunctions to require compliance with this chapter, including such legal or equitable relief incident thereto as may be appropriate, including, but not limited to, employment, reinstatement, promotion, and the payment of lost wages and benefits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private civil actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employer who violates this chapter shall be liable to the employee or prospective employee affected by such violation. Such employer shall be liable for such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate, including, but not limited to, employment, reinstatement, promotion, and the payment of lost wages and benefits.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An action to recover the liability prescribed in paragraph (1) may be maintained against the employer in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction by an employee or prospective employee for or on behalf of such employee, prospective employee, and other employees or prospective employees similarly situated. No such action may be commenced more than 3 years after the date of the alleged violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The court, in its discretion, may allow the prevailing party (other than the United States) reasonable costs, including attorney’s fees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of rights prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The rights and procedures provided by this chapter may not be waived by contract or otherwise, unless such waiver is part of a written settlement agreed to and signed by the parties to the pending action or complaint under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 647</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2006.</num>
<heading> Exemptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No application to governmental employers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not apply with respect to the United States Government, any State or local government, or any political subdivision of a State or local government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National defense and security exemption</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National defense</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the administration, by the Federal Government, in the performance of any counterintelligence function, of any lie detector test to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any expert or consultant under contract to the Department of Defense or any employee of any contractor of such Department; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any expert or consultant under contract with the Department of Energy in connection with the atomic energy defense activities of such Department or any employee of any contractor of such Department in connection with such activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the administration, by the Federal Government, in the performance of any intelligence or counterintelligence function, of any lie detector test to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any individual employed by, assigned to, or detailed to, the National Security Agency, the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, or the Central Intelligence Agency,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any expert or consultant under contract to any such agency,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any employee of a contractor to any such agency,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any individual applying for a position in any such agency, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any individual assigned to a space where sensitive cryptologic information is produced, processed, or stored for any such agency; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any expert, or consultant (or employee of such expert or consultant) under contract with any Federal Government department, agency, or program whose duties involve access to information that has been classified at the level of top secret or designated as being within a special access program under section 4.2(a) of Executive Order 12356 (or a successor Executive order).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FBI contractors exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the administration, by the Federal Government, in the performance of any counterintelligence function, of any lie detector test to an employee of a contractor of the Federal Bureau of Investigation of the Department of Justice who is engaged in the performance of any work under the contract with such Bureau.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited exemption for ongoing investigations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to sections 2007 and 2009 of this title, this chapter shall not prohibit an employer from requesting an employee to submit to a polygraph test if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the test is administered in connection with an ongoing investigation involving economic loss or injury to the employer’s business, such as theft, embezzlement, misappropriation, or an act of unlawful industrial espionage or sabotage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the employee had access to the property that is the subject of the investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the employer has a reasonable suspicion that the employee was involved in the incident or activity under investigation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the employer executes a statement, provided to the examinee before the test, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sets forth with particularity the specific incident or activity being investigated and the basis for testing particular employees,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is signed by a person (other than a polygraph examiner) authorized to legally bind the employer,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is retained by the employer for at least 3 years, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> contains at a minimum—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an identification of the specific economic loss or injury to the business of the employer,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a statement indicating that the employee had access to the property that is the subject of the investigation, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a statement describing the basis of the employer’s reasonable suspicion that the employee was involved in the incident or activity under investigation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for security services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2) and sections 2007 and 2009 of this title, this chapter shall not prohibit the use of polygraph tests on prospective employees by any private employer whose primary business purpose consists of providing armored car personnel, personnel engaged in the design, installation, and maintenance of security alarm systems, or other uniformed or plainclothes security personnel and whose function includes protection of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> facilities, materials, or operations having a significant impact on the health or safety of any State or political subdivision thereof, or the national security of the United States, as determined under rules and regulations issued by the Secretary within 90 days after <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> facilities engaged in the production, transmission, or distribution of electric or nuclear power,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> public water supply facilities,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shipments or storage of radioactive or other toxic waste materials, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> public transportation, or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> currency, negotiable securities, precious commodities or instruments, or proprietary information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The exemption provided under this subsection shall not apply if the test is administered to a prospective employee who would not be employed to protect facilities, materials, operations, or assets referred to in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for drug security, drug theft, or drug diversion investigations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2) and sections 2007 and 2009 of this title, this chapter shall not prohibit the use of a polygraph test by any employer authorized to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance listed in schedule I, II, III, or IV of <ref>section 812 of title 21</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The exemption provided under this subsection shall apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the test is administered to a prospective employee who would have direct access to the manufacture, storage, distribution, or sale of any such controlled substance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a test administered to a current employee, if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the test is administered in connection with an ongoing investigation of criminal or other misconduct involving, or potentially involving, loss or injury to the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of any such controlled substance by such employer, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the employee had access to the person or property that is the subject of the investigation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 7</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 648</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501(n)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1122(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 931(b)(3), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2007.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on use of exemptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Test as basis for adverse employment action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Under ongoing investigations exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the exemption under subsection (d) of <ref>section 2006 of this title</ref> shall not apply if an employee is discharged, disciplined, denied employment or promotion, or otherwise discriminated against in any manner on the basis of the analysis of a polygraph test chart or the refusal to take a polygraph test, without additional supporting evidence. The evidence required by such subsection may serve as additional supporting evidence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Under other exemptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of an exemption described in subsection (e) or (f) of such section, the exemption shall not apply if the results of an analysis of a polygraph test chart are used, or the refusal to take a polygraph test is used, as the sole basis upon which an adverse employment action described in paragraph (1) is taken against an employee or prospective employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of examinee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The exemptions provided under subsections (d), (e), and (f) of <ref>section 2006 of this title</ref> shall not apply unless the requirements described in the following paragraphs are met:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> All phases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Throughout all phases of the test—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the examinee shall be permitted to terminate the test at any time;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the examinee is not asked questions in a manner designed to degrade, or needlessly intrude on, such examinee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the examinee is not asked any question concerning—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> religious beliefs or affiliations,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> beliefs or opinions regarding racial matters,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> political beliefs or affiliations,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any matter relating to sexual behavior; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> beliefs, affiliations, opinions, or lawful activities regarding unions or labor organizations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the examiner does not conduct the test if there is sufficient written evidence by a physician that the examinee is suffering from a medical or psychological condition or undergoing treatment that might cause abnormal responses during the actual testing phase.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pretest phase</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">During the pretest phase, the prospective examinee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is provided with reasonable written notice of the date, time, and location of the test, and of such examinee’s right to obtain and consult with legal counsel or an employee representative before each phase of the test;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is informed in writing of the nature and characteristics of the tests and of the instruments involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> is informed, in writing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> whether the testing area contains a two-way mirror, a camera, or any other device through which the test can be observed,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> whether any other device, including any device for recording or monitoring the test, will be used, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that the employer or the examinee may (with mutual knowledge) make a recording of the test;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> is read and signs a written notice informing such examinee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that the examinee cannot be required to take the test as a condition of employment,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that any statement made during the test may constitute additional supporting evidence for the purposes of an adverse employment action described in subsection (a),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> of the limitations imposed under this section,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> of the legal rights and remedies available to the examinee if the polygraph test is not conducted in accordance with this chapter, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> of the legal rights and remedies of the employer under this chapter (including the rights of the employer under <ref>section 2008(c)(2) of this title</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> is provided an opportunity to review all questions to be asked during the test and is informed of the right to terminate the test at any time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actual testing phase</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">During the actual testing phase, the examiner does not ask such examinee any question relevant during the test that was not presented in writing for review to such examinee before the test.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Post-test phase</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Before any adverse employment action, the employer shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> further interview the examinee on the basis of the results of the test; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> provide the examinee with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a written copy of any opinion or conclusion rendered as a result of the test, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a copy of the questions asked during the test along with the corresponding charted responses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum number and minimum duration of tests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The examiner shall not conduct and complete more than five polygraph tests on a calendar day on which the test is given, and shall not conduct any such test for less than a 90-minute duration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications and requirements of examiners</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The exemptions provided under subsections (d), (e), and (f) of <ref>section 2006 of this title</ref> shall not apply unless the individual who conducts the polygraph test satisfies the requirements under the following paragraphs:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The examiner—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has a valid and current license granted by licensing and regulatory authorities in the State in which the test is to be conducted, if so required by the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintains a minimum of a $50,000 bond or an equivalent amount of professional liability coverage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The examiner—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> renders any opinion or conclusion regarding the test—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in writing and solely on the basis of an analysis of polygraph test charts,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that does not contain information other than admissions, information, case facts, and interpretation of the charts relevant to the purpose and stated objectives of the test, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that does not include any recommendation concerning the employment of the examinee; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintains all opinions, reports, charts, written questions, lists, and other records relating to the test for a minimum period of 3 years after administration of the test.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 8</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2008.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person, other than the examinee, may not disclose information obtained during a polygraph test, except as provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted disclosures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A polygraph examiner may disclose information acquired from a polygraph test only to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the examinee or any other person specifically designated in writing by the examinee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the employer that requested the test; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any court, governmental agency, arbitrator, or mediator, in accordance with due process of law, pursuant to an order from a court of competent jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure by employer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An employer (other than an employer described in subsection (a), (b), or (c) of <ref>section 2006 of this title</ref>) for whom a polygraph test is conducted may disclose information from the test only to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a person in accordance with subsection (b); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a governmental agency, but only insofar as the disclosed information is an admission of criminal conduct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 9</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 652</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2009.</num>
<heading> Effect on other law and agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsections (a), (b), and (c) of <ref>section 2006 of this title</ref>, this chapter shall not preempt any provision of any State or local law or of any negotiated collective bargaining agreement that prohibits lie detector tests or is more restrictive with respect to lie detector tests than any provision of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–347, § 10</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>