<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>HELEN KELLER NATIONAL CENTER FOR YOUTHS AND ADULTS WHO ARE DEAF-BLIND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1901.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> deaf-blindness is among the most severe of all forms of disabilities, and there is a great and continuing need for services and training to help individuals who are deaf-blind attain the highest possible level of development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> due to the rubella epidemic of the 1960’s, the rapidly increasing number of older persons many of whom are experiencing significant losses of both vision and hearing, and recent advances in medical technology that have sustained the lives of many severely disabled individuals, including individuals who are deaf-blind, who might not otherwise have survived, the need for services for individuals who are deaf-blind is even more pressing now than in the past;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> helping individuals who are deaf-blind to become self-sufficient, independent, and employable by providing the services and training necessary to accomplish that end will benefit the Nation, both economically and socially;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Helen Keller National Center for Youths and Adults who are Deaf-Blind is a vital national resource for meeting the needs of individuals who are deaf-blind and no State currently has the facilities or personnel to meet such needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Federal Government has made a substantial investment in capital, equipment, and operating funds for such Center since it was established; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> it is in the national interest to continue to provide support for the Center, and it is a proper function of the Federal Government to be the primary source of such support.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–569, title IX</ref>, §§ 901, 908(a), (c)(1), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4482</ref>, 4485, 4486.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1902.</num>
<heading> Continued operation of Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration by Secretary of Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education shall continue to administer and support the Helen Keller National Center for Youths and Adults who are Deaf-Blind in the same manner as such Center was administered prior to <date date="1984-02-22">February 22, 1984</date>, to the extent such manner of administration is not inconsistent with any purpose described in subsection (b) or any other requirement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of Center</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the Center are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide specialized intensive services, or any other services, at the Center or anywhere else in the United States, which are necessary to encourage the maximum personal development of any individual who is deaf-blind;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> train family members of individuals who are deaf-blind at the Center or anywhere else in the United States, in order to assist family members in providing and obtaining appropriate services for the individual who is deaf-blind;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> train professionals and allied personnel at the Center or anywhere else in the United States to provide services to individuals who are deaf-blind; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conduct applied research, development programs, and demonstrations with respect to communication techniques, teaching methods, aids and devices, and delivery of services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 33</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–569, title IX</ref>, §§ 902, 908, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4482</ref>, 4485.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1903.</num>
<heading> Audit; monitoring and evaluation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The books and accounts of the Center shall be audited annually by an independent auditor in the manner prescribed by the Secretary and a report on each such audit shall be submitted by the auditor to the Secretary within 15 days following the completion of the audit and acceptance of the audit by the Center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish procedures for monitoring, on a regular basis, the services performed and the training conducted by the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall, in addition to the regular monitoring required under paragraph (1), conduct an evaluation of the operation of the Center at the end of each fiscal year. A written report of such evaluation shall be submitted to the President, the Clerk of the House of Representatives, and the Secretary of the Senate within one hundred and eighty days after the end of the fiscal year for which such evaluation was conducted. The first such report shall be submitted for fiscal year 1983.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 33</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–569, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1904.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this chapter such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1999 through 2003. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any appropriation Act containing any appropriation authorized by subsection (a) shall contain a statement of the specific amount being made available to the Center.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 33</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–506, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–630, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3317</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–52, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-06">June 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 263</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–569, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title IV, § 412(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1905.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “Helen Keller National Center for Youths and Adults who are Deaf-Blind” and “Center” mean the Helen Keller National Center for Youths and Adults who are Deaf-Blind, and its affiliated network, operated pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “individual who is deaf-blind” means any individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who has a central visual acuity of 20/200 or less in the better eye with corrective lenses, or a field defect such that the peripheral diameter of visual field subtends an angular distance no greater than 20 degrees, or a progressive visual loss having a prognosis leading to one or both these conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who has a chronic hearing impairment so severe that most speech cannot be understood with optimum amplification, or a progressive hearing loss having a prognosis leading to this condition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> for whom the combination of impairments described in clauses (i) and (ii) cause extreme difficulty in attaining independence in daily life activities, achieving psychosocial adjustment, or obtaining a vocation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who despite the inability to be measured accurately for hearing and vision loss due to cognitive or behavioral constraints, or both, can be determined through functional and performance assessment to have severe hearing and visual disabilities that cause extreme difficulty in attaining independence in daily life activities, achieving psychosocial adjustment, or obtaining vocational objectives; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> meets such other requirements as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–569, title IX</ref>, §§ 905, 908(c)(1), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4482</ref>, 4486.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1906.</num>
<heading> Construction; effect on agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not be construed as modifying or affecting any agreement between the Department of Education or any other department or agency of the United States and the Helen Keller Services for the Blind, Incorporated, or any successor to or assignee of such corporation, with respect to the Center.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–569, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1907.</num>
<heading> Helen Keller National Center Federal Endowment Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the Board of Directors of the Helen Keller National Center are authorized to establish the Helen Keller National Center Federal Endowment Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Endowment Fund”) in accordance with the provisions of this section, to promote the financial independence of the Helen Keller National Center. The Secretary and the Board may enter into such agreements as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall make payments to the Endowment Fund from amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (h), consistent with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall make payments to the Endowment Fund in amounts equal to sums contributed to the Endowment Fund from non-Federal sources (excluding transfers from other endowment funds of the Center).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Center, in investing the Endowment Fund corpus and income, shall exercise the judgment and care, under the prevailing circumstances, which a person of prudence, discretion, and intelligence would exercise in the management of that person’s own business affairs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federally insured investments and other investments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Endowment Fund corpus and income shall be invested in federally insured bank savings accounts or comparable interest bearing accounts, certificates of deposit, money market funds, mutual funds, obligations of the United States, or other low-risk instruments and securities in which a regulated insurance company may invest under the laws of the State of New York.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real estate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Endowment Fund corpus and income may not be invested in real estate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflict of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Endowment Fund corpus or income may not be invested in instruments or securities issued by an organization in which an executive officer is a controlling shareholder, director, or owner within the meaning of Federal securities laws and other applicable laws.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Encumbrances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Center may not assign, hypothecate, encumber, or create a lien on the Endowment Fund corpus without specific written authorization of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawals and expenditures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For a 20-year period following the receipt of a payment under this section, the Center shall not withdraw or expend the Federal payment or matching contribution made to the Endowment Fund corpus. On the expiration of such period, the Center may use the Endowment Fund corpus plus any of the Endowment Fund income for any purpose that benefits individuals who are deaf-blind.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operational and commercial expenses</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Helen Keller National Center may withdraw or expend the Endowment Fund income for any expenses necessary for the operation of the Center, including expenses of operations and maintenance, administration, academic and support personnel, construction and renovation, community and client services programs, technical assistance, and research.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Center may not withdraw or expend the Endowment Fund income for any commercial purpose.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations and waiver of limitations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Center shall not withdraw or expend more than 50 percent of the total aggregate Endowment Fund income earned prior to the time of withdrawal or expenditure.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may permit the Center to withdraw or expend more than 50 percent of its total aggregate endowment income where the Center demonstrates to the Secretary’s satisfaction that such withdrawal or expenditure is necessary because of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a financial emergency, such as a pending insolvency or temporary liquidity problem;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a life-threatening situation occasioned by a natural disaster or arson; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> another unusual occurrence or exigent circumstance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Helen Keller National Center shall keep accurate financial records relating to the operation of the Endowment Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit and report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Center shall arrange for the conduct of an annual financial and compliance audit of the Endowment Fund in the manner prescribed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 1903(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Center shall submit a copy of the report on the audit required under subparagraph (A) to the Secretary within 15 days after completion of the audit and acceptance of the audit by the Center.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Center shall provide to the Secretary an annual report on the uses of funds provided by the Federal endowment program authorized under this section. Such report shall contain such information, and be in such form as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery of payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary is authorized to recover any Federal payments made under this section if the Helen Keller National Center—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> makes a withdrawal or expenditure from the Endowment Fund corpus or income which is not consistent with the provisions of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fails to comply with the investment standards and limitations under this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> fails to account properly to the Secretary concerning the investment of or expenditures from the Endowment Fund corpus or income.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Endowment fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “endowment fund” means a fund, or a tax-exempt foundation, established and maintained by the Helen Keller National Center for the purpose of generating income for the support of the Center.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Endowment Fund corpus</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Endowment Fund corpus” means an amount equal to the Federal payments made to the Endowment Fund and amounts contributed to the Endowment Fund from non-Federal sources.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Endowment Fund income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Endowment Fund income” means an amount equal to the total market value of the Endowment Fund minus the Endowment Fund corpus.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1999 through 2003. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 208</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–569, title IX, § 907</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4483</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title IV, § 412(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1908.</num>
<heading> Registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist the Center in providing services to individuals who are deaf-blind, the Center may establish and maintain registries of such individuals in each of the regional field offices of the network of the Center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary provision of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No individual who is deaf-blind may be required to provide information to the Center for any purpose with respect to a registry established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondisclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Center (including the network of the Center) may not disclose information contained in a registry established under subsection (a) to any individual or organization that is not affiliated with the Center, unless the individual to whom the information relates provides specific written authorization for the Center to disclose the information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privacy rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirements of <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the “Privacy Act of 1974”) shall apply to personally identifiable information contained in the registries established by the Center under subsection (a), in the same manner and to the same extent as such requirements apply to a record of an agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the request of an individual, the Center shall remove all information relating to the individual from any registry established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 209</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title IV, § 412(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>