<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 27—</num>
<heading>WOMEN IN APPRENTICESHIP AND NONTRADITIONAL OCCUPATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2501.</num>
<heading> Findings; statement of purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> American businesses now and for the remainder of the 20th century will face a dramatically different labor market than the one to which they have become accustomed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> two in every three new entrants to the work force will be women, and to meet labor needs such women must work in all occupational areas including in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> women face significant barriers to their full and effective participation in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the business community must be prepared to address the barriers that women have to such jobs, in order to successfully integrate them into the work force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> few resources are available to employers and unions who need assistance in recruiting, training, and retaining women in apprenticeable occupations and other nontraditional occupations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to provide technical assistance to employers and labor unions to encourage employment of women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations. Such assistance will enable business to meet the challenge of Workforce 2000 by preparing employers to successfully recruit, train, and retain women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations and will expand the employment and self-sufficiency options of women. This purpose will be achieved by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promoting the program to employers and labor unions to inform them of the availability of technical assistance which will assist them in preparing the workplace to employ women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> providing grants to community-based organizations to deliver technical assistance to employers and labor unions to prepare them to recruit, train, and employ women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authorizing the Department of Labor to serve as a liaison between employers, labor, and the community-based organizations providing technical assistance, through its national office and its regional administrators; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conducting a comprehensive study to examine the barriers to the participation of women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations and to develop recommendations for the workplace to eliminate such barriers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3465</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2502.</num>
<heading> Outreach to employers and labor unions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With funds available to the Secretary of Labor to carry out the operations of the Department of Labor in fiscal year 1994 and subsequent fiscal years, the Secretary shall carry out an outreach program to inform employers of technical assistance available under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref> to assist employers to prepare the workplace to employ women in apprenticeable occupations and other nontraditional occupations.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under such program the Secretary shall provide outreach to employers through, but not limited to, the private industry councils in each service delivery area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide outreach to labor unions through, but not limited to, the building trade councils, joint apprenticeable occupations councils, and individual labor unions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall give priority to providing outreach to employers located in areas that have nontraditional employment and training programs specifically targeted to women.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2503.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With funds appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary shall make grants to community-based organizations to provide technical assistance to employers and labor unions selected under subsection (b). Such technical assistance may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> developing outreach and orientation sessions to recruit women into the employers’ apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> developing preapprenticeable occupations or nontraditional skills training to prepare women for apprenticeable occupations or nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> providing ongoing orientations for employers, unions, and workers on creating a successful environment for women in apprenticeable occupations or nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> setting up support groups and facilitating networks for women in nontraditional occupations on or off the job site to improve their retention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> setting up a local computerized data base referral system to maintain a current list of tradeswomen who are available for work;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> serving as a liaison between tradeswomen and employers and tradeswomen and labor unions to address workplace issues related to gender; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> conducting exit interviews with tradeswomen to evaluate their on-the-job experience and to assess the effectiveness of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of employer and labor unions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall select a total of 50 employers or labor unions to receive technical assistance provided with grants made under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 4</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2504.</num>
<heading> Competitive grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each community-based organization that desires to receive a grant to provide technical assistance under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref> to employers and labor unions shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In awarding grants under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall give priority to applications from community-based organizations that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> demonstrate experience preparing women to gain employment in apprenticeable occupations or other nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> demonstrate experience working with the business community to prepare them to place women in apprenticeable occupations or other nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have tradeswomen or women in nontraditional occupations as active members of the organization, as either employed staff or board members; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> have experience delivering technical assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 5</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2505.</num>
<heading> Applications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible to be selected under <ref>section 2503(b) of this title</ref> to receive technical assistance provided with grants made under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref>, an employer or labor union shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require. At a minimum, the application should include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the need for technical assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the types of apprenticeable occupations or nontraditional occupations in which the employer or labor union would like to train or employ women;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assurances that there are or will be suitable and appropriate positions available in the apprenticeable occupations program or in the nontraditional occupations being targeted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> commitments that reasonable efforts shall be made to place qualified women in apprenticeable occupations or nontraditional occupations.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 6</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2506.</num>
<heading> Liaison role of Department of Labor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Department of Labor shall serve as a liaison among employers, labor unions, and community-based organizations. The liaison role may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordination of employers, labor unions, and community-based organizations with respect to technical assistance provided under <ref>section 2503(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conducting regular assessment meetings with representatives of employers, labor unions, and community-based organizations with respect to such technical assistance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> seeking the input of employers and labor unions with respect to strategies and recommendations for improving such technical assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 7</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2507.</num>
<heading> Study of barriers to participation of women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With funds available to the Secretary to carry out the operations of the Department of Labor in fiscal years 1994 and 1995, the Secretary shall conduct a study of the participation of women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations. The study shall examine—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the barriers to participation of women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> strategies for overcoming such barriers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the retention rates for women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> strategies for retaining women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of the technical assistance provided by the community-based organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other relevant issues affecting the participation of women in apprenticeable occupations and nontraditional occupations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="1992-10-27">October 27, 1992</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report containing a summary of the results of the study described in subsection (a) and such recommendations as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 8</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2508.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “community-based organization” means a community-based organization as defined in section 4(5) of the Job Training Partnership Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 1501(5)</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002193">1</ref> that has demonstrated experience administering programs that train women for apprenticeable occupations or other nontraditional occupations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “nontraditional occupation” means jobs in which women make up 25 percent or less of the total number of workers in that occupation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 9</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3468</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2509.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance program authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 to carry out <ref>section 2503 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–530, § 10</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3468</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>