<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 4B—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL EMPLOYMENT SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 49.</num>
<heading> United States Employment Service established</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to promote the establishment and maintenance of a national system of public employment service offices, the United States Employment Service shall be established and maintained within the Department of Labor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 1</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 113</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(a), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1392</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(a), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49a.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “chief elected official”, “institution of higher education”, “one-stop center”, “one-stop partner”, “training services”, “workforce development activity”, and “workplace learning advisor”, have the meaning given the terms in <ref>section 3102 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “local workforce development board” means a local workforce development board established under <ref>section 3122 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “one-stop delivery system” means a one-stop delivery system described in <ref>section 3151(e) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “employment service office” means a local office of a State agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> except in section 49<i>l</i>–2 of this title, the term “State agency”, used without further description, means an agency designated or authorized under <ref>section 49c of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 2</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(a), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1392</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(a), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49b.</num>
<heading> Duties of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to State public employment service offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall assist in coordinating the State public employment service offices throughout the country and in increasing their usefulness by developing and prescribing minimum standards of efficiency, assisting them in meeting problems peculiar to their localities, promoting uniformity in their administrative and statistical procedure, furnishing and publishing information as to opportunities for employment and other information of value in the operation of the system, and maintaining a system for clearing labor between the States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of unemployment compensation information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Secretary to assure that unemployment insurance and employment service offices in each State, as appropriate, upon request of a public agency administering or supervising the administration of a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.], of a public agency charged with any duty or responsibility under any program or activity authorized or required under part D of title IV of such Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.], or of a State agency charged with the administration of the supplemental nutrition assistance program in a State under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.), shall (and, notwithstanding any other provision of law, is authorized to) furnish to such agency making the request, from any data contained in the files of any such office, information with respect to any individual specified in the request as to (1) whether such individual is receiving, has received, or has made application for, unemployment compensation, and the amount of any such compensation being received by such individual, (2) the current (or most recent) home address of such individual, and (3) whether such individual has refused an offer of employment and, if so, a description of the employment so offered and the terms, conditions, and rate of pay therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public labor exchange services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assist in the coordination and development of a nationwide system of public labor exchange services, provided as part of the one-stop customer service systems of the States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist in the development of continuous improvement models for such nationwide system that ensure private sector satisfaction with the system and meet the demands of jobseekers relating to the system, and identify and disseminate information on best practices for such system; and and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure, for individuals otherwise eligible to receive unemployment compensation, the provision of reemployment services and other activities in which the individuals are required to participate to receive the compensation.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in coordination with the State agencies and the staff of such agencies, assist in the planning and implementation of activities to enhance the professional development and career advancement opportunities of such staff, in order to strengthen the provision of a broad range of career guidance services, the identification of job openings (including providing intensive outreach to small and medium-sized employers and enhanced employer services), the provision of technical assistance and training to other providers of workforce development activities (including workplace learning advisors) relating to counseling and employment-related services, and the development of new strategies for coordinating counseling and technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Colocation of employment service offices and one-stop centers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to improve service delivery, avoid duplication of services, and enhance coordination of services, including location of staff to ensure access to services under <ref>section 49f(a) of this title</ref> statewide in underserved areas, employment service offices in each State shall be colocated with one-stop centers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of national electronic tools</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with States, is authorized to assist the States in the development of national electronic tools that may be used to improve access to workforce information for individuals through—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the one-stop delivery systems established as described in <ref>section 3151(e) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other delivery systems as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 3</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref>Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 933, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Aug. 3, 1954, ch. 655, § 6(a)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 852, § 17(a)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 910</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 21(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–198, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-24">Dec. 24, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–566, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-20">Oct. 20, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2689</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(a), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1392</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(a), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1535(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title I, § 110(m)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2173</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III</ref>, §§ 302(a), 310, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1080</ref>, 1086; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(Q), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1095–1097</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(A), (B), (2)(Q), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1858; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49c.</num>
<heading> Acceptance by States; creation of State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to obtain the benefits of appropriations apportioned under <ref>section 49d of this title</ref>, a State shall, pursuant to State statute, accept the provisions of this chapter and, in accordance with such State statute, the Governor shall designate or authorize the creation of a State agency vested with all powers necessary to cooperate with the Secretary under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 4</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49c–1.</num>
<heading> Transfer to States of property used by United States Employment Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of assisting the State employment services established and maintained in accordance with the terms of the Act of <date date="1933-06-06">June 6, 1933</date>, entitled “An Act to provide for the establishment of a National Employment System and for cooperation with the States in the promotion of such system, and for other purposes”, as amended (<ref>48 Stat. 113</ref>; <ref>49 Stat. 216</ref>) [<ref>29 U.S.C. 49</ref> et seq.], the Secretary of Labor is authorized without payment of compensation to transfer and assign to the States in which it is located all property, including records, files, and office equipment, used by the United States Employment Service in its administrative and local employment offices in the respective States, except the records, files, and property used in the Veterans’ Service and in the Farm Placement Service maintained under the said Act, as soon as such States establish and maintain systems of public employment offices, in accordance with the terms of sections 4, 5, and 8 of the said Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 49c</ref>, 49d, 49g] and the regulations promulgated thereunder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 11, 1939, ch. 693</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1409</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 9247, <date date="1942-09-17">Sept. 17, 1942</date>, 7 F.R. 7379; Ex. Ord. No. 9617, <date date="1945-09-19">Sept. 19, 1945</date>, 10 F.R. 11929; <ref>June 16, 1948, ch. 472</ref>, title I, <ref>62 Stat. 446</ref>; 1949 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1949-08-20">Aug. 20, 1949</date>, 14 F.R. 5225, <ref>63 Stat. 1065</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49c–2.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49c–3.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 653</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49c–4.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49c–5.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49d.</num>
<heading> Appropriations; certification for payment to States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts from time to time as the Congress may deem necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification for payment to States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall from time to time certify to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment to each State which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> except in the case of Guam, has an unemployment compensation law approved by the Secretary under the Federal Unemployment Tax Act [<ref>26 U.S.C. 3301</ref> et seq.] and is found to be in compliance with <ref>section 503 of title 42</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is found to have coordinated the public employment services with the provision of unemployment insurance claimant services, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is found to be in compliance with this chapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">such amounts as the Secretary determines to be necessary for allotment in accordance with <ref>section 49e of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Beginning with fiscal year 1985 and thereafter appropriations for any fiscal year for programs and activities assisted or conducted under this chapter shall be available for obligation only on the basis of a program year. The program year shall begin on July 1 in the fiscal year for which the appropriation is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds obligated for any program year may be expended by the State during that program year and the two succeeding program years and no amount shall be deobligated on account of a rate of expenditure which is consistent with the program plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 5</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref>May 10, 1935, ch. 102</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref>June 29, 1938, ch. 816</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1244</ref>; <ref>Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 933, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 852, § 17(b)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 910</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–778, title V, § 543(c)</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 987</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–566, title I, § 116(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-20">Oct. 20, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2672</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(b)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(b), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1392</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(b), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49d–1.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49e.</num>
<heading> Allotment of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> From the funds appropriated and (except for Guam) certified under <ref>section 49d of this title</ref> and made available for allotments under this section for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall first allot to Guam and the Virgin Islands an amount which, in relation to the total amount available for the fiscal year, is equal to the allotment percentage which each received of amounts available under this chapter in fiscal year 1983.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, after making the allotments required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall allot the remainder of the funds described in subsection (a) for each fiscal year among the States as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> two-thirds of such remainder shall be allotted on the basis of the relative number of individuals in the civilian labor force in each State as compared to the total number of such individuals in all States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one-third of such remainder shall be allotted on the basis of the relative number of unemployed individuals in each State as compared to the total number of such individuals in all States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, the number of individuals in the civilian labor force and the number of unemployed individuals shall be based on data for the most recent calendar year available, as determined by the Secretary. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “State” does not include Guam or the Virgin Islands.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No State’s allotment under this section for any fiscal year shall be less than 90 percent of its allotment percentage for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the determination is made. For the purpose of this section, the Secretary shall determine the allotment percentage for each State (including Guam and the Virgin Islands) for fiscal year 1984 which is the percentage that the State received under this chapter for fiscal year 1983 of the total amounts available for payments to all States for such fiscal year. For each succeeding fiscal year, the allotment percentage for each such State shall be the percentage that the State received under this chapter for the preceding fiscal year of the total amounts available for allotments for all States for such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For each fiscal year, no State shall receive a total allotment under paragraphs (1) and (2) which is less than 0.28 percent of the total amount available for allotments for all States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall reserve such amount, not to exceed 3 percent of the sums available for allotments under this section for each fiscal year, as shall be necessary to assure that each State will have a total allotment under this section sufficient to provide staff and other resources necessary to carry out employment service activities and related administrative and support functions on a statewide basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall, not later than March 15 of fiscal year 1983 and each succeeding fiscal year, provide preliminary planning estimates and shall, not later than May 15 of each such fiscal year, provide final planning estimates, showing each State’s projected allocation for the following year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(c)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(c), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1393</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(c), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49f.</num>
<heading> Percentage disposition of allotted funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of 90 percent of funds allotted</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Ninety percent of the sums allotted to each State pursuant to <ref>section 49e of this title</ref> may be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for job search and placement services to job seekers, including unemployment insurance claimants, including counseling, testing, occupational and labor market information, assessment, and referral to employers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for appropriate recruitment services and special technical services for employers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> for any of the following activities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> evaluation of programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> developing linkages between services funded under this chapter and related Federal or State legislation, including the provision of labor exchange services at education sites;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> providing services for workers who have received notice of permanent layoff or impending layoff, or workers in occupations which are experiencing limited demand due to technological change, impact of imports, or plant closures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> developing and providing labor market and occupational information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> developing a management information system and compiling and analyzing reports therefrom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> administering the work test for the State unemployment compensation system, including making eligibility assessments, and providing job finding and placement services for unemployment insurance claimants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> providing unemployment insurance claimants with referrals to, and application assistance for, training and education resources and programs, including Federal Pell Grants under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1070a</ref> et seq.), educational assistance under chapter 30 of title 38 (commonly referred to as the Montgomery GI Bill), and chapter 33 of that title (Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance), student assistance under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.), State student higher education assistance, and training and education programs provided under titles I and II of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 3111</ref> et seq., 3271 et seq.], and title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 720</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of 10 percent of funds allotted</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Ten percent of the sums allotted to each State pursuant to <ref>section 49e of this title</ref> shall be reserved for use in accordance with this subsection by the Governor of each such State to provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> performance incentives for public employment service offices and programs, consistent with the performance accountability measures that are based on indicators described in section 116(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)</ref>], taking into account direct or indirect placements (including those resulting from self-directed job search or group job search activities assisted by such offices or programs), wages on entered employment, retention, and other appropriate factors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> services for groups with special needs, carried out pursuant to joint agreements between the employment service offices and the appropriate local workforce investment board and chief elected official or officials or other public agencies or private nonprofit organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the extra costs of exemplary models for delivering services of the types described in subsection (a), and models for enhancing professional development and career advancement opportunities of State agency staff, as described in <ref>section 49b(c)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Funds made available to States under this section may be used to provide additional funds under an applicable program if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such program otherwise meets the requirements of this chapter and the requirements of the applicable program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such program serves the same individuals that are served under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such program provides services in a coordinated manner with services provided under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such funds would be used to supplement, and not supplant, funds provided from non-Federal sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “applicable program” means any workforce investment activity carried out under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance of services and activities under contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the services and activities otherwise authorized by this chapter, the Secretary or any State agency designated under this chapter may perform such other services and activities as shall be specified in contracts for payment or reimbursement of the costs thereof made with the Secretary or with any Federal, State, or local public agency, or administrative entity under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, or private nonprofit organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of services as part of one-stop delivery system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All job search, placement, recruitment, workforce and labor market information, and other labor exchange services authorized under subsection (a) shall be provided, consistent with the other requirements of this chapter, as part of the one-stop delivery system established by the State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(c)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(c), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1394</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(c), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–392, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-09-25">Sept. 25, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III</ref>, §§ 305, 310, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1081</ref>, 1086; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49g.</num>
<heading> State plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any State desiring to receive assistance under <ref>section 49e of this title</ref> shall prepare and submit to, and have approved by, the Secretary and the Secretary of Education, a State plan in accordance with section 3112 or 3113 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 8</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Aug. 3, 1954, ch. 655, § 6(b)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(d)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(d), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1395</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(d), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1081</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1627</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49h.</num>
<heading> Fiscal controls and accounting procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each State shall establish such fiscal control and fund accounting procedures as may be necessary to assure the proper disbursal of, and accounting for, Federal funds paid to the recipient under this chapter. The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Comptroller General of the United States, shall establish guidance for the proper performance of audits. Such guidance shall include a review of fiscal controls and fund accounting procedures established by States under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At least once every two years, the State shall prepare or have prepared an independent financial and compliance audit of funds received under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each audit shall be conducted in accordance with applicable auditing standards set forth in the financial and compliance element of the Standards for Audit of Governmental Organizations, Programs, Activities, and Functions issued by the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluations by Comptroller General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General of the United States shall evaluate the expenditures by States of funds received under this chapter in order to assure that expenditures are consistent with the provisions of this chapter and to determine the effectiveness of the State in accomplishing the purposes of this chapter. The Comptroller General shall conduct evaluations whenever determined necessary and shall periodically report to the Congress on the findings of such evaluations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to relieve the Inspector General of the Department of Labor of his responsibilities under chapter 4 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purpose of evaluating and reviewing programs established or provided for by this chapter, the Comptroller General shall have access to and the right to copy any books, accounts, records, correspondence, or other documents pertinent to such programs that are in the possession, custody, or control of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment of funds by State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State shall repay to the United States amounts found not to have been expended in accordance with this chapter. No such finding shall be made except after notice and opportunity for a fair hearing. The Secretary may offset such amounts against any other amount to which the recipient is or may be entitled under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 9</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(e)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(e), <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1396</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(e), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(47)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49i.</num>
<heading> Recordkeeping and accountability</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State shall keep records that are sufficient to permit the preparation of reports required by this chapter and to permit the tracing of funds to a level of expenditure adequate to insure that the funds have not been spent unlawfully.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may investigate such facts, conditions, practices, or other matters which the Secretary finds necessary to determine whether any State receiving funds under this chapter or any official of such State has violated any provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In order to evaluate compliance with the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary shall conduct investigations of the use of funds received by States under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In order to insure compliance with the provisions of this chapter, the Comptroller General of the United States may conduct investigations of the use of funds received under this chapter by any State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In conducting any investigation under this chapter, the Secretary or the Comptroller General of the United States may not request new compilation of information not readily available to such State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each State receiving funds under this chapter shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make such reports concerning its operations and expenditures in such form and containing such information as shall be prescribed by the Secretary, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish and maintain a management information system in accordance with guidelines established by the Secretary designed to facilitate the compilation and analysis of programmatic and financial data necessary for reporting, monitoring, and evaluating purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 10</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(f)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(f), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1396</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(f), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49j.</num>
<heading> Notice of strikes and lockouts to applicants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this chapter the Secretary is authorized and directed to provide for the giving of notice of strikes or lockouts to applicants before they are referred to employment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49</ref>, §  11, <ref>48 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(g)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(g), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1397</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(g), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49k.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 12</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49l.</num>
<heading> Miscellaneous operating authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The activities carried out pursuant to <ref>section 49f of this title</ref> shall be subject to the performance accountability measures that are based on indicators described in <ref>section 3141(b)(2)(A)(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the referral of any applicant to private agencies as long as the applicant is not charged a fee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No funds paid under this chapter may be used by any State for advertising in newspapers for high paying jobs unless such State submits an annual report to the Secretary beginning in December 1984 concerning such advertising and the justifications therefor, and the justification may include that such jobs are part of a State industrial development effort.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 13</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(h)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(h), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1397</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(h), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–404, § 5</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1627</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49l–1.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to enable the Secretary to provide funds through reimburseable <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref> agreements with the States to operate statistical programs which are essential for development of estimates of the gross national product and other national statistical series, including those related to employment and unemployment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title VI, § 601(h)</ref>, formerly title V, § 501(h), <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1397</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 601(h), <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title VII, § 712(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49l–2.</num>
<heading> Workforce and labor market information system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System content</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in accordance with the provisions of this section, shall oversee the development, maintenance, and continuous improvement of a nationwide workforce and labor market information system that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> statistical data from cooperative statistical survey and projection programs and data from administrative reporting systems that, taken together, enumerate, estimate, and project employment opportunities and conditions at national, State, and local levels in a timely manner, including statistics on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> employment and unemployment status of national, State, and local populations, including self-employed, part-time, and seasonal workers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> industrial distribution of occupations, as well as current and projected employment opportunities, wages, benefits (where data is available), and skill trends by occupation and industry, with particular attention paid to State and local conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the incidence of, industrial and geographical location of, and number of workers displaced by, permanent layoffs and plant closings; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> employment and earnings information maintained in a longitudinal manner to be used for research and program evaluation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> information on State and local employment opportunities, and other appropriate statistical data related to labor market dynamics, which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be current and comprehensive;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall meet the needs identified through the consultations described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (e)(2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall meet the needs for the information identified in section 134(d); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> technical standards (which the Secretary shall publish annually) for data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) that, at a minimum, meet the criteria of chapter 35 of title 44;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> procedures to ensure compatibility and additivity of the data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) from national, State, and local levels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> procedures to support standardization and aggregation of data from administrative reporting systems described in subparagraph (A) of employment-related programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> analysis of data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) for uses such as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> national, State, and local policymaking;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> implementation of Federal policies (including allocation formulas);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> program planning and evaluation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> researching labor market dynamics;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> wide dissemination of such data, information, and analysis in a user-friendly manner and voluntary technical standards for dissemination mechanisms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> programs of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> training for effective data dissemination;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> research and demonstration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> programs and technical assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be confidential</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">No officer or employee of the Federal Government or agent of the Federal Government may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> use any submission that is furnished for exclusively statistical purposes under the provisions of this section for any purpose other than the statistical purposes for which the submission is furnished;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> make any publication or media transmittal of the data contained in the submission described in clause (i) that permits information concerning individual subjects to be reasonably inferred by either direct or indirect means; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> permit anyone other than a sworn officer, employee, or agent of any Federal department or agency, or a contractor (including an employee of a contractor) of such department or agency, to examine an individual submission described in clause (i);</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">without the consent of the individual, agency, or other person who is the subject of the submission or provides that submission.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immunity from legal process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any submission (including any data derived from the submission) that is collected and retained by a Federal department or agency, or an officer, employee, agent, or contractor of such a department or agency, for exclusively statistical purposes under this section shall be immune from the legal process and shall not, without the consent of the individual, agency, or other person who is the subject of the submission or provides that submission, be admitted as evidence or used for any purpose in any action, suit, or other judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide immunity from the legal process for such submission (including any data derived from the submission) if the submission is in the possession of any person, agency, or entity other than the Federal Government or an officer, employee, agent, or contractor of the Federal Government, or if the submission is independently collected, retained, or produced for purposes other than the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System responsibilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Structure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The workforce and labor market information system described in subsection (a) shall be evaluated and improved by the Secretary, in consultation with the Workforce Information Advisory Council established in subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants and responsibilities</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall carry out the provisions of this section in a timely manner, through grants to or agreements with States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Using amounts appropriated under subsection (g), the Secretary shall provide funds through those grants and agreements. In distributing the funds (relating to workforce and labor market information funding) for fiscal years 2015 through 2020, the Secretary shall continue to distribute the funds to States in the manner in which the Secretary distributed funds to the States under this section for fiscal years 2004 through 2008.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, with respect to data collection, analysis, and dissemination of workforce and labor market information for the system, shall carry out the following duties:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Assign responsibilities within the Department of Labor for elements of the workforce and labor market information system described in subsection (a) to ensure that the statistical and administrative data collected is consistent with appropriate Bureau of Labor Statistics standards and definitions, and that the information is accessible and understandable to users of such data.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Actively seek the cooperation of heads of other Federal agencies to establish and maintain mechanisms for ensuring complementarity and nonduplication in the development and operation of statistical and administrative data collection activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Solicit, receive, and evaluate the recommendations from the Workforce Information Advisory Council established in subsection (d) concerning the evaluation and improvement of the workforce and labor market information system described in subsection (a) and respond in writing to the Council regarding the recommendations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Eliminate gaps and duplication in statistical undertakings.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Through the Bureau of Labor Statistics and the Employment and Training Administration, and in collaboration with States, develop and maintain the elements of the workforce and labor market information system described in subsection (a), including the development of consistent procedures and definitions for use by the States in collecting the data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> Establish procedures for the system to ensure that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such data and information are timely; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> paperwork and reporting for the system are reduced to a minimum.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Two-year plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Labor Statistics and the Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training, and in consultation with the Workforce Information Advisory Council described in subsection (d) and heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall prepare a 2-year plan for the workforce and labor market information system. The plan shall be developed and implemented in a manner that takes into account the activities described in State plans submitted by States under section 3112 or 3113 of this title and shall be submitted to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate. The plan shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of how the Secretary will work with the States to manage the nationwide workforce and labor market information system described in subsection (a) and the statewide workforce and labor market information systems that comprise the nationwide system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the steps to be taken in the following 2 years to carry out the duties described in subsection (b)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the performance of the system, with particular attention to the improvements needed at the State and local levels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a description of the involvement of States in the development of the plan, through consultation by the Secretary with the Workforce Information Advisory Council in accordance with subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of the written recommendations received from the Workforce Information Advisory Council established under subsection (d), and the extent to which those recommendations were incorporated into the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Workforce Information Advisory Council</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, through the Commissioner of Labor Statistics and the Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training, shall formally consult at least twice annually with the Workforce Information Advisory Council established in accordance with paragraph (2). Such consultations shall address the evaluation and improvement of the nationwide workforce and labor market information system described in subsection (a) and the statewide workforce and labor market information systems that comprise the nationwide system and how the Department of Labor and the States will cooperate in the management of such systems. The Council shall provide written recommendations to the Secretary concerning the evaluation and improvement of the nationwide system, including any recommendations regarding the 2-year plan described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Council</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish an advisory council that shall be known as the Workforce Information Advisory Council (referred to in this section as the “Council”) to participate in the consultations and provide the recommendations described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall appoint the members of the Council, which shall consist of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 4 members who are representatives of lead State agencies with responsibility for workforce investment activities, or State agencies described in <ref>section 49c of this title</ref>, who have been nominated by such agencies or by a national organization that represents such agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 4 members who are representatives of the State workforce and labor market information directors affiliated with the State agencies that perform the duties described in subsection (e)(2), who have been nominated by the directors;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 1 member who is a representative of providers of training services under <ref>section 3152 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> 1 member who is a representative of economic development entities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> 1 member who is a representative of businesses, who has been nominated by national business organizations or trade associations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> 1 member who is a representative of labor organizations, who has been nominated by a national labor federation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> 1 member who is a representative of local workforce development boards, who has been nominated by a national organization representing such boards; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> 1 member who is a representative of research entities that utilize workforce and labor market information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographic diversity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall ensure that the membership of the Council is geographically diverse and that no 2 of the members appointed under clauses (i), (ii), and (vii) represent the same State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of appointment; vacancies</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each member of the Council shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, except that the initial terms for members may be 1, 2, or 3 years in order to establish a rotation in which one-third of the members are selected each year. Any such member may be appointed for not more than 2 consecutive terms.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term. A member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The members of the Council shall not receive compensation for the performance of services for the Council, but shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Council. Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary may accept the voluntary and uncompensated services of members of the Council.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permanent Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2"><ref>Section 1013 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to the Council.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State responsibilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of State agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In order to receive Federal financial assistance under this section, the Governor of a State shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designate a single State agency to be responsible for the management of the portions of the workforce and labor market information system described in subsection (a) that comprise a statewide workforce and labor market information system and for the State’s participation in the development of the plan described in subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish a process for the oversight of such system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In order to receive Federal financial assistance under this section, the State agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with State and local employers, participants, and local workforce investment boards about the labor market relevance of the data to be collected and disseminated through the statewide workforce and labor market information system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> consult with eligible agencies (defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2302</ref>)), State educational agencies, and local educational agencies concerning the provision of workforce and labor market information in order to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> meet the needs of secondary school and postsecondary school students who seek such information; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> annually inform the development and implementation of programs of study defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2302</ref>), and career pathways;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> collect and disseminate for the system, on behalf of the State and localities in the State, the information and data described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> maintain and continuously improve the statewide workforce and labor market information system in accordance with this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> perform contract and grant responsibilities for data collection, analysis, and dissemination for such system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> conduct such other data collection, analysis, and dissemination activities as will ensure an effective statewide workforce and labor market information system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> actively seek the participation of other State and local agencies in data collection, analysis, and dissemination activities in order to ensure complementarity, compatibility, and usefulness of data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> utilize the quarterly records described in <ref>section 3141(i)(2) of this title</ref> to assist the State and other States in measuring State progress on State performance measures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> provide, on an annual and timely basis to each eligible agency (defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2302</ref>)), the data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting the ability of a State agency to conduct additional data collection, analysis, and dissemination activities with State funds or with Federal funds from sources other than this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonduplication requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">None of the functions and activities carried out pursuant to this section shall duplicate the functions and activities carried out under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2301</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $60,153,000 for fiscal year 2015, $64,799,000 for fiscal year 2016, $66,144,000 for fiscal year 2017, $67,611,000 for fiscal year 2018, $69,200,000 for fiscal year 2019, and $70,667,000 for fiscal year 2020.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Local area” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “local area” means the smallest geographical area for which data can be produced with statistical reliability.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 15</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 309(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1082</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 403(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–416; <ref>Pub. L. 105–332, § 5(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–270, § 2(g)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 747</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–224, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2018-07-31">July 31, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(186)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 49m, 49n.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</chapter>