<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 4C—</num>
<heading>APPRENTICE LABOR</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50.</num>
<heading> Promotion of labor standards of apprenticeship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor is authorized and directed to formulate and promote the furtherance of labor standards necessary to safeguard the welfare of apprentices, to extend the application of such standards by encouraging the inclusion thereof in contracts of apprenticeship, to bring together employers and labor for the formulation of programs of apprenticeship, to cooperate with State agencies engaged in the formulation and promotion of standards of apprenticeship, and to cooperate with the Secretary of Education in accordance with <ref>section 17 of title 20</ref>. For the purposes of this chapter the term “State” shall include the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1937, ch. 663, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 664</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. I, §§  201, 204, 206, eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2728, <ref>53 Stat. 1424</ref>, 1425; <ref>July 12, 1943, ch. 221</ref>, title VII, <ref>57 Stat. 518</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref>67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–198, title II</ref>, §  204(h), <date date="1973-12-24">Dec. 24, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50a.</num>
<heading> Publication of information; national advisory committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor may publish information relating to existing and proposed labor standards of apprenticeship, and may appoint national advisory committees to serve without compensation. Such committees shall include representatives of employers, representatives of labor, educators, and officers of other executive departments, with the consent of the head of any such department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1937, ch. 663, § 2</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 665</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50b.</num>
<heading> Appointment of employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor is authorized to appoint such employees as he may from time to time find necessary for the administration of this chapter, with regard to existing laws applicable to the appointment and compensation of employees of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1937, ch. 663, § 3</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref>July 12, 1943, ch. 221</ref>, title VII, <ref>57 Stat. 518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50c.</num>
<heading> Improved apprenticeship program coordination between the Department of Labor and the Department of Veterans Affairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this Act:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registered apprenticeship program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “registered apprenticeship program” means an apprenticeship program registered under the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date> (<ref>50 Stat. 664</ref>; commonly referred to as the “National Apprenticeship Act”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional registered apprenticeship program requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for any program applying to become a registered apprenticeship program on or after the date that is 180 days after <date date="2020-03-26">March 26, 2020</date>, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> acquire from the program sponsor a written assurance that the sponsor—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is aware of the availability of educational assistance for a veteran or other individual eligible under chapters 30 through 36 of title 38 for use in connection with a registered apprenticeship program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will make a good faith effort to obtain approval for educational assistance described in subparagraph (A) for, at a minimum, each program location that employs or recruits a veteran or other individual eligible for educational assistance under chapters 30 through 36 of title 38; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> will not deny the application of a qualified candidate who is a veteran or other individual eligible for educational assistance described in subparagraph (A) for the purpose of avoiding making a good faith effort to obtain approval as described in subparagraph (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in accordance with paragraphs (5) and (12) of section 29.5(b) of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the day before <date date="2020-03-26">March 26, 2020</date>), require the program sponsor, to the extent practicable, to provide standards that contain provisions to grant advanced standing or credit, and provide increased wages commensurate to such standing or credit, for any veteran or other individual eligible for educational assistance under chapters 30 through 36 of title 38 who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is enrolled in the registered apprenticeship program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has a demonstrated competence applicable to the apprenticeship occupation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has acquired experience, training, or skills through military service that is applicable to the apprenticeship occupation; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> when the Secretary approves the registered apprenticeship program, provide a copy of the program’s certificate of registration to the State approving agency designated under chapter 36 of title 38 in the State where the program is located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–134, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-03-26">Mar. 26, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>