<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29—</num>
<heading>WORKERS TECHNOLOGY SKILL DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2701.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In an increasingly competitive world economy, the companies and nations that lead in the rapid development, commercialization, and application of new and advanced technologies, and in the high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services, will lead in economic growth, employment, and high living standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> While the United States remains the world leader in science and invention, it has not done well in rapidly making the transition from achievement in its research laboratories to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services. This lag and the unprecedented competitive challenge that the United States has faced from abroad have contributed to a drop in real wages and living standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Companies that are successfully competitive in the rapid development, commercialization, application, and implementation of advanced technologies, and in the successful delivery of goods and services, recognize that worker participation and labor-management cooperation in the deployment, application, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies make an important contribution to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services and in maintaining and improving real wages for workers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Federal Government has an important role in encouraging and augmenting private sector efforts relating to the development, application, manufacture, and deployment of new and advanced technologies. The role should be to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> work with private companies, States, worker organizations, nonprofit organizations, and institutions of higher education to ensure the development, application, production, and implementation of new and advanced technologies to promote the improvement of workers’ skills, wages, job security, and working conditions, and a healthy environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encourage worker and worker organization participation in the development, commercialization, evaluation, selection, application, and implementation of new and advanced technologies in the workplace; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promote the use and integration of new and advanced technologies in the workplace that enhance workers’ skills.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In working with the private sector to promote the technological leadership and economic growth of the United States, the Federal Government has a responsibility to ensure that Federal technology programs help the United States to remain competitive and to maintain and improve living standards and to create and retain secure jobs in economically stable communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 542</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4051</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2702.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve the ability of workers and worker organizations to recognize, develop, assess, and improve strategies for successfully integrating workers and worker organizations into the process of evaluating, selecting, and implementing advanced workplace technologies, and advanced workplace practices in a manner that creates and maintains stable well-paying jobs for workers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist workers and worker organizations in developing the expertise necessary for effective participation with employers in the development of strategies and programs for the successful evaluation, selection, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies and advanced workplace practices through the provision of a range of education, training, and related services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 543</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4052</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2703.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advanced workplace practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “advanced workplace practices” means innovations in work organization and performance, including high-performance workplace systems, flexible production techniques, quality programs, continuous improvement, concurrent engineering, close relationships between suppliers and customers, widely diffused decisionmaking and work teams, and effective integration of production technology, worker skills and training, and workplace organization, and such other characteristics as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advanced workplace technologies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “advanced workplace technologies” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> numerically controlled machine tools, robots, automated process control equipment, computerized flexible manufacturing systems, associated computer software, and other technology for improving the manufacturing and industrial production of goods and commercial services, which advance the state-of-the-art; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> novel industrial and commercial techniques and processes not previously generally available that improve quality, productivity, and practices, including engineering design, quality assurance, concurrent engineering, continuous process production technology, inventory management, upgraded worker skills, communications with customers and suppliers, and promotion of sustainable economic growth.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Department” means the Department of Labor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “nonprofit organization” means a tax-exempt organization, as described in paragraph (3), (4), or (5) of <ref>section 501(c) of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Worker organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “worker organization” means a labor organization within the meaning of <ref>section 501(c)(5) of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 544</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2704.</num>
<heading> Grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor, after consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall, to the extent appropriations are available, award grants to eligible entities to carry out the purposes described in <ref>section 2702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be a nonprofit organization, or a partnership consortium of such organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare and submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a description of the activities that the entity will carry out using amounts received under the grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> agree to make available (directly or through donations from public or private entities) non-Federal contributions toward the costs of the activities to be conducted with grant funds, in an amount equal to the amount required under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An entity shall use amounts received under a grant awarded under this section to carry out the purposes described in <ref>section 2702 of this title</ref> through activities such as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provision of technical assistance to workers, worker organizations, employers, State economic development agencies, State industrial extension programs, Advanced Technology Centers, and National Manufacturing Technology Centers to identify advanced workplace practices and strategies that enhance the effective evaluation, selection, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the researching and identification of new and advanced workplace technologies, and advanced workplace practices that promote the improvement of workers’ skills, wages, working conditions, and job security, that research the link between advanced workplace practices and long-term corporate performance, and which are consistent with the needs of local communities and the need for a healthy environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the development and dissemination of training programs and materials to be used for and by workers, worker organizations, employers, State economic development agencies, State industrial extension programs, Advanced Technology Centers, and National Manufacturing Technology Centers relating to the activities and services provided pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2), and regarding successful practices including practices which address labor-management cooperation and the involvement of workers in the design, development, and implementation of workplace practices and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of grants and non-Federal shares</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Grants awarded under this section shall be for a term not to exceed six years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Amounts required to be contributed by an entity under subsection (b)(3) shall equal—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 15 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the first year for which the grant is awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the second year for which the grant is awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 33 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the third year for which the grant is awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 40 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the fourth year for which the grant is awarded; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the fifth and sixth years for which the grant is awarded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department shall develop mechanisms for evaluating the effectiveness of the use of a grant awarded under this section in carrying out the purposes under <ref>section 2702 of this title</ref> and, not later than two years after <date date="1994-10-20">October 20, 1994</date>, and every two years thereafter, prepare and submit a report to Congress concerning such evaluation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 545</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2705.</num>
<heading> Identification and dissemination of best practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in cooperation and after consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall assist workers, worker organizations, and employers in successfully adopting advanced workplace technologies, and advanced workplace practices by identifying, collecting, and disseminating information on best workplace practices and workplace assessment tools, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> methods, techniques, and successful models of labor-management cooperation and of worker and worker organization participation in the development, evaluation, selection, and implementation of new and advanced workplace technologies, and advanced workplace practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> methods, techniques, and successful models for the design and implementation of new and advanced workplace practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> methods, techniques, and successful models for the design and implementation of advanced forms of work organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> methods, techniques, and successful models for the assessment of worker skills and training needs relating to the effective development, evaluation, selection, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies, and advanced workplace practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Such information on best workplace practices shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> summaries and analyses of best practice cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> criteria for assessment of current workplace practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> information on the best available education and training materials and services relating to the development, implementation, and operation of systems utilizing new and advanced workplace technologies, and advanced workplace practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The information and materials developed under this section shall be distributed through an appropriate entity designated by the Secretary of Commerce to the Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology, to the Manufacturing Outreach Center, to other technology training entities, and directly to others as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 546</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4055</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2706.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1995 through 1997.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 547</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4055</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>