<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 28—</num>
<heading>FAMILY AND MEDICAL LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2601.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of single-parent households and two-parent households in which the single parent or both parents work is increasing significantly;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> it is important for the development of children and the family unit that fathers and mothers be able to participate in early childrearing and the care of family members who have serious health conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the lack of employment policies to accommodate working parents can force individuals to choose between job security and parenting;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> there is inadequate job security for employees who have serious health conditions that prevent them from working for temporary periods;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> due to the nature of the roles of men and women in our society, the primary responsibility for family caretaking often falls on women, and such responsibility affects the working lives of women more than it affects the working lives of men; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> employment standards that apply to one gender only have serious potential for encouraging employers to discriminate against employees and applicants for employment who are of that gender.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this Act—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to balance the demands of the workplace with the needs of families, to promote the stability and economic security of families, and to promote national interests in preserving family integrity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to entitle employees to take reasonable leave for medical reasons, for the birth or adoption of a child, and for the care of a child, spouse, or parent who has a serious health condition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to accomplish the purposes described in paragraphs (1) and (2) in a manner that accommodates the legitimate interests of employers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to accomplish the purposes described in paragraphs (1) and (2) in a manner that, consistent with the Equal Protection Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment, minimizes the potential for employment discrimination on the basis of sex by ensuring generally that leave is available for eligible medical reasons (including maternity-related disability) and for compelling family reasons, on a gender-neutral basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to promote the goal of equal employment opportunity for women and men, pursuant to such clause.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, § 2</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 6</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS FOR LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2611.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “commerce” and “industry or activity affecting commerce” mean any activity, business, or industry in commerce or in which a labor dispute would hinder or obstruct commerce or the free flow of commerce, and include “commerce” and any “industry affecting commerce”, as defined in paragraphs (1) and (3) of <ref>section 142 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible employee” means an employee who has been employed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for at least 12 months by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for at least 1,250 hours of service with such employer during the previous 12-month period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible employee” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any Federal officer or employee covered under subchapter V of chapter 63 of title 5; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any employee of an employer who is employed at a worksite at which such employer employs less than 50 employees if the total number of employees employed by that employer within 75 miles of that worksite is less than 50.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of determining whether an employee meets the hours of service requirement specified in subparagraph (A)(ii), the legal standards established under <ref>section 207 of this title</ref> shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Airline flight crews</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For purposes of determining whether an employee who is a flight attendant or flight crewmember (as such terms are defined in regulations of the Federal Aviation Administration) meets the hours of service requirement specified in subparagraph (A)(ii), the employee will be considered to meet the requirement if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the employee has worked or been paid for not less than 60 percent of the applicable total monthly guarantee, or the equivalent, for the previous 12-month period, for or by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the employee has worked or been paid for not less than 504 hours (not counting personal commute time or time spent on vacation leave or medical or sick leave) during the previous 12-month period, for or by that employer.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> File</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each employer of an employee described in clause (i) shall maintain on file with the Secretary (in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe) containing information specifying the applicable monthly guarantee with respect to each category of employee to which such guarantee applies.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In this subparagraph, the term “applicable monthly guarantee” means—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> for an employee described in clause (i) other than an employee on reserve status, the minimum number of hours for which an employer has agreed to schedule such employee for any given month; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> for an employee described in clause (i) who is on reserve status, the number of hours for which an employer has agreed to pay such employee on reserve status for any given month,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> as established in the applicable collective bargaining agreement or, if none exists, in the employer’s policies.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> GAO employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an employee of the Government Accountability Office, the requirements of subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to leave under section 2612(a)(1)(A) or (B) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employ; employee; State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “employ”, “employee”, and “State” have the same meanings given such terms in subsections (c), (e), and (g) of <ref>section 203 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “employer”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> means any person engaged in commerce or in any industry or activity affecting commerce who employs 50 or more employees for each working day during each of 20 or more calendar workweeks in the current or preceding calendar year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any person who acts, directly or indirectly, in the interest of an employer to any of the employees of such employer; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any successor in interest of an employer;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> includes any “public agency”, as defined in <ref>section 203(x) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> includes the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii), a public agency shall be considered to be a person engaged in commerce or in an industry or activity affecting commerce.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “employment benefits” means all benefits provided or made available to employees by an employer, including group life insurance, health insurance, disability insurance, sick leave, annual leave, educational benefits, and pensions, regardless of whether such benefits are provided by a practice or written policy of an employer or through an “employee benefit plan”, as defined in <ref>section 1002(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Health care provider</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “health care provider” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a doctor of medicine or osteopathy who is authorized to practice medicine or surgery (as appropriate) by the State in which the doctor practices; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other person determined by the Secretary to be capable of providing health care services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “parent” means the biological parent of an employee or an individual who stood in loco parentis to an employee when the employee was a son or daughter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” has the same meaning given such term in <ref>section 203(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduced leave schedule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “reduced leave schedule” means a leave schedule that reduces the usual number of hours per workweek, or hours per workday, of an employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Serious health condition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “serious health condition” means an illness, injury, impairment, or physical or mental condition that involves—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inpatient care in a hospital, hospice, or residential medical care facility; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> continuing treatment by a health care provider.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Son or daughter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “son or daughter” means a biological, adopted, or foster child, a stepchild, a legal ward, or a child of a person standing in loco parentis, who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under 18 years of age; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 18 years of age or older and incapable of self-care because of a mental or physical disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Spouse</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “spouse” means a husband or wife, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered active duty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered active duty” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of a regular component of the Armed Forces, duty during the deployment of the member with the Armed Forces to a foreign country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces, duty during the deployment of the member with the Armed Forces to a foreign country under a call or order to active duty under a provision of law referred to in <ref>section 101(a)(13)(B) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered servicemember</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered servicemember” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves) who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, is otherwise in outpatient status, or is otherwise on the temporary disability retired list, for a serious injury or illness; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a veteran who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, for a serious injury or illness and who was a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves) at any time during the period of 5 years preceding the date on which the veteran undergoes that medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outpatient status</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “outpatient status”, with respect to a covered servicemember, means the status of a member of the Armed Forces assigned to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a military medical treatment facility as an outpatient; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a unit established for the purpose of providing command and control of members of the Armed Forces receiving medical care as outpatients.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Next of kin</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “next of kin”, used with respect to an individual, means the nearest blood relative of that individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Serious injury or illness</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “serious injury or illness”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves), means an injury or illness that was incurred by the member in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces (or existed before the beginning of the member’s active duty and was aggravated by service in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces) and that may render the member medically unfit to perform the duties of the member’s office, grade, rank, or rating; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a veteran who was a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves) at any time during a period described in paragraph (15)(B), means a qualifying (as defined by the Secretary of Labor) injury or illness that was incurred by the member in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces (or existed before the beginning of the member’s active duty and was aggravated by service in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces) and that manifested itself before or after the member became a veteran.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(19)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Veteran</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “veteran” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 101 of title 38</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 7</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 202(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 565(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), (3), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2309</ref>, 2310; <ref>Pub. L. 111–119, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-21">Dec. 21, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. F, title LXXVI, § 7604(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2308</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2612.</num>
<heading> Leave requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entitlement to leave</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to <ref>section 2613 of this title</ref> and subsection (d)(3), an eligible employee shall be entitled to a total of 12 workweeks of leave during any 12-month period for one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Because of the birth of a son or daughter of the employee and in order to care for such son or daughter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Because of the placement of a son or daughter with the employee for adoption or foster care.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In order to care for the spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee, if such spouse, son, daughter, or parent has a serious health condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Because of a serious health condition that makes the employee unable to perform the functions of the position of such employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Because of any qualifying exigency (as the Secretary shall, by regulation, determine) arising out of the fact that the spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent of the employee is on covered active duty (or has been notified of an impending call or order to covered active duty) in the Armed Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> During the period beginning on the date the Emergency Family and Medical Leave Expansion Act takes effect, and ending on <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, because of a qualifying need related to a public health emergency in accordance with <ref>section 2620 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expiration of entitlement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The entitlement to leave under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) for a birth or placement of a son or daughter shall expire at the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date of such birth or placement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Servicemember family leave</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to <ref>section 2613 of this title</ref>, an eligible employee who is the spouse, son, daughter, parent, or next of kin of a covered servicemember shall be entitled to a total of 26 workweeks of leave during a 12-month period to care for the servicemember. The leave described in this paragraph shall only be available during a single 12-month period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Combined leave total</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to subsection (d)(3), during the single 12-month period described in paragraph (3), an eligible employee shall be entitled to a combined total of 26 workweeks of leave under paragraphs (1) and (3). Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the availability of leave under paragraph (1) during any other 12-month period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation of leave for airline flight crews</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may provide, by regulation, a method for calculating the leave described in paragraph (1) with respect to employees described in <ref>section 2611(2)(D) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave taken intermittently or on reduced leave schedule</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) shall not be taken by an employee intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule unless the employee and the employer of the employee agree otherwise. Subject to paragraph (2), subsection (e)(2), and subsection (b)(5) or (f) (as appropriate) of <ref>section 2613 of this title</ref>, leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) or under subsection (a)(3) may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule when medically necessary. Subject to subsection (e)(3) and <ref>section 2613(f) of this title</ref>, leave under subsection (a)(1)(E) may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule. The taking of leave intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule pursuant to this paragraph shall not result in a reduction in the total amount of leave to which the employee is entitled under subsection (a) beyond the amount of leave actually taken.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative position</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If an employee requests intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) or under subsection (a)(3), that is foreseeable based on planned medical treatment, the employer may require such employee to transfer temporarily to an available alternative position offered by the employer for which the employee is qualified and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has equivalent pay and benefits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> better accommodates recurring periods of leave than the regular employment position of the employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unpaid leave permitted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), leave granted under subsection (a) (other than certain periods of leave under subsection (a)(1)(F)) may consist of unpaid leave. Where an employee is otherwise exempt under regulations issued by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 213(a)(1) of this title</ref>, the compliance of an employer with this subchapter by providing unpaid leave shall not affect the exempt status of the employee under such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to paid leave</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unpaid leave</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If an employer provides paid leave for fewer than 12 workweeks (or 26 workweeks in the case of leave provided under subsection (a)(3)), the additional weeks of leave necessary to attain the 12 workweeks (or 26 workweeks, as appropriate) of leave required under this subchapter may be provided without compensation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of paid leave</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An eligible employee may elect, or an employer may require the employee, to substitute any of the accrued paid vacation leave, personal leave, or family leave of the employee for leave provided under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (E) of subsection (a)(1) for any part of the 12-week period of such leave under such subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Serious health condition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An eligible employee may elect, or an employer may require the employee, to substitute any of the accrued paid vacation leave, personal leave, or medical or sick leave of the employee for leave provided under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) for any part of the 12-week period of such leave under such subsection, except that nothing in this subchapter shall require an employer to provide paid sick leave or paid medical leave in any situation in which such employer would not normally provide any such paid leave. An eligible employee may elect, or an employer may require the employee, to substitute any of the accrued paid vacation leave, personal leave, family leave, or medical or sick leave of the employee for leave provided under subsection (a)(3) for any part of the 26-week period of such leave under such subsection, except that nothing in this subchapter requires an employer to provide paid sick leave or paid medical leave in any situation in which the employer would not normally provide any such paid leave.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for GAO employees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of paid leave</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An employee of the Government Accountability Office may elect to substitute for any leave without pay under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) any paid leave which is available to such employee for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of paid leave</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The paid leave that is available to an employee of the Government Accountability Office for purposes of subparagraph (A) is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of weeks of paid parental leave in connection with the birth or placement involved that corresponds to the number of administrative workweeks of paid parental leave available to employees under <ref>section 6382(d)(2)(B)(i) of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> during the 12-month period referred to in subsection (a)(1) and in addition to the administrative workweeks described in clause (i), any additional paid vacation, personal, family, medical, or sick leave provided by such employer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this section shall be considered to require or permit an employer to require that an employee first use all or any portion of the leave described in subparagraph (B)(ii) before being allowed to use the paid parental leave described in clause (i) of subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Paid parental leave under subparagraph (B)(i)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be payable from any appropriation or fund available for salaries or expenses for positions with the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if not used by the employee of such employer before the end of the 12-month period (as referred to in subsection (a)(1)) to which it relates, shall not accumulate for any subsequent use; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall apply without regard to the limitations in subparagraph (E), (F), or (G) of <ref>section 6382(d)(2) of title 5</ref> or <ref>section 2614(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for Library of Congress employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Consistent with <ref>section 1301(a)(3)(J) of title 2</ref>, the rights and protections established by sections 2611 through 2615 of this title, including section 2612(d)(3), shall apply to employees of the Library of Congress under <ref>section 1312 of title 2</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreseeable leave</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which the necessity for leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) is foreseeable based on an expected birth or placement, the employee shall provide the employer with not less than 30 days’ notice, before the date the leave is to begin, of the employee’s intention to take leave under such subparagraph, except that if the date of the birth or placement requires leave to begin in less than 30 days, the employee shall provide such notice as is practicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of employee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In any case in which the necessity for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) or under subsection (a)(3) is foreseeable based on planned medical treatment, the employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall make a reasonable effort to schedule the treatment so as not to disrupt unduly the operations of the employer, subject to the approval of the health care provider of the employee or the health care provider of the son, daughter, spouse, parent, or covered servicemember of the employee, as appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide the employer with not less than 30 days’ notice, before the date the leave is to begin, of the employee’s intention to take leave under such subparagraph, except that if the date of the treatment requires leave to begin in less than 30 days, the employee shall provide such notice as is practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice for leave due to covered active duty of family member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which the necessity for leave under subsection (a)(1)(E) is foreseeable, whether because the spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee is on covered active duty, or because of notification of an impending call or order to covered active duty, the employee shall provide such notice to the employer as is reasonable and practicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Spouses employed by same employer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In any case in which a husband and wife entitled to leave under subsection (a) are employed by the same employer, the aggregate number of workweeks of leave to which both may be entitled may be limited to 12 workweeks during any 12-month period, if such leave is taken—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to care for a sick parent under subparagraph (C) of such subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Servicemember family leave</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The aggregate number of workweeks of leave to which both that husband and wife may be entitled under subsection (a) may be limited to 26 workweeks during the single 12-month period described in subsection (a)(3) if the leave is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> leave under subsection (a)(3); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a combination of leave under subsection (a)(3) and leave described in paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Both limitations applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the leave taken by the husband and wife includes leave described in paragraph (1), the limitation in paragraph (1) shall apply to the leave described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(a)(2)</ref>, (3)(A)–(D), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 129</ref>, 130; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 565(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (4), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2309</ref>, 2311; <ref>Pub. L. 111–119, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-21">Dec. 21, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. F, title LXXVI, § 7604(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–127, div. C, § 3102(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-18">Mar. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2613.</num>
<heading> Certification</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employer may require that a request for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) or paragraph (3) of <ref>section 2612(a) of this title</ref> be supported by a certification issued by the health care provider of the eligible employee or of the son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, or of the next of kin of an individual in the case of leave taken under such paragraph (3), as appropriate. The employee shall provide, in a timely manner, a copy of such certification to the employer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sufficient certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Certification provided under subsection (a) shall be sufficient if it states—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which the serious health condition commenced;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the probable duration of the condition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the appropriate medical facts within the knowledge of the health care provider regarding the condition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for purposes of leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref>, a statement that the eligible employee is needed to care for the son, daughter, spouse, or parent and an estimate of the amount of time that such employee is needed to care for the son, daughter, spouse, or parent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for purposes of leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>, a statement that the employee is unable to perform the functions of the position of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in the case of certification for intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, for planned medical treatment, the dates on which such treatment is expected to be given and the duration of such treatment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> in the case of certification for intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>, a statement of the medical necessity for the intermittent leave or leave on a reduced leave schedule, and the expected duration of the intermittent leave or reduced leave schedule; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> in the case of certification for intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref>, a statement that the employee’s intermittent leave or leave on a reduced leave schedule is necessary for the care of the son, daughter, parent, or spouse who has a serious health condition, or will assist in their recovery, and the expected duration and schedule of the intermittent leave or reduced leave schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Second opinion</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which the employer has reason to doubt the validity of the certification provided under subsection (a) for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of <ref>section 2612(a)(1) of this title</ref>, the employer may require, at the expense of the employer, that the eligible employee obtain the opinion of a second health care provider designated or approved by the employer concerning any information certified under subsection (b) for such leave.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A health care provider designated or approved under paragraph (1) shall not be employed on a regular basis by the employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resolution of conflicting opinions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which the second opinion described in subsection (c) differs from the opinion in the original certification provided under subsection (a), the employer may require, at the expense of the employer, that the employee obtain the opinion of a third health care provider designated or approved jointly by the employer and the employee concerning the information certified under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The opinion of the third health care provider concerning the information certified under subsection (b) shall be considered to be final and shall be binding on the employer and the employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent recertification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The employer may require that the eligible employee obtain subsequent recertifications on a reasonable basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification related to covered active duty or call to covered active duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employer may require that a request for leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(E) of this title</ref> be supported by a certification issued at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe. If the Secretary issues a regulation requiring such certification, the employee shall provide, in a timely manner, a copy of such certification to the employer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(a)(3)(E)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 130</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 565(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2614.</num>
<heading> Employment and benefits protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restoration to position</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (b), any eligible employee who takes leave under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref> for the intended purpose of the leave shall be entitled, on return from such leave—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to be restored by the employer to the position of employment held by the employee when the leave commenced; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to be restored to an equivalent position with equivalent employment benefits, pay, and other terms and conditions of employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loss of benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The taking of leave under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref> shall not result in the loss of any employment benefit accrued prior to the date on which the leave commenced.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to entitle any restored employee to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the accrual of any seniority or employment benefits during any period of leave; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any right, benefit, or position of employment other than any right, benefit, or position to which the employee would have been entitled had the employee not taken the leave.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition of restoration under paragraph (1) for an employee who has taken leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>, the employer may have a uniformly applied practice or policy that requires each such employee to receive certification from the health care provider of the employee that the employee is able to resume work, except that nothing in this paragraph shall supersede a valid State or local law or a collective bargaining agreement that governs the return to work of such employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit an employer from requiring an employee on leave under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref> to report periodically to the employer on the status and intention of the employee to return to work.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption concerning certain highly compensated employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of restoration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An employer may deny restoration under subsection (a) to any eligible employee described in paragraph (2) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such denial is necessary to prevent substantial and grievous economic injury to the operations of the employer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the employer notifies the employee of the intent of the employer to deny restoration on such basis at the time the employer determines that such injury would occur; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in any case in which the leave has commenced, the employee elects not to return to employment after receiving such notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affected employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible employee described in paragraph (1) is a salaried eligible employee who is among the highest paid 10 percent of the employees employed by the employer within 75 miles of the facility at which the employee is employed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of health benefits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coverage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), during any period that an eligible employee takes leave under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref>, the employer shall maintain coverage under any “group health plan” (as defined in <ref>section 5000(b)(1) of title 26</ref>) for the duration of such leave at the level and under the conditions coverage would have been provided if the employee had continued in employment continuously for the duration of such leave.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to return from leave</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The employer may recover the premium that the employer paid for maintaining coverage for the employee under such group health plan during any period of unpaid leave under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the employee fails to return from leave under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref> after the period of leave to which the employee is entitled has expired; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the employee fails to return to work for a reason other than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the continuation, recurrence, or onset of a serious health condition that entitles the employee to leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of <ref>section 2612(a)(1) of this title</ref> or under <ref>section 2612(a)(3) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other circumstances beyond the control of the employee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An employer may require that a claim that an employee is unable to return to work because of the continuation, recurrence, or onset of the serious health condition described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) be supported by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a certification issued by the health care provider of the son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, as appropriate, in the case of an employee unable to return to work because of a condition specified in <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a certification issued by the health care provider of the eligible employee, in the case of an employee unable to return to work because of a condition specified in <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a certification issued by the health care provider of the servicemember being cared for by the employee, in the case of an employee unable to return to work because of a condition specified in <ref>section 2612(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Copy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The employee shall provide, in a timely manner, a copy of such certification to the employer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sufficiency of certification</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave due to serious health condition of employee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The certification described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be sufficient if the certification states that a serious health condition prevented the employee from being able to perform the functions of the position of the employee on the date that the leave of the employee expired.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave due to serious health condition of family member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The certification described in subparagraph (A)(i) shall be sufficient if the certification states that the employee is needed to care for the son, daughter, spouse, or parent who has a serious health condition on the date that the leave of the employee expired.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 12</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(a)(3)(F)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 131</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2615.</num>
<heading> Prohibited acts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interference with rights</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exercise of rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall be unlawful for any employer to interfere with, restrain, or deny the exercise of or the attempt to exercise, any right provided under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discrimination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall be unlawful for any employer to discharge or in any other manner discriminate against any individual for opposing any practice made unlawful by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interference with proceedings or inquiries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to discharge or in any other manner discriminate against any individual because such individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has filed any charge, or has instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding, under or related to this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has given, or is about to give, any information in connection with any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this subchapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has testified, or is about to testify, in any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 14</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2616.</num>
<heading> Investigative authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To ensure compliance with the provisions of this subchapter, or any regulation or order issued under this subchapter, the Secretary shall have, subject to subsection (c), the investigative authority provided under <ref>section 211(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligation to keep and preserve records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employer shall make, keep, and preserve records pertaining to compliance with this subchapter in accordance with <ref>section 211(c) of this title</ref> and in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required submissions generally limited to annual basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall not under the authority of this section require any employer or any plan, fund, or program to submit to the Secretary any books or records more than once during any 12-month period, unless the Secretary has reasonable cause to believe there may exist a violation of this subchapter or any regulation or order issued pursuant to this subchapter, or is investigating a charge pursuant to <ref>section 2617(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpoena powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of any investigation provided for in this section, the Secretary shall have the subpoena authority provided for under <ref>section 209 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 15</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2617.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil action by employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any employer who violates <ref>section 2615 of this title</ref> shall be liable to any eligible employee affected—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for damages equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the amount of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation denied or lost to such employee by reason of the violation; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in a case in which wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation have not been denied or lost to the employee, any actual monetary losses sustained by the employee as a direct result of the violation, such as the cost of providing care, up to a sum equal to 12 weeks (or 26 weeks, in a case involving leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(3) of this title</ref>) of wages or salary for the employee;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the interest on the amount described in clause (i) calculated at the prevailing rate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an additional amount as liquidated damages equal to the sum of the amount described in clause (i) and the interest described in clause (ii), except that if an employer who has violated <ref>section 2615 of this title</ref> proves to the satisfaction of the court that the act or omission which violated <ref>section 2615 of this title</ref> was in good faith and that the employer had reasonable grounds for believing that the act or omission was not a violation of <ref>section 2615 of this title</ref>, such court may, in the discretion of the court, reduce the amount of the liability to the amount and interest determined under clauses (i) and (ii), respectively; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for such equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment, reinstatement, and promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An action to recover the damages or equitable relief prescribed in paragraph (1) may be maintained against any employer (including a public agency) in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction by any one or more employees for and in behalf of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the employees; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the employees and other employees similarly situated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees and costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The court in such an action shall, in addition to any judgment awarded to the plaintiff, allow a reasonable attorney’s fee, reasonable expert witness fees, and other costs of the action to be paid by the defendant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The right provided by paragraph (2) to bring an action by or on behalf of any employee shall terminate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the filing of a complaint by the Secretary in an action under subsection (d) in which restraint is sought of any further delay in the payment of the amount described in paragraph (1)(A) to such employee by an employer responsible under paragraph (1) for the payment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on the filing of a complaint by the Secretary in an action under subsection (b) in which a recovery is sought of the damages described in paragraph (1)(A) owing to an eligible employee by an employer liable under paragraph (1),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">unless the action described in subparagraph (A) or (B) is dismissed without prejudice on motion of the Secretary.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall receive, investigate, and attempt to resolve complaints of violations of <ref>section 2615 of this title</ref> in the same manner that the Secretary receives, investigates, and attempts to resolve complaints of violations of sections 206 and 207 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to recover the damages described in subsection (a)(1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sums recovered</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any sums recovered by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (2) shall be held in a special deposit account and shall be paid, on order of the Secretary, directly to each employee affected. Any such sums not paid to an employee because of inability to do so within a period of 3 years shall be deposited into the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), an action may be brought under this section not later than 2 years after the date of the last event constituting the alleged violation for which the action is brought.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Willful violation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of such action brought for a willful violation of <ref>section 2615 of this title</ref>, such action may be brought within 3 years of the date of the last event constituting the alleged violation for which such action is brought.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In determining when an action is commenced by the Secretary under this section for the purposes of this subsection, it shall be considered to be commenced on the date when the complaint is filed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action for injunction by Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, in an action brought by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to restrain violations of <ref>section 2615 of this title</ref>, including the restraint of any withholding of payment of wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation, plus interest, found by the court to be due to eligible employees; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to award such other equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment, reinstatement, and promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Solicitor of Labor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary on any litigation brought under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office and Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress, the authority of the Secretary of Labor under this subchapter shall be exercised respectively by the Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 15</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 202(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(a)(3)(G)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 131</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2618.</num>
<heading> Special rules concerning employees of local educational agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the rights (including the rights under <ref>section 2614 of this title</ref>, which shall extend throughout the period of leave of any employee under this section), remedies, and procedures under this subchapter shall apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any “local educational agency” (as defined in <ref>section 7801 of title 20</ref>) and an eligible employee of the agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any private elementary or secondary school and an eligible employee of the school.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of the application described in paragraph (1):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “eligible employee” means an eligible employee of an agency or school described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “employer” means an agency or school described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave does not violate certain other Federal laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A local educational agency and a private elementary or secondary school shall not be in violation of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1400</ref> et seq.), <ref>section 794 of this title</ref>, or title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq.), solely as a result of an eligible employee of such agency or school exercising the rights of such employee under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intermittent leave or leave on reduced schedule for instructional employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), in any case in which an eligible employee employed principally in an instructional capacity by any such educational agency or school requests leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of <ref>section 2612(a)(1) of this title</ref> or under <ref>section 2612(a)(3) of this title</ref> that is foreseeable based on planned medical treatment and the employee would be on leave for greater than 20 percent of the total number of working days in the period during which the leave would extend, the agency or school may require that such employee elect either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to take leave for periods of a particular duration, not to exceed the duration of the planned medical treatment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to transfer temporarily to an available alternative position offered by the employer for which the employee is qualified, and that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has equivalent pay and benefits; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> better accommodates recurring periods of leave than the regular employment position of the employee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The elections described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) shall apply only with respect to an eligible employee who complies with <ref>section 2612(e)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules applicable to periods near conclusion of academic term</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following rules shall apply with respect to periods of leave near the conclusion of an academic term in the case of any eligible employee employed principally in an instructional capacity by any such educational agency or school:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave more than 5 weeks prior to end of term</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the eligible employee begins leave under <ref>section 2612 of this title</ref> more than 5 weeks prior to the end of the academic term, the agency or school may require the employee to continue taking leave until the end of such term, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the leave is of at least 3 weeks duration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the return to employment would occur during the 3-week period before the end of such term.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave less than 5 weeks prior to end of term</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the eligible employee begins leave under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of <ref>section 2612(a)(1) of this title</ref> or under <ref>section 2612(a)(3) of this title</ref> during the period that commences 5 weeks prior to the end of the academic term, the agency or school may require the employee to continue taking leave until the end of such term, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the leave is of greater than 2 weeks duration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the return to employment would occur during the 2-week period before the end of such term.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave less than 3 weeks prior to end of term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the eligible employee begins leave under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of <ref>section 2612(a)(1) of this title</ref> or under <ref>section 2612(a)(3) of this title</ref> during the period that commences 3 weeks prior to the end of the academic term and the duration of the leave is greater than 5 working days, the agency or school may require the employee to continue to take leave until the end of such term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restoration to equivalent employment position</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of determinations under <ref>section 2614(a)(1)(B) of this title</ref> (relating to the restoration of an eligible employee to an equivalent position), in the case of a local educational agency or a private elementary or secondary school, such determination shall be made on the basis of established school board policies and practices, private school policies and practices, and collective bargaining agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction of amount of liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a local educational agency or a private elementary or secondary school that has violated this subchapter proves to the satisfaction of the court that the agency, school, or department had reasonable grounds for believing that the underlying act or omission was not a violation of this subchapter, such court may, in the discretion of the court, reduce the amount of the liability provided for under <ref>section 2617(a)(1)(A) of this title</ref> to the amount and interest determined under clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, of such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 394(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076(v)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(a)(3)(H)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 131</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(hh)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2619.</num>
<heading> Notice</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each employer shall post and keep posted, in conspicuous places on the premises of the employer where notices to employees and applicants for employment are customarily posted, a notice, to be prepared or approved by the Secretary, setting forth excerpts from, or summaries of, the pertinent provisions of this subchapter and information pertaining to the filing of a charge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employer that willfully violates this section may be assessed a civil money penalty not to exceed $100 for each separate offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2620.</num>
<heading> Public health emergency leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following shall apply with respect to leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of certain terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The definitions in <ref>section 2611 of this title</ref> shall apply, except as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employee</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In lieu of the definition in sections 2611(2)(A) and 2611(2)(B)(ii) of this title, the term “eligible employee” means an employee who has been employed for at least 30 calendar days by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002194">1</ref> Rule regarding rehired employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), the term “employed for at least 30 calendar days”, used with respect to an employee and an employer described in clause (i), includes an employee who was laid off by that employer not earlier than <date date="2020-03-01">March 1, 2020</date>, had worked for the employer for not less than 30 of the last 60 calendar days prior to the employee’s layoff, and was rehired by the employer.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <sup>1</sup> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For purposes of applying <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref> and this section under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 [<ref>2 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.], in lieu of the definition in section 202(a)(2)(B) of that Act (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1312(a)(2)(B)</ref>), the term “eligible employee” means a covered employee (as defined in section 101 of that Act (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1301</ref>)) who has been employed for at least 30 calendar days by the employing office (as so defined) with respect to whom leave is requested under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employer threshold</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2"><ref>Section 2611(4)(A)(i) of this title</ref> shall be applied by substituting “fewer than 500 employees” for “50 or more employees for each working day during each of 20 or more calendar workweeks in the current or preceding calendar year”.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to the definitions described in paragraph (1), the following definitions shall apply with respect to leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref>:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying need related to a public health emergency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualifying need related to a public health emergency”, with respect to leave, means the employee is unable to work (or telework) due to a need for leave to care for the son or daughter under 18 years of age of such employee if the school or place of care has been closed, or the child care provider of such son or daughter is unavailable, due to a public health emergency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public health emergency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “public health emergency” means an emergency with respect to COVID–19 declared by a Federal, State, or local authority.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child care provider</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “child care provider” means a provider who receives compensation for providing child care services on a regular basis, including an “eligible child care provider” (as defined in <ref>section 9858n of title 42</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> School</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “school” means an “elementary school” or “secondary school” as such terms are defined in <ref>section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Labor shall have the authority to issue regulations for good cause under sections 553(b)(B) and 553(d)(3) of title 5—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to exclude certain health care providers and emergency responders from the definition of eligible employee under subsection (a)(1)(A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to exempt small businesses with fewer than 50 employees from the requirements of <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref> when the imposition of such requirements would jeopardize the viability of the business as a going concern; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act, including to ensure consistency between this Act and Division E and Division G of the Families First Coronavirus Response Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall have the authority to exclude for good cause from the requirements under subsection (b) certain employers of the United States Government with respect to certain categories of Executive Branch employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to paid leave</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unpaid leave for initial 10 days</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The first 10 days for which an employee takes leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref> may consist of unpaid leave.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee election</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An employee may elect to substitute any accrued vacation leave, personal leave, or medical or sick leave for unpaid leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref> in accordance with <ref>section 2612(d)(2)(B) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Paid leave for subsequent days</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An employer shall provide paid leave for each day of leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref> that an employee takes after taking leave under such section for 10 days.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), paid leave under subparagraph (A) for an employee shall be calculated based on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an amount that is not less than two-thirds of an employee’s regular rate of pay (as determined under <ref>section 207(e) of this title</ref>); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the number of hours the employee would otherwise be normally scheduled to work (or the number of hours calculated under subparagraph (C)).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An employer shall not be required to pay more than $200 per day and $10,000 in the aggregate for each employee for paid leave under this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Varying schedule hours calculation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of an employee whose schedule varies from week to week to such an extent that an employer is unable to determine with certainty the number of hours the employee would have worked if such employee had not taken leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref>, the employer shall use the following in place of such number:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to clause (ii), a number equal to the average number of hours that the employee was scheduled per day over the 6-month period ending on the date on which the employee takes such leave, including hours for which the employee took leave of any type.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the employee did not work over such period, the reasonable expectation of the employee at the time of hiring of the average number of hours per day that the employee would normally be scheduled to work.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case where the necessity for leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref> for the purpose described in subsection (a)(2)(A) is foreseeable, an employee shall provide the employer with such notice of leave as is practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restoration to position</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1"><ref>Section 2614(a)(1) of this title</ref> shall not apply with respect to an employee of an employer who employs fewer than 25 employees if the conditions described in paragraph (2) are met.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The conditions described in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The employee takes leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The position held by the employee when the leave commenced does not exist due to economic conditions or other changes in operating conditions of the employer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that affect employment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are caused by a public health emergency during the period of leave.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The employer makes reasonable efforts to restore the employee to a position equivalent to the position the employee held when the leave commenced, with equivalent employment benefits, pay, and other terms and conditions of employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> If the reasonable efforts of the employer under subparagraph (C) fail, the employer makes reasonable efforts during the period described in paragraph (3) to contact the employee if an equivalent position described in subparagraph (C) becomes available.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contact period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The period described under this paragraph is the 1-year period beginning on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date on which the qualifying need related to a public health emergency concludes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date that is 12 weeks after the date on which the employee’s leave under <ref>section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title</ref> commences.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title I, § 110</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–127, div. C, § 3102(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-18">Mar. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 3601, 3604(a), 3605, 3611(1), (3), (7), div. B, title IX, § 19008, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 410</ref>, 411, 414, 415, 579.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COMMISSION ON LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2631.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a commission to be known as the Commission on Leave (referred to in this subchapter as the “Commission”).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 23</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2632.</num>
<heading> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> conduct a comprehensive study of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> existing and proposed mandatory and voluntary policies relating to family and temporary medical leave, including policies provided by employers not covered under this Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the potential costs, benefits, and impact on productivity, job creation and business growth of such policies on employers and employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> possible differences in costs, benefits, and impact on productivity, job creation and business growth of such policies on employers based on business type and size;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the impact of family and medical leave policies on the availability of employee benefits provided by employers, including employers not covered under this Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> alternate and equivalent State enforcement of subchapter I with respect to employees described in <ref>section 2618(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> methods used by employers to reduce administrative costs of implementing family and medical leave policies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the ability of the employers to recover, under <ref>section 2614(c)(2) of this title</ref>, the premiums described in such section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the impact on employers and employees of policies that provide temporary wage replacement during periods of family and medical leave.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than 2 years after the date on which the Commission first meets, prepare and submit, to the appropriate Committees of Congress, a report concerning the subjects listed in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 23</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2633.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall be composed of 12 voting members and 4 ex officio members to be appointed not later than 60 days after <date date="1993-02-05">February 5, 1993</date>, as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">One Senator shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate, and one Senator shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members of House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">One Member of the House of Representatives shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and one Member of the House of Representatives shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional members</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Two members each shall be appointed by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Majority Leader of the Senate;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the Minority Leader of the Senate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expertise</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Such members shall be appointed by virtue of demonstrated expertise in relevant family, temporary disability, and labor management issues. Such members shall include representatives of employers, including employers from large businesses and from small businesses.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ex officio members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall serve on the Commission as nonvoting ex officio members.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made. The vacancy shall not affect the power of the remaining members to execute the duties of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson and vice chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall elect a chairperson and a vice chairperson from among the members of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Eight members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for all purposes, except that a lesser number may constitute a quorum for the purpose of holding hearings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 24</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2634.</num>
<heading> Compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Commission shall be allowed reasonable travel expenses, including a per diem allowance, in accordance with <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> when performing duties of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2635.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall first meet not later than 30 days after the date on which all members are appointed, and the Commission shall meet thereafter on the call of the chairperson or a majority of the members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings and sessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers appropriate. The Commission may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before it.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any Federal agency information necessary to enable it to carry out this subchapter, if the information may be disclosed under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>. Subject to the previous sentence, on the request of the chairperson or vice chairperson of the Commission, the head of such agency shall furnish such information to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of facilities and services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may make available to the Commission any of the facilities and services of such agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel from other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may detail any of the personnel of such agency to serve as an Executive Director of the Commission or assist the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission. Any detail shall not interrupt or otherwise affect the civil service status or privileges of the Federal employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the chairperson of the Commission may accept for the Commission voluntary services provided by a member of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2636.</num>
<heading> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall terminate 30 days after the date of the submission of the report of the Commission to Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2651.</num>
<heading> Effect on other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal and State antidiscrimination laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall be construed to modify or affect any Federal or State law prohibiting discrimination on the basis of race, religion, color, national origin, sex, age, or disability.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall be construed to supersede any provision of any State or local law that provides greater family or medical leave rights than the rights established under this Act or any amendment made by this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2652.</num>
<heading> Effect on existing employment benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> More protective</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall be construed to diminish the obligation of an employer to comply with any collective bargaining agreement or any employment benefit program or plan that provides greater family or medical leave rights to employees than the rights established under this Act or any amendment made by this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Less protective</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The rights established for employees under this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall not be diminished by any collective bargaining agreement or any employment benefit program or plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2653.</num>
<heading> Encouragement of more generous leave policies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall be construed to discourage employers from adopting or retaining leave policies more generous than any policies that comply with the requirements under this Act or any amendment made by this Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2654.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out subchapter I and this subchapter not later than 120 days after <date date="1993-02-05">February 5, 1993</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>