<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2—</num>
<heading>ACTS AND RESOLUTIONS; FORMALITIES OF ENACTMENT; REPEALS; SEALING OF INSTRUMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Enacting clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The enacting clause of all Acts of Congress shall be in the following form: “Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled.”</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Resolving clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The resolving clause of all joint resolutions shall be in the following form: “Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled.”</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Enacting or resolving words after first section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No enacting or resolving words shall be used in any section of an Act or resolution of Congress except in the first.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 104.</num>
<heading> Numbering of sections; single proposition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each section shall be numbered, and shall contain, as nearly as may be, a single proposition of enactment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 105.</num>
<heading> Title of appropriation Acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The style and title of all Acts making appropriations for the support of Government shall be as follows: “An Act making appropriations (here insert the object) for the year ending September 30 (here insert the calendar year).”</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 634</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–344, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 106.</num>
<heading> Printing bills and joint resolutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every bill or joint resolution in each House of Congress shall, when such bill or resolution passes either House, be printed, and such printed copy shall be called the engrossed bill or resolution as the case may be. Said engrossed bill or resolution shall be signed by the Clerk of the House or the Secretary of the Senate, and shall be sent to the other House, and in that form shall be dealt with by that House and its officers, and, if passed, returned signed by said Clerk or Secretary. When such bill, or joint resolution shall have passed both Houses, it shall be printed and shall then be called the enrolled bill, or joint resolution, as the case may be, and shall be signed by the presiding officers of both Houses and sent to the President of the United States. During the last six days of a session such engrossing and enrolling of bills and joint resolutions may be done otherwise than as above prescribed, upon the order of Congress by concurrent resolution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 106a.</num>
<heading> Promulgation of laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever a bill, order, resolution, or vote of the Senate and House of Representatives, having been approved by the President, or not having been returned by him with his objections, becomes a law or takes effect, it shall forthwith be received by the Archivist of the United States from the President; and whenever a bill, order, resolution, or vote is returned by the President with his objections, and, on being reconsidered, is agreed to be passed, and is approved by two-thirds of both Houses of Congress, and thereby becomes a law or takes effect, it shall be received by the Archivist of the United States from the President of the Senate, or Speaker of the House of Representatives in whichsoever House it shall last have been so approved, and he shall carefully preserve the originals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 2(b)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 710</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 106b.</num>
<heading> Amendments to Constitution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever official notice is received at the National Archives and Records Administration that any amendment proposed to the Constitution of the United States has been adopted, according to the provisions of the Constitution, the Archivist of the United States shall forthwith cause the amendment to be published, with his certificate, specifying the States by which the same may have been adopted, and that the same has become valid, to all intents and purposes, as a part of the Constitution of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 2(b)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 710</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 107.</num>
<heading> Parchment or paper for printing enrolled bills or resolutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Enrolled bills and resolutions of either House of Congress shall be printed on parchment or paper of suitable quality as shall be determined by the Joint Committee on Printing.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 108.</num>
<heading> Repeal of repealing act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever an Act is repealed, which repealed a former Act, such former Act shall not thereby be revived, unless it shall be expressly so provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 109.</num>
<heading> Repeal of statutes as affecting existing liabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The repeal of any statute shall not have the effect to release or extinguish any penalty, forfeiture, or liability incurred under such statute, unless the repealing Act shall so expressly provide, and such statute shall be treated as still remaining in force for the purpose of sustaining any proper action or prosecution for the enforcement of such penalty, forfeiture, or liability. The expiration of a temporary statute shall not have the effect to release or extinguish any penalty, forfeiture, or liability incurred under such statute, unless the temporary statute shall so expressly provide, and such statute shall be treated as still remaining in force for the purpose of sustaining any proper action or prosecution for the enforcement of such penalty, forfeiture, or liability.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110.</num>
<heading> Saving clause of Revised Statutes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All acts of limitation, whether applicable to civil causes and proceedings, or to the prosecution of offenses, or for the recovery of penalties or forfeitures, embraced in the Revised Statutes and covered by the repeal contained therein, shall not be affected thereby, but all suits, proceedings, or prosecutions, whether civil or criminal, for causes arising, or acts done or committed prior to said repeal, may be commenced and prosecuted within the same time as if said repeal had not been made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 111.</num>
<heading> Repeals as evidence of prior effectiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No inference shall be raised by the enactment of the Act of <date date="1933-03-03">March 3, 1933</date> (ch. 202, <ref>47 Stat. 1431</ref>), that the sections of the Revised Statutes repealed by such Act were in force or effect at the time of such enactment: <i>Provided, however</i>, That any rights or liabilities existing under such repealed sections shall not be affected by their repeal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112.</num>
<heading> Statutes at Large; contents; admissibility in evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Archivist of the United States shall cause to be compiled, edited, indexed, and published, the United States Statutes at Large, which shall contain all the laws and concurrent resolutions enacted during each regular session of Congress; all proclamations by the President in the numbered series issued since the date of the adjournment of the regular session of Congress next preceding; and also any amendments to the Constitution of the United States proposed or ratified pursuant to article V thereof since that date, together with the certificate of the Archivist of the United States issued in compliance with the provision contained in <ref>section 106b of this title</ref>. In the event of an extra session of Congress, the Archivist of the United States shall cause all the laws and concurrent resolutions enacted during said extra session to be consolidated with, and published as part of, the contents of the volume for the next regular session. The United States Statutes at Large shall be legal evidence of laws, concurrent resolutions, treaties, international agreements other than treaties, proclamations by the President, and proposed or ratified amendments to the Constitution of the United States therein contained, in all the courts of the United States, the several States, and the Territories and insular possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1001, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 979</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 3</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112a.</num>
<heading> United States Treaties and Other International Agreements; contents; admissibility in evidence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State shall cause to be compiled, edited, indexed, and published, beginning as of <date date="1950-01-01">January 1, 1950</date>, a compilation entitled “United States Treaties and Other International Agreements,” which shall contain all treaties to which the United States is a party that have been proclaimed during each calendar year, and all international agreements other than treaties to which the United States is a party that have been signed, proclaimed, or with reference to which any other final formality has been executed, during each calendar year. The said United States Treaties and Other International Agreements shall be legal evidence of the treaties, international agreements other than treaties, and proclamations by the President of such treaties and agreements, therein contained, in all the courts of the United States, the several States, and the Territories and insular possessions of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Copies of international agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments in the possession of the Department of State, but not published, other than the agreements described in section 112b(b)(3)(A), shall be made available by the Department of State upon request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1001, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 980</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 138</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7121(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5947(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112b.</num>
<heading> United States international agreements and non-binding instruments; transparency provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not less frequently than once each month, the Secretary shall provide in writing to the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the appropriate congressional committees the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A list of all international agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments signed, concluded, or otherwise finalized during the prior month.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The text of all international agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A detailed description of the legal authority that, in the view of the Secretary, provides authorization for each international agreement and that, in the view of the appropriate department or agency, provides authorization for each qualifying non-binding instrument provided under clause (ii) to become operative. If multiple authorities are relied upon in relation to an international agreement, the Secretary shall cite all such authorities, and if multiple authorities are relied upon in relation to a qualifying non-binding instrument, the appropriate department or agency shall cite all such authorities. All citations to the Constitution of the United States, a treaty, or a statute shall include the specific article or section and subsection reference whenever available and, if not available, shall be as specific as possible. If the authority relied upon is or includes article II of the Constitution of the United States, the Secretary or appropriate department or agency shall explain the basis for that reliance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A list of all international agreements that entered into force and qualifying non-binding instruments that became operative for the United States or an agency of the United States during the prior month.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The text of all international agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments described in clause (i) if such text differs from the text of the agreement or instrument previously provided pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A statement describing any new or amended statutory or regulatory authority anticipated to be required to fully implement each proposed international agreement and qualifying non-binding instrument included in the list described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The information and text required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 120 days after the date on which an international agreement enters into force, the Secretary shall make the text of the agreement, and the information described in subparagraphs (A)(iii) and (B)(iii) of subsection (a)(1) relating to the agreement, available to the public on the website of the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not less frequently than once every 120 days, the Secretary shall make the text of each qualifying non-binding instrument that became operative during the preceding 120 days, and the information described in subparagraphs (A)(iii) and (B)(iii) of subsection (a)(1) relating to each such instrument, available to the public on the website of the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The requirements under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply to the following categories of international agreements or qualifying non-binding instruments, or to information described in subparagraphs (A)(iii) and (B)(iii) of subsection (a)(1) relating to such agreements or qualifying non-binding instruments:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> International agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments that contain information that has been given a national security classification pursuant to Executive Order 13526 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3161</ref> note; relating to classified national security information) or any predecessor or successor order, or that contain any information that is otherwise exempt from public disclosure pursuant to United States law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> International agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments that address military operations, military exercises, acquisition and cross servicing, logistics support, military personnel exchange or education programs, or the provision of health care to military personnel on a reciprocal basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> International agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments that establish the terms of grant or other similar assistance, including in-kind assistance, financed with foreign assistance funds pursuant to the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.) or the Food for Peace Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> International agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments, such as project annexes and other similar instruments, for which the principal function is to establish technical details for the implementation of a specific project undertaken pursuant to another agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument that has been published in accordance with paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> International agreements and qualifying non-binding instruments that have been separately published by a depositary or other similar administrative body, except that the Secretary shall make the information described in subparagraphs (A)(iii) and (B)(iii) of subsection (a)(1), relating to such agreements or qualifying non-binding instruments, available to the public on the website of the Department of State within the timeframes required by paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For any international agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument for which an implementing agreement or arrangement, or any document of similar purpose or function to the aforementioned regardless of the title of the document, is not otherwise required to be submitted to the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the appropriate congressional committees under subparagraphs (A)(ii) or (B)(ii) of subsection (a)(1), not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a written communication from the Chair or Ranking Member of either of the appropriate congressional committees requesting the text of any such implementing agreements or arrangements, whether binding or non-binding, the Secretary shall submit such implementing agreements or arrangements to the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Any department or agency of the United States Government that enters into any international agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument on behalf of itself or the United States shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary the text of each international agreement not later than 15 days after the date on which such agreement is signed or otherwise concluded;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary the text of each qualifying non-binding instrument not later than 15 days after the date on which such instrument is concluded or otherwise becomes finalized;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary a detailed description of the legal authority that provides authorization for each qualifying non-binding instrument to become operative not later than 15 days after such instrument is signed or otherwise becomes finalized; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> on an ongoing basis, provide any implementing material to the Secretary for transmittal to the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the appropriate congressional committees as needed to satisfy the requirements described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each department or agency of the United States Government that enters into any international agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument on behalf of itself or the United States shall designate a Chief International Agreements Officer, who shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be selected from among employees of such department or agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve concurrently as the Chief International Agreements Officer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> subject to the authority of the head of such department or agency, have department- or agency-wide responsibility for efficient and appropriate compliance with this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There shall be a Chief International Agreements Officer who serves at the Department of State with the title of International Agreements Compliance Officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The substance of oral international agreements shall be reduced to writing for the purpose of meeting the requirements of subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an international agreement may not be signed or otherwise concluded on behalf of the United States without prior consultation with the Secretary. Such consultation may encompass a class of agreements rather than a particular agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, and not less frequently than once every 3 years thereafter during the 9-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit of the compliance of the Secretary with the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In any instance in which a failure by the Secretary to comply with such requirements is determined by the Comptroller General to have been due to the failure or refusal of another agency to provide information or material to the Department of State, or the failure to do so in a timely manner, the Comptroller General shall engage such other agency to determine—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the cause and scope of such failure or refusal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the specific office or offices responsible for such failure or refusal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommendations for measures to ensure compliance with statutory requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General shall submit to the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the appropriate congressional committees in writing the results of each audit required by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General and the Secretary shall make the results of each audit required by paragraph (1) publicly available on the websites of the Government Accountability Office and the Department of State, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The President shall, through the Secretary, promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> It is the sense of Congress that the executive branch should not prescribe or otherwise commit to or include specific legislative text in a treaty, executive agreement, or non-binding instrument unless Congress has authorized such action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “appropriate department or agency” means the department or agency of the United States Government that negotiates and enters into a qualifying non-binding instrument on behalf of itself or the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “international agreement” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any treaty that requires the advice and consent of the Senate, pursuant to article II of the Constitution of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other international agreement to which the United States is a party and that is not subject to the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “qualifying non-binding instrument”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> except as provided in subparagraph (B), means a non-binding instrument that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is or will be under negotiation, is signed or otherwise becomes operative, or is implemented with one or more foreign governments, international organizations, or foreign entities, including non-state actors; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> could reasonably be expected to have a significant impact on the foreign policy of the United States; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is the subject of a written communication from the Chair or Ranking Member of either of the appropriate congressional committees to the Secretary; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include any non-binding instrument that is signed or otherwise becomes operative or is implemented pursuant to the authorities relied upon by the Department of Defense, the Armed Forces of the United States, or any element of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “text” with respect to an international agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any annex, appendix, codicil, side agreement, side letter, or any document of similar purpose or function to the aforementioned, regardless of the title of the document, that is entered into contemporaneously and in conjunction with the international agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any implementing agreement or arrangement, or any document of similar purpose or function to the aforementioned regardless of the title of the document, that is entered into contemporaneously and in conjunction with the international agreement or qualifying non-binding instrument.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> As used in subparagraph (A), the term “contemporaneously and in conjunction with”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be construed liberally; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may not be interpreted to require any action to have occurred simultaneously or on the same day.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section may be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to authorize the withholding from disclosure to the public of any record if such disclosure is required by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to require the provision of any implementing agreement or arrangement, or any document of similar purpose or function regardless of its title, which was entered into by the Department of Defense, the Armed Forces of the United States, or any element of the intelligence community or any implementing material originating with the aforementioned agencies, if such implementing agreement, arrangement, document, or material was not required to be provided to the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, or the appropriate congressional committees prior to the date of the enactment of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–403, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-08-22">Aug. 22, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 619</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–45, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-06-15">June 15, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–426, title VII, § 708</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 993</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 1</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7121(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3807</ref>, 3808; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title XVII, § 1708(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5947(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 113.</num>
<heading> “Little and Brown’s” edition of laws and treaties; slip laws; Treaties and Other International Acts Series; admissibility in evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The edition of the laws and treaties of the United States, published by Little and Brown, and the publications in slip or pamphlet form of the laws of the United States issued under the authority of the Archivist of the United States, and the Treaties and Other International Acts Series issued under the authority of the Secretary of State shall be competent evidence of the several public and private Acts of Congress, and of the treaties, international agreements other than treaties, and proclamations by the President of such treaties and international agreements other than treaties, as the case may be, therein contained, in all the courts of law and equity and of maritime jurisdiction, and in all the tribunals and public offices of the United States, and of the several States, without any further proof or authentication thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–497, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-07-08">July 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 114.</num>
<heading> Sealing of instruments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In all cases where a seal is necessary by law to any commission, process, or other instrument provided for by the laws of Congress, it shall be lawful to affix the proper seal by making an impression therewith directly on the paper to which such seal is necessary; which shall be as valid as if made on wax or other adhesive substance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 636</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>