<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 34—</num>
<heading>INLAND NAVIGATIONAL RULES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>RULES</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 2001 to 2038.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1042</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2071.</num>
<heading> Inland navigation rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating may issue inland navigation regulations applicable to all vessels upon the inland waters of the United States and technical annexes that are as consistent as possible with the respective annexes to the International Regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–591, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1042</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2072.</num>
<heading> Violations of Inland Navigational Rules</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of operator for civil penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever operates a vessel in violation of this chapter, or of any regulation issued thereunder, or in violation of a certificate of alternative compliance issued under Rule 1 is liable to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of vessel for civil penalty; seizure of vessel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every vessel subject to this chapter, other than a public vessel being used for noncommercial purposes, that is operated in violation of this chapter, or of any regulation issued thereunder, or in violation of a certificate of alternative compliance issued under Rule 1 is liable to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each violation, for which penalty the vessel may be seized and proceeded against in the district court of the United States of any district within which the vessel may be found.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of civil penalty by Secretary; collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may assess any civil penalty authorized by this section. No such penalty may be assessed until the person charged, or the owner of the vessel charged, as appropriate, shall have been given notice of the violation involved and an opportunity for a hearing. For good cause shown, the Secretary may remit, mitigate, or compromise any penalty assessed. Upon the failure of the person charged, or the owner of the vessel charged, to pay an assessed penalty, as it may have been mitigated or compromised, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to commence an action in the appropriate district court of the United States for collection of the penalty as assessed, without regard to the amount involved, together with such other relief as may be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding of clearance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If any owner, operator, or individual in charge of a vessel is liable for a penalty under this section, or if reasonable cause exists to believe that the owner, operator, or individual in charge may be subject to a penalty under this section, the Secretary of the Treasury, upon the request of the Secretary, shall with respect to such vessel refuse or revoke any clearance required by <ref>section 60105 of title 46</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Clearance or a permit refused or revoked under this subsection may be granted upon filing of a bond or other surety satisfactory to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–591, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 312(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3920</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2073.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title VI, § 601(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4290</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>