<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 53—</num>
<heading>HARMFUL ALGAL BLOOM AND HYPOXIA RESEARCH AND CONTROL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4001.</num>
<heading> Assessments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Inter-Agency Task Force</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President, through the Committee on Environment and Natural Resources of the National Science and Technology Council, shall establish an Inter-Agency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia. The Task Force shall consist of a representative from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Department of Commerce (who shall serve as Chairman of the Task Force);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Environmental Protection Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Department of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Department of the Navy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Department of Health and Human Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the National Science Foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Food and Drug Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the Council on Environmental Quality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the Army Corps of Engineers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> other Federal agencies as the President considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of harmful algal blooms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 12 months after <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, the Task Force, in cooperation with the coastal States, Indian tribes, and local governments, industry (including agricultural organizations), academic institutions, and non-governmental organizations with expertise in coastal zone management, shall complete and submit to the Congress an assessment which examines the ecological and economic consequences of harmful algal blooms, alternatives for reducing, mitigating, and controlling harmful algal blooms, and the social and economic costs and benefits of such alternatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The assessment shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify alternatives for preventing unnecessary duplication of effort among Federal agencies and departments with respect to harmful algal blooms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for Federal cooperation and coordination with and assistance to the coastal States, Indian tribes, and local governments in the prevention, reduction, management, mitigation, and control of harmful algal blooms and their environmental and public health impacts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of hypoxia</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 12 months after <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, the Task Force, in cooperation with the States, Indian tribes, local governments, industry, agricultural, academic institutions, and non-governmental organizations with expertise in watershed and coastal zone management, shall complete and submit to the Congress an assessment which examines the ecological and economic consequences of hypoxia in United States coastal waters, alternatives for reducing, mitigating, and controlling hypoxia, and the social and economic costs and benefits of such alternatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The assessment shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish needs, priorities, and guidelines for a peer-reviewed, inter-agency research program on the causes, characteristics, and impacts of hypoxia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify alternatives for preventing unnecessary duplication of effort among Federal agencies and departments with respect to hypoxia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide for Federal cooperation and coordination with and assistance to the States, Indian tribes, and local governments in the prevention, reduction, management, mitigation, and control of hypoxia and its environmental impacts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress on harmful algal bloom impacts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2004-12-10">December 10, 2004</date>, the President, in consultation with the chief executive officers of the States, shall develop and submit to the Congress a report that describes and evaluates the effectiveness of measures described in paragraph (2) that may be utilized to protect environmental and public health from impacts of harmful algal blooms. In developing the report, the President shall consult with the Task Force, the coastal States, Indian tribes, local governments, appropriate industries (including fisheries, agriculture, and fertilizer), academic institutions, and nongovernmental organizations with expertise in coastal zone science and management, and also consider the scientific assessments developed under this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review techniques for prediction of the onset, course, and impacts of harmful algal blooms including evaluation of their accuracy and utility in protecting environmental and public health and provisions for their development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify innovative research and development methods for the prevention, control, and mitigation of harmful algal blooms and provisions for their development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> include incentive-based partnership approaches regarding subparagraphs (A) and (B) where practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication and opportunity for comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At least 90 days before submitting the report to the Congress, the President shall cause a summary of the proposed plan to be published in the Federal Register for a public comment period of not less than 60 days.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Task Force and to the extent of funds available, shall provide for Federal cooperation with and assistance to the coastal States, Indian tribes, and local governments regarding the measures described in paragraph (2), as requested.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local and regional scientific assessments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Task Force and appropriate State, Indian tribe, and local governments, to the extent of funds available, shall provide for local and regional scientific assessments of hypoxia and harmful algal blooms, as requested by States, Indian tribes, and local governments, or for affected areas as identified by the Secretary. If the Secretary receives multiple requests, the Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that assessments under this subsection cover geographically and ecologically diverse locations with significant ecological and economic impacts from hypoxia or harmful algal blooms. The Secretary shall establish a procedure for reviewing requests for local and regional assessments. The Secretary shall ensure, through consultation with Sea Grant Programs, that the findings of the assessments are communicated to the appropriate State, Indian tribe, and local governments, and to the general public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Local and regional assessments shall examine—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the causes and ecological consequences, and the economic cost, of hypoxia or harmful algal blooms in that area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> potential methods to prevent, control, and mitigate hypoxia or harmful algal blooms in that area and the potential ecological and economic costs and benefits of such methods; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other topics the Task Force considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scientific assessments of hypoxia</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not less than once every 5 years the Task Force shall complete and submit to the Congress a scientific assessment of hypoxia in United States coastal waters including the Great Lakes. The first such assessment shall be completed not less than 24 months after <date date="2004-12-10">December 10, 2004</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The assessments under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> examine the causes and ecological consequences, and the economic costs, of hypoxia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describe the potential ecological and economic costs and benefits of possible policy and management actions for preventing, controlling, and mitigating hypoxia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> evaluate progress made by, and the needs of, Federal research programs on the causes, characteristics, and impacts of hypoxia, including recommendations of how to eliminate significant gaps in hypoxia modeling and monitoring data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identify ways to improve coordination and to prevent unnecessary duplication of effort among Federal agencies and departments with respect to research on hypoxia.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scientific assessments of marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not less than once every 5 years the Task Force shall complete and submit to Congress a scientific assessment of harmful algal blooms in United States coastal waters and freshwater systems. Each assessment shall examine both marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms, including those in the Great Lakes and upper reaches of estuaries, those in freshwater lakes and rivers, and those that originate in freshwater lakes or rivers and migrate to coastal waters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National scientific research, development, demonstration, and technology transfer plan on reducing impacts from harmful algal blooms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 12 months after <date date="2004-12-10">December 10, 2004</date>, the Task Force shall develop and submit to Congress a plan providing for a comprehensive and coordinated national research program to develop and demonstrate prevention, control, and mitigation methods to reduce the impacts of harmful algal blooms on coastal ecosystems (including the Great Lakes), public health, and the economy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The plan shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish priorities and guidelines for a competitive, peer reviewed, merit based interagency research, development, demonstration, and technology transfer program on methods for the prevention, control, and mitigation of harmful algal blooms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify ways to improve coordination and to prevent unnecessary duplication of effort among Federal agencies and departments with respect to the actions described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> include to the maximum extent practicable diverse institutions, including Historically Black Colleges and Universities and those serving large proportions of Hispanics, Native Americans, Asian Pacific Americans, and other underrepresented populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce, in conjunction with other appropriate Federal agencies, shall establish a research, development, demonstration, and technology transfer program that meets the priorities and guidelines established under paragraph (2)(A). The Secretary shall ensure, through consultation with Sea Grant Programs, that the results and findings of the program are communicated to State, Indian tribe, and local governments, and to the general public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after the date the Action Strategy is submitted under <ref>section 4003 of this title</ref>, the Under Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that describes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the proceedings of the annual Task Force meetings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the activities carried out under the Program, including the regional and subregional parts of the Action Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the budget related to the activities under paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the progress made on implementing the Action Strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any need to revise or terminate research and activities under the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3448</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–456, title I</ref>, §§ 102–104, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3630</ref>, 3631; <ref>Pub. L. 113–124</ref>, §§ 3, 6, 10(b), <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1379</ref>, 1383, 1386; <ref>Pub. L. 115–423, § 9(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="2019-01-07">Jan. 7, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4001a.</num>
<heading> Consultation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing the assessments, reports, and plans under the Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Research and Control Act of 1998, the Task Force shall consult with the coastal States, Indian tribes, local governments, appropriate industries (including fisheries, agriculture, and fertilizer), academic institutions, and nongovernmental organizations with expertise in coastal zone science and management.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–456, title I, § 102</ref> (part), <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–423, § 9(f)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-07">Jan. 7, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5463</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4002.</num>
<heading> National harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, the Under Secretary, acting through the Task Force, shall maintain and enhance a national harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a statement of objectives, including understanding, detecting, predicting, controlling, mitigating, and responding to marine and freshwater harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the comprehensive research plan and action strategy under <ref>section 4003 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic revision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Task Force shall periodically review and revise the Program, as necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Task Force functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Task Force shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate interagency review of the objectives and activities of the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expedite the interagency review process by ensuring timely review and dispersal of required reports and assessments under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> support the implementation of the Action Strategy, including the coordination and integration of the research of all Federal programs, including ocean and Great Lakes science and management programs and centers, that address the chemical, biological, and physical components of marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> support the development of institutional mechanisms and financial instruments to further the objectives and activities of the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> review the Program’s distribution of Federal funding to address the objectives and activities of the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> promote the development of new technologies for predicting, monitoring, and mitigating harmful algal bloom and hypoxia conditions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> establish such interagency working groups as it considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead Federal agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (h), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall have primary responsibility for administering the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In administering the Program, the Under Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote the Program, including to local and regional stakeholders through the establishment and maintenance of a publicly accessible Internet website that provides information as to Program activities completed under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare work and spending plans for implementing the research and activities identified under the Action Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> administer peer-reviewed, merit-based, competitive grant funding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to maintain and enhance baseline monitoring programs established by the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to support the projects maintained and established by the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to address the research and management needs and priorities identified in the Action Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to accelerate the utilization of effective methods of intervention and mitigation to reduce the frequency, severity, and impacts of harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordinate with, and work cooperatively to provide technical assistance to, regional, State, tribal, and local government agencies and programs that address marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> coordinate with the Secretary of State to support international efforts on marine and freshwater harmful algal bloom and hypoxia information sharing, research, prediction, mitigation, control, and response activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> identify additional research, development, and demonstration needs and priorities relating to monitoring, prevention, control, mitigation, and response to marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia, including methods and technologies to protect the ecosystems affected by marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> integrate, coordinate, and augment existing education and extension programs to improve public understanding and awareness of the causes, impacts, intervention, and mitigation efforts for marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> facilitate and provide resources to train State and local coastal and water resource managers in the methods and technologies for monitoring, preventing, controlling, and mitigating marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> support regional efforts to control and mitigate outbreaks through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> communication of the contents of the Action Strategy and maintenance of online data portals for other information about harmful algal blooms and hypoxia to State, tribal, and local stakeholders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> overseeing the development, review, and periodic updating of the Action Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> convene at least 1 meeting of the Task Force each year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> perform such other tasks as may be delegated by the Task Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain and enhance the existing competitive programs at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration relating to harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carry out marine and Great Lakes harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events response activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop and enhance, including with respect to infrastructure, which shall include unmanned systems, as necessary, critical observations, monitoring, modeling, data management, information dissemination, and operational forecasts relevant to harmful algal blooms and hypoxia events;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> enhance communication and coordination among Federal agencies carrying out marine and freshwater harmful algal bloom and hypoxia activities and research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to the greatest extent practicable, leverage existing resources and expertise available from local research universities and institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> increase the availability to appropriate public and private entities of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> analytical facilities and technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operational forecasts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> reference and research materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> use cost effective methods in carrying out this Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> develop contingency plans for the long-term monitoring of hypoxia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall work cooperatively and avoid duplication of effort with other offices, centers, and programs within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, other agencies on the Task Force, and States, tribes, and nongovernmental organizations concerned with marine and freshwater issues to coordinate harmful algal bloom and hypoxia (and related) activities and research.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Freshwater</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to the freshwater aspects of the Program, the Administrator, through the Task Force, shall carry out the duties otherwise assigned to the Under Secretary under this section, except the activities described in subsection (f).</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator’s participation under this section shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> research on the ecology and impacts of freshwater harmful algal blooms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> forecasting and monitoring of and event response to freshwater harmful algal blooms in lakes, rivers, estuaries (including their tributaries), and reservoirs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonduplication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall ensure that activities carried out under this chapter focus on new approaches to addressing freshwater harmful algal blooms and are not duplicative of existing research and development programs authorized by this chapter or any other law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The collection of monitoring and observation data under this chapter shall comply with all data standards and protocols developed pursuant to the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.). Such data shall be made available through the system established under that Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 603A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–124, § 4</ref>, <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1379</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–423, § 9(e)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-07">Jan. 7, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4003.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive research plan and action strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, the Under Secretary, through the Task Force, shall develop and submit to Congress a comprehensive research plan and action strategy to address marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia. The Action Strategy shall identify—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the specific activities to be carried out by the Program and the timeline for carrying out those activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the roles and responsibilities of each Federal agency in the Task Force in carrying out the activities under paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the appropriate regions and subregions requiring specific research and activities to address harmful algal blooms and hypoxia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional focus</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The regional and subregional parts of the Action Strategy shall identify—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> regional priorities for ecological, economic, and social research on issues related to the impacts of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> research, development, and demonstration activities needed to develop and advance technologies and techniques for minimizing the occurrence of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia and improving capabilities to detect, predict, monitor, control, mitigate, respond to, and remediate harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ways to reduce the duration and intensity of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia, including deployment of response technologies in a timely manner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> research and methods to address human health dimensions of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> mechanisms, including the potential costs and benefits of those mechanisms, to protect ecosystems that may be or have been affected by harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> mechanisms by which data, information, and products may be transferred between the Program and the State, tribal, and local governments and research entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> communication and information dissemination methods that State, tribal, and local governments may undertake to educate and inform the public concerning harmful algal blooms and hypoxia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> roles that Federal agencies may have to assist in the implementation of the Action Strategy, including efforts to support local and regional scientific assessments under <ref>section 4001(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilizing available studies and information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing the Action Strategy, the Under Secretary shall utilize existing research, assessments, reports, and program activities, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> those carried out under existing law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other relevant peer-reviewed and published sources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of the Action Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing the Action Strategy, the Under Secretary shall, as appropriate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> coordinate with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State coastal management and planning officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> tribal resource management officials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> water management and watershed officials from both coastal States and noncoastal States with water sources that drain into water bodies affected by harmful algal blooms and hypoxia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> consult with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> public health officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> emergency management officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> science and technology development institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> economists;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> industries and businesses affected by marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> scientists with expertise concerning harmful algal blooms or hypoxia from academic or research institutions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> other stakeholders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall publish the Action Strategy in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic revision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary, in coordination and consultation with the individuals and entities under subsection (d), shall periodically review and revise the Action Strategy prepared under this section, as necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 603B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–124, § 5</ref>, <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1382</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4004.</num>
<heading> Northern Gulf of Mexico hypoxia</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial progress reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning not later than 12 months after <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Administrator, through the Mississippi River/Gulf of Mexico Watershed Nutrient Task Force, shall submit a progress report to the appropriate congressional committees and the President that describes the progress made by activities directed by the Mississippi River/Gulf of Mexico Watershed Nutrient Task Force and carried out or funded by the Environmental Protection Agency and other State and Federal partners toward attainment of the goals of the Gulf Hypoxia Action Plan 2008.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report required under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assess the progress made toward nutrient load reductions, the response of the hypoxic zone and water quality throughout the Mississippi/Atchafalaya River Basin, and the economic and social effects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> evaluate lessons learned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recommend appropriate actions to continue to implement or, if necessary, revise the strategy set forth in the Gulf Hypoxia Action Plan 2008.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3449</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–124, § 7</ref>, <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4004a.</num>
<heading> South Florida harmful algal blooms and hypoxia</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> South Florida</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “South Florida” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all lands and waters within the administrative boundaries of the South Florida Water Management District;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regional coastal waters, including Biscayne Bay, the Caloosahatchee Estuary, Florida Bay, Indian River Lagoon, and St. Lucie River Estuary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Florida Reef Tract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated assessment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim integrated assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 540 days after <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, the Task Force, in accordance with the authority under <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref>, shall complete and submit to Congress and the President an interim integrated assessment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finalized integrated assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, the Task Force shall finalize, and submit to Congress and the President, the interim integrated assessment required by paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of integrated assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The integrated assessment required by paragraphs (1) and (2) shall examine the causes, consequences, and potential approaches to reduce harmful algal blooms and hypoxia in South Florida, and the status of, and gaps within, current harmful algal bloom and hypoxia research, monitoring, management, prevention, response, and control activities that directly affect the region by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Federal agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> State agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> regional research consortia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> academia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> private industry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> nongovernmental organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Indian tribes (as defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 3 years and 180 days after <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, the Task Force shall develop and submit to Congress a plan, based on the integrated assessment under subsection (b), for reducing, mitigating, and controlling harmful algal blooms and hypoxia in South Florida.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The plan submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> address the monitoring needs identified in the integrated assessment under subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop a timeline and budgetary requirements for deployment of future assets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> identify requirements for the development and verification of South Florida harmful algal bloom and hypoxia models, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all assumptions built into the models; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> data quality methods used to ensure the best available data are utilized; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> propose a plan to implement a remote monitoring network and early warning system for alerting local communities in the region to harmful algal bloom risks that may impact human health.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing the action plan, the Task Force shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with the State of Florida, and affected local and tribal governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consult with representatives from regional academic, agricultural, industry, and other stakeholder groups;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensure that the plan complements and does not duplicate activities conducted by other Federal or State agencies, including the South Florida Ecosystem Restoration Task Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identify critical research for reducing, mitigating, and controlling harmful algal bloom events and their effects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> evaluate cost-effective, incentive-based partnership approaches;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> ensure that the plan is technically sound and cost-effective;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> utilize existing research, assessments, reports, and program activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> publish a summary of the proposed plan in the Federal Register at least 180 days prior to submitting the completed plan to Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> after submitting the completed plan to Congress, provide biennial progress reports on the activities toward achieving the objectives of the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 605</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–144, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4005.</num>
<heading> Great Lakes hypoxia and harmful algal blooms</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, the Task Force, in accordance with the authority under <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref>, shall complete and submit to the Congress and the President an integrated assessment that examines the causes, consequences, and approaches to reduce hypoxia and harmful algal blooms in the Great Lakes, including the status of and gaps within current research, monitoring, management, prevention, response, and control activities by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> State agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> regional research consortia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> academia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> private industry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> nongovernmental organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, the Task Force shall develop and submit to the Congress a plan, based on the integrated assessment under subsection (a), for reducing, mitigating, and controlling hypoxia and harmful algal blooms in the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The plan shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> address the monitoring needs identified in the integrated assessment under subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop a timeline and budgetary requirements for deployment of future assets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> identify requirements for the development and verification of Great Lakes hypoxia and harmful algal bloom models, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all assumptions built into the models; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> data quality methods used to ensure the best available data are utilized; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> describe efforts to improve the assessment of the impacts of hypoxia and harmful algal blooms by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> characterizing current and past biological conditions in ecosystems affected by hypoxia and harmful algal blooms; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> quantifying effects, including economic effects, at the population and community levels.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing the plan, the Task Force shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate with State and local governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consult with representatives from academic, agricultural, industry, and other stakeholder groups, including relevant Canadian agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensure that the plan complements and does not duplicate activities conducted by other Federal or State agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identify critical research for reducing, mitigating, and controlling hypoxia events and their effects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> evaluate cost-effective, incentive-based partnership approaches;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> ensure that the plan is technically sound and cost effective;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> utilize existing research, assessments, reports, and program activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> publish a summary of the proposed plan in the Federal Register at least 180 days prior to submitting the completed plan to Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> after submitting the completed plan to Congress, provide biennial progress reports on the activities toward achieving the objectives of the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 606</ref>, formerly § 605, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3449</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–456, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. B, title V, § 528</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–124, § 8</ref>, <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1384</ref>; renumbered § 606, <ref>Pub. L. 117–144, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4006.</num>
<heading> Protection of States’ rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be interpreted to adversely affect existing State regulatory or enforcement power which has been granted to any State through the Clean Water Act [<ref>33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.] or Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1451</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be interpreted to expand the regulatory or enforcement power of the Federal Government which has been delegated to any State through the Clean Water Act or Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 607</ref>, formerly § 606, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3450</ref>; renumbered § 607, <ref>Pub. L. 117–144, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4007.</num>
<heading> Effect on other Federal authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority preserved</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter supersedes or limits the authority of any agency to carry out its responsibilities and missions under other laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter may be construed as establishing new regulatory authority for any agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 608</ref>, formerly § 607, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–124, § 9</ref>, <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1385</ref>; renumbered § 608, <ref>Pub. L. 117–144, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4008.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action Strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Action Strategy” means the comprehensive research plan and action strategy established under <ref>section 4003 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Harmful algal bloom</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “harmful algal bloom” means marine and freshwater phytoplankton that proliferate to high concentrations, resulting in nuisance conditions or harmful impacts on marine and aquatic ecosystems, coastal communities, and human health through the production of toxic compounds or other biological, chemical, and physical impacts of the algae outbreak.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hypoxia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “hypoxia” means a condition where low dissolved oxygen in aquatic systems causes stress or death to resident organisms.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the national harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program established under <ref>section 4002 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, any other territory or possession of the United States, and any Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Task Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Task Force” means the Inter-Agency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia under <ref>section 4001(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Under Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Under Secretary” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States coastal waters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States coastal waters” includes the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 609</ref>, formerly § 608, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–124, § 10(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1385</ref>; renumbered § 609, <ref>Pub. L. 117–144, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4009.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary to carry out sections 4002 and 4003 of this title $20,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018, and $20,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extramural research activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall ensure that a substantial portion of funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) that are used for research purposes are allocated to extramural research activities. For each fiscal year, the Under Secretary shall publish a list of all grant recipients and the amounts for all of the funds allocated for research purposes, specifying those allocated for extramural research activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 610</ref>, formerly § 609, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–124, § 11</ref>, <date date="2014-06-30">June 30, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1386</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–423, § 9(h)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-07">Jan. 7, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5464</ref>; renumbered § 610, <ref>Pub. L. 117–144, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4010.</num>
<heading> Hypoxia or harmful algal bloom of national significance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Upon a determination under paragraph (2) that there is an event of national significance, the appropriate Federal official is authorized to make sums available to the affected State or local government for the purposes of assessing and mitigating the detrimental environmental, economic, subsistence use, and public health effects of the event of national significance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal share of the cost of any activity carried out under this paragraph for the purposes described in subparagraph (A) may not exceed 50 percent of the cost of that activity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Donations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an appropriate Federal official may accept donations of funds, services, facilities, materials, or equipment that the appropriate Federal official considers necessary for the purposes described in subparagraph (A). Any funds donated to an appropriate Federal official under this paragraph may be expended without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At the discretion of an appropriate Federal official, or at the request of the Governor of an affected State, an appropriate Federal official shall determine whether a hypoxia or harmful algal bloom event is an event of national significance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In making a determination under subparagraph (A), the appropriate Federal official shall consider the toxicity of the harmful algal bloom, the severity of the hypoxia, its potential to spread, the economic impact, the relative size in relation to the past 5 occurrences of harmful algal blooms or hypoxia events that occur on a recurrent or annual basis, and the geographic scope, including the potential to affect several municipalities, to affect more than 1 State, or to cross an international boundary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate federal official</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “appropriate Federal official” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a marine or coastal hypoxia or harmful algal bloom event, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a freshwater hypoxia or harmful algal bloom event, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Event of national significance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “event of national significance” means a hypoxia or harmful algal bloom event that has had or will likely have a significant detrimental environmental, economic, subsistence use, or public health impact on an affected State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hypoxia or harmful algal bloom event</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “hypoxia or harmful algal bloom event” means the occurrence of hypoxia or a harmful algal bloom as a result of a natural, anthropogenic, or undetermined cause.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–423, § 9(g)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-07">Jan. 7, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5463</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>