<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 54—</num>
<heading>COMMERCIAL ENGAGEMENT THROUGH OCEAN TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administration” means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative activities of the Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002156">1</ref> “cooperative activities of the Administration” means cooperative activities between the Administration and an external entity, such as the Cooperative Institutes, Sea Grant Colleges, National Estuarine Research Reserves, the National Oceanographic Partnership Program established under chapter 665 of title 10, and regional associations of the Integrated Ocean Observing System.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data specifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “data specifications” shall refer to the type, resolution, periodicity, and quality of data required by an program of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Test or training range</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “test or training range” means an area designated for operating unmanned maritime systems and other types of systems for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> evaluating the performance of such systems; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> training personnel on operating procedures for such systems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “test or training range” may include specialized fixed or portable instrumentation for the operation of unmanned maritime systems and other types of systems.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unmanned maritime systems</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “unmanned maritime systems” means remotely operated or autonomous vehicles produced by the commercial sector—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> designed to function without an on-board human presence; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that may include associated components such as control and communications, instrumentation, data transmission, and processing systems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Examples</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “unmanned maritime systems” includes the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Unmanned undersea vehicles.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Unmanned surface vehicles.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Autonomous underwater vehicles.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Autonomous surface vehicles.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of aerial vehicles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “unmanned maritime systems” includes unmanned aerial vehicles and autonomous aerial vehicles that are used to address maritime issues to the extent the Administrator determines it is necessary and appropriate to achieve the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–394, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4102.</num>
<heading> Coordination regarding assessment and acquisition by National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of unmanned maritime systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall direct the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (in this chapter referred to as “OAR”) and the Office of Marine and Aviation Operations (in this chapter referred to as “OMAO”)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to coordinate the Administration’s research, assessment, and acquisition of unmanned maritime systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to consider the use of unmanned maritime systems in cooperative activities of the Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination within the Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unmanned Systems Executive Oversight Board</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In meeting the requirements described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> utilize the Unmanned Systems Executive Oversight Board (in this chapter referred to as the “USEOB”) as the coordinating mechanism; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that OAR and OMAO address requirements throughout the Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In utilizing the USEOB under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall ensure that representation on the USEOB is included from the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Office of Ocean Exploration (OER).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The program office of the Integrated Ocean Observing System.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Such other offices of the Administration as the Administrator determines are actively engaged with unmanned maritime systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with the Navy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out this chapter, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make efforts to coordinate with the Secretary of the Navy to leverage expertise in the development and operational transition of unmanned maritime systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> align with, utilize, and inform the Deputy Under Secretary of Commerce for Operations and the Oceanographer of the Navy’s strategic and operational priorities, particularly for missions and geography within the Administration’s purview;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> seek to utilize Naval unmanned systems test or training ranges, such as the Gulf of Mexico Unmanned Systems Test and Training Range of the Naval Meteorology and Oceanography Command, and maximize interagency cooperation and sharing of best practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> to formalize coordination, execute a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of the Navy that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> incorporating consideration of priorities and requirements of the Administration into research and development activities conducted by the Secretary of the Navy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> consultation intended to encourage and facilitate efforts by the Administration to partner with the Navy to procure unmanned maritime systems and to establish, instrument, and operate test or training ranges and related facilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> adopting procedures defined by the Secretary of the Navy for the Administration to access and utilize test or training ranges or related Naval facilities for purposes identified in paragraph (2)(B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> such other topics as the Administrator considers necessary or advisable, including mapping, bathymetry, observations, and ocean exploration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall, if practicable, carry out the activities authorized by this chapter at a facility where the Navy and the Administration are co-located, for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Gaining efficiencies through collaboration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Advancing development of unmanned maritime systems, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> systems research and development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> systems testing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> systems modifications; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> systems integration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Accelerating transition from concept to manufacturing and acquisition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Administrator and the Secretary of the Navy may utilize the National Oceanographic Partnership Program, established under chapter 665 of title 10, as a mechanism for providing interagency coordination for the advancement of unmanned maritime systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with academic sector</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Navy, may coordinate and co-locate with an academic research institution, or consortium of academic research institutions, for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Maximizing opportunities for research and development of unmanned maritime systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Providing training in unmanned maritime systems as part of an accredited certificate or degree program of education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Facilitating the commercialization of unmanned maritime systems through public-private partnerships that includes academic research institutions, private industry, and public safety agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Arranging access to and use of additional facilities that support testing and assessment of or training with respect to unmanned maritime systems under environmental conditions of interest, increasing operational tolerance under such conditions, certifying operational capacity under such conditions, whether real or simulated, and training operators of unmanned maritime systems in real or simulated environments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Facilitating engagement with other academic institutions with interest or relevant expertise in unmanned maritime systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Promoting information sharing between the academic, environmental, and military institutions to lead to more robust, mission-oriented unmanned maritime systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Engagement with the private sector</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Other than as described in subsection (e), the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Navy, may, in carrying out this chapter, to the extent practicable, coordinate and consult with the private sector—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support the commercialization of unmanned maritime systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist with their assessment of commercially available unmanned maritime systems to support the missions and goals of the Navy, the Administration, and cooperative activities of the Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–394, § 3</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4103.</num>
<heading> Regular assessment of unmanned maritime systems to support National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration missions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, acting through the Assistant Administrator for Oceanic and Atmospheric Research and the Director of the Office of Marine and Aviation Operations and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps, shall regularly assess publicly and commercially available unmanned maritime systems for potential use to support missions of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Science-based assessments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall carry out subsection (a) through the Assistant Administrator for all matters relating to assessment of the suitability, feasibility, and cost-effectiveness of unmanned maritime systems to meet data specifications required by programs of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of operational utility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall carry out subsection (a) through the Director for all matters relating to assessment of whether unmanned maritime systems are operationally reliable, feasible, and cost effective enough to make observations required by programs of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Engagement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Assistant Administrator and the Director shall jointly—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> convene and consult the Unmanned Maritime Systems Ocean Technology Coordinating Committee established under <ref>section 4102(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consult with the heads of other offices of the Administration, the academic sector, and developers and manufacturers of unmanned maritime systems to conduct the assessments under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–394, § 4</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4104.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of unmanned maritime systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall coordinate and centralize the acquisition by the Administration of unmanned maritime systems to meet the prioritized list of data requirements identified by OAR and OMAO in carrying out this chapter in their regular assessments and approved by the USEOB.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memoranda of understanding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to realize greater savings and efficiency, the Administrator may develop and execute a memorandum of agreement with the Secretary of the Navy to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> participate in procurements conducted by the signatories to the memorandum of understanding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accept decommissioned unmanned maritime systems from the Navy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop policies and procedures to share unmanned maritime systems; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide for other means of creating efficiency and savings in Federal acquisition of unmanned maritime systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to modify Federal procurement law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–394, § 5</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4105.</num>
<heading> Reports on unmanned maritime systems and usage for mission of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Administrator shall, not later than one year after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, and every 4 years thereafter, submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the usage of unmanned maritime systems for the mission of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An inventory of current unmanned maritime systems used by programs of the Administration, a summary of the data they have returned, and the benefits realized from having such data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A prioritized list of data requirements of the Administration that could be met with unmanned maritime systems, and the commercially available unmanned maritime systems with the operational capabilities to collect such data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Natural Resources, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–394, § 6</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4106.</num>
<heading> Funding and additional authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall carry out this chapter using existing amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Administrator may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into contracts, cooperative agreements, and other transactions with any domestic or foreign government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, accept donations and voluntary and uncompensated services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> accept funds from other Federal departments and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> utilize the National Oceanographic Partnership Program established under chapter 665 of title 10 to accept funds from other Federal departments and agencies, to accept donations, and to enter into contracts and award grants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> under an agreement entered into under paragraph (1), transfer funds appropriated to carry our this chapter to any organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> use, with their consent, with or without reimbursement, and subject to the availability of appropriations, the land, services, equipment, personnel, and facilities of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any State or local government or tribal government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any foreign government or international organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–394, § 7</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>