<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 17—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 851.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 851a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 3, 1948, ch. 390, § 22(a)</ref>, formerly § 21(a), <ref>62 Stat. 300</ref>; renumbered § 22(a), <date date="1961-09-14">Sept. 14, 1961</date>, <ref>Pub. L. 87–233, § 1(f)</ref>, <ref>75 Stat. 506</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 852 to 852b.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 853.</num>
<heading> Power to settle claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to consider, ascertain, adjust, and determine all claims for damages, where the amount of the claim does not exceed $2,500, occasioned, subsequent to <date date="1920-06-05">June 5, 1920</date>, by acts for which the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration is responsible.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 5, 1920, ch. 256</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–608, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–176</ref>, <date date="1983-11-29">Nov. 29, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 853a to 853l.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 853m, 853n.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 12, 1949, ch. 681</ref>, title V, § 531(b)(41), <ref>63 Stat. 840</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 853o.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 853o–1.</num>
<heading> Credit of service as deck officer or junior engineer and certain other active service for retirement and retirement pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Active service in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as a deck officer or junior engineer and active service counted on <date date="1922-06-30">June 30, 1922</date>, for longevity pay, shall be credited to commissioned officers as active commissioned service for purposes of retirement and retirement pay.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 9(c)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 496</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 853p to 853r.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 853s.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 88–431, § 1(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 440</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 853t to 854.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 854a.</num>
<heading> Service credit as deck officer or junior engineer for promotion purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of promotion which is now or may hereafter be authorized for officers appointed after <date date="1922-06-30">June 30, 1922</date>, there shall be counted in addition to active commissioned service, service as deck officer and junior engineer.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Jan. 19, 1942, ch. 6, § 2</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref>June 3, 1948, ch. 390, § 22(a)</ref>, formerly § 21(a), <ref>62 Stat. 300</ref>, renumbered § 22(a), <ref>Pub. L. 87–233, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1961-09-14">Sept. 14, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref>Oct. 12, 1949, ch. 681</ref>, title V, § 531(b)(32), <ref>63 Stat. 839</ref>; <ref>June 21, 1955, ch. 172, § 3(a)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 169</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 854a–1.</num>
<heading> Temporary appointment or advancement of commissioned officers in time of war or national emergency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Personnel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall be subject in like manner and to the same extent as personnel of the Navy to all laws authorizing temporary appointment or advancement of commissioned officers in time of war or national emergency subject to the following limitations:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Commissioned officers in the service of a military department, under the provisions of sections 854, 855, 856, 857, and 858 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">1</ref> of this title may, upon the recommendation of the Secretary of the military department concerned, be temporarily promoted to higher ranks or grades.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Commissioned officers in the service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration may be temporarily promoted to fill vacancies in ranks and grades caused by the transfer of commissioned officers to the service and jurisdiction of a military department under the provisions of sections 854, 855, 856, 857, and 858 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Temporary appointments may be made in all grades to which original appointments in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration are authorized: <i>Provided</i>, That the number of officers holding temporary appointments shall not exceed the number of officers transferred to a military department under the provisions of sections 854, 855, 856, 857, and 858 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Dec. 3, 1942, ch. 670, § 1</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 1038</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–657, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-10-14">Oct. 14, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 907</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 854a–2.</num>
<heading> Pay and allowances; date of acceptance of promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any commissioned officer of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration promoted to a higher grade at any time after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, shall be deemed for all purposes to have accepted his promotion to higher grade upon the date such promotion is made by the President unless he shall expressly decline such promotion, and shall receive the pay and allowances of the higher grade from such date unless he is entitled under some other provision of law to receive the pay and allowances of the higher grade from an earlier date. No such officer who shall have subscribed to the oath of office required by <ref>section 3331 of title 5</ref>, shall be required to renew such oath or to take a new oath upon his promotion to a higher grade, if his service after the taking of such an oath shall have been continuous.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Dec. 3, 1942, ch. 670, § 3</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 1039</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 854b, 854c.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 3, 1948, ch. 390, § 22(a)</ref>, formerly § 21(a), <ref>62 Stat. 300</ref>; renumbered § 22(a), <date date="1961-09-14">Sept. 14, 1961</date>, <ref>Pub. L. 87–233, § 1(f)</ref>, <ref>75 Stat. 506</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 855.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(4)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 855a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 85–857, § 14(79)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1272</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 856 to 857–5.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 857–6 to 857–12.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–63, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 267</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–13.</num>
<heading> National Advisory Committee on Oceans and Atmosphere</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established a committee of 18 members to be known as the National Advisory Committee on Oceans and Atmosphere (hereinafter in sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title referred to as the “Committee”).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–63, § 2</ref>, <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–14.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The members of the Committee, who may not be full-time officers or employees of the United States, shall be appointed by the President. Members shall be appointed only from among individuals who are eminently qualified by way of knowledge and expertise in the following areas of direct concern to the Committee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one or more of the disciplines and fields included in marine science and technology, marine industry, marine-related State and local governmental functions, coastal zone management, or other fields directly appropriate for consideration of matters of ocean policy; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> one or more of the disciplines and fields included in atmospheric science, atmospheric-related State and local governmental functions, or other fields directly appropriate for consideration of matters of atmospheric policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term of office of a member of the Committee shall be 3 years; except that of the original appointees, 6 shall be appointed for a term to expire on <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, 6 shall be appointed for a term to expire on <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, and 6 shall be appointed for a term to expire on <date date="1981-07-01">July 1, 1981</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which his or her predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term. No individual may be reappointed to the Committee for more than one additional 3-year term. A member may serve after the date of the expiration of the term of office for which appointed until his or her successor has taken office. The terms of office for members first appointed after <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, shall begin on <date date="1977-07-01">July 1, 1977</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall designate one of the members of the Committee as the Chairman and one of the members as the Vice Chairman. The Vice Chairman shall act as Chairman in the absence or incapacity of, or in the event of a vacancy in the office of, the Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> undertake a continuing review, on a selective basis, of national ocean policy, coastal zone management, and the status of the marine and atmospheric science and service programs of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise the Secretary of Commerce with respect to the carrying out of the programs administered by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–63, § 3</ref>, <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 265</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–304, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-29">June 29, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 347</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–87, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–15.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee shall submit an annual report to the President and to the Congress setting forth an assessment, on a selective basis, of the status of the Nation’s marine and atmospheric activities, and shall submit such other reports as may from time to time be requested by the President or the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each annual report shall also be submitted to the Secretary of Commerce, who shall, within 60 days after receipt thereof, transmit his or her comments and recommendations to the President and to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report submittal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The annual report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted on or before June 30 of each year, beginning with <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–63, § 4</ref>, <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–16.</num>
<heading> Compensation and travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Committee shall each be entitled to receive compensation not to exceed the daily rate for a GS–18 for each day (including traveltime) during which they are engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Committee. In addition, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of the duties of the Committee, each member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002028">1</ref> of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–63, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–87, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–17.</num>
<heading> Interagency cooperation and assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liaison</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of each department or agency of the Federal Government concerned with marine and atmospheric matters shall designate a senior policy official to participate as observer in the work of the Committee and offer necessary assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee is authorized to request from the head of any department, agency, or independent instrumentality of the Federal Government any information and assistance it deems necessary to carry out the functions assigned under sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title. The head of each such department, agency, or instrumentality is authorized to cooperate with the Committee, and, to the extent permitted by law, to furnish such information and assistance to the Committee upon request made by the Chairman, without reimbursement for such services and assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall make available to the Committee such staff, information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance as may reasonably be required to carry out the provisions of sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–63, § 6</ref>, <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–18.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for purposes of carrying out sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title not to exceed $520,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, $572,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, $565,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, $600,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, and $555,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>. Such sums as may be appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–63, § 8</ref>, <date date="1977-07-05">July 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 267</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–304, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-29">June 29, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 347</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–26</ref>, <date date="1979-06-21">June 21, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 74</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–87, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–19.</num>
<heading> Biennial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning in September, 2001, the President shall transmit to the Congress biennially a report that includes a detailed listing of all existing Federal programs related to ocean and coastal activities, including a description of each program, the current funding for the program, linkages to other Federal programs, and a projection of the funding level for the program for each of the next 5 fiscal years beginning after the report is submitted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–256, § 5</ref>, <date date="2000-08-07">Aug. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 648</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 857–20.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–221, § 10</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1061</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 857a, 858.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(2)</ref>, (4), <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 859.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 16, 1942, ch. 413, § 19</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 369</ref>, eff. <date date="1942-06-01">June 1, 1942</date></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 860.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14b</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 499</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 861.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 861a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 861b, 861c.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 862.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14b</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 498</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 862a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 863.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 21, 1955, ch. 172, § 5(4)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 170</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 864.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(6)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 864a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 864b, 864c.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 3, 1948, ch. 390, § 22(a)</ref>, formerly § 21(a), <ref>62 Stat. 300</ref>; renumbered § 22(a), <date date="1961-09-14">Sept. 14, 1961</date>, <ref>Pub. L. 87–233, § 1(f)</ref>, <ref>75 Stat. 506</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 864d.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 12, 1949, ch. 681</ref>, title V, § 531(b)(31), <ref>63 Stat. 839</ref>, eff. <date date="1949-10-01">Oct. 1, 1949</date></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 864e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 86–465, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-05-13">May 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 130</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 865.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 866.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 10(1)</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 867, 868.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 1(39)</ref>, (60), <ref>65 Stat. 702</ref>, 703</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 868a.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 869.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIII, § 1313 <ref>58 Stat. 714</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 870.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 837</ref>, title V, § 502(7), <ref>70 Stat. 886</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 871.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Dec. 28, 1945, ch. 597, § 4</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 662</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 872.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 873.</num>
<heading> Extra compensation for instrument observers, recorders and other Federal employees for oceanographic, seismographic and magnetic observations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to pay extra compensation to members of crews of vessels when assigned duties as instrument observer or recorder, and to employees of other Federal agencies while observing tides or currents, or tending seismographs or magnetographs, at such rates as may be specified from time to time by him and without regard to <ref>section 5533 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 22, 1947, ch. 286, § 2</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 400</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–397, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-03-28">Mar. 28, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–448, title IV, § 401</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 491</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 874.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 271(5)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3094</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 875.</num>
<heading> Powers of officers as notaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In places where the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration is serving which are not within the jurisdiction of any one of the States of the continental United States, excluding Alaska, commanding officers of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration vessels, and such other officers of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as the Secretary of Commerce may designate, may exercise the general powers of the notary public in the administration of oaths for the execution, acknowledgment, and attestation of instruments and papers, and the performance of all other notarial acts. The powers conferred shall be limited to acts performed in behalf of the personnel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or in connection with the proper execution of the functions of that agency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 932, § 1</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 988</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 24</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 418</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 876.</num>
<heading> Fees for notarial acts; prima facie evidence of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No fee of any kind shall be paid to any officer for the performance of any notarial act authorized by <ref>section 875 of this title</ref>. The signature without seal together with indication of grade of any officer performing any notarial act shall be prima facie evidence of his authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 932, § 2</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 988</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 877.</num>
<heading> Appropriations; advances from</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Advances of money from available appropriations may be made to the National Ocean Survey and by authority of the Director thereof to chiefs of parties and accounts arising under such advances shall be rendered through and by the disbursing officer of the National Ocean Survey to the Government Accountability Office as under advances made to chiefs of parties prior to <date date="1918-07-01">July 1, 1918</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 1, 1918, ch. 113, § 1</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 688</ref>; <ref>June 5, 1920, ch. 235, § 1</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref>June 10, 1921, ch. 18</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref>42 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 231(z)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 878.</num>
<heading> Appropriations; purchases from</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to purchase, from the appropriation for the National Ocean Survey, provisions, clothing, and small stores for the enlisted men, and food supplies for field parties working in remote localities, such provisions, clothing, small stores, and food supplies to be sold to the employees of said survey and the appropriation reimbursed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 853, § 1</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 1144</ref>; <ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 878a.</num>
<heading> Contract for development of a major program; costs; Major Program Annual Report for satellite development program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Under Secretary” means Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Science, Space and Technology of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “satellite” means the satellites proposed to be acquired for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “development” means the phase of a program following the formulation phase and beginning with the approval to proceed to implementation, as defined in NOAA Administrative Order 216–108, Department of Commerce Administrative Order 208–3, and NASA’s Procedural Requirements 7120.5c, dated <date date="2005-03-22">March 22, 2005</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “development cost” means the total of all costs, including construction of facilities and civil servant costs, from the period beginning with the approval to proceed to implementation through the achievement of operational readiness, without regard to funding source or management control, for the life of the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “life-cycle cost” means the total of the direct, indirect, recurring, and nonrecurring costs, including the construction of facilities and civil servant costs, and other related expenses incurred or estimated to be incurred in the design, development, verification, production, operation, maintenance, support, and retirement of a program over its planned lifespan, without regard to funding source or management control;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “major program” means an activity approved to proceed to implementation that has an estimated life-cycle cost of more than $250,000,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “baseline” means the program as set following contract award and preliminary design review of the space and ground systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract requirements for major programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> NOAA shall not enter into a contract for development of a major program, unless the Under Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the technical, cost, and schedule risks of the program are clearly identified and the program has developed a plan to manage those risks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the technologies required for the program have been demonstrated in a relevant laboratory or test environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the program complies with all relevant policies, regulations, and directives of NOAA and the Department of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the program has demonstrated a high likelihood of accomplishing its intended goals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the acquisition of satellites for use in the program represents a good value to accomplishing NOAA’s mission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall transmit a report describing the basis for the determination required under paragraph (1) to the appropriate congressional committees at least 30 days before entering into a contract for development under a major program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary may not delegate the determination requirement under this subsection, except in cases in which the Under Secretary has a conflict of interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Annually, at the same time as the President’s annual budget submission to the Congress, the Under Secretary shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the information required by this section for the satellite development program for which NOAA proposes to expend funds in the subsequent fiscal year. The report under this paragraph shall be known as the Major Program Annual Report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The first Major Program Annual Report for NOAA’s satellite development program shall include a Baseline Report that shall, at a minimum, include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the purposes of the program and key technical characteristics necessary to fulfill those purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an estimate of the life-cycle cost for the program, with a detailed breakout of the development cost, program reserves, and an estimate of the annual costs until development is completed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the schedule for development, including key program milestones;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the plan for mitigating technical, cost, and schedule risks identified in accordance with subsection (b)(1)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the name of the person responsible for making notifications under subsection (d), who shall be an individual whose primary responsibility is overseeing the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the major program for which a Baseline Report has been submitted, subsequent Major Program Annual Reports shall describe any changes to the information that had been provided in the Baseline Report, and the reasons for those changes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Under Secretary of excess development costs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The individual identified under subsection (c)(2)(E) shall immediately notify the Under Secretary any time that individual has reasonable cause to believe that, for the major program for which he or she is responsible, the development cost of the program has exceeded the estimate provided in the Baseline Report of the program by 20 percent or more.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after the notification required under paragraph (1), the individual identified under subsection (c)(2)(E) shall transmit to the Under Secretary a written notification explaining the reasons for the change in the cost of the program for which notification was provided under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not later than 15 days after the Under Secretary receives a written notification under paragraph (2), the Under Secretary shall transmit the notification to the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by Under Secretary of excess development costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after receiving a written notification under subsection (d)(2), the Under Secretary shall determine whether the development cost of the program has exceeded the estimate provided in the Baseline Report of the program by 20 percent or more. If the determination is affirmative, the Under Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> transmit to the appropriate congressional committees, not later than 15 days after making the determination, a report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the increase in cost and a detailed explanation for the increase;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of actions taken or proposed to be taken in response to the cost increase; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of any impacts the cost increase, or the actions described under subparagraph (B), will have on any other program within NOAA; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> if the Under Secretary intends to continue with the program, promptly initiate an analysis of the program, which shall include, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the projected cost and schedule for completing the program if current requirements of the program are not modified;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the projected cost and the schedule for completing the program after instituting the actions described under paragraph (1)(B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of, and the projected cost and schedule for, a broad range of alternatives to the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Completion and transmittal of analysis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">NOAA shall complete an analysis initiated under subsection (e)(2) not later than 6 months after the Under Secretary makes a determination under subsection (e). The Under Secretary shall transmit the analysis to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 30 days after its completion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–55, div. B, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2011-11-18">Nov. 18, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–6, div. B, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-26">Mar. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 878b.</num>
<heading> Safety and health regulations for scientific and occupational diving</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="2009-03-11">March 11, 2009</date>, the Secretary of Commerce is permitted to prescribe and enforce standards or regulations affecting safety and health in the context of scientific and occupational diving within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. B, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>SURVEYS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 881 to 883.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 10(2)</ref>–(5), <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883a.</num>
<heading> Surveys and other activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To provide charts and related information for the safe navigation of marine and air commerce, and to provide basic data for engineering and scientific purposes and for other commercial and industrial needs, the Secretary of Commerce, is authorized to conduct the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Hydrographic and topographic surveys;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Tide and current observations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Geodetic-control surveys;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Field surveys for aeronautical charts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Geomagnetic, seismological, gravity, and related geophysical measurements and investigations, and observations for the determination of variation in latitude and longitude.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 1</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 787</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–409</ref>, <date date="1960-04-05">Apr. 5, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 16</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883b.</num>
<heading> Dissemination of data; further activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order that full public benefit may be derived from the operations of the National Ocean Survey by the dissemination of data resulting from the activities herein authorized and of related data from other sources, the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to conduct the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Analysis and prediction of tide and current data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Processing and publication of data, information, compilations, and reports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Compilation and printing of nautical charts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Distribution of nautical charts and related navigational publications.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 2</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 787</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883c.</num>
<heading> Geomagnetic data; collection, correlation, and dissemination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To provide for the orderly collection of geomagnetic data from domestic and foreign sources, and to assure that such data shall be readily available to Government and private agencies and individuals, the National Ocean Survey is designated as the central depository of the United States Government for geomagnetic data, and the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to collect, correlate, and disseminate such data.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 3</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 787</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883d.</num>
<heading> Improvement of methods, instruments, and equipments; investigations and research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To improve the efficiency of the National Ocean Survey and to increase engineering and scientific knowledge, the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to conduct developmental work for the improvement of surveying and cartographic methods, instruments, and equipments; and to conduct investigations and research in geophysical sciences (including geodesy, oceanography, seismology, and geomagnetism).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 4</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883e.</num>
<heading> Agreements for surveys and investigations; contribution of costs incurred by National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements, or any other agreements, with, and to receive and expend funds made available by, any State or subdivision thereof, any Federal agency, or any public or private organization, or individual, for surveys or investigations authorized herein, or for performing related surveying and mapping activities, including special-purpose maps, and for the preparation and publication of the results thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to establish the terms of any agreement entered into under this section, including the amount of funds to be received, and may contribute that portion of the costs incurred by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including shiptime and personnel expenses, which the Secretary determines represents the amount of benefits derived by the Administration from the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 5</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title VI, § 6085</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title VI, § 605(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883f.</num>
<heading> Contracts with qualified organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to contract with qualified organizations for the performance of any part of the authorized functions of the National Ocean Survey when he deems such procedure to be in the public interests.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 6</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883g.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 88–611, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-02">Oct. 2, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 991</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883h.</num>
<heading> Employment of public vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to cause to be employed such of the public vessels as he deems it expedient to employ, and to give such instructions for regulating their conduct as he deems proper in order to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 8</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883i.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such funds as may be necessary to acquire, construct, maintain, and operate ships, stations, equipment, and facilities and for such other expenditures, including personal services at the seat of government and elsewhere and including the erection of temporary observatory buildings and lease of sites therefor, as may be necessary for the conduct of the activities herein authorized.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 9</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883j.</num>
<heading> Ocean satellite data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (hereinafter referred to in this subtitle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref> as the “Administration”) shall take such actions, including the sponsorship of applied research, as may be necessary to assure the future availability and usefulness of ocean satellite data to the maritime community.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title VI, § 6082</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883k.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of land for facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For fiscal year 1990 and hereafter funds appropriated under this heading shall be available for acquisition of land for facilities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–162, title I</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 883l.</num>
<heading> Contracts for surveying and mapping services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="2003-02-20">February 20, 2003</date>, the Secretary of Commerce may award contracts for hydrographic, geodetic, and photogrammetric surveying and mapping services in accordance with title IX of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002030">1</ref></p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. B, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 77</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 884.</num>
<heading> Power to use books, maps, etc., and to employ persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized, in executing the provisions of title 56 of the Revised Statutes relating to the coast survey, to use all maps, charts, books, instruments, and apparatus belonging to the United States, and to direct where the same shall be deposited, and to employ all persons in the land or naval service of the United States, and such astronomers and other persons as he shall deem proper.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 4685.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 885.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 6, 1947, ch. 504, § 10(6)</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 788</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 886, 887.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 21, 1955, ch. 172, § 5(1)</ref>, (2), <ref>69 Stat. 170</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 888.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 889, 890.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 21, 1955, ch. 172, § 5(5)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 170</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>NOAA FLEET MODERNIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 891.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “NOAA” means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration within the Department of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “NOAA fleet” means the fleet of research vessels owned or operated by NOAA.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Plan” means the NOAA Fleet Replacement and Modernization Plan described in <ref>section 891b of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “UNOLS” means University-National Oceanographic Laboratory System.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4299</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891a.</num>
<heading> Fleet replacement and modernization program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to implement, subject to the requirements of this subchapter, a 15-year program to replace and modernize the NOAA fleet.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891b.</num>
<heading> Fleet replacement and modernization Plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the program authorized in <ref>section 891a of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall develop and submit to Congress a replacement and modernization Plan for the NOAA fleet covering the years authorized under <ref>section 891h of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Plan required in subsection (a) shall be submitted to Congress within 30 days of <date date="1992-10-29">October 29, 1992</date>, and updated on an annual basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Plan required in subsection (a) shall include the following—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of vessels proposed to be modernized or replaced, the schedule for their modernization or replacement, and anticipated funding requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of vessels proposed to be constructed, leased, or chartered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of vessels, or days at sea, that can be obtained by using the vessels of the UNOLS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of vessels that will be made available to NOAA by the Secretary of the Navy, or any other federal <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref> official, and the terms and conditions for their availability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the proposed acquisition of modern scientific instrumentation for the NOAA fleet, including acoustic systems, data transmission positioning and communication systems, physical, chemical, and meteorological oceanographic systems, and data acquisition and processing systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the appropriate role of the NOAA Corps in operating and maintaining the NOAA fleet.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracting limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may not enter into any contract for the construction, lease, or service life extension of a vessel of the NOAA fleet before the date of the submission to Congress of the Plan required in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891c.</num>
<heading> Design of NOAA vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Design requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except for the vessel designs identified under subsection (b), the Secretary, working through the Office of the NOAA Corps Operations and the Systems Procurement Office, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prepare requirements for each class of vessel to be constructed or converted under the Plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> contract competitively from nongovernmental entities with expertise in shipbuilding for vessel design and construction based on the requirements for each class of vessel to be acquired.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> report to Congress identifying any existing vessel design or design proposal that meets the requirements of the Plan within 30 days after <date date="1992-10-29">October 29, 1992</date>, and shall promptly advise the Congress of any modification of these designs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to Congress as part of the annual update of the Plan required in <ref>section 891b of this title</ref>, any subsequent existing vessel design or design proposals that meet the requirements of the Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891d.</num>
<heading> Contract authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiyear contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), and notwithstanding <ref>section 1341 of title 31</ref> and subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 6301 of title 41</ref>, the Secretary may acquire vessels for the NOAA fleet by purchase, lease, lease-purchase, or otherwise, under one or more multiyear contracts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may not enter into a contract pursuant to this subsection unless the Secretary finds with respect to that contract that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is a reasonable expectation that throughout the contemplated contract period the Secretary will request from Congress funding for the contract at the level required to avoid contract termination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of the contract will promote the best interests of the United States by encouraging competition and promoting economic efficiency in the operation of the NOAA fleet.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required contract provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may not enter into a contract pursuant to this subsection unless the contract includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a provision under which the obligation of the United States to make payments under the contract for any fiscal year is subject to the availability of appropriations provided in advance for those payments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a provision that specifies the term of effectiveness of the contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> appropriate provisions under which, in case of any termination of the contract before the end of the term specified pursuant to subparagraph (B), the United States shall only be liable for the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an amount specified in the contract for such a termination; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> amounts that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> were appropriated before the date of the termination for the performance of the contract or for procurement of the type of acquisition covered by the contract; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> are unobligated on the date of the termination.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may enter into multiyear contracts for oceanographic research, fisheries research, and mapping and charting services to assist the Secretary in fulfilling NOAA missions. The Secretary may only enter into these contracts if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary finds that it is in the public interest to do so;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the contract is for not more than 7 years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the cost of the contract is less than the cost (including the cost of operation, maintenance, and personnel) to the NOAA of obtaining those services on NOAA vessels; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> NOAA vessels are not available or cannot provide those services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bonding authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, the Secretary may not require a contractor for the construction, alteration, repair or maintenance of a NOAA vessel to provide a bid bond, payment bond, performance bond, completion bond, or other surety instrument in an amount greater than 20 percent of the value of the base contract quantity (excluding options) unless the Secretary determines that requiring an instrument in that amount will not prevent a responsible bidder or offeror from competing for the award of the contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891e.</num>
<heading> Restriction with respect to certain shipyard subsidies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce may not award a contract for the construction, repair (except emergency repairs), or alteration of any vessel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in a shipyard, if that vessel benefits or would benefit from significant subsidies for the construction, repair, or alteration of vessels in that shipyard.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Significant subsidy” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “significant subsidy” includes, but is not limited to, any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Officially supported export credits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Direct official operating support to the commercial shipbuilding and repair industry, or to a related entity that favors the operation of shipbuilding and repair, including but not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> grants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> loans and loan guarantees other than those available on the commercial market;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> forgiveness of debt;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> equity infusions on terms inconsistent with commercially reasonable investment practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> preferential provision of goods and services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Direct official support for investment in the commercial shipbuilding and repair industry, or to a related entity that favors the operation of shipbuilding and repair, including but not limited to the kinds of support listed in paragraph (2)(A) through (E), and any restructuring support, except public support for social purposes directly and effectively linked to shipyard closures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Assistance in the form of grants, preferential loans, preferential tax treatment, or otherwise, that benefits or is directly related to shipbuilding and repair for purposes of research and development that is not equally open to domestic and foreign enterprises.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Tax policies and practices that favor the shipbuilding and repair industry, directly or indirectly, such as tax credits, deductions, exemptions, and preferences, including accelerated depreciation, if such benefits are not generally available to persons or firms not engaged in shipbuilding or repair.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any official regulation or practice that authorizes or encourages persons or firms engaged in shipbuilding or repair to enter into anticompetitive arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Any indirect support directly related, in law or in fact, to shipbuilding and repair at national yards, including any public assistance favoring shipowners with an indirect effect on shipbuilding or repair activities, and any assistance provided to suppliers of significant inputs to shipbuilding, which results in benefits to domestic shipbuilders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Any export subsidy identified in the Illustrative List of Export Subsidies in the Annex to the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures referred to in <ref>section 3511(d)(12) of title 19</ref>, or any other export subsidy prohibited by that agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1002(f)</ref>, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 133</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891e–1.</num>
<heading> Shipyards located outside of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="2007-12-26">December 26, 2007</date>, none of the funds made available in this Act or any other Act may be used for the construction, repair (other than emergency repair), overhaul, conversion, or modernization of vessels for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in shipyards located outside of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. B, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891f.</num>
<heading> Use of vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vessel agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing the NOAA fleet replacement and modernization program, the Secretary shall use excess capacity of UNOLS vessels where appropriate and may enter into memoranda of agreement with the operators of these vessels to carry out this requirement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within one year after <date date="1992-10-29">October 29, 1992</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide a report to Congress, in consultation with the Secretary, comparing the cost-efficiency, accounting, and operating practices of the vessels of NOAA, UNOLS, other Federal agencies, and the United States private sector in meeting the missions of NOAA.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 608</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891g.</num>
<heading> Interoperability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult with the Oceanographer of the Navy regarding appropriate measures that should be taken, on a reimbursable basis, to ensure that NOAA vessels are interoperable with vessels of the Department of the Navy, including with respect to operation, maintenance, and repair of those vessels.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 609</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 891h.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1993;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 for fiscal year 1994; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such sums as are necessary for each of the fiscal years 1995, 1996, and 1997.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on fleet modernization activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration fleet modernization shipbuilding, and conversion shall be conducted in accordance with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 610</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>NOAA HYDROGRAPHIC SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 892.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administration” means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hydrographic data</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “hydrographic data” means information that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> is acquired through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> hydrographic, bathymetric, photogrammetric, lidar, radar, remote sensing, or shoreline and other ocean- and coastal-related surveying;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> geodetic, geospatial, or geomagnetic measurements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> tide, water level, and current observations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> other methods; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is used in providing hydrographic services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hydrographic services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “hydrographic services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the management, maintenance, interpretation, certification, and dissemination of bathymetric, hydrographic, shoreline, geodetic, geospatial, geomagnetic, and tide, water level, and current information, including the production of nautical charts, nautical information databases, hydrodynamic forecast and datum transformation models, and other products derived from hydrographic data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the development of nautical information systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> related activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coast and Geodetic Survey Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Coast and Geodetic Survey Act” means the Act entitled “An Act to define the functions and duties of the Coast and Geodetic Survey, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1947-08-06">August 6, 1947</date> (<ref>33 U.S.C. 883a</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–384, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–386, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10308(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 892a.</num>
<heading> Functions of the Administrator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To fulfill the data gathering and dissemination duties of the Administration under the Coast and Geodetic Survey Act, promote safe, efficient and environmentally sound marine transportation, and otherwise fulfill the purposes of this subchapter, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire and disseminate hydrographic data and provide hydrographic services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promulgate standards for hydrographic data used by the Administration in providing hydrographic services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promulgate standards for hydrographic services provided by the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure comprehensive geographic coverage of hydrographic services, in cooperation with other appropriate Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> maintain a national database of hydrographic data, in cooperation with other appropriate Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide hydrographic services in uniform, easily accessible formats;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> participate in the development of, and implement for the United States in cooperation with other appropriate Federal agencies, international standards for hydrographic data and hydrographic services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to the greatest extent practicable and cost-effective, fulfill the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (6) through contracts or other agreements with private sector entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To fulfill the data gathering and dissemination duties of the Administration under the Coast and Geodetic Survey Act, promote precision navigation, safe, efficient, and environmentally sound marine transportation, and otherwise fulfill the purposes of this subchapter, subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may procure, lease, evaluate, test, develop, and operate vessels, equipment, and technologies necessary to ensure safe navigation and maintain operational expertise in hydrographic data acquisition and hydrographic services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, design, install, maintain, and operate real-time hydrographic monitoring systems and hydrodynamic forecast models to enhance navigation safety and efficiency and provide foundational information and services required to support coastal resilience planning for coastal transportation and other infrastructure, coastal protection and restoration projects, and related activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> where appropriate and to the extent that it does not detract from the promotion of safe and efficient navigation, may acquire hydrographic data and provide hydrographic services to support the conservation and management of coastal and ocean resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> where appropriate, may acquire hydrographic data and provide hydrographic services to save and protect life and property and support the resumption of commerce in response to emergencies, natural and man-made disasters, and homeland security and maritime domain awareness needs, including obtaining mission assignments (as defined in <ref>section 741 of title 6</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may create, support, and maintain such joint centers with other Federal agencies and other entities as the Administrator deems appropriate or necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> notwithstanding the existence of such joint centers, shall award contracts for the acquisition of hydrographic data in accordance with subchapter VI of chapter 10 of title 40.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002032">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation and management of coastal and ocean resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where appropriate and to the extent that it does not detract from the promotion of safe and efficient navigation, the Secretary may use hydrographic data and services to support the conservation and management of coastal and ocean resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–384, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–386, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10308(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 892b.</num>
<heading> Quality assurance program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “hydrographic product” means any publicly or commercially available product or service produced or disseminated by a non-Federal entity that includes or displays hydrographic data.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by not later than 2 years after <date date="2002-12-19">December 19, 2002</date>, shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, develop and implement a quality assurance program that is equally available to all applicants, under which the Administrator may certify hydrographic products that satisfy the standards promulgated by the Administrator under <ref>section 892a(a)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may authorize the use of the emblem or any trademark of the Administration on a hydrographic product certified under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may charge a fee for such certification and use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on fee amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any fee under paragraph (1)(C) shall not exceed the costs of conducting the quality assurance testing, evaluation, or studies necessary to determine whether the hydrographic product satisfies the standards adopted under <ref>section 892a(a)(3) of this title</ref>, including the cost of administering such a program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Government of the United States shall not be liable for any negligence by a person that produces hydrographic products certified under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hydrographic Services Account</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury a separate account, which shall be known as the “Hydrographic Services Account”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The account shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts received by the United States as fees charged under subsection (b)(1)(C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other amounts as may be provided by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts in the account shall be available to the Administrator, without further appropriation, for hydrographic services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on new fees and increases in existing fees for hydrographic services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, the Administrator may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish any fee or other charge for the provision of any hydrographic service except as authorized by this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increase the amount of any fee or other charge for the provision of any hydrographic service except as authorized by this section and <ref>section 1307 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–384, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3455</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10308(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 892c.</num>
<heading> Hydrographic Services Review Panel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No later than 1 year after <date date="2002-12-19">December 19, 2002</date>, the Secretary shall establish the Hydrographic Services Review Panel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The panel shall advise the Administrator on matters related to the responsibilities and authorities set forth in <ref>section 892a of this title</ref> and such other appropriate matters as the Administrator refers to the panel for review and advice.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall make available to the panel such information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance as it may reasonably require to carry out its duties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The panel shall consist of 15 voting members who shall be appointed by the Administrator. The Co-directors of the Center for Coastal and Ocean Mapping/Joint Hydrographic Center and no more than 2 employees of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration appointed by the Administrator shall serve as nonvoting members of the panel. The voting members of the panel shall be individuals who, by reason of knowledge, experience, or training, are especially qualified in 1 or more of the disciplines and fields relating to hydrographic data and hydrographic services, marine transportation, port administration, vessel pilotage, coastal and fishery management, and other disciplines as determined appropriate by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An individual may not be appointed as a voting member of the panel if the individual is a full-time officer or employee of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any voting member of the panel who is an applicant for, or beneficiary (as determined by the Secretary) of, any assistance under this subchapter shall disclose to the panel that relationship, and may not vote on any matter pertaining to that assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term of office of a voting member of the panel shall be 4 years, except that of the original appointees, five shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, five shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, and five shall be appointed for a term of 4 years, as specified by the Administrator at the time of appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any individual appointed to a partial or full term may be reappointed for one additional full term. A voting member may serve after the date of the expiration of the term of office for which appointed until his or her successor has taken office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nominations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At least once each year, the Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for membership on the panel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman and Vice Chairman</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The panel shall select one voting member to serve as the Chairman and another voting member to serve as the Vice Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Vice Chairman shall act as Chairman in the absence or incapacity of the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Voting members of the panel shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receive compensation at a rate established by the Secretary, not to exceed the maximum daily rate payable under <ref>section 5376 of title 5</ref> when actually engaged in the performance of duties for such panel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be reimbursed for actual and reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of such duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The panel shall meet on a biannual basis and, at any other time, at the call of the Chairman or upon the request of a majority of the voting members or of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The panel may exercise such powers as are reasonably necessary in order to carry out its duties under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–384, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title IV, § 432(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–386, § 4</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 892d.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To carry out nautical mapping and charting functions under sections 892b and 892c of this title, except for conducting hydrographic surveys, $71,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To contract for hydrographic surveys under <ref>section 892b(b)(1) of this title</ref>, including the leasing or time chartering of vessels, $34,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To operate hydrographic survey vessels owned by the United States and operated by the Administration, $38,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To carry out geodetic functions under this subchapter, $45,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To carry out tide and current measurement functions under this subchapter, $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To acquire a replacement hydrographic survey vessel capable of staying at sea continuously for at least 30 days $75,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arctic programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amount authorized by this section for each fiscal year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> $10,000,000 is authorized for use in the Arctic—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to acquire hydrographic data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide hydrographic services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to conduct coastal change analyses necessary to ensure safe navigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to improve the management of coastal change; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to reduce risks of harm to subsistence and coastal communities associated with increased international maritime traffic; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $2,000,000 is authorized for use to acquire hydrographic data and provide hydrographic services in the Arctic necessary to delineate the United States extended Continental Shelf.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on administrative expenses for surveys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of amounts authorized by this section for each fiscal year for contract hydrographic surveys, not more than 5 percent is authorized for administrative costs associated with contract management.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–384, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title IV, § 432(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3081</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–386, § 5</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title X, § 1001</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10308(d)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH, DEVELOPMENT, EDUCATION, AND INNOVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 893.</num>
<heading> Ocean and atmospheric research and development program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, shall establish a coordinated program of ocean, coastal, Great Lakes, and atmospheric research and development, in collaboration with academic institutions and other nongovernmental entities, that shall focus on the development of advanced technologies and analytical methods that will promote United States leadership in ocean and atmospheric science and competitiveness in the applied uses of such knowledge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oceanic and atmospheric research and development program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall implement programs and activities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to identify emerging and innovative research and development priorities to enhance United States competitiveness, support development of new economic opportunities based on NOAA research, observations, monitoring modeling, and predictions that sustain ecosystem services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote United States leadership in oceanic and atmospheric science and competitiveness in the applied uses of such knowledge, including for the development and expansion of economic opportunities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to advance ocean, coastal, Great Lakes, and atmospheric research and development, including potentially transformational research, in collaboration with other relevant Federal agencies, academic institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental programs, consistent with NOAA’s mission to understand, observe, and model the Earth’s atmosphere and biosphere, including the oceans, in an integrated manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No later than 12 months after <date date="2011-01-04">January 4, 2011</date>, the Administrator, in consultation with the National Science Foundation or other such agencies with mature transformational research portfolios, shall develop and submit a report to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Science and Technology that describes NOAA’s strategy for enhancing transformational research in its research and development portfolio to increase United States competitiveness in oceanic and atmospheric science and technology. The report shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> define “transformational research”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identify emerging and innovative areas of research and development where transformational research has the potential to make significant and revolutionary – <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref> advancements in both understanding and U.S. science leadership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> describe how transformational research priorities are identified and appropriately – <sup>1</sup> balanced in the context of NOAA’s broader research portfolio;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> describe NOAA’s plan for developing a competitive peer review and priority-setting – <sup>1</sup> process, funding mechanisms, performance and evaluation measures, and transition-to-operation guidelines for transformational research; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> describe partnerships with other agencies involved in transformational research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–69, title IV, § 4001</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 893a.</num>
<heading> NOAA ocean and atmospheric science education programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall conduct, develop, support, promote, and coordinate formal and informal educational activities at all levels to enhance public awareness and understanding of ocean, coastal, Great Lakes, and atmospheric science and stewardship by the general public and other coastal stakeholders, including underrepresented groups in ocean and atmospheric science and policy careers. In conducting those activities, the Administrator shall build upon the educational programs and activities of the agency, with consideration given to the goal of promoting the participation of individuals identified in sections 1885a and 1885b of title 42 in STEM fields and in promoting the acquisition and retention of highly qualified and motivated young scientists to complement and supplement workforce needs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Educational program goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The education programs developed by NOAA shall, to the extent applicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out and support research based programs and activities designed to increase student interest and participation in STEM;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improve public literacy in STEM;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> employ proven strategies and methods for improving student learning and teaching in STEM;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> provide curriculum support materials and other resources that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are designed to be integrated with comprehensive STEM education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are aligned with national science education standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are designed considering the unique needs of underrepresented groups, translating such materials and other resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promote the adoption and implementation of high-quality education practices that build toward college and career-readiness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> are promoted widely, especially among individuals identified in sections 1885a and 1885b of title 42; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> create and support opportunities for enhanced and ongoing professional development for teachers using best practices that improves the STEM content and knowledge of the teachers, including through programs linking STEM teachers with STEM educators at the higher education level.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NOAA science education plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, appropriate National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration programs, ocean atmospheric science and education experts, and interested members of the public shall maintain a science education plan setting forth education goals and strategies for the Administration, as well as programmatic actions to carry out such goals and priorities over the next 20 years, and evaluate and update such plan every 5 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Metrics</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In executing the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration science education plan under subsection (c), the Administrator shall maintain a comprehensive system for evaluating the Administration’s educational programs and activities. In so doing, the Administrator shall ensure that such education programs have measurable objectives and milestones as well as clear, documented metrics for evaluating programs. For each such education program or portfolio of similar programs, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> encourage the collection of evidence as relevant to the measurable objectives and milestones; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that program or portfolio evaluations focus on educational outcomes and not just inputs, activities completed, or the number of participants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed to affect the application of <ref>section 1232a of title 20</ref> or sections 794 and 794d of title 29.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> STEM defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “STEM” means the academic and professional disciplines of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–69, title IV, § 4002</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3997</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–329, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="2017-01-06">Jan. 6, 2017</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 3015</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 893b.</num>
<heading> NOAA’s contribution to innovation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation in interagency activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall be a full participant in any interagency effort to promote innovation and economic competitiveness through near-term and long-term basic scientific research and development and the promotion of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, consistent with the agency mission, including authorized activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Historic foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to carry out the participation described in subsection (a), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall build on the historic role of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in stimulating excellence in the advancement of ocean and atmospheric science and engineering disciplines and in providing opportunities and incentives for the pursuit of academic studies in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–69, title IV, § 4003</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 893c.</num>
<heading> Workforce study</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, in cooperation with the Secretary of Education, shall request the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study on the scientific workforce in the areas of oceanic and atmospheric research and development. The study shall investigate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether there is a shortage in the number of individuals with advanced degrees in oceanic and atmospheric sciences who have the ability to conduct high quality scientific research in physical and chemical oceanography, meteorology, and atmospheric modeling, and related fields, for government, nonprofit, and private sector entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether there is a shortage in the number of individuals with technical or trade-based degrees, skillsets, or credentials suited to a career in oceanic and atmospheric data collection, processing, satellite production, or satellite operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> what Federal programs are available to help facilitate the education of students hoping to pursue these degrees, skillsets, or credentials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> barriers to transitioning highly qualified oceanic and atmospheric scientists or highly qualified technical professionals and tradespeople into Federal civil service scientist career tracks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> what institutions of higher education, the private sector, and the Congress could do to increase the number of individuals with such post baccalaureate degrees, skillsets, or credentials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the impact of an aging Federal workforce on the ability of Federal agencies to conduct high quality scientific research, observations, and monitoring;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> what actions the Federal government can take to assist the transition of highly qualified scientists, technical professionals, and tradespeople into Federal career positions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> workforce diversity and actions the Federal Government can take to increase diversity in the scientific workforce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> actions the Federal Government can take to shorten the hiring backlog for such workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and the Secretary of Education shall consult with the heads of other Federal agencies and departments with oceanic and atmospheric expertise or authority in preparing the specifications for the study.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No later than 18 months after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and the Secretary of Education shall transmit a joint report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, detailing the findings and recommendations of the study and setting forth a prioritized plan to implement the recommendations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program and plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall evaluate the National Academy of Sciences study and develop a workforce program and plan to institutionalize the Administration’s Federal science career pathways and address aging workforce issues. The program and plan shall be developed in consultation with the Administration’s cooperative institutes and other academic partners.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3998</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CI, § 10103</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3957</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>SEXUAL HARASSMENT AND ASSAULT PREVENTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 894.</num>
<heading> Actions to address sexual harassment at National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2016-12-23">December 23, 2016</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, develop a policy on the prevention of and response to sexual harassment involving employees of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, and individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters to be specified in policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The policy developed under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establishment of a program to promote awareness of the incidence of sexual harassment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> clear procedures an individual should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a specification of the person or persons to whom an alleged occurrence of sexual harassment should be reported by an individual and options for confidential reporting, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> options and contact information for after-hours contact; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a procedure for obtaining assistance and reporting sexual harassment while working in a remote scientific field camp, at sea, or in another field status; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a specification of any other person whom the victim should contact;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> establishment of a mechanism by which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> questions regarding sexual harassment can be confidentially asked and confidentially answered; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> incidents of sexual harassment can be reported on a restricted or unrestricted basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a prohibition on retaliation and consequences for retaliatory actions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing the policy required by subsection (a), the Secretary may consult or receive assistance from such State, local, and national organizations and subject matter experts as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under subsection (a) is available to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all employees of the Administration and members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, including those employees and members who conduct field work for the Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographic distribution of equal employment opportunity personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall designate out of existing staff at least 1 employee of the Administration who is tasked with handling matters relating to equal employment opportunity or sexual harassment at each marine and aviation center of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarterly reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less frequently than 4 times each year, the Director of the Civil Rights Office of the Administration shall submit to the Under Secretary a report on sexual harassment in the Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The number of sexual harassment cases, both actionable and non-actionable, involving individuals covered by the policy developed under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The number of open actionable sexual harassment cases and how long the cases have been open.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Such trends or region-specific issues as the Director may have discovered with respect to sexual harassment in the Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Such recommendations as the Director may have with respect to sexual harassment in the Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3541</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2800</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title V, § 504(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894a.</num>
<heading> Actions to address sexual assault at National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive policy on prevention of and response to sexual assaults</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2016-12-23">December 23, 2016</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, develop a comprehensive policy on the prevention of and response to sexual assaults involving employees of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, and individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements of comprehensive policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The comprehensive policy developed under subsection (a) shall, at minimum, address the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Prevention measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Education and training on prevention and response.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A list of support resources an individual may use in the occurrence of sexual assault, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> options and contact information for after-hours contact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a procedure for obtaining assistance and reporting sexual assault while working in a remote scientific field camp, at sea, or in another field status.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Easy and ready availability of information described in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Establishing a mechanism by which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> questions regarding sexual assault can be confidentially asked and confidentially answered; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> incidents of sexual assault can be reported on a restricted or unrestricted basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Protocols for the investigation of complaints by command and law enforcement personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Prohibiting retaliation and consequences for retaliatory actions against someone who reports a sexual assault.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Oversight by the Under Secretary of administrative and disciplinary actions in response to substantiated incidents of sexual assault.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Victim advocacy, including establishment of and the responsibilities and training requirements for victim advocates as described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Availability of resources for victims of sexual assault within other Federal agencies and State, local, and national organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victim advocacy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary, shall establish victim advocates to advocate for victims of sexual assaults involving employees of the Administration, members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, and individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victim advocates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, a victim advocate is an existing permanent employee of the Administration who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is trained in matters relating to sexual assault and the comprehensive policy developed under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serves as a victim advocate voluntarily and in addition to the employee’s other duties as an employee of the Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Primary duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The primary duties of a victim advocate established under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Supporting victims of sexual assault and informing them of their rights and the resources available to them as victims.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Acting as a companion in navigating investigative, medical, mental and emotional health, and recovery processes relating to sexual assault.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Helping to identify resources to ensure the safety of victims of sexual assault.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that at least 1 victim advocate established under paragraph (1) is stationed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in each region in which the Administration conducts operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in each marine and aviation center of the Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hotline</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall provide a telephone number at which a victim of a sexual assault can contact a victim advocate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 24-hour access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall ensure that the telephone number established under subparagraph (A) is monitored at all times.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall, where possible, use established hotlines for purposes of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Formal relationships with other entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may enter into formal relationships with other entities to make available additional victim advocates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under subsection (a) is available to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all employees of the Administration and members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, including those employees and members who conduct field work for the Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing the policy required by subsection (a), the Secretary may consult or receive assistance from such State, local, and national organizations and subject matter experts as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3542</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2801</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894b.</num>
<heading> Rights of the victim of a sexual assault</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A victim of a sexual assault covered by the comprehensive policy developed under <ref>section 894a(a) of this title</ref> has the right to be reasonably protected from the accused.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3543</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894c.</num>
<heading> Change of station</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Change of station, unit transfer, or change of work location of victims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timely consideration and action upon request</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of the commissioned officer corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration who was a victim of a sexual assault, in order to reduce the possibility of retaliation or further sexual assault, provide for timely determination and action on an application submitted by the victim for consideration of a change of station or unit transfer of the victim; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee of the Administration who was a victim of a sexual assault, to the degree practicable and in order to reduce the possibility of retaliation against the employee for reporting the sexual assault, accommodate a request for a change of work location of the victim.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period for approval and disapproval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary, shall ensure that an application or request submitted under paragraph (1) for a change of station, unit transfer, or change of work location is approved or denied within 72 hours of the submission of the application or request.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If an application or request submitted under paragraph (1) by a victim of a sexual assault for a change of station, unit transfer, or change of work location of the victim is denied—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the victim may request the Secretary to review the denial; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary, shall, not later than 72 hours after receiving such request, affirm or overturn the denial.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Change of station, unit transfer, and change of work location of alleged perpetrators</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary, shall develop a policy for the protection of victims of sexual assault described in subsection (a)(1) by providing the alleged perpetrator of the sexual assault with a change of station, unit transfer, or change of work location, as the case may be, if the alleged perpetrator is a member of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration or an employee of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The policy required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A means to control access to the victim.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Due process for the victim and the alleged perpetrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">When practicable, the Secretary shall make regulations promulgated under this section consistent with similar regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Defense.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3544</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894d.</num>
<heading> Applicability of policies to crews of vessels secured by National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration under contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere shall ensure that each contract into which the Under Secretary enters for the use of a vessel by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that covers the crew of the vessel, if any, shall include as a condition of the contract a provision that subjects such crew to the policy developed under <ref>section 894(a) of this title</ref> and the comprehensive policy developed under <ref>section 894a(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3545</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894d–1.</num>
<heading> Investigation requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to investigate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, shall ensure that each allegation of sexual harassment reported under <ref>section 894 of this title</ref> and each allegation of sexual assault reported under <ref>section 894a of this title</ref> is investigated thoroughly and promptly.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress on commencement of investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary should ensure that an investigation of alleged sexual harassment reported under <ref>section 894 of this title</ref> or sexual assault reported under <ref>section 894a of this title</ref> commences not later than 48 hours after the time at which the allegation was reported.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of delay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which the time between the reporting of alleged sexual harassment or sexual assault under section 894 or 894a of this title, respectively, and commencement of an investigation of the allegation exceeds 48 hours, the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives of the delay.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3546</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title V, § 504(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894d–2.</num>
<heading> Criminal referral</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary of Commerce finds, pursuant to an investigation under <ref>section 894d–1 of this title</ref>, evidence that a crime may have been committed, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the appropriate law enforcement authorities, including the appropriate United States Attorney.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3547</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title V, § 504(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894e.</num>
<heading> Annual report on sexual assaults in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than January 15 of each year, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the sexual assaults involving employees of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, and individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to the previous calendar year, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of alleged sexual assaults involving employees, members, and individuals described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A synopsis of each case and the disciplinary action taken, if any, in each case.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The policies, procedures, and processes implemented by the Secretary, and any updates or revisions to such policies, procedures, and processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A summary of the reports received by the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere under <ref>section 894(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privacy protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In preparing and submitting a report under subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that no individual involved in an alleged sexual assault can be identified by the contents of the report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3548</ref>, formerly § 3546, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2804</ref>; renumbered § 3548, <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title V, § 504(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 894f.</num>
<heading> Sexual assault defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “sexual assault” shall have the meaning given such term in <ref>section 12291(a) of title 34</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3549</ref>, formerly § 3547, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2805</ref>; renumbered § 3549, <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title V, § 504(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>