<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 10—</num>
<heading>ANCHORAGE GROUNDS AND HARBOR REGULATIONS GENERALLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 471.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 472.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 473.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 637</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 474.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVIII, § 11808(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4165</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 475.</num>
<heading> Regulations for Pearl Harbor, Hawaii</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the proper control, protection, and defense of the naval station, harbor, and entrance channel at Pearl Harbor, Territory of Hawaii, the Secretary of the Navy is authorized, empowered, and directed to adopt and prescribe suitable rules and regulations governing the navigation, movement, and anchorage of vessels of whatsoever character in the waters of Pearl Harbor, island of Oahu, Hawaiian Islands, and in the entrance channel to said harbor, and to take all necessary measures for the proper enforcement of such rules and regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 22, 1912, ch. 335</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 476.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on tanker traffic in Puget Sound and adjacent waters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the navigable waters of Puget Sound in the State of Washington, and the natural resources therein, are a fragile and important national asset;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Puget Sound and the shore area immediately adjacent thereto is threatened by increased domestic and international traffic of tankers carrying crude oil in bulk which increases the possibility of vessel collisions and oil spills; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> it is necessary to restrict such tanker traffic in Puget Sound in order to protect the navigable waters thereof, the natural resources therein, and the shore area immediately adjacent thereto, from environmental harm.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on and after <date date="1977-10-18">October 18, 1977</date>, no officer, employee, or other official of the Federal Government shall, or shall have authority to, issue, renew, grant, or otherwise approve any permit, license, or other authority for constructing, renovating, modifying, or otherwise altering a terminal, dock, or other facility in, on, or immediately adjacent to, or affecting the navigable waters of Puget Sound, or any other navigable waters in the State of Washington east of Port Angeles, which will or may result in any increase in the volume of crude oil capable of being handled at any such facility (measured as of <date date="1977-10-18">October 18, 1977</date>), other than oil to be refined for consumption in the State of Washington.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–136, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-10-18">Oct. 18, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1168</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>