<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 28—</num>
<heading>POLLUTION CASUALTIES ON THE HIGH SEAS: UNITED STATES INTERVENTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1471.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “a substance other than convention oil” means those oils, noxious substances, liquefied gases, and radioactive substances—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enumerated in the protocol, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise determined to be hazardous under <ref>section 1473(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “convention” means the International Convention Relating to Intervention on the High Seas in Cases of Oil Pollution Casualties, 1969, including annexes thereto;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “convention oil” means crude oil, fuel oil, diesel oil, and lubricating oil;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> “ship” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a seagoing vessel of any type whatsoever, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any floating craft, except an installation or device engaged in the exploration and exploitation of the resources of the seabed and the ocean floor and the subsoil thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “protocol” means the Protocol Relating to Intervention on the High Seas in Cases of Marine Pollution by Substances Other Than Oil, 1973, including annexes thereto; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “United States” means the States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Canal Zone, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–302, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-26">June 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1472.</num>
<heading> Grave and imminent danger from oil pollution casualties to coastline or related interests of United States; Federal nonliability for Federal preventive measures on the high seas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever a ship collision, stranding, or other incident of navigation or other occurrence on board a ship or external to it resulting in material damage or imminent threat of material damage to the ship or her cargo creates, as determined by the Secretary, a grave and imminent danger to the coastline or related interests of the United States from pollution or threat of pollution of the sea by convention oil or of the sea or atmosphere by a substance other than convention oil which may reasonably be expected to result in major harmful consequences, the Secretary may, except as provided for in <ref>section 1479 of this title</ref>, without liability for any damage to the owners or operators of the ship, to her cargo or crew, to underwriters or other parties interested therein, take measures on the high seas, in accordance with the provisions of the convention, the protocol and this chapter, to prevent, mitigate, or eliminate that danger.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–302, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-26">June 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1473.</num>
<heading> Consultations and determinations respecting creation of hazards to human health, etc.; criteria for determinations respecting grave and imminent dangers of major harmful consequences to United States coastline or related interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Commerce, shall determine when a substance other than those enumerated in the protocol is liable to create a hazard to human health, to harm living resources, to damage amenities, or to interfere with other legitimate uses of the sea.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In determining whether there is grave and imminent danger of major harmful consequences to the coastline or related interests of the United States, the Secretary shall consider the interests of the United States directly threatened or affected including but not limited to, human health, fish, shellfish, and other living marine resources, wildlife, coastal zone and estuarine activities, and public and private shorelines and beaches.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–302, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-26">June 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1474.</num>
<heading> Federal intervention actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon a determination under <ref>section 1472 of this title</ref> of a grave and imminent danger to the coastline or related interests of the United States, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate and direct all public and private efforts directed at the removal or elimination of the threatened pollution damage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> directly or indirectly undertake the whole or any part of any salvage or other action he could require or direct under subsection (1) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> remove, and, if necessary, destroy the ship and cargo which is the source of the danger.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 5</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1475.</num>
<heading> Consultation procedure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Before taking any measure under <ref>section 1474 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult, through the Secretary of State, with other countries affected by the marine casualty, and particularly with the flag country of any ship involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notify without delay the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and any other persons known to the Secretary, or of whom he later becomes aware, who have interests which can reasonably be expected to be affected by any proposed measures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> consider any views submitted in response to the consultation or notification required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 6</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1476.</num>
<heading> Emergencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In cases of extreme urgency requiring measures to be taken immediately, the Secretary may take those measures rendered necessary by the urgency of the situation without the prior consultation or notification as required by <ref>section 1475 of this title</ref> or without the continuation of consultations already begun.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 7</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1477.</num>
<heading> Reasonable measures; considerations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Measures directed or conducted under this chapter shall be proportionate to the damage, actual or threatened, to the coastline or related interests of the United States and may not go beyond what is reasonably necessary to prevent, mitigate, or eliminate that damage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In considering whether measures are proportionate to the damage the Secretary shall, among other things, consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the extent and probability of imminent damage if those measures are not taken;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the likelihood of effectiveness of those measures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the extent of the damage which may be caused by those measures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 8</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1478.</num>
<heading> Personal, flag state, and foreign state considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the direction and conduct of measures under this chapter the Secretary shall use his best endeavors to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assure the avoidance of risk to human life;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> render all possible aid to distressed persons, including facilitating repatriation of ships’ crews; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not unnecessarily interfere with rights and interests of others, including the flag state of any ship involved, other foreign states threatened by damage, and persons otherwise concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 9</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1479.</num>
<heading> Federal liability for unreasonable damages</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States shall be obliged to pay compensation to the extent of the damage caused by measures which exceed those reasonably necessary to achieve the end mentioned in <ref>section 1472 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Actions against the United States seeking compensation for any excessive measures may be brought in the United States Court of Federal Claims, in any district court of the United States, and in those courts enumerated in <ref>section 460 of title 28</ref>. For purposes of this chapter, American Samoa shall be included within the judicial district of the District Court of the United States for the District of Hawaii, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands shall be included within the judicial districts of both the District Court of the United States for the District of Hawaii and the District Court of Guam.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Burden of proof</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to intervention for a substance identified pursuant to <ref>section 1473(a) of this title</ref>, the United States has the burden of establishing that, under the circumstances present at the time of the intervention, the substance could reasonably pose a grave and imminent danger analogous to that posed by a substance enumerated in the protocol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 10</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–302, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-26">June 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 345</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 161(6)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1480.</num>
<heading> Notification by Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall notify without delay foreign states concerned, the Secretary-General of the Inter-Governmental Maritime Consultative Organization, and persons affected by measures taken under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 11</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1481.</num>
<heading> Violations; penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A person commits a class A misdemeanor if that person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> willfully violates a provision of this chapter or a regulation issued thereunder; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> willfully refuses or fails to comply with any lawful order or direction given pursuant to this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> willfully obstructs any person who is acting in compliance with an order or direction under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In a criminal proceeding for an offense under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) of this section it shall be a defense for the accused to prove that he used all due diligence to comply with any order or direction that he had reasonable cause to believe that compliance would have resulted in serious risk to human life.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 12</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4302</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 539</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1482.</num>
<heading> Consultation for nomination and nomination of experts, negotiators, etc.; proposal of amendments to list of substances other than convention oil; Presidential acceptance of amendments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nomination of experts and proposal of amendments to list of substances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, may nominate individuals to the list of experts provided for in article III of the convention and article II of the protocol and may propose amendments to the list of substances other than convention oil in accordance with article III of the protocol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations for designation or nomination of negotiators, etc., provided for by convention and protocol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary, shall designate or nominate, as appropriate and necessary, the negotiators, conciliators, or arbitrators provided for by the convention and the protocol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential acceptance of amendments to list of substances other than convention oil in accordance with protocol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may accept amendments to the list of substances other than convention oil in accordance with article III of the protocol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 13</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–302, § 1(5)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-26">June 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1483.</num>
<heading> Foreign government ships; immunity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No measures may be taken under authority of this chapter against any warship or other ship owned or operated by a country and used, for the time being, only on Government noncommercial service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 14</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1484.</num>
<heading> Interpretation and administration; other right, duty, privilege, or immunity and other remedy unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall be interpreted and administered in a manner consistent with the convention, the protocol, and other international law. Except as specifically provided, nothing in this chapter may be interpreted to prejudice any otherwise applicable right, duty, privilege, or immunity or deprive any country or person of any remedy otherwise applicable.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 15</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–302, § 1(6)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-26">June 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1485.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may issue reasonable rules and regulations which he considers appropriate and necessary for the effective implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 16</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1486.</num>
<heading> Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund shall be available to the Secretary for actions taken under sections 1474 and 1476 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 17</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–380, title II, § 2001</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 506</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1487.</num>
<heading> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall be effective upon <date date="1974-02-05">February 5, 1974</date>, or upon the date the convention becomes effective as to the United States, whichever is later.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–248, § 18</ref>, <date date="1974-02-05">Feb. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 10</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>