<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32—</num>
<heading>INLAND WATERWAYS TRUST FUND</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1801, 1802.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XIV, § 1405(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4271</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1803.</num>
<heading> Study with respect to inland waterway user taxes and charges</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study directed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation, and the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Attorney General of the United States, the Secretary of the Army, the Chairman of the Water Resources Council, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make a full and complete study with respect to inland waterway user taxes and charges, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make findings and policy recommendations with respect thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such study shall include (but shall not be limited to) a consideration of the matters listed in subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f) of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations relating to the taxing mechanism</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The extent to which the Federal Government should seek to recover some or all of Federal expenditures for the benefit of inland waterway transportation from the users of the facilities for which such expenditures are made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The various forms of inland waterway user taxes and charges which could be established.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The various methods of collecting inland waterway user taxes and charges, and the administrative costs of such taxes and charges.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The classes and categories of users and other persons on whom inland waterway user taxes and charges should be imposed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The waterways of the United States (including the Great Lakes, deep draft channels, and coastal ports) which should be included in any system of user taxes and charges, together with the economic effects of such taxes and charges.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The use of revenues derived from inland waterway user taxes and charges, including consideration of changes in, or alternatives to, the Trust Fund mechanism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations relating to economic effects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The economic effects of waterway user taxes and charges on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Carriers and users</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carriers and shippers using the inland waterways, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> users (including ultimate consumers) of commodities which are transported on the inland waterways.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regions, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> existing investment in industrial plants, agricultural interests, and commercial enterprises, and on related employment, in regions of the country served by inland water transportation directly or in combination with other modes, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> future economic growth prospects in such regions, including anticipated shifts of industry and employment to other areas together with an evaluation of effects on regional economies and their development, including consistency with Federal policies as set forth in other legislation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Small business and industrial concentration and competition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> small business enterprise, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> industrial concentration and competition, both within the transportation industry and in any line of commerce (within the meaning of the antitrust laws).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On the freight rates charged by other modes of transportation and the extent of short-term and long-term diversion of traffic from the inland waterways to such other modes. In considering such diversion of traffic, there shall also be considered the effects of such diversion on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the development of alternative sources of supply and on alternative modes of transportation and alternative routing to market,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the comparative safety of the handling and transportation of hazardous materials, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the comparative energy efficiency of the modes and routes of the transportation involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On prices of commodities shipped by inland waterways and by competing modes, including the costs of energy materials and the effects on electric power rates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Balance of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On the balance of payments of the United States based on our international trade.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations relating to economic feasibility of waterway improvement projects; level of benefits from waterway expenditures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The effects of inland waterway user taxes and charges on the economic feasibility of inland waterway improvement projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The comparative levels of benefits received from Federal expenditures on inland waterways for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> commercial uses, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other uses, including (but not limited to) recreation, reclamation, water supply, low-flow augmentation, fish and wildlife enhancement, hydroelectric power, flood control, and irrigation uses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations relating to Federal assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The extent of past, present, and expected future Federal assistance to the several modes of freight transportation. Such consideration shall include an evaluation and comparison of the public benefits resulting from such assistance to each of the several transportation modes in terms of adequacy, efficiency, and economy of service, safety, technological progress, and energy conservation. The Federal assistance considered under this paragraph shall include all forms of such assistance, such as tax advantages, direct grants, rate adjustments for improvement purposes, assumption of pension fund liabilities, loans, guarantees, capital participation, revenues from land grants, and provision of right-of-way operation, maintenance, and improvement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The competitive effects of past, present, and expected future Federal expenditures on inland waterways on competitive modes of transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The need for Federal assistance to agricultural, industrial, and other interests affected by inland waterway user taxes and charges.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations relating to policy and future development</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The effects of inland waterway user taxes and charges on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The achievement of the objectives of the National Transportation Policy as set forth in sections 10101 and 13101 of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The expansion and improvement of the inland waterways determined to be necessary by the Secretary of the Army under section 158 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1976 (<ref>Public Law 94–587</ref>) or estimated to be necessary under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The requirements of the Nation through the year 2000 for transportation service, the portion thereof which should be provided by inland waterway carriers, and an estimate of the expansion and improvement of inland waterway capacity necessary to meet such requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Inland waterway user taxes and charges” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “inland waterway user taxes and charges” means taxes imposed on the use of the inland and intra­coastal waterways of the United States and all alternatives to such taxes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, the Secretary of Transportation shall transmit to Congress a final report of the study required by this section, together with his findings and recommendations (including necessary legislation) and the findings and recommendations of the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Attorney General of the United States, the Secretary of the Army, the Chairman of the Water Resources Council, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated from time to time to the Secretary of Transportation such sums, not to exceed $8,000,000 in the aggregate, as may be necessary to carry out the study required by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–502, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 338</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1804.</num>
<heading> Inland and intracoastal waterways of the United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of <ref>section 4042 of title 26</ref> (relating to tax on fuel used in commercial transportation on inland waterways) and for purposes of section 1802 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002085">1</ref> of this title, the following inland and intracoastal waterways of the United States are described in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Alabama-Coosa Rivers: From junction with the Tombigbee River at river mile (hereinafter referred to as RM) 0 to junction with Coosa River at RM 314.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Allegheny River: From confluence with the Monongahela River to form the Ohio River at RM 0 to the head of the existing project at East Brady, Pennsylvania, RM 72.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Apalachicola-Chattahoochee and Flint Rivers: Apalachicola River from mouth at Apalachicola Bay (intersection with the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway) RM 0 to junction with Chattachoochee <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">2</ref> and Flint Rivers at RM 107.8. Chattachoochee <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">2</ref> River from junction with Apalachicola and Flint Rivers at RM 0 to Columbus, Georgia, at RM 155 and Flint River, from junction with Apalachicola and Chattahoochee Rivers at RM 0 to Bainbridge, Georgia, at RM 28.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Arkansas River (McClellan-Kerr Arkansas River Navigation System): From junction with Mississippi River at RM 0 to port of Catoosa, Oklahoma, at RM 448.2.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Atchafalaya River: From RM 0 at its intersection with the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway at Morgan City, Louisiana, upstream to junction with Red River at RM 116.8.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway: Two inland water routes approximately paralleling the Atlantic coast between Norfolk, Virginia, and Miami, Florida, for 1,192 miles via both the Albermarle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002087">3</ref> and Chesapeake Canal and Great Dismal Swamp Canal routes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Black Warrior-Tombigbee-Mobile Rivers: Black Warrior River System from RM 2.9, Mobile River (at Chickasaw Creek) to confluence with Tombigbee River at RM 45. Tombigbee River (to Demopolis at RM 215.4) to port of Birmingham, RM’s 374–411 and upstream to head of navigation on Mulberry Fork (RM 429.6), Locust Fork (RM 407.8), and Sipsey Fork (RM 430.4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Columbia River (Columbia-Snake Rivers Inland Waterways): From The Dalles at RM 191.5 to Pasco, Washington (McNary Pool), at RM 330, Snake River from RM 0 at the mouth to RM 231.5 at Johnson Bar Landing, Idaho.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Cumberland River: Junction with Ohio River at RM 0 to head of navigation, upstream to Carthage, Tennessee, at RM 313.5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Green and Barren Rivers: Green River from junction with the Ohio River at RM 0 to head of navigation at RM 149.1.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Gulf Intracoastal Waterway: From St. Mark’s River, Florida, to Brownsville, Texas, 1,134.5 miles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Illinois Waterway (Calumet-Sag Channel): From the junction of the Illinois River with the Mississippi River RM 0 to Chicago Harbor at Lake Michigan, approximately RM 350.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Kanawha River: From junction with Ohio River at RM 0 to RM 90.6 at Deepwater, West Virginia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Kaskaskia River: From junction with the Mississippi River at RM 0 to RM 36.2 at Fayetteville, Illinois.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Kentucky River: From junction with Ohio River at RM 0 to confluence of Middle and North Forks at RM 258.6.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Lower Mississippi River: From Baton Rouge, Louisiana, RM 233.9 to Cairo, Illinois, RM 953.8.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> Upper Mississippi River: From Cairo, Illinois, RM 953.8 to Minneapolis, Minnesota, RM 1,811.4.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Missouri River: From junction with Mississippi River at RM 0 to Sioux City, Iowa, at RM 734.8.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Monongahela River: From junction with Allegheny River to form the Ohio River at RM 0 to junction of the Tygart and West Fork Rivers, Fairmont, West Virginia, at RM 128.7.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> Ohio River: From junction with the Mississippi River at RM 0 to junction of the Allegheny and Monongahela Rivers at Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, at RM 981.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> Ouachita-Black Rivers: From the mouth of the Black River at its junction with the Red River at RM 0 to RM 351 at Camden, Arkansas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> Pearl River: From junction of West Pearl River with the Rigolets at RM 0 to Bogalusa, Louisiana, RM 58.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> Red River: From RM 0 to the mouth of Cypress Bayou at RM 236.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> Tennessee River: From junction with Ohio River at RM 0 to confluence with Holstein and French Rivers at RM 652.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> White River: From RM 9.8 to RM 255 at Newport, Arkansas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<content> Willamette River: From RM 21 upstream of Portland, Oregon, to Harrisburg, Oregon, at RM 194.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<content> Tennessee-Tombigbee Waterway: From its confluence with the Tennessee River to the Warrior River at Demopolis, Alabama.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–502, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XIV, § 1404(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>