<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 47—</num>
<heading>OCEAN EXPLORATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>EXPLORATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3401.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to establish the national ocean exploration program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12001</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3402.</num>
<heading> Program established</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall, in consultation with the National Science Foundation and other appropriate Federal agencies, establish a coordinated national ocean exploration program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that promotes collaboration with other Federal ocean research and exploration programs. To the extent appropriate, the Administrator shall seek to facilitate coordination of data and information management systems, outreach and education programs to improve public understanding of ocean and coastal resources, and development and transfer of technologies to facilitate ocean research and ocean exploration and characterization efforts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12002</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3403.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties of the Administrator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the program authorized by <ref>section 3402 of this title</ref>, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in consultation with the Ocean Policy Committee established under <ref>section 8932 of title 10</ref>, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct interdisciplinary expeditions or other scientific activities in conjunction with other Federal and State agencies, Tribal Governments, private industry, academia (including secondary schools, community colleges, and universities), and nongovernmental organizations, to map, explore, and characterize little known areas of the marine environment, inventory, observe, characterize, and assess living and nonliving marine resources, and report such findings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> give priority attention to deep ocean regions of the exclusive economic zone, with a focus on deep water marine systems that hold potential for important scientific discoveries, such as hydrothermal vent communities and seamounts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct scientific expeditions to locate, define, and document historic shipwrecks, submerged sites, and other ocean exploration activities that combine archaeology and oceanographic sciences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop and implement a transparent, competitive process for merit-based peer-review and approval of proposals for activities to be conducted under this program, taking into consideration advice of the Board established under <ref>section 3405 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> support technological innovation of the United States marine science community by promoting the development and use of new and emerging technologies for research, communication, navigation, and data collection, such as sensors and autonomous vehicles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> establish an ocean exploration forum, in consultation with the National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council established under section 5405 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002133">1</ref> of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, to encourage partnerships and promote communication among experts and other stakeholders in order to enhance the scientific and technical expertise and relevance of the national program.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002134">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide guidance, in consultation with the National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council, to Federal and State agencies, Tribal Governments, private industry, academia (including secondary schools, community colleges, and universities), and nongovernmental organizations on data standards, protocols for accepting data, and coordination of data collection, compilation, processing, archiving, and dissemination for data relating to ocean exploration and characterization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> coordinate with applicable ocean mapping, ocean monitoring, and ocean observation programs to maximize coordination and collaboration opportunities, prevent duplication of such activities and identify gaps in data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Donations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of mapping, exploring, and characterizing the oceans or increasing the knowledge of the oceans, the Administrator may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> accept monetary donations, which shall be credited as discretionary offsetting collections to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and shall be made available for such purposes only to the extent and in the amounts provided in advance in appropriations Acts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accept donations of property, data, and equipment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> pay all necessary expenses in connection with the conveyance or transfer of a gift, devise, or bequest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of exclusive economic zone</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “exclusive economic zone” means the zone established by Presidential Proclamation Number 5030, dated <date date="1983-03-10">March 10, 1983</date> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1453</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12003</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3404.</num>
<heading> Education, workforce training, and outreach</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct education and outreach efforts in order to broadly disseminate information to the public on the discoveries made by the program under <ref>section 3402 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent possible, coordinate the efforts described in paragraph (1) with the outreach strategies of other domestic or international ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization initiatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish a fellowship program at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to provide year-long fellowships to undergraduate students from institutions described in <ref>section 1067q(a) of title 20</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Education and outreach efforts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Efforts described in subsection (a)(1) may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> education of the general public, teachers, students, and ocean and coastal resource managers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> workforce training, reskilling, and opportunities to encourage development of ocean-related science, technology, engineering, and mathematics technical training programs involving secondary schools, community colleges, and universities, including institutions described in <ref>section 1067q(a) of title 20</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the National Ocean Exploration Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002135">1</ref> the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall develop an outreach strategy to broadly disseminate information on the discoveries made by the program under <ref>section 3402 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12004</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3973</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3405.</num>
<heading> Ocean Exploration Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall appoint an Ocean Exploration Advisory Board composed of experts in relevant fields, including representatives from academic, commercial, nonprofit, philanthropic, policy, and Tribal entities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to advise the Administrator on priority areas for survey, discovery, and opportunities for extramural collaboration and partnerships;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist the program in the development of a 5-year strategic plan for the fields of ocean, marine, and Great Lakes science, exploration, and discovery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to annually review the quality and effectiveness of the proposal review process established under <ref>section 3403(a)(4) of this title</ref>; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002136">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to identify market barriers to development or commercialization of novel ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization products, processes, and tools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to identify best practices to improve data management, processing, storage, and archiving standards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to provide other assistance and advice as requested by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chapter 10 of title 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1013 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to the Board appointed under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application with Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter supersedes, or limits the authority of the Secretary of the Interior under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12005</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1418</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(f)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3973</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(208)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3406.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out this subchapter $60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002137">1</ref></p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12006</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(g)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3407.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Characterization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “characterization”, “characterize”, and “characterizing” mean activities that provide comprehensive data and interpretations for a specific area of interest of the sea floor, sub-bottom, water column, or hydrologic features, such as water masses and currents, in direct support of specific research, environmental protection, resource management, policymaking, or applied mission objectives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exploration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002138">1</ref> “exploration”, “explore”, and “exploring” means <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002138">1</ref> activities that provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a multidisciplinary view of an unknown or poorly understood area of the sea floor, sub-bottom, or water column; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an initial assessment of the physical, chemical, geological, biological, archaeological, or other characteristics of such an area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mapping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “map” and “mapping” mean activities that provide comprehensive data and information needed to understand sea floor characteristics, including depth, topography, bottom type, sediment composition and distribution, underlying geologic structure, and benthic flora and fauna.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12007</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(h)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3408.</num>
<heading> National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish a council, to be known as the “National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council” (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> update national priorities for ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate and facilitate activities to advance those priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall report to the Ocean Science and Technology Subcommittee of the Ocean Policy Committee established under <ref>section 8932(c) of title 10</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall be composed of senior-level representatives from the appropriate Federal agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Co-Chairs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall be co-chaired by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> two senior-level representatives from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> one senior-level representative from the Department of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> set national ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization priorities and strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cultivate and facilitate transparent and sustained partnerships among Federal and State agencies, Indian Tribes, private industry, academia, and nongovernmental organizations to conduct ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization activities and related technology development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate improved processes for data compilation, management, access, synthesis, and visualization with respect to ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization, with a focus on building on existing ocean data management systems and with appropriate safeguards on the public accessibility of data to protect national security equities, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> encourage education, workforce training, and public engagement activities that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advance interdisciplinary principles that contribute to ocean mapping, exploration, research, and characterization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improve public engagement with and understanding of ocean science; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide opportunities for underserved populations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> coordinate activities as appropriate with domestic and international ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization initiatives or programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> establish and monitor metrics to track progress in achieving the priorities set under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency Working Group on Ocean Exploration and Characterization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall establish a new interagency working group to be known as the “Interagency Working Group on Ocean Exploration and Characterization”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Interagency Working Group on Ocean Exploration and Characterization shall be comprised of senior representatives from Federal agencies with ocean exploration and characterization responsibilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Interagency Working Group on Ocean Exploration and Characterization shall support the Council and the Ocean Science and Technology Subcommittee of the Ocean Policy Committee established under <ref>section 8932(c) of title 10</ref> on ocean exploration and characterization activities and associated technology development across the Federal Government, State governments, Indian Tribes, private industry, nongovernmental organizations, and academia.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall oversee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Interagency Working Group on Ocean Exploration and Characterization established under subsection (g)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Interagency Working Group on Ocean and Coastal Mapping under <ref>section 3502 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Council shall develop or update and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a plan for an integrated cross-sectoral ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization initiative.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The plan required by paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> discuss the utility and benefits of ocean exploration and characterization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify and describe national ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization priorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identify and describe Federal and federally funded ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> facilitate and incorporate non-Federal input into national ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization priorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> ensure effective coordination of ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization activities among programs described in subparagraph (C);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> identify opportunities for combining overlapping or complementary needs, activities, and resources of Federal agencies and non-Federal organizations relating to ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization while not reducing benefits from existing mapping, explorations, and characterization activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> promote new and existing partnerships among Federal and State agencies, Indian Tribes, private industry, academia, and nongovernmental organizations to conduct or support ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization activities and technology development needs, including through coordination under <ref>section 4102 of this title</ref> and the National Oceanographic Partnership Program under <ref>section 8931 of title 10</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> develop a transparent and sustained mechanism for non-Federal partnerships and stakeholder engagement in strategic planning and mission execution to be implemented not later than <date date="2023-12-31">December 31, 2023</date>, for coordinating such activities with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> institutions of higher education (as such term is defined in <ref>section 1001(a) of title 20</ref>, the private sector, philanthropic organizations, and nonprofits; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> international partners for activities relating to maritime areas (including the sea floor) beyond the jurisdiction of the Federal Government;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> establish standardized collection and data management protocols, including with respect to metadata, for ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are publicly accessible and locatable via appropriate Federal repositories;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> can facilitate the integration of ocean data into products and use innovations from non-Federal partners; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> have appropriate safeguards on the public accessibility of data to protect national security;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> encourage the development, testing, demonstration, and adoption of innovative ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization technologies and applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> promote protocols for accepting data, equipment, approaches, or other resources that support national ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization priorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> identify best practices for the protection of marine life during mapping, exploration, and characterization activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> identify training, technology, and other resource requirements for enabling the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and other appropriate Federal agencies to support a coordinated national ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization effort;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> identify and facilitate a centralized mechanism or office for coordinating data collection, compilation, processing, archiving, and dissemination activities relating to ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization that meets Federal mandates for data accuracy and accessibility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> designate repositories responsible for archiving and managing ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> set forth a timetable and estimated costs for implementation and completion of the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, align ocean exploration and characterization efforts with existing programs and identify key gaps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(R)</num>
<content> identify criteria for determining the optimal frequency of observations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(S)</num>
<content> provide recommendations, developed in coordination with the private sector, to improve incentives, access, and processes for the private sector to share ocean-related data with the public and Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Council shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> progress made toward meeting the national priorities described in subsection (i)(2)(B); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recommendations for meeting such priorities, such as additional authorities that may be needed to develop a mechanism for non-Federal partnerships and stakeholder engagement described in subsection (i)(2)(H).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10304</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3968</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>NOAA UNDERSEA RESEARCH PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 3421 to 3426.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10306(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3974</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>