<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 38—</num>
<heading>DUMPING OF MEDICAL WASTE BY PUBLIC VESSELS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2501.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The washing ashore of potentially infectious medical wastes from public vessels of the United States may pose serious and widespread risks to public health and to the welfare of coastal communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Current Federal law provides inadequate protections against the disposal of such wastes from such vessels into ocean waters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Operators of such vessels must take immediate action to stop disposing of such wastes into ocean waters.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title III, § 3102</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2502.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Potentially infectious medical waste</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “potentially infectious medical waste” includes isolation wastes; infectious agents; human blood and blood products; pathological wastes; sharps; body parts; contaminated bedding; surgical wastes; and other disposable medical equipment and material that may pose a risk to the public health, welfare or the marine environment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public vessel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “public vessel” means a vessel of any type whatsoever (including hydrofoils, air-cushion vehicles, submersibles, floating craft whether propelled or not, and fixed or floating platforms) that is owned, or demise chartered, and operated by the United States Government, and is not engaged in commercial service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title III, § 3103</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2503.</num>
<heading> Prohibition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After 6 months after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, no public vessel shall dispose of potentially infectious medical waste into ocean waters unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the health or safety of individuals on board the vessel is threatened; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during time of war or a declared national emergency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the waste is disposed of beyond 50 nautical miles from the nearest land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a public vessel which is not a submersible, the waste is sterilized, properly packaged, and sufficiently weighted to prevent the waste from coming ashore after disposal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a public vessel which is a submersible, the waste is properly packaged and sufficiently weighted to prevent the waste from coming ashore after disposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title III, § 3104</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2504.</num>
<heading> Guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 3 months after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, the Secretary of Defense and the head of each affected agency, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall each issue guidance for public vessels under the jurisdiction of their agency regarding implementation of <ref>section 2503 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title III, § 3105</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>