<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 39—</num>
<heading>SHORE PROTECTION FROM MUNICIPAL OR COMMERCIAL WASTE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>SHORE PROTECTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2601.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “coastal waters” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the territorial sea of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Great Lakes and their connecting waters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the marine and estuarine waters of the United States up to the head of tidal influence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Exclusive Economic Zone as established by Presidential Proclamation Number 5030, dated <date date="1983-03-10">March 10, 1983</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “municipal or commercial waste” means solid waste (as defined in <ref>section 6903 of title 42</ref>) except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> solid waste identified and listed under <ref>section 6921 of title 42</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> waste generated by the vessel during normal operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> debris solely from construction activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> sewage sludge subject to regulation under title I of the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 [<ref>33 U.S.C. 1411</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> dredged or fill material subject to regulation under title I of the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 [<ref>33 U.S.C. 1411</ref> et seq.], the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.), or the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1899 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “person” means an individual, trust, firm, joint stock company, corporation (including a government corporation), partnership, association, State, municipality, commission, political subdivision of a State, or any interstate body.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “receiving facility” means a facility or operation where municipal or commercial waste is unloaded from a vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “United States”, when used in a geographic sense, means the States of the United States, Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “waste source” means a facility or vessel from which municipal or commercial waste is loaded onto a vessel, including any rolling stock or motor vehicles from which that waste is directly loaded.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4101</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2602.</num>
<heading> Vessel permits and numbers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A vessel (except a public vessel as defined in <ref>section 2101 of title 46</ref>) may not transport municipal or commercial waste in coastal waters without—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a permit for that vessel from the Secretary of Transportation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> displaying a number or other marking on the vessel as prescribed by the Secretary under chapter 123 or <ref>section 12502(b) of title 46</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permit applications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Application for a permit required by subsection (a) of this section shall be made by the vessel owner or operator and include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name, address, and telephone number of the vessel owner and operator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the vessel’s name and identification number;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the vessel’s area of operation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the vessel’s transport capacity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> a history of the types of cargo transported by that vessel during the previous year, including identifying the type of municipal or commercial waste transported as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> municipal waste;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> commercial waste;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> medical waste; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> waste of another character.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any other information the Secretary may require; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> an acknowledgment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of permits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A permit issued under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is effective 30 days after the date on which it was issued;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be issued only for a period of not more than 5 years after the effective date of the permit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may be renewed for periods of not more than 5 years only by the vessel owner or operator that applied for the original permit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is terminated when the vessel is sold.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of permits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may, or at the request of the Administrator shall, deny the issuance of a permit for any vessel if the owner or operator of the vessel has a record of a pattern of serious violations of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq., 1447 et seq.; <ref>33 U.S.C. 1401</ref> et seq., 2801 et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1899 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permit decision</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator, shall issue or deny a vessel permit under this section within 30 days after receiving a complete application. On denying the issuance of the permit for a vessel the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notify the applicant of the denial and the reasons for the denial; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide an opportunity for a hearing on the denial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintaining permit</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The permit issued for a vessel under this chapter shall be maintained in a manner prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Endorsements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a vessel is a documented vessel, the Secretary may endorse a permit on the vessel’s certificate of documentation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vessel information system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may include information in a permit in the vessel information system maintained under chapter 125 of title 46.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4102</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2603.</num>
<heading> Waste handling practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loading</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owner or operator of the waste source shall take all reasonable steps to assure that all municipal or commercial waste is loaded onto a vessel in a manner that assures that waste deposited in coastal waters is minimized.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Securing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owner or operator of a vessel shall assure that all municipal or commercial waste loaded onto the vessel is secured by netting or other means to assure that waste will not be deposited into coastal waters during transport.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offloading</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owner or operator of the receiving facility shall take all reasonable steps to assure that any municipal or commercial waste is offloaded from a vessel in a manner that assures that waste deposited into coastal waters is minimized.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cleaning up</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owner or operator of any waste source or receiving facility shall provide adequate control measures to clean up any municipal or commercial waste which is deposited into coastal waters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall prescribe regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> requiring that waste sources, receiving facilities, and vessels provide the means and facilities to assure that the waste will not be deposited into coastal waters during loading, offloading, and transport;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requiring, as appropriate, the submission and adoption by each responsible party of an operation and maintenance manual identifying procedures to be used to prevent, report, and clean up any deposit of municipal or commercial waste into coastal waters, including record keeping requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if the Administrator determines that tracking systems are required to assure adequate enforcement of laws preventing the deposit of municipal or commercial waste into coastal waters, requiring installation of the appropriate systems within 18 months after the Administrator makes that determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4103</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4156</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2604.</num>
<heading> Suspension, revocation, and injunctions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension and revocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After notice and opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary of Transportation may, and at the request of the Administrator shall, suspend or revoke a permit issued to a vessel under this chapter for a violation of this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Injunctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary or the Administrator may bring a civil action to enjoin any operation in violation of this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter in the district court of the United States for the district in which the violation occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4104</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2605.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall enforce this chapter under section 89 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002111">1</ref> of title 14. The Secretary may authorize other officers or employees of the United States Government to enforce this chapter under that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic examinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct periodic examinations of vessels operating under this chapter transporting municipal or commercial waste to determine that each of these vessels has a permit issued under <ref>section 2602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refusal of clearance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury may refuse the clearance required by <ref>section 60105 of title 46</ref>, to any vessel subject to this chapter which does not have a permit required under <ref>section 2602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of entry and detention</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If a vessel does not comply with this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> deny entry to any place in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> detain at the place in the United States from which it is about to depart.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persistent violators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall conduct an investigation of the owner or operator of a vessel or facility if the owner has 5 or more separate violations during a 6-month period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4105</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2606.</num>
<heading> Subpena authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In an investigation under this chapter, the attendance and testimony of witnesses, including parties in interest, and the production of any evidence may be compelled by subpena. The subpena authority granted by this section is coextensive with that of a district court of the United States, in civil matters, for the district in which the investigation is conducted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpena authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An official designated by the Secretary of Transportation or Administrator to conduct an investigation under this chapter may issue subpenas as provided in this section and administer oaths to witnesses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to comply</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a person fails to obey a subpena issued under this section, the district court of the United States for the district in which the investigation is conducted or in which the person failing to obey is found, shall on proper application issue an order directing that person to comply with the subpena. The court may punish as contempt any disobedience of its order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witness fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A witness complying with a subpena issued under this section may be paid for actual travel and attendance at the rate provided for witnesses in the district courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4106</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2607.</num>
<heading> Fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation may collect a fee under <ref>section 9701 of title 31</ref> of not more than $1,000, from each person to whom a permit is issued under this subchapter for a permitting system and to maintain information.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4107</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2608.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, a person found by the Secretary of Transportation to have violated this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter for which a civil penalty is provided, is liable to the United States Government for the civil penalty provided. The amount of the civil penalty shall be assessed by the Secretary by written notice. In determining the amount of the penalty, the Secretary shall consider the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the prohibited acts committed and, with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior offenses, ability to pay, and other matters that justice requires.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compromising penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit, with or without consideration, a civil penalty under this chapter until the assessment is referred to the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral to Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty after it has become final, the Secretary may refer the matter to the Attorney General for collection in an appropriate district court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refund of penalty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may refund or remit a civil penalty collected under this chapter if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> application has been made for refund or remission of the penalty within one year from the date of payment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary finds that the penalty was unlawfully, improperly, or excessively imposed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4108</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2609.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person violating this chapter is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $25,000. Each day of a continuing violation is a separate violation. A vessel involved in the violation also is liable in rem for the penalty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operating without a permit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person violating <ref>section 2602 of this title</ref> is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $10,000. Each day of a continuing violation is a separate violation. A vessel involved in the violation also is liable in rem for the penalty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person that knowingly violates, or that knowingly aids, abets, authorizes, or instigates a violation of this chapter, shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments for information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The court, the Secretary of Transportation, or the Administrator, as the case may be, may pay up to one-half of a fine or penalty to any person giving information leading to the assessment of the fine or penalty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4109</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>RELATED PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2621.</num>
<heading> Study and recommendations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall conduct a study to determine the need for, and effectiveness of additional tracking systems for vessels to assure that municipal or commercial waste is not deposited in coastal waters. In conducting this study, the Administrator shall use the data collected from its permitting and enforcement activities under this chapter. In determining the effectiveness of tracking systems, the Administrator shall rely on the information provided by the Secretary under subsection (b) of this section. The report shall include a recommendation whether additional tracking systems are needed. This study shall be submitted to Congress within 24 months after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide recommendations to the Administrator concerning the various tracking systems that might be applicable to vessels transporting municipal or commercial waste which the Secretary currently is studying. The Secretary shall consider the relative effectiveness of various systems and the relative costs of the systems both to the United States Government and to the vessel owner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4201</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2622.</num>
<heading> Relation to other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on Federal and State laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not affect the application of any other Federal or State law, statutory or common, including the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq., 1447 et seq.; <ref>33 U.S.C. 1401</ref> et seq., 2801 et seq.] and the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on foreign vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall be carried out with respect to foreign vessels consistent with the obligations of the United States under international law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4202</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2623.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $1,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 1989 and 1990, to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–688, title IV, § 4203</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>