<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 24—</num>
<heading>VESSEL BRIDGE-TO-BRIDGE COMMUNICATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1201.</num>
<heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to provide a positive means whereby the operators of approaching vessels can communicate their intentions to one another through voice radio, located convenient to the operator’s navigation station. To effectively accomplish this, there is need for a specific frequency or frequencies dedicated to the exchange of navigational information, on navigable waters of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 164</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1202.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “power-driven vessel” means any vessel propelled by machinery; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “towing vessel” means any commercial vessel engaged in towing another vessel astern, alongside, or by pushing ahead.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 164</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1203.</num>
<heading> Radiotelephone requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vessel coverage; exchange of navigational information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 1206 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> every power-driven vessel of twenty meters or over in length while navigating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> every vessel of one hundred gross tons as measured under <ref>section 14502 of title 46</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under section 14302 of that title as prescribed by the Secretary under section 14104 of that title, and upward carrying one or more passengers for hire while navigating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> every towing vessel of twenty-six feet or over in length while navigating; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> every dredge and floating plant engaged in or near a channel or fairway in operations likely to restrict or affect navigation of other vessels—</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall have a radiotelephone capable of operation from its navigational bridge or, in the case of a dredge, from its main control station and capable of transmitting and receiving on the frequency or frequencies within the 156–162 Mega-Hertz band using the classes of emissions designated by the Federal Communications Commission, after consultation with other cognizant agencies, for the exchange of navigational information.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vessels upon navigable waters of United States inside high seas lines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The radiotelephone required by subsection (a) shall be carried on board the described vessels, dredges, and floating plants upon the navigable waters of the United States, which includes all waters of the territorial sea of the United States as described in Presidential Proclamation 5928 of <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 4</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–241, § 16</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3933</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1204.</num>
<heading> Radiotelephone for exclusive use of master, person in charge, or pilot; frequency listening watch; portable radiotelephone equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The radiotelephone required by this chapter is for the exclusive use of the master or person in charge of the vessel, or the person designated by the master or person in charge to pilot or direct the movement of the vessel, who shall maintain a listening watch on the designated frequency. Nothing contained herein shall be interpreted as precluding the use of portable radiotelephone equipment to satisfy the requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 5</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1205.</num>
<heading> Radiotelephone capability; maintenance; restoration; consequences of loss: navigation of vessel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever radiotelephone capability is required by this chapter, a vessel’s radiotelephone equipment shall be maintained in effective operating condition. If the radiotelephone equipment carried aboard a vessel ceases to operate, the master shall exercise due diligence to restore it or cause it to be restored to effective operating condition at the earliest practicable time. The failure of a vessel’s radiotelephone equipment shall not, in itself, constitute a violation of this chapter, nor shall it obligate the master of any vessel to moor or anchor his vessel; however, the loss of radiotelephone capability shall be given consideration in the navigation of the vessel.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 6</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1206.</num>
<heading> Exemptions; terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, if he considers that marine navigational safety will not be adversely affected or where a local communication system fully complies with the intent of this concept but does not conform in detail, issue exemptions from any provisions of this chapter, on such terms and conditions as he considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 7</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1207.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operating and technical conditions and characteristics; frequencies, emission, and power of radiotelephone equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Communications Commission shall, after consultation with other cognizant agencies, prescribe regulations necessary to specify operating and technical conditions and characteristics including frequencies, emission, and power of radiotelephone equipment required under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, subject to the concurrence of the Federal Communications Commission, prescribe regulations for the enforcement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 8</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1208.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Master, person in charge, or pilot subject to penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being the master or person in charge of a vessel subject to this chapter, fails to enforce or comply with this chapter or the regulation, hereunder; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being designated by the master or person in charge of a vessel subject to this chapter to pilot or direct the movement of the vessel, fails to enforce or comply with this chapter or the regulations hereunder—</p>
<p class="indent0">Is liable to a civil penalty of not more than $500 to be assessed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vessels subject to penalty; jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every vessel navigating in violation of this chapter or the regulations hereunder is liable to a civil penalty of not more than $500 to be assessed by the Secretary for which the vessel may be proceeded against in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remission or mitigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any penalty assessed under this section may be remitted or mitigated by the Secretary upon such terms as he may deem proper.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–63, § 9</ref>, <date date="1971-08-04">Aug. 4, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>