<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>MISSISSIPPI RIVER COMMISSION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 641.</num>
<heading> Creation of Mississippi River Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A commission is created to be called “The Mississippi River Commission”, to consist of seven members.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1879, ch. 43, § 1</ref>, <ref>21 Stat. 37</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 642.</num>
<heading> Appointment of commissioners; vacancies; chairman; tenure of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President of the United States shall appoint seven commissioners, three of whom shall be selected from the Engineer Corps of the Army, one from the National Ocean Survey, and three from civil life, two of whom shall be civil engineers. And any vacancy which may occur in the commission shall in like manner be filled by the President of the United States; and he shall designate one of the commissioners appointed from the Engineer Corps of the Army to be president of the commission. The commissioners appointed under sections 641 to 644, 646, and 647 of this title, except those appointed from civil life, shall remain in office subject to removal by the President of the United States. Each commissioner appointed from civil life after <date date="1966-11-07">November 7, 1966</date>, shall be appointed for a term of nine years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1879, ch. 43, § 2</ref>, <ref>21 Stat. 37</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–789, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1966-11-07">Nov. 7, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(y)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1289</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 642a.</num>
<heading> Rank, pay, and allowances of Corps of Engineers officers serving as President of Mississippi River Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any officer of the Corps of Engineers who has served or shall serve four years as President of the Mississippi River Commission and who has been or shall subsequently be retired, shall, from the date of such retirement, receive the rank, pay, and allowances of a retired major general.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1936, ch. 548</ref> (pt.), as added <ref>Aug. 18, 1941, ch. 377, § 3</ref>, <ref>55 Stat. 644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 643.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 644.</num>
<heading> Secretary of commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army may detail from the Engineer Corps of the Army of the United States an officer to act as secretary of said commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1879, ch. 43, § 6</ref>, <ref>21 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 645.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 642</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 646.</num>
<heading> Headquarters and meetings of commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The headquarters and general offices of said commission shall be located at some city or town on the Mississippi River, to be designated by the Secretary of the Army, and the meetings of the commission except such as are held on Government boats during the time of the semiannual inspection trips of the commission shall be held at said headquarters and general offices, the times of said meetings to be fixed by the president of the commission, who shall cause due notice of such meetings to be given members of the commission and the public.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1879, ch. 43, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 18, 1901, ch. 377</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 647.</num>
<heading> Mississippi River survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">[Detail of assistants; vessels; instruments.]</inline> It shall be the duty of the Mississippi River Commission to direct and complete such surveys of the Mississippi River, between the Head of the Passes near its mouth to its headwaters as may have been in progress <date date="1879-06-28">June 28, 1879</date>, and to make such additional surveys, examinations, and investigations, topographical, hydrographical, and hydrometrical, of said river and its tributaries, as may be deemed necessary by said commission to carry out the objects of sections 641 to 644, 646, and 647 of this title. And to enable said commission to complete such surveys, examinations, and investigations, the Secretary of the Army shall, when requested by said commission, detail from the Engineer Corps of the Army such officers and men as may be necessary, and shall place in the charge and for the use of said commission such vessel or vessels and such machinery and instruments as may be under his control and may be deemed necessary. And the Secretary of Commerce shall, when requested by said commission in like manner detail from the National Ocean Survey such officers and men as may be necessary, and shall place in the charge and for the use of said commission such vessel or vessels and such machinery and instruments as may be under his control and may be deemed necessary. And the said commission may, with the approval of the Secretary of the Army, employ such additional force and assistants, and provide, by purchase or otherwise, such vessels or boats and such instruments and means as may be deemed necessary.</p>
<p class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">[Plans; report.]</inline> It shall be the duty of said commission to take into consideration and mature such plan or plans and estimates as will correct, permanently locate, and deepen the channel and protect the banks of the Mississippi River; improve and give safety and ease to the navigation thereof; prevent destructive floods; promote and facilitate commerce, trade, and the postal service; and when so prepared and matured, to submit to the Secretary of the Army a full and detailed report of their proceedings and actions, and of such plans, with estimates of the cost thereof, for the purposes aforesaid, to be by him transmitted to Congress: <i>Provided</i>, That the commission shall report in full upon the practicability, feasibility, and probable cost of the various plans known as the jetty system, the levee system, and the outlet system, as well as upon such others as they deem necessary.</p>
<p class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">[Plans for immediate works.]</inline> The said commission may, prior to the completion of all the surveys and examinations contemplated by sections 641 to 644, 646, and 647 of this title, prepare and submit to the Secretary of the Army, plans, specifications, and estimates of costs for such immediate works as, in the judgment of said commission, may constitute a part of the general system of works herein contemplated, to be by him transmitted to Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1879, ch. 43</ref>, §§ 3–5, <ref>21 Stat. 37</ref>, 38; <ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 826</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 648.</num>
<heading> Arkansas River; levee and bank protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The jurisdiction of the Mississippi River Commission is extended so as to include that part of the Arkansas River between its mouth and the intersection thereof with the division line between Lincoln and Jefferson Counties, and any funds which are appropriated by Congress for improving the Mississippi River between Head of Passes and the mouth of the Ohio River, and which may be allotted to levees and bank revetment, may be expended within the limits of said extended jurisdiction under the direction of the Secretary of the Army, in accordance with the plans, specifications, and recommendations of the Mississippi River Commission, as approved by the Chief of Engineers, and upon like terms and conditions for levees and bank revetment upon any part of the Mississippi River now under the jurisdiction of said commission, and in such manner as will best promote and accomplish the purposes for which commission was created, in so far as the territory hereby added to its said jurisdiction may be involved.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 27, 1916, ch. 260, § 1</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649.</num>
<heading> Vicksburg Harbor and Ohio River below Cache River</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The harbor at Vicksburg, Mississippi, and the Ohio River from its mouth to the mouth of the Cache River, are transferred to and placed under the control and jurisdiction of the Mississippi River Commission: <i>Provided</i>, That no part of the improvement of the Ohio River, with a view to the construction of locks and dams, shall be considered as transferred to or placed under the control and jurisdiction of the Mississippi River Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 27, 1916, ch. 260, § 1</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 650.</num>
<heading> Mississippi River below Rock Island; levee and bank protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any funds which are appropriated by Congress for improving the Mississippi River between Head of Passes and the mouth of the Ohio River, and which may be allotted to levees, may be expended, under the direction of the Secretary of the Army, in accordance with the plans, specifications, and recommendations of the Mississippi River Commission, as approved by the Chief of Engineers, for levees upon any part of said river between Head of Passes and Rock Island, Illinois, in such manner as, in their opinion, shall best improve navigation and promote the interest of commerce at all stages of the river.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 27, 1916, ch. 260, § 1</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 651.</num>
<heading> Tributaries of Mississippi River below Cairo; levee and bank protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The jurisdiction of the Mississippi River Commission is extended, for the purposes of levee protection and bank protection, to the tributaries and outlets of the Mississippi River between Cairo, Illinois, and the Head of the Passes, in so far as these tributaries and outlets are affected by the flood waters of the Mississippi River.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 22, 1922, ch. 427, § 13</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 1047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 652.</num>
<heading> Upper Mississippi River Management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title; Congressional declaration of intent</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section may be cited as the “Upper Mississippi River Management Act of 1986”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To ensure the coordinated development and enhancement of the Upper Mississippi River system, it is hereby declared to be the intent of Congress to recognize that system as a nationally significant ecosystem and a nationally significant commercial navigation system. Congress further recognizes that the system provides a diversity of opportunities and experiences. The system shall be administered and regulated in recognition of its several purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “Upper Mississippi River system” and “system” mean those river reaches having commercial navigation channels on the Mississippi River main stem north of Cairo, Illinois; the Minnesota River, Minnesota; Black River, Wisconsin; Saint Croix River, Minnesota and Wisconsin; Illinois River and Waterway, Illinois; and Kaskaskia River, Illinois;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Master Plan” means the comprehensive master plan for the management of the Upper Mississippi River system, dated <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, prepared by the Upper Mississippi River Basin Commission and submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>Public Law 95–502</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “GREAT I, GREAT II, and GRRM studies” means the studies entitled “GREAT Environmental Action Team—GREAT I—A Study of the Upper Mississippi River”, dated September 1980, “GREAT River Environmental Action Team—GREAT II—A Study of the Upper Mississippi River”, dated December 1980, and “GREAT River Resource Management Study”, dated September 1982; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Upper Mississippi River Basin Association” means an association of the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri, and Wisconsin, formed for the purposes of cooperative effort and united assistance in the comprehensive planning for the use, protection, growth, and development of the Upper Mississippi River System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional approval of Master Plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Congress hereby approves the Master Plan as a guide for future water policy on the Upper Mississippi River system. Such approval shall not constitute authorization of any recommendation contained in the Master Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Omitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative effort and mutual assistance among States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The consent of the Congress is hereby given to the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri, and Wisconsin, or any two or more of such States, to enter into negotiations for agreements, not in conflict with any law of the United States, for cooperative effort and mutual assistance in the comprehensive planning for the use, protection, growth, and development of the Upper Mississippi River system, and to establish such agencies, joint or otherwise, or designate an existing multi-State entity, as they may deem desirable for making effective such agreements. To the extent required by Article I, section 10 of the Constitution, such agreements shall become final only after ratification by an Act of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with the Upper Mississippi River Basin Association or any other agency established under paragraph (1) of this subsection to promote and facilitate active State government participation in the river system management, development, and protection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purpose of ensuring the coordinated planning and implementation of programs authorized in subsections (e) and (h)(2) of this section, the Secretary shall enter into an interagency agreement with the Secretary of the Interior to provide for the direct participation of, and transfer of funds to, the Fish and Wildlife Service and any other agency or bureau of the Department of the Interior for the planning, design, implementation, and evaluation of such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Upper Mississippi River Basin Association or any other agency established under paragraph (1) of this subsection is hereby designated by Congress as the caretaker of the master plan. Any changes to the master plan recommended by the Secretary shall be submitted to such association or agency for review. Such association or agency may make such comments with respect to such recommendations and offer other recommended changes to the master plan as such association or agency deems appropriate and shall transmit such comments and other recommended changes to the Secretary. The Secretary shall transmit such recommendations along with the comments and other recommended changes of such association or agency to the Congress for approval within 90 days of the receipt of such comments or recommended changes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri, and Wisconsin, may undertake, as identified in the master plan—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a program for the planning, construction, and evaluation of measures for fish and wildlife habitat rehabilitation and enhancement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> implementation of a long-term resource monitoring, computerized data inventory and analysis, and applied research program, including research on water quality issues affecting the Mississippi River (including elevated nutrient levels) and the development of remediation strategies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advisory committee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out subparagraph (A)(i), the Secretary shall establish an independent technical advisory committee to review projects, monitoring plans, and habitat and natural resource needs assessments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>, and not later than December 31 of every sixth year thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri, and Wisconsin, shall submit to Congress a report that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contains an evaluation of the programs described in paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describes the accomplishments of each of the programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provides updates of a systemic habitat needs assessment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identifies any needed adjustments in the authorization of the programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of carrying out paragraph (1)(A)(i) of this subsection, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $75,000,000 for fiscal year 1999 and each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For purposes of carrying out paragraph (1)(A)(ii) of this subsection, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1999 through 2024, and $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out paragraph (1)(B) $350,000 for each of fiscal years 1999 through 2009.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For fiscal year 1999 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri, and Wisconsin, may transfer not to exceed 20 percent of the amounts appropriated to carry out clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) to the amounts appropriated to carry out the other of those clauses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2) of this section, the costs of each project carried out pursuant to paragraph (1)(A)(i) of this subsection shall be allocated between the Secretary and the appropriate non-Federal sponsor in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 2283(e) of this title</ref>; except that the costs of operation and maintenance of projects located on Federal lands or lands owned or operated by a State or local government shall be borne by the Federal, State, or local agency that is responsible for management activities for fish and wildlife on such lands and, in the case of any project requiring non-Federal cost sharing, the non-Federal share of the cost of the project shall be 35 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2) of this section, the cost of implementing the activities authorized by paragraph (1)(A)(ii) of this subsection shall be allocated in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 2283 of this title</ref>, as if such activity was required to mitigate losses to fish and wildlife.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> None of the funds appropriated pursuant to any authorization contained in this subsection shall be considered to be chargeable to navigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recreational projects authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary, in consultation with any agency established under subsection (d)(1) of this section, is authorized to implement a program of recreational projects for the system substantially in accordance with the recommendations of the GREAT I, GREAT II, and GRRM studies and the master plan reports. In addition, the Secretary, in consultation with any such agency, shall, at Federal expense, conduct an assessment of the economic benefits generated by recreational activities in the system. The cost of each such project shall be allocated between the Secretary and the appropriate non-Federal sponsor in accordance with title I of this Act [<ref>33 U.S.C. 2211</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of carrying out the program of recreational projects authorized in paragraph (1) of this subsection, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary not to exceed $500,000 per fiscal year for each of the first 15 fiscal years beginning after <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increases in lock capacity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in his budget request, identify those measures developed by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and any agency established under subsection (d)(1) of this section, to be undertaken to increase the capacity of specific locks throughout the system by employing nonstructural measures and making minor structural improvements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring of traffic movements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary, in consultation with any agency established under subsection (d)(1) of this section, shall monitor traffic movements on the system for the purpose of verifying lock capacity, updating traffic projections, and refining the economic evaluation so as to verify the need for future capacity expansion of the system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Determination.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the States of Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri, and Wisconsin, shall determine the need for river rehabilitation and environmental enhancement and protection based on the condition of the environment, project developments, and projected environmental impacts from implementing any proposals resulting from recommendations made under subsection (g) and paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> complete the ongoing habitat needs assessment conducted under this paragraph not later than <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include in each report under subsection (e)(2) the most recent habitat needs assessment conducted under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposal of dredged material</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall, as he determines feasible, dispose of dredged material from the system pursuant to the recommendations of the GREAT I, GREAT II, and GRRM studies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish and request appropriate Federal funding for a program to facilitate productive uses of dredged material. The Secretary shall work with the States which have, within their boundaries, any part of the system to identify potential users of dredged material.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of second lock at locks and dam 26, Mississippi River, Alton, Illinois and Missouri</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to provide for the engineering, design, and construction of a second lock at locks and dam 26, Mississippi River, Alton, Illinois and Missouri, at a total cost of $220,000,000, with a first Federal cost of $220,000,000. Such second lock shall be one hundred and ten feet by six hundred feet and shall be constructed at or in the vicinity of the location of the replacement lock authorized by <ref>section 102 of Public Law 95–502</ref>. <ref>Section 2212 of this title</ref> shall apply to the project authorized by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XI, § 1103</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–640, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4646</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–580, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1992-10-31">Oct. 31, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–53, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 339</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–109, § 2</ref>, <date date="1999-11-24">Nov. 24, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1494</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title III, § 3177</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2704</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8345</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3796</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title III, § 1354</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 653.</num>
<heading> Extension of jurisdiction of Mississippi River Commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The jurisdiction of the Mississippi River Commission (established by the Act of <date date="1879-06-29">June 29, 1879</date> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002024">1</ref> (<ref>33 U.S.C. 641</ref>)) is extended to include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Terrebonne Parish, Louisiana; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the area bounded by the East Atchafalaya Basin Protection Levee, the Mississippi River Levee, and Bayou Lafourche and extending from Morganza, Louisiana, to the Gulf of Mexico, insofar as such area is affected by the flood waters of the Mississippi River.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–580, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1992-10-31">Oct. 31, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 653a.</num>
<heading> Extension of jurisdiction of Mississippi River Commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The jurisdiction of the Mississippi River Commission, established by <ref>section 641 of this title</ref>, is extended to include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all of the area between the eastern side of the Bayou Lafourche Ridge from Donaldsonville, Louisiana, to the Gulf of Mexico and the west guide levee of the Mississippi River from Donaldsonville, Louisiana, to the Gulf of Mexico;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Alexander County, Illinois; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the area in the State of Illinois from the confluence of the Mississippi and Ohio Rivers northward to the vicinity of Mississippi River mile 39.5, including the Len Small Drainage and Levee District, insofar as such area is affected by the flood waters of the Mississippi River.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title V, § 517</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3764</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>