<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION OF NAVIGABLE WATERS AND OF HARBOR AND RIVER IMPROVEMENTS GENERALLY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>IN GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 400.</num>
<heading> Continuing authority programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of continuing authority program project</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “continuing authority program” means 1 of the following authorities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>Section 701s of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 426i of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2330 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2309a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content><ref>Section 577 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content><ref>Section 426g of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content><ref>Section 701r of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Section 103 of the River and Harbor Act of 1962 (<ref>Public Law 87–874</ref>; <ref>76 Stat. 1178</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2326(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content><ref>Section 701b–8a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content><ref>Section 610(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register and on a publicly available website, the criteria the Secretary uses for prioritizing annual funding for continuing authority program projects.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register and on a publicly available website, a report on the status of each continuing authority program, which, at a minimum, shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name and a short description of each active continuing authority program project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost estimate to complete each active project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the funding available in that fiscal year for each continuing authority program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On publication in the Federal Register under paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a copy of all information published under those paragraphs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1030(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1231</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 401.</num>
<heading> Construction of bridges, causeways, dams or dikes generally; exemptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be lawful to construct or commence the construction of any bridge, causeway, dam, or dike over or in any port, roadstead, haven, harbor, canal, navigable river, or other navigable water of the United States until the consent of Congress to the building of such structures shall have been obtained and until the plans for (1) the bridge or causeway shall have been submitted to and approved by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, or (2) the dam or dike shall have been submitted to and approved by the Chief of Engineers and Secretary of the Army. However, such structures may be built under authority of the legislature of a State across rivers and other waterways the navigable portions of which lie wholly within the limits of a single State, provided the location and plans thereof are submitted to and approved by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating or by the Chief of Engineers and Secretary of the Army before construction is commenced. When plans for any bridge or other structure have been approved by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating or by the Chief of Engineers and Secretary of the Army, it shall not be lawful to deviate from such plans either before or after completion of the structure unless modification of said plans has previously been submitted to and received the approval of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating or the Chief of Engineers and the Secretary of the Army. The approval required by this section of the location and plans or any modification of plans of any bridge or causeway does not apply to any bridge or causeway over waters that are not subject to the ebb and flow of the tide and that are not used and are not susceptible to use in their natural condition or by reasonable improvement as a means to transport interstate or foreign commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 9</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–322, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1582</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–449, § 2(f)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 306(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 55</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 402.</num>
<heading> Construction of bridges, etc., over Illinois and Mississippi Canal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 401 of this title</ref> are made applicable alike to the completed and uncompleted portions of the Illinois and Mississippi Canal. Whenever the Secretary of the Army shall approve plans for a bridge to be built across said canal he may, in his discretion, and subject to such terms and conditions as in his judgment are equitable, expedient, and just to the public, grant to the person or corporation building and owning such bridge a right of way across the lands of the United States on either side of and adjacent to the said canal; also the privilege of occupying so much of said lands as may be necessary for the piers, abutments, and other portions of the bridge structure and approaches.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 13, 1902, ch. 1079, § 10</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 403.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of navigable waters generally; wharves; piers, etc.; excavations and filling in</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The creation of any obstruction not affirmatively authorized by Congress, to the navigable capacity of any of the waters of the United States is prohibited; and it shall not be lawful to build or commence the building of any wharf, pier, dolphin, boom, weir, breakwater, bulkhead, jetty, or other structures in any port, roadstead, haven, harbor, canal, navigable river, or other water of the United States, outside established harbor lines, or where no harbor lines have been established, except on plans recommended by the Chief of Engineers and authorized by the Secretary of the Army; and it shall not be lawful to excavate or fill, or in any manner to alter or modify the course, location, condition, or capacity of, any port, roadstead, haven, harbor, canal, lake, harbor of refuge, or inclosure within the limits of any breakwater, or of the channel of any navigable water of the United States, unless the work has been recommended by the Chief of Engineers and authorized by the Secretary of the Army prior to beginning the same.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 10</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 403a.</num>
<heading> Creation or continuance of obstruction of navigable waters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The creation of any obstruction, not affirmatively authorized by law, to the navigable capacity of any waters, in respect of which the United States has jurisdiction, is hereby prohibited. The continuance of any such obstruction, except bridges, piers, docks, and wharves, and similar structures erected for business purposes, whether heretofore or hereafter created, shall constitute an offense and each week’s continuance of any such obstruction shall be deemed a separate offense. Every person and every corporation which shall be guilty of creating or continuing any such unlawful obstruction in this act mentioned, or who shall violate the provisions of the last four preceding sections of this act, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine not exceeding five thousand dollars, or by imprisonment (in the case of a natural person) not exceeding one year, or by both such punishments, in the discretion of the court, the creating or continuing of any unlawful obstruction in this act mentioned may be prevented and such obstruction may be caused to be removed by the injunction of any district court exercising jurisdiction in any district in which such obstruction may be threatened or may exist; and proper proceedings in equity to this end may be instituted under the direction of the Attorney-General of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 19, 1890, ch. 907, § 10</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 454</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 291</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 1167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 403b.</num>
<heading> Lighting at docks and boat launching facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary considers a permit application for a dock or a boat launching facility under <ref>section 403 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall consider the needs of such facility for lighting from sunset to sunrise to make such facility’s presence known within a reasonable distance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 946</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 404.</num>
<heading> Establishment of harbor lines; conditions to grants for extension of piers, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where it is made manifest to the Secretary of the Army that the establishment of harbor lines is essential to the preservation and protection of harbors he may, and is, authorized to cause such lines to be established, beyond which no piers, wharves, bulkheads, or other works shall be extended or deposits made, except under such regulations as may be prescribed from time to time by him: <i>Provided</i>, That, whenever the Secretary of the Army grants to any person or persons permission to extend piers, wharves, bulkheads, or other works, or to make deposits in any tidal harbor or river of the United States beyond any harbor lines established under authority of the United States, he shall cause to be ascertained the amount of tidewater displaced by any such structure or by any such deposits, and he shall, if he deem it necessary, require the parties to whom the permission is given to make compensation for such displacement either by excavating in some part of the harbor, including tidewater channels between high and low water mark, to such an extent as to create a basin for as much tidewater as may be displaced by such structure or by such deposits, or in any other mode that may be satisfactory to him.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 11</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 405.</num>
<heading> Establishment and modification of harbor lines on Potomac and Anacostia Rivers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 404 of this title</ref> are made applicable to the Potomac and Anacostia Rivers, and after <date date="1912-07-25">July 25, 1912</date>, harbor lines in the District of Columbia, or elsewhere on said rivers, shall be established or modified as therein provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 25, 1912, ch. 253, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 406.</num>
<heading> Penalty for wrongful construction of bridges, piers, etc.; removal of structures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person and every corporation that shall violate any of the provisions of sections 401, 403, and 404 of this title or any rule or regulation made by the Secretary of the Army in pursuance of the provisions of <ref>section 404 of this title</ref> shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $2,500 nor less than $500, or by imprisonment (in the case of a natural person) not exceeding one year, or by both such punishments, in the discretion of the court. And further, the removal of any structures or parts of structures erected in violation of the provisions of the said sections may be enforced by the injunction of any district court exercising jurisdiction in any district in which such structures may exist, and proper proceedings to this end may be instituted under the direction of the Attorney General of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 12</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>Feb. 20, 1900, ch. 23, § 2</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 291</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 1167</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 407.</num>
<heading> Deposit of refuse in navigable waters generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be lawful to throw, discharge, or deposit, or cause, suffer, or procure to be thrown, discharged, or deposited either from or out of any ship, barge, or other floating craft of any kind, or from the shore, wharf, manufacturing establishment, or mill of any kind, any refuse matter of any kind or description whatever other than that flowing from streets and sewers and passing therefrom in a liquid state, into any navigable water of the United States, or into any tributary of any navigable water from which the same shall float or be washed into such navigable water; and it shall not be lawful to deposit, or cause, suffer, or procure to be deposited material of any kind in any place on the bank of any navigable water, or on the bank of any tributary of any navigable water, where the same shall be liable to be washed into such navigable water, either by ordinary or high tides, or by storms or floods, or otherwise, whereby navigation shall or may be impeded or obstructed: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein contained shall extend to, apply to, or prohibit the operations in connection with the improvement of navigable waters or construction of public works, considered necessary and proper by the United States officers supervising such improvement or public work: <i>And provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Army, whenever in the judgment of the Chief of Engineers anchorage and navigation will not be injured thereby, may permit the deposit of any material above mentioned in navigable waters, within limits to be defined and under conditions to be prescribed by him, provided application is made to him prior to depositing such material; and whenever any permit is so granted the conditions thereof shall be strictly complied with, and any violation thereof shall be unlawful.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 13</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 407a.</num>
<heading> Deposit of debris of mines and stamp works</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In places where harbor-lines have not been established, and where deposits of debris of mines or stamp works can be made without injury to navigation, within lines to be established by the Secretary of the Army, said officer may, and is authorized to, cause such lines to be established; and within such lines such deposits may be made, under regulations to be from time to time prescribed by him.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 5, 1886, ch. 929, § 2</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 329</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 408.</num>
<heading> Taking possession of, use of, or injury to harbor or river improvements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibitions and permissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be lawful for any person or persons to take possession of or make use of for any purpose, or build upon, alter, deface, destroy, move, injure, obstruct by fastening vessels thereto or otherwise, or in any manner whatever impair the usefulness of any sea wall, bulkhead, jetty, dike, levee, wharf, pier, or other work built by the United States, or any piece of plant, floating or otherwise, used in the construction of such work under the control of the United States, in whole or in part, for the preservation and improvement of any of its navigable waters or to prevent floods, or as boundary marks, tide gauges, surveying stations, buoys, or other established marks, nor remove for ballast or other purposes any stone or other material composing such works: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of the Army may, on the recommendation of the Chief of Engineers, grant permission for the temporary occupation or use of any of the aforementioned public works when in his judgment such occupation or use will not be injurious to the public interest: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary may, on the recommendation of the Chief of Engineers, grant permission for the alteration or permanent occupation or use of any of the aforementioned public works when in the judgment of the Secretary such occupation or use will not be injurious to the public interest and will not impair the usefulness of such work.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrent review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NEPA review</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In any case in which an activity subject to this section requires a review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), review and approval of the activity under this section shall, to the maximum extent practicable, occur concurrently with any review and decisions made under that Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Corps of Engineers as a cooperating agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the Corps of Engineers is not the lead Federal agency for an environmental review described in subparagraph (A), the Corps of Engineers shall, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with Federal laws—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> participate in the review as a cooperating agency (unless the Corps of Engineers does not intend to submit comments on the project); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> adopt and use any environmental document prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) by the lead agency to the same extent that a Federal agency could adopt or use a document prepared by another Federal agency under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> parts 1500 through 1508 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviews by Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In any case in which the Secretary must approve an action under this section and under another authority, including sections 401 and 403 of this title, <ref>section 1344 of this title</ref>, and <ref>section 1413 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate applicable reviews and, to the maximum extent practicable, carry out the reviews concurrently; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adopt and use any document prepared by the Corps of Engineers for the purpose of complying with the same law and that addresses the same types of impacts in the same geographic area if such document, as determined by the Secretary, is current and applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contributed funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may accept and expend funds received from non-Federal public or private entities to evaluate under this section an alteration or permanent occupation or use of a work built by the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review process</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish clear, concise, and specific guidance to be used within the Corps of Engineers and by non-Federal entities developing applications for permission standardizing the review process across Districts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preapplication meeting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">At the request of a non-Federal entity that is planning on submitting an application for permission pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall meet with the non-Federal entity to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide clear, concise, and specific design standards that the non-Federal entity must use in the development of the application;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommend, based on coordination with the non-Federal entity, the appropriate number of design packages for submission for the proposed action, and the stage of development at which such packages should be submitted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identify potential concerns or conflicts with such proposed actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contributed funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may use funds accepted from a non-Federal entity under subsection (b)(3) for purposes of conducting a meeting described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timely review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Complete application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On or before the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives an application for permission to take action affecting public projects pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall inform the applicant whether the application is complete and, if it is not, what items are needed for the application to be complete.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decision</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On or before the date that is 90 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a complete application for permission under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make a decision on the application; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide a schedule to the applicant identifying when the Secretary will make a decision on the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which a schedule provided under paragraph (2)(B) extends beyond 120 days from the date of receipt of a complete application, the Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives an explanation justifying the extended timeframe for review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Work Defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “work” shall not include unimproved real estate owned or operated by the Secretary as part of a water resources development project if the Secretary determines that modification of such real estate would not affect the function and usefulness of the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 14</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–88, title I, § 100</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 315</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1156(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1165</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3797</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1105</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 408a.</num>
<heading> Expediting approval of modifications and alterations of projects by non-Federal interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section 14 application defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “section 14 application” means an application submitted by an applicant to the Secretary requesting permission for the temporary occupation or use of a public work, or the alteration or permanent occupation or use of a public work, under <ref>section 14 of the Act of March 3, 1899</ref> (commonly known as the “Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1899”) (<ref>33 U.S.C. 408</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, the Secretary, after providing notice and an opportunity for comment, shall establish a process for the review of section 14 applications in a timely and consistent manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benchmark goals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of benchmark goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish benchmark goals for determining the amount of time it should take the Secretary to determine whether a section 14 application is complete;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish benchmark goals for determining the amount of time it should take the Secretary to approve or disapprove a section 14 application; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, use such benchmark goals to make a decision on section 14 applications in a timely and consistent manner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benchmark goals</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benchmark goals for determining whether section 14 applications are complete</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To the extent practicable, the benchmark goals established under paragraph (1) shall provide that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary reach a decision on whether a section 14 application is complete not later than 15 days after the date of receipt of the application; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the Secretary determines that a section 14 application is not complete, the Secretary promptly notify the applicant of the specific information that is missing or the analysis that is needed to complete the application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benchmark goals for reviewing completed applications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To the extent practicable, the benchmark goals established under paragraph (1) shall provide that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary generally approve or disapprove a completed section 14 application not later than 45 days after the date of receipt of the completed application; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in a case in which the Secretary determines that additional time is needed to review a completed section 14 application due to the type, size, cost, complexity, or impacts of the actions proposed in the application, the Secretary generally approve or disapprove the application not later than 180 days after the date of receipt of the completed application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In any case in which the Secretary determines that it will take the Secretary more than 45 days to review a completed section 14 application, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide written notification to the applicant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include in the written notice a best estimate of the Secretary as to the amount of time required for completion of the review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to achieve benchmark goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any case in which the Secretary fails make <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref> a decision on a section 14 application in accordance with the process established under this section, the Secretary shall provide written notice to the applicant, including a detailed description of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> why the Secretary failed to make a decision in accordance with such process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the additional actions required before the Secretary will issue a decision; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount of time the Secretary will require to issue a decision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide a copy of any written notice provided under subsection (d) to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall maintain a publicly available database, including on the Internet, on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all section 14 applications received by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the current status of such applications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, the Secretary shall issue guidance on the implementation of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incorporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In issuing guidance under paragraph (1), or any other regulation, guidance, or engineering circular related to activities covered under <ref>section 408 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall incorporate the requirements under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prioritize and complete the activities required of the Secretary under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1007</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1214</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1156(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1665</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 409.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of navigable waters by vessels; floating timber; marking and removal of sunken vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be lawful to tie up or anchor vessels or other craft in navigable channels in such a manner as to prevent or obstruct the passage of other vessels or craft; or to sink, or permit or cause to be sunk, vessels or other craft in navigable channels; or to float loose timber and logs, or to float what is known as “sack rafts of timber and logs” in streams or channels actually navigated by steamboats in such manner as to obstruct, impede, or endanger navigation. And whenever a vessel, raft or other craft is wrecked and sunk in a navigable channel, it shall be the duty of the owner, lessee, or operator of such sunken craft to immediately mark it with a buoy or beacon during the day and, unless otherwise granted a waiver by the Commandant of the Coast Guard, a light at night, and to maintain such marks until the sunken craft is removed or abandoned, and the neglect or failure of the said owner, lessee, or operator so to do shall be unlawful; and it shall be the duty of the owner, lessee, or operator of such sunken craft to commence the immediate removal of the same, and prosecute such removal diligently, and failure to do so shall be considered as an abandonment of such craft, and subject the same to removal by the United States as provided for in sections 411 to 416, 418, and 502 of this title. The Commandant of the Coast Guard may waive the requirement to mark a wrecked vessel, raft, or other craft with a light at night if the Commandant determines that placing a light would be impractical and granting such a waiver would not create an undue hazard to navigation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 15</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 939(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1041</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 410.</num>
<heading> Exception as to floating loose timber, sack rafts, etc.; violation of regulations; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The prohibition contained in <ref>section 409 of this title</ref> against floating loose timber and logs, or sack rafts, so called, of timber and logs in streams or channels actually navigated by steamboats, shall not apply to any navigable river or waterway of the United States or any part thereof whereon the floating of loose timber and logs and sack rafts of timber and logs is the principal method of navigation. But such method of navigation on such river or waterway or part thereof shall be subject to the rules and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Army as provided in this section.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army shall have power, and he is authorized and directed to prescribe rules and regulations, which he may at any time modify, to govern and regulate the floating of loose timber and logs, and sack rafts, (so called) of timber and logs and other methods of navigation on the streams and waterways, or any thereof, of the character, as to navigation, heretofore in this section described. The said rules and regulations shall be so framed as to equitably adjust conflicting interests between the different methods or forms of navigation; and the said rules and regulations shall be published at least once in such newspaper or newspapers of general circulation as in the opinion of the Secretary of the Army shall be best adapted to give notice of said rules and regulations to persons affected thereby and locally interested therein. And all modifications of said rules and regulations shall be similarly published. And such rules and regulations when so prescribed and published as to any such stream or waterway shall have the force of law, and any violation thereof shall be a misdemeanor, and every person convicted of such violation shall be punished by a fine of not exceeding $2,500 nor less than $500, or by imprisonment (in case of a natural person) for not less than thirty days nor more than one year, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court: <i>Provided</i>, That the proper action to enforce the provisions of this section may be commenced before any magistrate judge, judge, or court of the United States, and such magistrate judge, judge, or court shall proceed in respect thereto as authorized by law in the case of crimes or misdemeanors committed against the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">The right to alter, amend, or repeal this section at any time is reserved.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 9, 1900, ch. 387</ref>, §§ 1–3, <ref>31 Stat. 172</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 411.</num>
<heading> Penalty for wrongful deposit of refuse; use of or injury to harbor improvements, and obstruction of navigable waters generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person and every corporation that shall violate, or that shall knowingly aid, abet, authorize, or instigate a violation of the provisions of sections 407, 408, 409, 414, and 415 of this title shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of up to $25,000 per day, or by imprisonment (in the case of a natural person) for not less than thirty days nor more than one year, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court, one-half of said fine to be paid to the person or persons giving information which shall lead to conviction.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 16</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 218(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 412.</num>
<heading> Liability of masters, pilots, etc., and of vessels engaged in violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any and every master, pilot, and engineer, or person or persons acting in such capacity, respectively, on board of any boat or vessel who shall knowingly engage in towing any scow, boat, or vessel loaded with any material specified in <ref>section 407 of this title</ref> to any point or place of deposit or discharge in any harbor or navigable water, elsewhere than within the limits defined and permitted by the Secretary of the Army, or who shall willfully injure or destroy any work of the United States contemplated in <ref>section 408 of this title</ref>, or who shall willfully obstruct the channel of any waterway in the manner contemplated in <ref>section 409 of this title</ref>, shall be deemed guilty of a violation of this Act, and shall upon conviction be punished as provided in <ref>section 411 of this title</ref>, and shall also have his license revoked or suspended for a term to be fixed by the judge before whom tried and convicted. And any boat, vessel, scow, raft, or other craft used or employed in violating any of the provisions of sections 407, 408, 409, 414, and 415 of this title shall be liable for the pecuniary penalties specified in <ref>section 411 of this title</ref>, and in addition thereto for the amount of the damages done by said boat, vessel, scow, raft, or other craft, which latter sum shall be placed to the credit of the appropriation for the improvement of the harbor or waterway in which the damage occurred, and said boat, vessel, scow, raft, or other craft may be proceeded against summarily by way of libel in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 16</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1153</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 218(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 413.</num>
<heading> Duty of United States attorneys and other Federal officers in enforcement of provisions; arrest of offenders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Justice shall conduct the legal proceedings necessary to enforce the provisions of sections 401, 403, 404, 406, 407, 408, 409, 411, and 412 of this title; and it shall be the duty of United States attorneys to vigorously prosecute all offenders against the same whenever requested to do so by the Secretary of the Army or by any of the officials hereinafter designated, and it shall furthermore be the duty of said United States attorneys to report to the Attorney General of the United States the action taken by him against offenders so reported, and a transcript of such reports shall be transmitted to the Secretary of the Army by the Attorney General; and for the better enforcement of the said provisions and to facilitate the detection and bringing to punishment of such offenders, the officers and agents of the United States in charge of river and harbor improvements, and the assistant engineers and inspectors employed under them by authority of the Secretary of the Army, and the United States collectors of customs and other revenue officers shall have power and authority to swear out process, and to arrest and take into custody, with or without process, any person or persons who may commit any of the acts or offenses prohibited by the said sections, or who may violate any of the provisions of the same: <i>Provided</i>, That no person shall be arrested without process for any offense not committed in the presence of some one of the aforesaid officials: <i>And provided further</i>, That whenever any arrest is made under such sections, the person so arrested shall be brought forthwith before a magistrate judge, judge, or court of the United States for examination of the offenses alleged against him; and such magistrate judge, judge, or court shall proceed in respect thereto as authorized by law in case of crimes against the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 17</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1153</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 414.</num>
<heading> Vessel removal by Corps of Engineers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of obstructive vessels</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever the navigation of any river, lake, harbor, sound, bay, canal, or other navigable waters of the United States shall be obstructed or endangered by any sunken vessel, boat, water craft, raft, or other similar obstruction, and such obstruction has existed for a longer period than thirty days, or whenever the abandonment of such obstruction can be legally established in a less space of time, the sunken vessel, boat, water craft, raft, or other obstruction shall be subject to be broken up, removed, sold, or otherwise disposed of by the Secretary of the Army at his discretion, without liability for any damage to the owners of the same: <i>Provided</i>, That in his discretion, the Secretary of the Army may cause reasonable notice of such obstruction of not less than thirty days, unless the legal abandonment of the obstruction can be established in a less time, to be given by publication, addressed “To whom it may concern,” in a newspaper published nearest to the locality of the obstruction, requiring the removal thereof: <i>And provided also</i>, That the Secretary of the Army may, in his discretion, at or after the time of giving such notice, cause sealed proposals to be solicited by public advertisement, giving reasonable notice of not less than ten days, for the removal of such obstruction as soon as possible after the expiration of the above specified thirty days’ notice, in case it has not in the meantime been so removed, these proposals and contracts, at his discretion, to be conditioned that such vessel, boat, water craft, raft, or other obstruction, and all cargo and property contained therein, shall become the property of the contractor, and the contract shall be awarded to the bidder making the proposition most advantageous to the United States: <i>Provided</i>, That such bidder shall give satisfactory security to execute the work: <i>Provided further</i>, That any money received from the sale of any such wreck, or from any contractor for the removal of wrecks, under this paragraph shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of owner, lessee, or operator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owner, lessee, or operator of such vessel, boat, watercraft, raft, or other obstruction as described in this subsection shall be liable to the United States for the cost of removal or destruction and disposal as described which exceeds the costs recovered under paragraph (1). Any amount recovered from the owner, lessee, or operator of such vessel pursuant to this subsection to recover costs in excess of the proceeds from the sale or disposition of such vessel shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of abandoned vessel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized to remove from the navigable waters of the United States a covered vessel that does not obstruct the navigation of such waters, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such removal is determined to be in the public interest by the Secretary, in consultation with any State in which the vessel is located or any Indian Tribe with jurisdiction over the area in which the vessel is located, as applicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a vessel that is not under the control of the United States by reason of seizure or forfeiture, the Commandant of the Coast Guard determines that the vessel is abandoned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In removing a covered vessel under this subsection, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is authorized to enter into an interagency agreement with the head of any Federal department, agency, or instrumentality that has control of such vessel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is authorized to accept funds from such department, agency, or instrumentality for the removal of such vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owner of a covered vessel shall be liable to the United States for the costs of removal, destruction, and disposal of such vessel under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered vessel defined</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this subsection, the term “covered vessel” means a vessel—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determined to be abandoned by the Commandant of the Coast Guard; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under the control of the United States by reason of seizure or forfeiture pursuant to any law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “covered vessel” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any vessel for which the Secretary has removal authority under subsection (a) or <ref>section 415 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an abandoned barge for which the Commandant of the Coast Guard has the authority to remove under chapter 47 of title 46; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> a vessel—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> for which the owner is not identified, unless determined to be abandoned by the Commandant of the Coast Guard; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> for which the owner has not agreed to pay the costs of removal, destruction, or disposal.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 19</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1154</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 939(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1124(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 415.</num>
<heading> Summary removal of water craft obstructing navigation; liability of owner, lessee, or operator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under emergency, in the case of any vessel, boat, water craft, or raft, or other similar obstruction, sinking of grounding, or being unnecessarily delayed in any Government canal or lock, or in any navigable waters mentioned in <ref>section 414 of this title</ref>, in such manner as to stop, seriously interfere with, or specially endanger navigation, in the opinion of the Secretary of the Army, or any agent of the United States to whom the Secretary may delegate proper authority, the Secretary of the Army or any such agent shall have the right to take immediate possession of such boat, vessel, or other water craft, or raft, so far as to remove or to destroy it and to clear immediately the canal, lock, or navigable waters aforesaid of the obstruction thereby caused, using his best judgment to prevent any unnecessary injury; and no one shall interfere with or prevent such removal or destruction: <i>Provided</i>, That the officer or agent charged with the removal or destruction of an obstruction under this section may in his discretion give notice in writing to the owners of any such obstruction requiring them to remove it: <i>And provided further</i>, That the actual expense, including administrative expenses, of removing any such obstruction as aforesaid shall be a charge against such craft and cargo; and if the owners thereof fail or refuse to reimburse the United States for such expense within thirty days after notification, then the officer or agent aforesaid may sell the craft or cargo, or any part thereof that may not have been destroyed in removal, and the proceeds of such sale shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 24 hours after the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating issues an order to stop or delay navigation in any navigable waters of the United States because of conditions related to the sinking or grounding of a vessel, the owner or operator of the vessel, with the approval of the Secretary of the Army, shall begin removal of the vessel using the most expeditious removal method available or, if appropriate, secure the vessel pending removal to allow navigation to resume. If the owner or operator fails to begin removal or to secure the vessel pending removal or fails to complete removal on an expedited basis, the Secretary of the Army shall remove or destroy the vessel using the summary removal procedures under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of owner, lessee, or operator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The owner, lessee, or operator of such vessel, boat, watercraft, raft, or other obstruction as described in this section shall be liable to the United States for the actual cost, including administrative costs, of removal or destruction and disposal as described which exceeds the costs recovered under subsection (a). Any amount recovered from the owner, lessee, or operator of such vessel pursuant to this subsection to recover costs in excess of the proceeds from the sale or disposition of such vessel shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 20</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1154</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 939(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 218(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 416.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for removal of sunken water craft</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such sum of money as may be necessary to execute sections 414(a) and 415 of this title is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to be paid out on the requisition of the Secretary of the Army.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 20(a)</ref>, formerly § 20, <ref>30 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; renumbered § 20(a), <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 939(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1124(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 417.</num>
<heading> Expenses of investigations by Department of the Army</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Expenses incurred by the Engineer Department of the Department of the Army in all investigations, inspections, hearings, reports, service of notice, or other action incidental to examination of plans or sites of bridges or other structures built or proposed to be built in or over navigable waters, or to examinations into alleged violations of laws for the protection and preservation of navigable waters, or to the establishment or marking of harbor lines, shall be payable from any funds which may be available for the improvement, maintenance, operation, or care of the waterways or harbors affected, or if such funds are not available in sums judged by the Chief of Engineers to be adequate, then from any funds available for examinations, surveys, and contingencies of rivers and harbors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1905, ch. 1482, § 6</ref>, <ref>33 Stat. 1148</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 418.</num>
<heading> Provisions for protection of New York Harbor unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in sections 401, 403, 404, 406, 407, 408, 409, 411 to 416, and 502 of this title shall be construed as repealing, modifying, or in any manner affecting the provisions of subchapter III of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, § 20(a)</ref>, formerly § 20, <ref>30 Stat. 1154</ref>; <ref>Feb. 20, 1900, ch. 23, § 3</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>June 13, 1902, ch. 1079, § 12</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 375</ref>; renumbered § 20(a), <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 939(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 419.</num>
<heading> Regulation by Secretary governing transportation and dumping of dredgings, refuse, etc., into navigable waters; oyster lands; appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized and empowered to prescribe regulations to govern the transportation and dumping into any navigable water, or waters adjacent thereto, of dredgings, earth, garbage, and other refuse materials of every kind or description, whenever in his judgment such regulations are required in the interest of navigation. Such regulations shall be posted in conspicuous and appropriate places for the information of the public; and every person or corporation which shall violate the said regulations, or any of them, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be subject to the penalties prescribed in sections 411 and 412 of this title, for violation of the provisions of <ref>section 407 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That any regulations made in pursuance hereof may be enforced as provided in <ref>section 413 of this title</ref>, the provisions whereof are made applicable to the said regulations: <i>Provided further</i>, That this section shall not apply to any waters within the jurisdictional boundaries of any State which are now or may hereafter be used for the cultivation of oysters under the laws of such State, except navigable channels which have been or may hereafter be improved by the United States, or to be designated as navigable channels by competent authority, and in making such improvements of channels, the material dredged shall not be deposited upon any ground in use in accordance with the laws of such State for the cultivation of oysters, except in compliance with said laws: <i>And provided further</i>, That any expense necessary in executing this section may be paid from funds available for the improvement of the harbor or waterway, for which regulations may be prescribed, and in case no such funds are available the said expense may be paid from appropriations made by Congress for examinations, surveys, and contingencies of rivers and harbors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1905, ch. 1482, § 4</ref>, <ref>33 Stat. 1147</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 419a.</num>
<heading> Management practices to extend capacity and useful life of dredged material disposal areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall utilize and encourage the utilization of such management practices as he determines appropriate to extend the capacity and useful life of dredged material disposal areas such that the need for new dredged material disposal areas is kept to a minimum. Management practices authorized by this section shall include, but not be limited to, the construction of dikes, consolidation and dewatering of dredged material, and construction of drainage and outflow facilities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 148</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2931</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 420.</num>
<heading> Piers and cribs on Mississippi and St. Croix Rivers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The owners of sawmills on the Mississippi River and the Saint Croix River in the States of Wisconsin and Minnesota are authorized and empowered under the direction of the Secretary of the Army, to construct piers or cribs in front of their mill property on the banks of the river, for the protection of their mills and rafts against damage by floods and ice: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the piers or cribs so constructed shall not interfere with or obstruct the navigation of the river. And in case any pier or crib constructed under authority of this section shall at any time, and for any cause, be found to obstruct the navigation of the river, the Government expressly reserves the right to remove or direct the removal of it, at the cost and expense of the owners thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 5254; <ref>May 1, 1882, ch. 112</ref>, <ref>22 Stat. 52</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 421.</num>
<heading> Deposit of refuse, etc., in Lake Michigan near Chicago</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be lawful to throw, discharge, dump, or deposit, or cause, suffer, or procure, to be thrown, discharged, dumped, or deposited, any refuse matter of any kind or description whatever other than that flowing from streets and sewers and passing therefrom in a liquid state into Lake Michigan, at any point opposite or in front of the county of Cook, in the State of Illinois, or the county of Lake in the State of Indiana, within eight miles from the shore of said lake, unless said material shall be placed inside of a breakwater so arranged as not to permit the escape of such refuse material into the body of the lake and cause contamination thereof; and no officer of the Government shall dump or cause or authorize to be dumped any material contrary to the provisions of this section: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the provisions of this section shall not apply to work in connection with the construction, repair, and protection of breakwaters and other structures built in aid of navigation, or for the purpose of obtaining water supply. Any person violating any provision of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be fined for each offense not exceeding $1,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 23, 1910, ch. 359</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 422.</num>
<heading> Modification and extension of harbor lines at Chicago</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized, in his discretion, to modify and extend harbor lines in front of the city of Chicago in such manner as to permit park extension work which may be desired by the municipal authorities, including the changing and widening of the southern entrance to the Chicago Harbor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 26, 1912, ch. 408, § 5</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 626</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 423.</num>
<heading> Establishment of pierhead and bulkhead lines in Wilmington Harbor, California</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized to fix and establish pierhead and bulkhead lines, either or both, in the inner harbor of San Pedro, otherwise known as Wilmington Harbor, California, beyond which no piers, wharves, bulkheads, or other works shall be extended or deposits made except under such regulations as shall be prescribed from time to time by the Secretary of the Army.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<date date="1908-03-26">Mar. 26, 1908</date>, No. 14, <ref>35 Stat. 569</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 424.</num>
<heading> Establishment of pierhead or bulkhead lines in Newport Harbor, California</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized and directed to fix and establish pierhead and bulkhead lines, either or both, at Newport Harbor, California, in accordance with plan dated United States Engineer Office, Los Angeles, California, <date date="1913-03-25">March 25, 1913</date>, and entitled “Newport Bay, California”, showing harbor lines, beyond which no piers, wharfs, bulkheads, or other works shall be extended or deposit made, except under such regulations as shall be prescribed from time to time by the Secretary of the Army.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 27, 1916, ch. 260, § 3</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 424a.</num>
<heading> Modification of harbor lines in Newport Harbor, California</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized to modify from time to time, the harbor lines at Newport Harbor, California, established in pursuance of <ref>section 424 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That in his opinion such modification will not injuriously affect the interests of navigation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 467, § 10</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1197</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 425.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426.</num>
<heading> Investigations concerning erosion of shores of coastal and lake waters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief of Engineers of the United States Army, under the direction of the Secretary of the Army, is authorized and directed to cause investigations and studies to be made in cooperation with the appropriate agencies of the various States on the Atlantic, Pacific, and gulf coasts and on the Great Lakes, and of the States of Alaska and Hawaii, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the possessions of the United States, with a view to devising effective means of preventing erosion of the shores of coastal and lake waters by waves and currents; and any expenses incident and necessary thereto may be paid from funds appropriated for General Investigations, Civil Functions, Department of the Army: <i>Provided</i>, That the Department of the Army may release to the appropriate cooperating agencies information obtained by these investigations and studies prior to the formal transmission of reports to Congress: <i>Provided further</i>, That no money shall be expended under authority of this section in any State which does not provide for cooperation with the agents of the United States and contribute to the project such funds or services as the Secretary of the Army may deem appropriate and require; that there shall be organized under the Chief of Engineers, United States Army, a Board of seven members, of whom four shall be officers of the Corps of Engineers and three shall be civilian engineers selected by the Chief of Engineers with regard to their special fitness in the field of beach erosion and shore protection. The Board will furnish such technical assistance as may be directed by the Chief of Engineers in the conduct of such studies as may be undertaken and will review the reports of the investigations made. In the consideration of such studies as may be referred to the Board by the Chief of Engineers, the Board shall, when it considers it necessary and with the sanction of the Chief of Engineers, make, as a board or through its members, personal examination of localities under investigation: <i>Provided further</i>, That the civilian members of the Board may be paid at rates not to exceed $100 a day for each day of attendance at Board meetings, not to exceed thirty days per annum, in addition to the traveling and other necessary expenses connected with their duties on the Board in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1930, ch. 847, § 2</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 945</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–645, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426–1.</num>
<heading> Coastal Engineering Research Center; establishment; powers and functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be established under the Chief of Engineers, United States Army, a Coastal Engineering Research Center which, except as hereinafter provided in <ref>section 426–3 of this title</ref>, shall be vested with all the functions of the Beach Erosion Board, including the authority to make general investigations as provided in <ref>section 426a of this title</ref>, and such additional functions as the Chief of Engineers may assign.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–172, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426–2.</num>
<heading> Board on Coastal Engineering Research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The functions of the Coastal Engineering Research Center established by <ref>section 426–1 of this title</ref>, shall be conducted with the guidance and advice of a Board on Coastal Engineering Research, constituted by the Chief of Engineers in the same manner as the present Beach Erosion Board.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–172, § 2</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 305</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426–3.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions of Beach Erosion Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All functions of the Beach Erosion Board pertaining to review of reports of investigations made concerning erosion of the shores of coastal and lake waters, and the protection of such shores, are hereby transferred to the Board established by <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, referred to as the Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–172, § 3</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 305</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426a.</num>
<heading> Additional investigations concerning erosion of shores of coastal and lake waters; payment of costs; “shores” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to participating in cooperative investigations and studies with agencies of the various States as authorized in <ref>section 426 of this title</ref>, it shall be the duty of the Chief of Engineers, through the Coastal Engineering Research Center, to make general investigations with a view to preventing erosion of the shores of the United States by waves and currents and determining the most suitable methods for the protection, restoration, and development of beaches; and to publish from time to time such useful data and information concerning the erosion and protection of beaches and shore lines as the Center may deem to be of value to the people of the United States. The cost of the general investigations authorized by sections 426a to 426d of this title shall be borne wholly by the United States. As used in said sections, the word “shores” includes the shore lines of the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans, the Gulf of Mexico, the Great Lakes, Lake Champlain, and estuaries and bays directly connected therewith.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 31, 1945, ch. 334, § 1</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–172, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426b.</num>
<heading> Applicability of existing laws; projects referred to Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All provisions of existing law relating to examinations and surveys and to works of improvement of rivers and harbors shall apply, insofar as practicable, to examinations and surveys and to works of improvement relating to shore protection; except that all projects having to do with shore protection shall be referred for consideration and recommendation to the Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 31, 1945, ch. 334, § 2</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–172, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426c.</num>
<heading> Report by Coastal Engineering Research Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Coastal Engineering Research Center, in making its report on any cooperative investigation and studies under the provisions of <ref>section 426 of this title</ref>, relating to shore protection work shall, in addition to any other matters upon which it may be required to report, state its opinion as to (a) the advisability of adopting the project; (b) what public interest, if any, is involved in the proposed improvement; and (c) what share of the expense, if any, should be borne by the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 31, 1945, ch. 334, § 3</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–172, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426d.</num>
<heading> Payment of expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any expenses incident and necessary in the undertaking of the general investigations authorized by sections 426a to 426d of this title may be paid from funds appropriated prior to or after <date date="1945-07-31">July 31, 1945</date>, for examinations, surveys, and contingencies for rivers and harbors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 31, 1945, ch. 334, § 4</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426e.</num>
<heading> Federal aid in protection of shores</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With the purpose of preventing damage to the shores and beaches of the United States, its Territories and possessions and promoting and encouraging the healthful recreation of the people, it is declared to be the policy of the United States, subject to sections 426e to 426h–1 of this title, to promote shore protection projects and related research that encourage the protection, restoration, and enhancement of sandy beaches, including beach restoration and periodic beach nourishment, on a comprehensive and coordinated basis by the Federal Government, States, localities, and private enterprises. In carrying out this policy, preference shall be given to areas in which there has been a Federal investment of funds and areas with respect to which the need for prevention or mitigation of damage to shores and beaches is attributable to Federal navigation projects or other Federal activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal contribution; maximum amount; exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal contribution in the case of any project referred to in subsection (a) shall not exceed one-half of the cost of the project, and the remainder shall be paid by the State, municipality, or other political subdivision in which the project is located, except that (1) the costs allocated to the restoration and protection of Federal property shall be borne fully by the Federal Government, (2) Federal participation in the cost of a project for restoration and protection of State, county, and other publicly owned shore parks and conservation areas may be, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers, not more than 70 per centum of the total cost exclusive of land costs, when such areas: Include a zone which excludes permanent human habitation; include but are not limited to recreational beaches; satisfy adequate criteria for conservation and development of the natural resources of the environment; extend landward a sufficient distance to include, where appropriate, protective dunes, bluffs, or other natural features which serve to protect the uplands from damage; and provide essentially full park facilities for appropriate public use, all of which shall meet with the approval of the Chief of Engineers, and (3) Federal participation in the cost of a project providing hurricane protection may be, in the discretion of the Secretary <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> not more than 70 per centum of the total cost exclusive of land costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic beach nourishment; “construction” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When in the opinion of the Chief of Engineers the most suitable and economical remedial measures would be provided by periodic beach nourishment, the term “construction” may be construed for the purposes of sections 426e to 426h–1 of this title to include the deposit of sand fill at suitable intervals of time to furnish sand supply to project shores for a length of time specified by the Chief of Engineers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Shores other than public</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Shores other than public will be eligible for Federal assistance if there is benefit such as that arising from public use or from the protection of nearby public property or if the benefits to those shores are incidental to the project, and the Federal contribution to the project shall be adjusted in accordance with the degree of such benefits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No Federal contributions shall be made with respect to a project under sections 426e to 426h–1 of this title unless the plan therefor shall have been specifically adopted and authorized by Congress after investigation and study by the Coastal Engineering Research Center under the provisions of <ref>section 426 of this title</ref> as amended and supplemented, or, in the case of a small project under section 426g or 426h <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">2</ref> of this title, unless the plan therefor has been approved by the Chief of Engineers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Studies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> recommend to Congress studies concerning shore protection projects that meet the criteria established under sections 426e to 426h–1 of this title (including subparagraph (B)(iii)) and other applicable law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> conduct such studies as Congress requires under applicable laws; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> report the results of the studies to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations for shore protection projects</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall recommend to Congress the authorization or reauthorization of shore protection projects based on the studies conducted under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In making recommendations, the Secretary shall consider the economic and ecological benefits of the shore protection project.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In conducting studies and making recommendations for a shore protection project under this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determine whether there is any other project being carried out by the Secretary or the head of another Federal agency that may be complementary to the shore protection project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if there is such a complementary project, describe the efforts that will be made to coordinate the projects.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Shore protection projects</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall construct, or cause to be constructed, any shore protection project authorized by Congress, or separable element of such a project, for which funds have been appropriated by Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">After authorization by Congress, and before commencement of construction, of a shore protection project or separable element, the Secretary shall enter into a written agreement with a non-Federal interest with respect to the project or separable element.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The agreement shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> specify the life of the project; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ensure that the Federal Government and the non-Federal interest will cooperate in carrying out the project or separable element.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In constructing a shore protection project or separable element under this paragraph, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, coordinate the project or element with any complementary project identified under paragraph (2)(C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 960, § 1</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1056</ref>; <ref>July 28, 1956, ch. 768</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–874, title I, § 103(a)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–172, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–611, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 227(a)</ref>, (b), (e)(2)(A), (B), <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3698</ref>, 3703.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426e–1.</num>
<heading> Shore protection projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with the Act of <date date="1930-07-03">July 3, 1930</date> (<ref>33 U.S.C. 426</ref>) of this title, and notwithstanding administrative actions, it is the policy of the United States to promote beach nourishment for the purposes of flood damage reduction and hurricane and storm damage reduction and related research that encourage the protection, restoration, and enhancement of sandy beaches, including beach restoration and periodic beach renourishment for a period of 50 years, on a comprehensive and coordinated basis by the Federal Government, States, localities, and private enterprises.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preference</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the policy under subsection (a), preference shall be given to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> areas in which there has been a Federal investment of funds for the purposes described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> areas with respect to which the need for prevention or mitigation of damage to shores and beaches is attributable to Federal navigation projects or other Federal activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall apply the policy under subsection (a) to each shore protection and beach renourishment project (including shore protection and beach renourishment projects constructed before <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2018</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426e–2.</num>
<heading> Clarification of munition disposal authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may, at full Federal expense, implement any response action the Secretary determines to be necessary at a site where—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary has carried out a project under civil works authority of the Secretary that includes placing sand on a beach; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as a result of the project described in paragraph (1), military munitions that were originally released as a result of Department of Defense activities are deposited on the beach, posing a threat to human health or the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response action funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A response action described in subsection (a) shall be reimbursed from amounts made available to the agency within the Department of Defense responsible for the original release of the munitions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1027</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1230</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1154</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1663</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426e–3.</num>
<heading> Coastal storm damage reduction contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For any project for coastal storm damage reduction, the Secretary may seek input from a non-Federal interest for a project that may be affected by the timing of the coastal storm damage reduction activities under the project, in order to minimize, to the maximum extent practicable, any negative effects resulting from the timing of those activities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title I, § 140</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2652</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426f.</num>
<heading> Reimbursements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to reimburse non-Federal interests for work done by them, after initiation of the survey studies which form the basis for the project or separable element of the project, on authorized projects or separable elements which individually do not exceed $1,000,000 in total cost: <i>Provided</i>, That the work which may have been done on the projects or separable elements is approved by the Chief of Engineers as being in accordance with the authorized projects or separable elements: <i>Provided further</i>, That such reimbursement shall be subject to appropriations applicable thereto or funds available therefor and shall not take precedence over other pending projects or separable elements of higher priority for improvements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After authorization of reimbursement by the Secretary under this section, and before commencement of construction, of a shore protection project, the Secretary shall enter into a written agreement with the non-Federal interest with respect to the project or separable element.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The agreement shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specify the life of the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that the Federal Government and the non-Federal interest will cooperate in carrying out the project or separable element.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 960, § 2</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1056</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>July 28, 1956, ch. 768</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 703</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–874, title I, § 103(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 227(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426g.</num>
<heading> Storm and hurricane restoration and impact minimization program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of small shore and beach restoration and protection projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may carry out a program for the construction of small shore and beach restoration and protection projects not specifically authorized by Congress that otherwise comply with <ref>section 426e of this title</ref> if the Secretary determines that such construction is advisable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The local cooperation requirement of <ref>section 426e of this title</ref> shall apply to a project under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Completeness</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A project under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be complete; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> shall not commit the United States to any additional improvement to ensure the successful operation of the project; except for participation in periodic beach nourishment in accordance with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content><ref>section 426e of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the procedure for projects authorized after submission of a survey report.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National shoreline erosion control development and demonstration program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct under the program authorized by subsection (a) a national shoreline erosion control development and demonstration program (referred to in this section as the “demonstration program”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The demonstration program shall include provisions for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> projects consisting of planning, design, construction, and monitoring of prototype engineered and native and naturalized vegetative shoreline erosion control devices and methods;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> monitoring of the applicable prototypes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> detailed engineering and environmental reports on the results of each project carried out under the demonstraton <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> technology transfers, as appropriate, to private property owners, State and local entities, nonprofit educational institutions, and nongovernmental organizations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of feasibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A project under the demonstration program shall not be carried out until the Secretary determines that the project is feasible.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emphasis</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A project under the demonstration program shall emphasize, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the development and demonstration of innovative technologies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> efficient designs to prevent erosion at a shoreline site, taking into account the lifecycle cost of the design, including cleanup, maintenance, and amortization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> new and enhanced shore protection project design and project formulation tools the purposes of which are to improve the physical performance, and lower the lifecycle costs, of the projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> natural designs, including the use of native and naturalized vegetation or temporary structures that minimize permanent structural alterations to the shoreline;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the avoidance of negative impacts to adjacent shorefront communities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> in areas with substantial residential or commercial interests located adjacent to the shoreline, designs that do not impair the aesthetic appeal of the interests;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the potential for long-term protection afforded by the technology; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<chapeau> recommendations developed from evaluations of the program established under the Shoreline Erosion Control Demonstration Act of 1974 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1962–5</ref> note),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">2</ref> including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> adequate consideration of the subgrade;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> proper filtration;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> durable components;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> adequate connection between units; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> consideration of additional relevant information.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sites</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Each project under the demonstration program may be carried out at—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a privately owned site with substantial public access; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a publicly owned site on open coast or in tidal waters.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Secretary shall develop criteria for the selection of sites for projects under the demonstration program, including criteria based on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a variety of geographic and climatic conditions;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the size of the population that is dependent on the beaches for recreation or the protection of private property or public infrastructure;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the rate of erosion;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> significant natural resources or habitats and environmentally sensitive areas; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> significant threatened historic structures or landmarks.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall carry out the demonstration program in consultation with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, particularly with respect to native and naturalized vegetative means of preventing and controlling shoreline erosion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Federal, State, and local agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> private organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Coastal Engineering Research Center established by <ref>section 426–1 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> applicable university research facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Completion of demonstration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After carrying out the initial construction and evaluation of the performance and cost of a project under the demonstration program, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amend, at the request of a non-Federal interest of the project, the partnership agreement for a federally authorized shore protection project in existence on the date on which initial construction of the project under the demonstration program is complete to incorporate the project constructed under the demonstration program as a feature of the shore protection project, with the future cost sharing of the project constructed under the demonstration program to be determined by the project purposes of the shore protection project; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transfer all interest in and responsibility for the completed project constructed under the demonstration program to a non-Federal interest or another Federal agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may enter into a partnership agreement with the non-Federal interest or a cooperative agreement with the head of another Federal agency under the demonstration program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to share the costs of construction, operation, maintenance, and monitoring of a project under the demonstration program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to share the costs of removing the project, or element of the project if the Secretary determines that the project or element of the project is detrimental to public or private property, public infrastructure, or public safety; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to specify ownership of the completed project if the Secretary determines that the completed project will not be part of a Corps of Engineers project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>, and every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the activities carried out and accomplishments made under the demonstration program since the previous report under this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any recommendations of the Secretary relating to the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may expend, from any appropriations made available to the Secretary for the purpose of carrying out civil works, not more than $62,500,000 during any fiscal year to pay the Federal share of the costs of construction of small shore and beach restoration and protection projects or small projects under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The total amount expended for a project under this section shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be sufficient to pay the cost of Federal participation in the project (including periodic nourishment as provided for under <ref>section 426e of this title</ref>), as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be not more than $15,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 960, § 3</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1056</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>July 28, 1956, ch. 768</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 703</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–874, title I, § 103(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–298, title III, § 310(b)</ref>, <date date="1965-10-27">Oct. 27, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–611, title I, § 112(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 915(e)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4191</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 227(e)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3703</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–53, title II, § 226</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2038(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1097</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1167</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1157(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3793</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1107(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426g–1.</num>
<heading> State and regional plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> cooperate with any State in the preparation of a comprehensive State or regional plan for the conservation of coastal resources located within the boundaries of the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage State participation in the implementation of the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> submit to Congress reports and recommendations with respect to appropriate Federal participation in carrying out the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 960, § 4</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 227(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426h.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2038(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1100</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426h–1.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In sections 426e and 426f to 426h–1 of this title, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Erosion control program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “erosion control program” means the national shoreline erosion control development and demonstration program established under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Army.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separable element</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “separable element” has the meaning provided by <ref>section 2213(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Shore</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “shore” includes each shoreline of the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans, the Gulf of Mexico, the Great Lakes, and lakes, estuaries, and bays directly connected therewith.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Shore protection project</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “shore protection project” includes a project for beach nourishment, including the replacement of sand.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 960, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 227(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426i.</num>
<heading> Shore damage prevention or mitigation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized to investigate, study, plan, and implement structural and nonstructural measures for the prevention or mitigation of shore damages attributable to Federal navigation works and shore damage attributable to the Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway and the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway, if a non-Federal public body agrees to operate and maintain such measures, and, in the case of interests in real property acquired in conjunction with nonstructural measures, to operate and maintain the property for public purposes in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The costs of implementing measures, including a study, shall be cost-shared in the same proportion as the cost-sharing provisions applicable to construction of the project causing the shore damage.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for specific authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No such project shall be initiated without specific authorization by Congress if the Federal first cost exceeds $15,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate the implementation of the measures under this section with other Federal and non-Federal shore protection projects in the same geographic area; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, combine mitigation projects with other shore protection projects in the same area into a comprehensive regional project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for feasibility studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning on <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, in any case in which the Secretary implements a project under this section, the Secretary shall reimburse or credit the non-Federal interest for any amounts contributed for the study evaluating the damage in excess of the non-Federal share of the costs, as determined under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–483, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1968-08-13">Aug. 13, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX</ref>, §§ 915(f), 940, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4191</ref>, 4199; <ref>Pub. L. 106–53, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1030(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1169</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1157(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3794</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1107(h)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3005</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426i–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1014(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1222</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426i–2.</num>
<heading> National coastal data bank</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of data bank</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="1999-08-17">August 17, 1999</date>, the Secretary shall establish a national coastal data bank containing data on the geophysical and climatological characteristics of the shores of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent practicable, the national coastal data bank shall include data regarding current and predicted shore positions, information on federally authorized shore protection projects, and data on the movement of sand along the shores of the United States, including impediments to such movement caused by natural and manmade features.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The national coastal data bank shall be made readily accessible to the public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–53, title II, § 215(d)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426j.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2037(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1096</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426k.</num>
<heading> Five year demonstration program to temporarily increase diversion of water from Lake Michigan at Chicago, Illinois</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of Secretary of the Army; purpose; amounts of increase; incremental accomplishment; effects on Illinois Waterway; responsibilities for development, implementation, and supervision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to alleviate water damage on the shoreline of Lake Michigan and others of the Great Lakes during periods of abnormally high water levels in the Great Lakes, and to improve the water quality of the Illinois Waterway, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to carry out a five-year demonstration program to temporarily increase the diversion of water from Lake Michigan at Chicago, Illinois, for the purpose of testing the practicability of increasing the average annual diversion from the present limit of three thousand two hundred cubic feet per second to ten thousand cubic feet per second. The demonstration program will increase the controllable diversion by various amounts calculated to raise the average annual diversion above three thousand two hundred cubic feet per second up to ten thousand cubic feet per second. The increase in diversion rate will be accomplished incrementally and will take into consideration the effects of such increase on the Illinois Waterway. The program will be developed by the Chief of Engineers in cooperation with the State of Illinois and the Metropolitan Sanitary District of Greater Chicago. The program will be implemented by the State of Illinois and the Metropolitan Sanitary District of Greater Chicago under the supervision of the Chief of Engineers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of monthly controllable diversion rates; average annual level of Lake Michigan and total diversion for succeeding accounting year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the demonstration program a controllable diversion rate will be established for each month calculated to establish an annual average diversion from three thousand two hundred cubic feet per second to not more than ten thousand cubic feet per second. When the level of Lake Michigan is below its average level, the total diversion for the succeeding accounting year shall not exceed three thousand two hundred cubic feet per second on an annual basis. The average level of Lake Michigan will be based upon the average monthly level for the period from 1900 to 1975.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> River stages approaching bankfull conditions on Illinois Waterway or Mississippi River or further increased diversion adversely affecting St. Lawrence Seaway water levels: limitation on diversion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When river stages approach or are predicted to approach bankfull conditions at the established flood warning stations on the Illinois Waterway or the Mississippi River, or when further increased diversion of water from Lake Michigan would adversely affect water levels necessary for navigational requirements of the Saint Lawrence Seaway in its entirety throughout the Saint Lawrence River and Great Lakes-Saint Lawrence Seaway, water shall not be diverted directly from Lake Michigan at the Wilmette, O’Brien, or Chicago River control structures other than as necessary for navigational requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional study and demonstration program: determination of effects on Great Lakes levels and Illinois Waterway water quality and susceptibility to additional flooding and investigation of other adverse or beneficial impacts; report and recommendations to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief of Engineers shall conduct a study and a demonstration program to determine the effects of the increased diversion on the levels of the Great Lakes, on the water quality of the Illinois Waterway, and on the susceptibility of the Illinois Waterway to additional flooding. The study and demonstration program will also investigate any adverse or beneficial impacts which result from this section. The Chief of Engineers, at the end of five years after <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, will submit to the Congress the results of this study and demonstration program including recommendations whether to continue this authority or to change the criteria stated in subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Controllable diversion” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, controllable diversion is defined as that diversion at Wilmette, O’Brien, and Chicago River control structures which is not attributable to leakage or which is not necessary for navigational requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 166</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2934</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426l.</num>
<heading> Protection of Lake Ontario</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan for shoreline protection and beach erosion control; report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is directed to develop a plan for shoreline protection and beach erosion control along Lake Ontario, and report on such plan to the Congress as soon as practicable. Such report shall include recommendations on measures of protection and proposals for equitable cost sharing, together with recommendations for regulating the level of Lake Ontario to assure maximum protection of the natural environment and to hold shoreline damage to a minimum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimization of damage and erosion to Lake Ontario shoreline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until the Congress receives and acts upon the report required under subsection (a) of this section, all Federal agencies having responsibilities affecting the level of Lake Ontario shall, consistent with existing authority, make every effort to discharge such responsibilities in a manner so as to minimize damage and erosion to the shoreline of Lake Ontario.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Lake Ontario Protection Act of 1976.”</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 180</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2939</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426m.</num>
<heading> Collection and removal of drift and debris from publicly maintained commercial boat harbors and adjacent land and water areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that drift and debris on or in publicly maintained commercial boat harbors and the land and water areas immediately adjacent thereto threaten navigational safety, public health, recreation, and the harborfront environment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility of Secretary of the Army for development of projects; project undertakings exempt from specific Congressional approval</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall be responsible for developing projects for the collection and removal of drift and debris from publicly maintained commercial boat harbors and from land and water areas immediately adjacent thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to undertake projects developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection without specific congressional approval when the total Federal cost for the project is less than $400,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share of costs; responsibility of non-Federal interests in future project development to recover cost or repair sources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal share of the cost of any project developed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be two-thirds of the cost of the project. The remainder of such costs shall be paid by the State, municipality, or other political subdivision in which the project is to be located, except that any costs associated with the collections and removal of drift and debris from federally owned lands shall be borne by the Federal Government. Non-Federal interests in future project development under subsection (b) of this section shall be required to recover the full cost of drift or debris removal from any identified owner of piers or other potential sources of drift or debris, or to repair such sources so that they no longer create a potential source of drift or debris.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility for providing lands, easements, and right-of-way necessary for projects; agreement to maintain projects and hold United States free from damages; regulation of project area following project completion; technical advice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any State, municipality, or other political subdivision where any project developed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section is located shall provide all lands, easements, and right-of-way necessary for the project, including suitable access and disposal areas, and shall agree to maintain such projects and hold and save the United States free from any damages which may result from the non-Federal sponsor’s performance of, or failure to perform, any of its required responsibilities of cooperation for the project. Non-Fededal <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002013">1</ref> interest shall agree to regulate any project area following project completion so that such area will not become a future source of drift and debris. The Chief of Engineers shall provide technical advice to non-Federal interests on the implementation of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “drift” includes any buoyant material that, when floating in the navigable waters of the United States, may cause damage to a commercial or recreational vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “debris” includes any abandoned or dilapidated structure or any sunken vessel or other object that can reasonably be expected to collapse or otherwise enter the navigable waters of the United States as drift within a reasonable period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 202</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2945</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426n.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance to States and local governments; cost sharing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Upon request of the Governor of a State, or the appropriate official of local government, the Secretary is authorized to provide designs, plans, and specifications, and such other technical assistance as he deems advisable to such State or local government for its use in carrying out—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> projects for removing accumulated snags and other debris, and clearing and straightening channels in navigable streams and tributaries thereof; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> projects for renovating navigable streams and tributaries thereof by means of predominantly nonstructural methods judged by the Secretary to be cost effective, for the purpose of improved drainage, water quality, and habitat diversity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The non-Federal share of the cost of any designs, plans, specifications or technical assistance provided under subsection (a) shall be 50 percent.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 942</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426o.</num>
<heading> Great Lakes material disposal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In planning and implementing any navigation project (including maintenance thereof) on the Great Lakes and adjacent waters, the Secretary shall consult and cooperate with concerned States in selecting disposal areas for dredged material which is suitable for beach nourishment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XI, § 1154</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426o–1.</num>
<heading> Great Lakes dredging levels adjustment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of Great Lake</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “Great Lake” means Lake Superior, Lake Michigan, Lake Huron (including Lake St. Clair), Lake Erie, and Lake Ontario (including the St. Lawrence River to the 45th parallel of latitude).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dredging levels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In operating and maintaining Federal channels and harbors of, and the connecting channels between, the Great Lakes, the Secretary shall conduct such dredging as is necessary to ensure minimal operation depths consistent with the original authorized depths of the channels and harbors when water levels in the Great Lakes are, or are forecast to be, below the International Great Lakes Datum of 1985.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–541, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="2000-12-11">Dec. 11, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426o–2.</num>
<heading> Great Lakes navigation and protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes navigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Using available funds, the Secretary shall expedite the operation and maintenance, including dredging, of the navigation features of the Great Lakes and Connecting Channels for the purpose of supporting commercial navigation to authorized project depths.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes pilot project</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Using available funds, the Director of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, in coordination with the Secretary, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, shall carry out a pilot project, on an emergency basis, to control and prevent further spreading of viral hemorrhagic septicemia in the Great Lakes and Connecting Channels.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes and Connecting Channels defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “Great Lakes and Connecting Channels” includes Lakes Superior, Huron, Michigan, Erie, and Ontario, all connecting waters between and among such lakes used for commercial navigation, any navigation features in such lakes or waters that are a Federal operation or maintenance responsibility, and areas of the Saint Lawrence River that are operated or maintained by the Federal Government for commercial navigation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title V, § 5014</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426p.</num>
<heading> Corps of Engineers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical and other assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide emergency assistance to prevent or reduce damage attributable to high water levels in the Great Lakes, including provision of sandbags, sheeting, and stones and other armoring devices (taking account of flooding and erosion of other property which may be caused by such activity) but not including construction of permanent structures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance to individuals and local governments with respect to measures to prevent or reduce such damage; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> compile and disseminate information on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> water levels of the Great Lakes,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> techniques for prevention or reduction of such damage, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> emergency relief available to persons who suffer economic injury attributable to high water levels in the Great Lakes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of permits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of flooding and erosion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In issuing a permit under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 403 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 1344 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">for any activity carried out with assistance under this title, the Secretary of the Army shall take account of flooding and erosion of other property which may be caused by such activity.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bank stabilization</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In issuing permits under sections 403 and 1344 of this title for a project involving dredging of any portion of the Great Lakes, the Secretary of the Army shall, if feasible, encourage for bank stabilization purposes the disposal of nonhazardous compatible sand from such project on shorelines affected by erosion.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary of the Army shall consult affected State and local governments.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–707, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4712</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 427 to 430.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 31, 1945, ch. 334, § 5</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 508</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OIL POLLUTION OF COASTAL WATERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 431 to 437.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–224, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1970-04-03">Apr. 3, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 113</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>NEW YORK HARBOR, HARBOR OF HAMPTON ROADS, AND HARBOR OF BALTIMORE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 441.</num>
<heading> Deposit of refuse prohibited; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The placing, discharging, or depositing, by any process or in any manner, of refuse, dirt, ashes, cinders, mud, sand, dredgings, sludge, acid, or any other matter of any kind, other than that flowing from streets, sewers, and passing therefrom in a liquid state, in the waters of any harbor subject to this subchapter, within the limits which shall be prescribed by the supervisor of the harbor, is strictly forbidden, and every such act is made a misdemeanor, and every person engaged in or who shall aid, abet, authorize, or instigate a violation of this section, shall, upon conviction, be punishable by fine or imprisonment, or both, such fine to be not less than $250 nor more than $2,500, and the imprisonment to be not less than thirty days nor more than one year, either or both united, as the judge before whom conviction is obtained shall decide, one-half of said fine to be paid to the person or persons giving information which shall lead to conviction of this misdemeanor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 1</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 442.</num>
<heading> Liability of officers of towing vessel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any and every master and engineer, or person or persons acting in such capacity, respectively, on board of any boat or vessel, who shall knowingly engage in towing any scow, boat, or vessel loaded with any such prohibited matter to any point or place of deposit, or discharge in the waters of any harbor subject to this subchapter, or to any point or place elsewhere than within the limits defined and permitted by the supervisor of the harbor, shall be deemed guilty of a violation of <ref>section 441 of this title</ref>, and shall, upon conviction, be punishable as provided for offenses in violation of <ref>section 441 of this title</ref>, and shall also have his license revoked or suspended for a term to be fixed by the judge before whom tried and convicted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 2</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 443.</num>
<heading> Permit for dumping; penalty for taking or towing boat or scow without permit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In all cases of receiving on board of any scows or boats such forbidden matter or substance as described in <ref>section 441 of this title</ref>, the owner or master, or person acting in such capacity on board of such scows or boats, before proceeding to take or tow the same to the place of deposit, shall apply for and obtain from the supervisor of the harbor appointed, as provided in <ref>section 451 of this title</ref>, a permit defining the precise limits within which the discharge of such scows or boats may be made; and it shall not be lawful for the owner or master, or person acting in such capacity, of any tug or towboat to tow or move any scow or boat so loaded with such forbidden matter until such permit shall have been obtained; and every person violating the foregoing provisions of this section shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 nor less than $500, and in addition thereto the master of any tug or towboat so offending shall have his license revoked or suspended for a term to be fixed by the judge before whom tried and convicted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 3</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Aug. 18, 1894, ch. 299, § 3</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>May 28, 1908, ch. 212, § 8</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 444.</num>
<heading> Dumping at other place than designated dumping grounds; penalty; person liable; excuses for deviation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any deviation from such dumping or discharging place specified in such permit shall be a misdemeanor, and the owner and master, or person acting in the capacity of master, of any scows or boats dumping or discharging such forbidden matter in any place other than that specified in such permit shall be liable to punishment therefor as provided in <ref>section 441 of this title</ref>; and the owner and master, or person acting in the capacity of master, of any tug or towboat towing such scows or boats shall be liable to equal punishment with the owner and master, or person acting in the capacity of master, of the scows or boats; and, further, every scowman or other employee on board of both scows and towboats shall be deemed to have knowledge of the place of dumping specified in such permit, and the owners and masters, or persons acting in the capacity of masters, shall be liable to punishment, as aforesaid, for any unlawful dumping, within the meaning of this Act and this subchapter, which may be caused by the negligence or ignorance of such scowman or other employee; and, further, neither defect in machinery nor avoidable accidents to scows or towboats, nor unfavorable weather, nor improper handling or moving of scows or boats of any kind whatsoever shall operate to release the owners and master and employees of scows and towboats from the penalties mentioned in <ref>section 441 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 3</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Aug. 18, 1894, ch. 299, § 3</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>May 28, 1908, ch. 212, § 8</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 445.</num>
<heading> Equipment and marking of boats or scows</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every scow or boat engaged in the transportation of dredgings, earth, sand, mud, cellar dirt, garbage, or other offensive material of any description shall have its name or number and owner’s name painted in letters and numbers at least fourteen inches long on both sides of the scow or boat; these names and numbers shall be kept distinctly legible at all times, and no scow or boat not so marked shall be used to transport or dump any such material. Each such scow or boat shall be equipped at all times with a life line or rope extending at least the length of and three feet above the deck thereof, such rope to be attached to the coaming thereof, also with a life preserver and a life buoy for each person on board thereof, also with anchor to weigh not less than two hundred and seventy-five pounds, and at least one hundred feet of cable attached thereto; a list of the names of all men employed on any such scow or boat shall be kept by the owner or master thereof and the said list shall be open to the inspection of all parties. Failure to comply with any of the foregoing provisions shall render the owner of such scow or boat liable upon conviction thereof to a penalty of not more than $500: <i>Provided</i>, That the requirements in regard to life line or rope contained in this section shall not apply to any scow or boat the deck outside the coaming or rail of which shall not exceed one foot in width: <i>And provided further</i>, That on any such scow or boat its name or number and owner’s name painted in letters and numbers, at least fourteen inches long on both ends of such scow or boat, shall be a compliance with the provisions of this section in regard to name, number, and owner’s name.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 3</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Aug. 18, 1894, ch. 299, § 3</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>May 28, 1908, ch. 212, § 8</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 427</ref>; <ref>Feb. 16, 1909, ch. 132</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 623</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 446.</num>
<heading> Inspectors; appointment, powers, and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each supervisor of a harbor is authorized and directed to appoint inspectors and deputy inspectors, and for the purposes of enforcing this subchapter and the Act of <date date="1894-08-18">August 18, 1894</date>, entitled “An Act making appropriations for the construction, repair, and preservation of certain public works on rivers and harbors, and for other purposes” (<ref>28 Stat. 338</ref>), and of detecting and bringing to punishment offenders against the same, the said supervisor of the harbor, and the inspectors and deputy inspectors so appointed by him, shall have power and authority.</p>
<p class="indent0">First. To arrest and take into custody, with or without process, any person or persons who may commit any of the acts or offenses prohibited by this subchapter, or who may violate any of the provisions of the same: <i>Provided</i>, That no person shall be arrested without process for any offense not committed in the presence of the supervisor or his inspectors or deputy inspectors, or either of them: <i>And provided further</i>, That whenever any such arrest is made the person or persons so arrested shall be brought forthwith before a magistrate judge, judge, or court of the United States for examination of the offenses alleged against him; and such magistrate judge, judge, or court shall proceed in respect thereto as authorized by law in case of crimes against the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">Second. To go on board of any scow or towboat engaged in unlawful dumping of prohibited material, or in moving the same without a permit, as required in sections 443 to 448 of this title, or otherwise violating sections 443 to 448 of this title, and to seize and hold said boats until they are discharged by action of the magistrate judge, judge, or court of the United States before whom the offending persons are brought.</p>
<p class="indent0">Third. To arrest and take into custody any witness or witnesses to such unlawful dumping of prohibited material, the said witnesses to be released under proper bonds.</p>
<p class="indent0">Fourth. To go on board of any towboat having in tow scows or boats loaded with such prohibited material, and accompany the same to the place of dumping, whenever such action appears to be necessary to secure compliance with the requirements of this subchapter and of the Act aforesaid.</p>
<p class="indent0">Fifth. To enter gas and oil works and all other manufacturing works for the purpose of discovering the disposition made of sludge, acid, or other injurious material, whenever there is good reason to believe that such sludge, acid, or other injurious material is allowed to run into tidal waters of the harbor in violation of <ref>section 441 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 3</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Aug. 18, 1894, ch. 299, § 3</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>May 28, 1908, ch. 212, § 8</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 447.</num>
<heading> Bribery of inspector; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person who, directly or indirectly, gives any sum of money or other bribe, present, or reward, or makes any offer of the same to any inspector, deputy inspector, or other employee of the office of any supervisor of a harbor with intent to influence such inspector, deputy inspector, or other employee to permit or overlook any violation of the provisions of this subchapter, shall, on conviction thereof, be fined not less than $500 nor more than $1,000, and be imprisoned not less than six months nor more than one year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 3</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Aug. 18, 1894, ch. 299, § 3</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>May 28, 1908, ch. 212, § 8</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 428</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 448.</num>
<heading> Return of permit; penalty for failure to return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every permit issued in accordance with the provisions of sections 443 to 448 of this title, which may not be taken up by an inspector or deputy inspector, shall be returned within four days after issuance to the office of the supervisor of the harbor; such permit shall bear an indorsement by the master of the towboat, or the person acting in such capacity, stating whether the permit has been used, and, if so, the time and place of dumping. Any person violating the provisions of this section shall be liable to a fine of not more than $500 nor less than $100.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 3</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Aug. 18, 1894, ch. 299, § 3</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>May 28, 1908, ch. 212, § 8</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 449.</num>
<heading> Disposition of dredged matter; persons liable; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All mud, dirt, sand, dredgings, and material of every kind and description whatever taken, dredged, or excavated from any slip, basin, or shoal in any harbor subject to this subchapter, and placed on any boat, scow, or vessel for the purpose of being taken or towed upon the waters of that harbor to a place of deposit, shall be deposited and discharged at such place or within such limits as shall be defined and specified by the supervisor of the harbor, as in sections 443 to 448 of this title prescribed, and not otherwise. Every person, firm, or corporation being the owner of any slip, basin, or shoal, from which such mud, dirt, sand, dredgings, and material shall be taken, dredged, or excavated, and every person, firm, or corporation in any manner engaged in the work of dredging or excavating any such slip, basin, or shoal, or of removing such mud, dirt, sand, or dredgings therefrom, shall severally be responsible for the deposit and discharge of all such mud, dirt, sand, or dredgings at such place or within such limits so defined and prescribed by said supervisor of the harbor; and for every violation of the provisions of this section the person offending shall be guilty of an offense, and shall be punished by a fine equal to the sum of $5 for every cubic yard of mud, dirt, sand, dredgings, or material not deposited or discharged as required by this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 4</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 210</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(5)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 450.</num>
<heading> Liability of vessel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any boat or vessel used or employed in violating any provision of this subchapter, shall be liable to the pecuniary penalties imposed thereby, and may be proceeded against, summarily by way of libel in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 4</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 451.</num>
<heading> Supervisor of harbor; appointment and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer of the Corps of Engineers shall, for each harbor subject to this subchapter, be designated by the Secretary of the Army as supervisor of the harbor, to act under the direction of the Chief of Engineers in enforcing the provisions of this subchapter, and in detecting offenders against the same. Each such officer shall have personal charge and supervision under the Chief of Engineers, and shall direct the patrol boats and other means to detect and bring to punishment offenders against the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 5</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 210</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>June 29, 1949, ch. 278</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 300</ref>; <ref>July 12, 1952, ch. 707</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(6)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 451a.</num>
<heading> Harbors subject to this subchapter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following harbors shall be subject to this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The harbor of New York.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The harbor of Hampton Roads.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The harbor of Baltimore.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 6</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 210</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(7)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 451b.</num>
<heading> Waters included within subchapter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “harbor of New York” means the tidal waters of the harbor of New York, its adjacent and tributary waters, and those of Long Island Sound.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “harbor of Hampton Roads” means the tidal waters of the harbors of Norfolk, Portsmouth, Newport News, Hampton Roads, and their adjacent and tributary waters, so much of the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries as lies within the State of Virginia, and so much of the Atlantic Ocean and its tributaries as lies within the jurisdiction of the United States within or to the east of the State of Virginia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “harbor of Baltimore” means the tidal waters of the harbor of Baltimore and its adjacent and tributary waters, and so much of Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries as lies within the State of Maryland.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1888, ch. 496, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 85–802, § 1(8)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 452.</num>
<heading> Taking shellfish or otherwise interfering with navigation in New York Harbor channels; penalty; arrest and procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person or persons to engage in fishing or dredging for shellfish in any of the channels leading to and from the harbor of New York, or to interfere in any way with the safe navigation of those channels by ocean steamships and ships of deep draft.</p>
<p class="indent0">Any person or persons violating the foregoing provisions of this section shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by fine or imprisonment, or both, such fine to be not more than $250 nor less than $50, and the imprisonment to be not more than six months nor less than thirty days, either or both united, as the judge before whom conviction is obtained shall decide.</p>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the United States supervisor of the harbor to enforce this section, and the deputy inspectors of the said supervisor shall have authority to arrest and take into custody, with or without process, any person or persons, who may commit any of the acts or offenses prohibited by this section: <i>Provided</i>, That no person shall be arrested without process for any offense not committed in the presence of the supervisor or his inspector or deputy inspectors, or either of them: <i>And provided further</i>, That whenever any such arrest is made the person or persons so arrested shall be brought forthwith before a magistrate judge, judge, or court of the United States for examination of the offenses alleged against him; and such magistrate judge, judge or court shall proceed in respect thereto as authorized by law in case of crimes against the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 18, 1894, ch. 299, § 2</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 453.</num>
<heading> Regulations for navigation of Ambrose Channel; exclusion of tows and sailing vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized to make such rules and regulations for the navigation of Ambrose Channel as he may deem necessary or expedient to insure its safe use in all kinds of weather, night and day, for all vessels under control and running under their own power, and to this end he may, in his discretion, forbid its use to tows of every description and to sailing vessels.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 144, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 803</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 454.</num>
<heading> Consent of Congress to obstruction of waters by New York City</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The consent of Congress is given to the city of New York, in the State of New York, to obstruct navigation of any river or other waterway which does not form a connecting link between other navigable waters of the United States, and lying wholly within the limits of said city, by closing all or any portion of the same or by building structures in or over the same when the said city shall be lawfully authorized to do so by the State of New York: <i>Provided, however</i>, That any such obstruction shall be unlawful unless the location and plans for the proposed work or works before the commencement thereof shall have been filed with and approved by the Secretary of the Army and Chief of Engineers; and when the plans for any such obstruction have been approved by the Chief of Engineers and by the Secretary of the Army it shall not be lawful to deviate from such plans either before or after the completion of such obstruction, unless the modification of such plans has previously been submitted to and received the approval of the Chief of Engineers and the Secretary of the Army: <i>And provided further</i>, That the city of New York shall be liable for any damage that may be inflicted upon private property by reason of any of the provisions of this section.</p>
<p class="indent0">The right to alter, amend, or repeal this section is expressly reserved, and the United States shall incur no liability for the alteration, amendment, or repeal thereof to the city of New York, or to the owner or owners, or any other persons interested in any obstruction which shall have been constructed under its provisions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1910, ch. 436</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref>36 Stat. 866</ref>, 867; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>POTOMAC RIVER AND TRIBUTARIES IN DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 461 to 464.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 854, § 1636</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 1434</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>NAVIGABLE WATERS OF MARYLAND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 465.</num>
<heading> Authority to dredge; riparian rights of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 403 of this title</ref> authority is granted to dredge, without cost to the United States, in the navigable waters of the United States included within the State of Maryland and outside the limits of projects for improvement of navigation facilities approved by Congress, regardless of rights accruing to the United States as riparian owner under the laws of the State of Maryland: <i>Provided</i>, That in the opinion of the Chief of Engineers such dredging will improve facilities for navigation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1930, ch. 847, § 12</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>WATER POLLUTION CONTROL</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 466 to 466g.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 466g–1.</num>
<heading> Controversies involving construction or application of interstate compacts and pollution of waters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of actions by States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States district courts shall have original jurisdiction (concurrent with that of the Supreme Court of the United States, and concurrent with that of any other court of the United States or of any State of the United States in matters in which the Supreme Court, or any other court, has original jurisdiction) of any case or controversy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which involves the construction or application of an interstate compact which (A) in whole or in part relates to the pollution of the waters of an interstate river system or any portion thereof, and (B) expresses the consent of the States signatory to said compact to be sued in a district court in any case or controversy involving the application or construction thereof; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which involves pollution of the waters of such river system, or any portion thereof, alleged to be in violation of the provisions of said compact; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in which one or more of the States signatory to said compact is a plaintiff or plaintiffs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> which is within the judicial power of the United States as set forth in the Constitution of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount in controversy; residence, situs or citizenship; nature, character, or legal status of parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The district courts shall have original jurisdiction of a case or controversy such as is referred to in subsection (a) of this section, without any requirement, limitation, or regard as to the sum or value of the matter in controversy, or of the place of residence or situs or citizenship, or of the nature, character, or legal status, of any of the proper parties plaintiff or defendant in said case or controversy other than the signatory State or States plaintiff or plaintiffs referred to in paragraph (3) of subsection (a) of this section: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing a State to sue its own citizens in said courts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suits between States signatory to interstate compact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The original jurisdiction conferred upon the district courts by this section shall include, but not be limited to, suits between States signatory to such interstate compact: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing a State to sue another State which is not a signatory to such compact in said courts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Venue</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The venue of such case or controversy shall be as prescribed by law: <i>Provided</i>, That in addition thereto, such case or controversy may be brought in in any judicial district in which the acts of pollution complained of, or any portion thereof, occur, regardless of the place or places of residence, or situs, of any of the parties plaintiff or defendant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–830, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 957</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 466h to 466l.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 466m, 466n.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–224, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1970-04-03">Apr. 3, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 91</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>DAM INSPECTION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 467.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Board” means a National Dam Safety Review Board established under <ref>section 467f(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dam</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “dam”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means any artificial barrier that has the ability to impound water, wastewater, or any liquid-borne material, for the purpose of storage or control of water, that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> is 25 feet or more in height from—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the natural bed of the stream channel or watercourse measured at the downstream toe of the barrier; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if the barrier is not across a stream channel or watercourse, from the lowest elevation of the outside limit of the barrier;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> to the maximum water storage elevation; or</continuation>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has an impounding capacity for maximum storage elevation of 50 acre-feet or more; but</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a levee; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> a barrier described in subparagraph (A) that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is 6 feet or less in height regardless of storage capacity; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has a storage capacity at the maximum water storage elevation that is 15 acre-feet or less regardless of height;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> unless the barrier, because of the location of the barrier or another physical characteristic of the barrier, is likely to pose a significant threat to human life or property if the barrier fails (as determined by the Administrator).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible high hazard potential dam</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible high hazard potential dam” means a non-Federal dam that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is located in a State with a State dam safety program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is classified as “high hazard potential” by the State dam safety agency in the State in which the dam is located;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> has an emergency action plan that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is approved by the relevant State dam safety agency; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is in conformance with State law and pending approval by the relevant State dam safety agency;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> fails to meet minimum dam safety standards of the State in which the dam is located, as determined by the State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> poses an unacceptable risk to the public, as determined by the Administrator, in consultation with the Board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible high hazard potential dam” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a licensed hydroelectric dam under a hydropower project with an authorized installed capacity of greater than 1.5 megawatts; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a dam built under the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal agency” means a Federal agency that designs, finances, constructs, owns, operates, maintains, or regulates the construction, operation, or maintenance of a dam.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety” means the FEMA publication, numbered 93 and dated June 1979, that defines management practices for dam safety at all Federal agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FEMA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “FEMA” means the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hazard reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “hazard reduction” means the reduction in the potential consequences to life and property of dam failure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> ICODS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “ICODS” means the Interagency Committee on Dam Safety established by <ref>section 467e of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible subrecipient</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible subrecipient”, in the case of a project receiving assistance under <ref>section 467f–2 of this title</ref>, includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a governmental organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a nonprofit organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the national dam safety program established under <ref>section 467f of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rehabilitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “rehabilitation” means the repair, replacement, reconstruction, or removal of a dam that is carried out to meet applicable State dam safety and security standards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State dam safety agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State dam safety agency” means a State agency that has regulatory authority over the safety of non-Federal dams.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State dam safety program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State dam safety program” means a State dam safety program approved and assisted under <ref>section 467f(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underserved community</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “underserved community” means a community with a population of less than 50,000 that has a median household income of less than 80 percent of the statewide median household income.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means all of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3685</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–310, § 3(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2451</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title IV, § 5006(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1892</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title I, § 132(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1132(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467a.</num>
<heading> Inspection of dams</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall carry out a national program of inspection of dams for the purpose of protecting human life and property. All dams in the United States shall be inspected by the Secretary except (1) dams under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Reclamation, the Tennessee Valley Authority, or the International Boundary and Water Commission, (2) dams which have been constructed pursuant to licenses issued under the authority of the Federal Power Act [<ref>16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.], (3) dams which have been inspected within the twelve-month period immediately prior to <date date="1972-08-08">August 8, 1972</date>, by a State agency and which the Governor of such State requests be excluded from inspection, and (4) dams which the Secretary of the Army determines do not pose any threat to human life or property. The Secretary may inspect dams which have been licensed under the Federal Power Act upon request of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and dams under the jurisdiction of the International Boundary and Water Commission upon request of such Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On request of a State dam safety agency, with respect to any dam the failure of which would affect the State, the head of a Federal agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide information to the State dam safety agency on the construction, operation, maintenance, condition, or provisions for emergency operations of the dam; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> allow any official of the State dam safety agency to participate in the Federal inspection of the dam.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 3</ref>, formerly § 2, <date date="1972-08-08">Aug. 8, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–91, title IV, § 402(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 583</ref>; renumbered § 3 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(3)</ref>, (5), <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3685</ref>, 3687; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467b.</num>
<heading> Investigation reports to Governors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after inspection of a dam, the Secretary shall notify the Governor of the State in which such dam is located the results of such investigation. In any case in which any hazardous conditions are found during an inspection, upon request by the owner, the Secretary, acting through the Chief of Engineers, may perform detailed engineering studies to determine the structural integrity of the dam, subject to reimbursement of such expense by the owner of such dam. The Secretary shall immediately notify the Governor of any hazardous conditions found during an inspection. The Secretary shall provide advice to the Governor, upon request, relating to timely remedial measures necessary to mitigate or obviate any hazardous conditions found during an inspection.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 4</ref>, formerly § 3, <date date="1972-08-08">Aug. 8, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4263</ref>; renumbered § 4 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(3)</ref>, (6), <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3685</ref>, 3687.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467c.</num>
<heading> Determination of danger to human life and property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of determining whether a dam (including the waters impounded by such dam) constitutes a danger to human life or property, the Secretary shall take into consideration the possibility that the dam might be endangered by overtopping, seepage, settlement, erosion, sediment, cracking, earth movement, earthquakes, failure of bulkheads, flashboard, gates on conduits, or other conditions which exist or which might occur in any area in the vicinity of the dam.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 5</ref>, formerly § 4, <date date="1972-08-08">Aug. 8, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 507</ref>; renumbered § 5 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(3)</ref>, (7), <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3685</ref>, 3687.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467d.</num>
<heading> National inventory of dams and low-head dams</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army shall maintain and update information on the inventory of dams and low-head dams in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dams</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The inventory maintained under subsection (a) shall include any available information assessing each dam based on inspections completed by a Federal agency, a State dam safety agency, or a Tribal government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low-head dams</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The inventory maintained under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the location, ownership, description, current use, condition, height, and length of each low-head dam;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any information on public safety conditions at each low-head dam; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other relevant information concerning low-head dams.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate with Federal and State agencies, Tribal governments, and other relevant entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use data provided to the Secretary by those agencies and entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall make the inventory maintained under subsection (a) publicly available (including on a publicly available website), including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> public safety information on the dangers of low-head dams; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a directory of financial and technical assistance resources available to reduce safety hazards and fish passage barriers at low-head dams.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clarification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section provides authority to the Secretary to carry out an activity, with respect to a low-head dam, that is not explicitly authorized under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low-head dam defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “low-head dam” means a river-wide artificial barrier that generally spans a stream channel, blocking the waterway and creating a backup of water behind the barrier, with a drop off over the wall of not less than 6 inches and not more than 25 feet.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3687</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–460, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1132(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467e.</num>
<heading> Interagency Committee on Dam Safety</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established an Interagency Committee on Dam Safety—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> comprised of a representative of each of the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Labor, FEMA, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Tennessee Valley Authority, and the United States Section of the International Boundary Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> chaired by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">ICODS shall encourage the establishment and maintenance of effective Federal programs, policies, and guidelines intended to enhance dam safety for the protection of human life and property through coordination and information exchange among Federal agencies concerning implementation of the Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3687</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–310, § 2</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467f.</num>
<heading> National dam safety program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator, in consultation with ICODS and State dam safety agencies, and the Board shall establish and maintain, in accordance with this section, a coordinated national dam safety program. The Program shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be administered by FEMA to achieve the objectives set forth in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> involve, to the extent appropriate, each Federal agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each of the components described in subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the strategic plan described in subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assistance for State dam safety programs described in subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall prepare a strategic plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish goals, priorities, performance measures, and target dates toward effectively administering this subchapter in order to improve the safety of dams in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent feasible, to establish cooperation and coordination with, and assistance to, interested governmental entities in all States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The objectives of the Program are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that new and existing dams are safe through the development of technologically and economically feasible programs and procedures for national dam safety hazard reduction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage acceptable engineering policies and procedures to be used for dam site investigation, design, construction, operation and maintenance, and emergency preparedness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage the establishment and implementation of effective dam safety programs in each State based on State standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop and implement a comprehensive dam safety hazard education and public awareness initiative to assist the public in preparing for, mitigating, responding to, and recovering from dam incidents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop technical assistance materials for Federal and non-Federal dam safety programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> develop mechanisms with which to provide Federal technical assistance for dam safety to the non-Federal sector; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> develop technical assistance materials, seminars, and guidelines to improve security for dams in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Components</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Program shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Federal element and a non-Federal element; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> leadership activity, technical assistance activity, and public awareness activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal element shall incorporate the activities and practices carried out by Federal agencies under <ref>section 467e of this title</ref> to implement the Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The non-Federal element shall consist of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the activities and practices carried out by States, local governments, and the private sector to safely build, regulate, operate, and maintain dams; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Federal activities that foster State efforts to develop and implement effective programs for the safety of dams.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functional activities</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leadership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The leadership activity shall be the responsibility of FEMA and shall be exercised by chairing the Board to coordinate national efforts to improve the safety of the dams in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The technical assistance activity shall consist of the transfer of knowledge and technical information among the Federal and non-Federal elements described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public awareness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The public awareness activity shall provide for the education of the public, including State and local officials, in the hazards of dam failure, methods of reducing the adverse consequences of dam failure, and related matters.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance for State dam safety programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To encourage the establishment and maintenance of effective State programs intended to ensure dam safety, to protect human life and property, and to improve State dam safety programs, the Administrator shall provide assistance with amounts made available under section 467j <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref> of this title to assist States in establishing, maintaining, and improving dam safety programs in accordance with the criteria specified in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria and budgeting requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For a State to be eligible for assistance under this subsection, a State dam safety program must be working toward meeting the following criteria and budgeting requirement:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A State dam safety program must be authorized by State legislation to include, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the authority to review and approve plans and specifications to construct, enlarge, modify, remove, and abandon dams;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the authority to perform periodic inspections during dam construction to ensure compliance with approved plans and specifications;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a requirement that, on completion of dam construction, State approval must be given before operation of the dam;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the authority to require or perform periodic evaluations of all dams and reservoirs to determine the extent of the threat to human life and property in case of failure;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the authority to require or perform the inspection, at least once every 5 years, of all dams and reservoirs that would pose a significant threat to human life and property in case of failure to determine the continued safety of the dams and reservoirs; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a procedure for more detailed and frequent safety inspections;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a requirement that all inspections be performed under the supervision of a State-registered professional engineer with related experience in dam design and construction;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the authority to issue notices, when appropriate, to require owners of dams to perform necessary maintenance or remedial work, install and monitor instrumentation, improve security, revise operating procedures, or take other actions, including breaching dams when necessary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> regulations for carrying out the legislation of the State described in this subparagraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<chapeau> provision for necessary funds—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to ensure timely repairs or other changes to, or removal of, a dam in order to protect human life and property; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if the owner of the dam does not take action described in subclause (I), to take appropriate action as expeditiously as practicable;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> a system of emergency procedures to be used if a dam fails or if the failure of a dam is imminent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<chapeau> an identification of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> each dam the failure of which could be reasonably expected to endanger human life;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the maximum area that could be flooded if the dam failed; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> necessary public facilities that would be affected by the flooding.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budgeting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For a State to be eligible for assistance under this subsection, State appropriations must be budgeted to carry out the legislation of the State under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Work plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall enter into a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">2</ref> agreement with each State receiving assistance under paragraph (2) to develop a work plan necessary for the State dam safety program to reach a level of program performance specified in the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance may not be provided to a State under this subsection for a fiscal year unless the State enters into such agreement with the Administrator as the Administrator requires to ensure that the State will maintain the aggregate expenditures of the State from all other sources for programs to ensure dam safety for the protection of human life and property at or above a level equal to the average annual level of such expenditures for the 2 fiscal years preceding the fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of programs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For a State to be eligible for assistance under this subsection, a plan for a State dam safety program shall be submitted to the Administrator for approval.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A State dam safety program shall be deemed to be approved 120 days after the date of receipt by the Administrator unless the Administrator determines within the 120-day period that the State dam safety program fails to meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (3).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of disapproval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Administrator determines that a State dam safety program does not meet the requirements for approval, the Administrator shall immediately notify the State in writing and provide the reasons for the determination and the changes that are necessary for the plan to be approved.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of State dam safety programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Using the expertise of the Board, the Administrator shall periodically review State dam safety programs. If the Board finds that a State dam safety program has proven inadequate to reasonably protect human life and property and the Administrator concurs, the Administrator shall revoke approval of the State dam safety program, and withhold assistance under this subsection, until the State dam safety program again meets the requirements for approval.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall establish an advisory board to be known as the “National Dam Safety Review Board” to monitor the safety of dams in the United States, to monitor State implementation of this section, and to advise the Administrator on national dam safety policy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board may use the expertise of Federal agencies and enter into contracts for necessary studies to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Board shall consist of 11 voting members selected by the Administrator for expertise in dam safety, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 1 member shall represent the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 1 member shall represent the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 member shall represent the Department of the Interior;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 1 member shall represent FEMA;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> 1 member shall represent the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> 5 members shall be selected by the Administrator from among State dam safety officials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> 1 member shall be selected by the Administrator to represent the private sector.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonvoting membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator, in consultation with the Board, may invite a representative of the National Laboratories of the Department of Energy and may invite representatives from Federal or State agencies, representatives from nongovernmental organizations, or dam safety experts, as needed, to participate in meetings of the Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Board shall encourage the establishment and maintenance of effective programs, policies, and guidelines to enhance dam safety for the protection of human life and property throughout the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination and information exchange among agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Board shall encourage coordination and information exchange among Federal and State dam safety agencies that share common problems and responsibilities for dam safety, including planning, design, construction, operation, emergency action planning, inspections, maintenance, regulation or licensing, technical or financial assistance, research, and data management.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Work groups</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator may establish work groups under the Board to assist the Board in accomplishing its goals. The work groups shall consist of members of the Board and other individuals selected by the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of members</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each member of the Board who is an officer or employee of the United States shall serve without compensation in addition to compensation received for the services of the member as an officer or employee of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each member of the Board who is not an officer or employee of the United States shall serve without compensation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representatives of Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent amounts are made available in advance in appropriations Acts, each member of the Board who represents a Federal agency shall be reimbursed of appropriations for travel expenses by his or her agency, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of services for the Board.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent amounts are made available in advance in appropriations Acts, each member of the Board who represents a State agency, the member of the Board who represents the private sector, and each member of a work group created under paragraph (1) shall be reimbursed for travel expenses by FEMA, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from home or regular place of business of the member in performance of services for the Board.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3688</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–310, § 3(a)</ref>–(e)(1), (f), (g), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2450</ref>, 2451; <ref>Pub. L. 109–460, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(a)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(198)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467f–1.</num>
<heading> Lock and dam security</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Tennessee Valley Authority, and the Coast Guard, shall develop standards for the security of locks and dams, including the testing and certification of vessel exclusion barriers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Site surveys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of a lock or dam owner, the Secretary shall provide technical assistance, on a reimbursable basis, to improve lock or dam security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement with a nonprofit alliance of public and private organizations that has the mission of promoting safe waterways and seaports to carry out testing and certification activities, and to perform site surveys, under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title V, § 5024</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467f–2.</num>
<heading> Rehabilitation of high hazard potential dams</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish, within FEMA, a program to provide technical, planning, design, and construction assistance in the form of grants to States with dam safety programs for rehabilitation of eligible high hazard potential dams.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A grant awarded under this section to a State may be used by the State to award grants to eligible subrecipients for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> repair;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> removal; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other structural or nonstructural measures to rehabilitate an eligible high hazard potential dam.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A State interested in receiving a grant under this section may submit to the Administrator an application for the grant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An application submitted to the Administrator under this section shall be submitted at such time, be in such form, and contain such information as the Administrator may prescribe by regulation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Administrator may make a grant in accordance with this section for rehabilitation of eligible high hazard potential dams to a State that submits an application for the grant in accordance with the regulations prescribed by the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Administrator shall enter into a grant agreement with the State to establish the terms of the grant and the projects for which the grant is awarded, including the amount of the grant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant assurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As part of a grant agreement under subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall require that each eligible subrecipient to which the State awards a grant under this section provides an assurance from the dam owner, with respect to the dam to be rehabilitated, that the dam owner will carry out a plan for maintenance of the dam during the expected life of the dam.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A State may not award a grant to an eligible subrecipient under this section that exceeds, for any 1 dam, the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 12.5 percent of the total amount of funds made available to carry out this section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $7,500,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A grant awarded under this section to an eligible subrecipient for a project shall be approved by the relevant State dam safety agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible subrecipient requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To receive a grant under this section, an eligible subrecipient shall, with respect to the dam to be rehabilitated by the eligible subrecipient—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> demonstrate that the community in which the dam is located participates in, and complies with, all applicable Federal flood insurance programs, including demonstrating that such community is participating in the National Flood Insurance Program, and is not on probation, suspended, or withdrawn from such Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> beginning not later than 2 years after the date on which the Administrator publishes criteria for hazard mitigation plans under paragraph (3), demonstrate that the Tribal or local government with jurisdiction over the area in which the dam is located has in place a hazard mitigation plan that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> includes all dam risks; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> complies with the Disaster Mitigation Act of 2000 (<ref>Public Law 106–390</ref>; <ref>114 Stat. 1552</ref>);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for a project not including removal, obtain a commitment from the dam owner to provide operation and maintenance of the project for the expected life of the dam following completion of rehabilitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> comply with such minimum eligibility requirements as the Administrator may establish to ensure that each owner and operator of a dam under a participating State dam safety program and that receives assistance under this section—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> acts in accordance with the State dam safety program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> carries out activities relating to the public in the area around the dam in accordance with the hazard mitigation plan described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> comply with <ref>section 5196(j)(9) of title 42</ref> (as in effect on <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>) with respect to projects receiving assistance under this section in the same manner as recipients are required to comply in order to receive financial contributions from the Administrator for emergency preparedness purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hazard mitigation plan criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Administrator, in consultation with the Board, shall publish criteria for hazard mitigation plans required under paragraph (2)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Floodplain management plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As a condition of receipt of assistance under this section, an eligible subrecipient shall demonstrate that a floodplain management plan to reduce the impacts of future flood events from a controlled or uncontrolled release from the dam or management of water levels in the area impacted by the dam—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for a removal—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is in place; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> identifies areas that would be impacted by the removal of the dam and includes a communication and outreach plan for the project and the impact of the project on the affected communities; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for a project not including removal—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is in place; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> will be—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> developed not later than 2 years after the date of execution of a project agreement for assistance under this section; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> implemented not later than 2 years after the date of completion of construction of the project.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a plan for a removal, the Administrator may not impose any additional requirements or conditions other than the requirements in paragraph (1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A plan under paragraph (1)(B) shall address—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> potential measures, practices, and policies to reduce loss of life, injuries, damage to property and facilities, public expenditures, and other adverse impacts of flooding in the area protected or impacted by the dam;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> plans for flood fighting and evacuation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> public education and awareness of flood risks.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan criteria and technical support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator, in consultation with the Board, shall provide criteria, and may provide technical support, for the development and implementation of floodplain management plans prepared under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in consultation with the Board, shall develop a risk-based priority system for use in identifying eligible high hazard potential dams for which grants may be made under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), any assistance provided under this section for a project shall be subject to a non-Federal cost-sharing requirement of not less than 35 percent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In-kind contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The non-Federal share under subparagraph (A) may be provided in the form of in-kind contributions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underserved communities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a project carried out by or for the benefit of an underserved community.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The total amount of funds made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year shall be distributed as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equal distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">⅓ shall be distributed equally among the States in which the projects for which applications are submitted under subsection (c)(1) are located.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Need-based</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">⅔ shall be distributed among the States in which the projects for which applications are submitted under subsection (c)(1) are located based on the proportion that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of eligible high hazard potential dams in the State; bears to</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of eligible high hazard potential dams in all such States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">None of the funds provided in the form of a grant or otherwise made available under this section shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to rehabilitate a Federal dam;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to perform routine operation or maintenance of a dam;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to modify a dam to produce hydroelectric power;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to increase water supply storage capacity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to make any other modification to a dam that does not also improve the safety of the dam.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contractual requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), as a condition on the receipt of a grant under this section of an amount greater than $1,000,000, an eligible subrecipient that receives the grant shall require that each contract and subcontract for program management, construction management, planning studies, feasibility studies, architectural services, preliminary engineering, design, engineering, surveying, mapping, and related services entered into using funds from the grant be awarded in the same manner as a contract for architectural and engineering services is awarded under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> chapter 11 of title 40; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an equivalent qualifications-based requirement prescribed by the relevant State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No proprietary interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A contract awarded in accordance with paragraph (1) shall not be considered to confer a proprietary interest upon the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 for fiscal years 2017 and 2018;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2019;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2020; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2026.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 8A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title IV, § 5006(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1893</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title I, § 132(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1132(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467g.</num>
<heading> Research</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator, in cooperation with the Board, shall carry out a program of technical and archival research to develop and support—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improved techniques, historical experience, and equipment for rapid and effective dam construction, rehabilitation, and inspection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> devices for the continued monitoring of the safety of dams;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> development and maintenance of information resources systems needed to support managing the safety of dams; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> initiatives to guide the formulation of effective public policy and advance improvements in dam safety engineering, security, and management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall provide for State participation in research under subsection (a) and periodically advise all States and Congress of the results of the research.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3692</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–310, § 4</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2453</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467g–1.</num>
<heading> Dam safety training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of any State that has or intends to develop a State dam safety program, the Administrator shall provide training for State dam safety staff and inspectors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 10</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–310, § 5(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2453</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467g–2.</num>
<heading> Public awareness and outreach for dam safety</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator, in consultation with other Federal agencies, State and local governments, dam owners, the emergency management community, the private sector, nongovernmental organizations and associations, institutions of higher education, and any other appropriate entities shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, carry out a nationwide public awareness and outreach initiative to assist the public in preparing for, mitigating, responding to, and recovering from dam incidents.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 11</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467h.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after the end of each odd-numbered fiscal year, the Administrator shall submit a report to Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes the status of the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describes the progress achieved by Federal agencies during the 2 preceding fiscal years in implementing the Federal Guidelines for Dam Safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> describes the progress achieved in dam safety by States participating in the Program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> includes any recommendations for legislative and other action that the Administrator considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 12</ref>, formerly § 10, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3692</ref>; renumbered § 11 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–310</ref>, §§ 5(1), 6, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2453</ref>; renumbered § 12 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(a)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282</ref>, 1283.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467i.</num>
<heading> Statutory construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter and no action or failure to act under this subchapter shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> create any liability in the United States or its officers or employees for the recovery of damages caused by such action or failure to act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> relieve an owner or operator of a dam of the legal duties, obligations, or liabilities incident to the ownership or operation of the dam; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> preempt any other Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 13</ref>, formerly § 11, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3693</ref>; renumbered § 12, <ref>Pub. L. 107–310, § 5(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2453</ref>; renumbered § 13, <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467j.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National dam safety program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to FEMA to carry out sections 467e, 467f, and 467h of this title (in addition to any amounts made available for similar purposes included in any other Act and amounts made available under subsections (b) through (e)), $9,200,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), for each fiscal year, amounts made available under this subsection to carry out <ref>section 467f of this title</ref> shall be allocated among the States as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> One-third among States that qualify for assistance under <ref>section 467f(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> Two-thirds among States that qualify for assistance under <ref>section 467f(e) of this title</ref>, to each such State in proportion to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of dams in the State that are listed as State-regulated dams on the inventory of dams and low-head dams maintained under <ref>section 467d of this title</ref>; as compared to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the number of dams in all States that are listed as State-regulated dams on the inventory of dams and low-head dams maintained under <ref>section 467d of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount of allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The amount of funds allocated to a State under this paragraph for a fiscal year may not exceed the amount that is equal to 4 times the amount of funds committed by the State to implement dam safety activities for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Administrator and the Board shall determine the amount allocated to States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National inventory of dams and low-head dams</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 467d of this title</ref> $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public awareness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 467g–2 of this title</ref> $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 467g of this title</ref> $1,450,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028, to remain until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dam safety training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 467g–1 of this title</ref> $750,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to FEMA for the employment of such additional staff personnel as are necessary to carry out sections 467f through 467g–1 of this title $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts made available under this subchapter may not be used to construct or repair any Federal or non-Federal dam.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–367, § 14</ref>, formerly § 12, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3693</ref>; renumbered § 13 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–310</ref>, §§ 5(1), 7, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2453</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–460, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3401</ref>; renumbered § 14 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(a)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), (e), (f), <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1282–1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1163</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3796</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1132(d)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3023</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 467k to 467m.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3685</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467n.</num>
<heading> Recovery of dam modification costs required for safety purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> After <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>, costs incurred in the modification by the Secretary of dams and related facilities constructed or operated by the Secretary, the cause of which results from new hydrologic or seismic data or changes in state-of-the-art design or construction criteria deemed necessary for safety purposes, shall be recovered in accordance with the provisions in this subsection:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Fifteen percent of the modification costs shall be assigned to project purposes in accordance with the cost allocation in effect for the project at the time the work is initiated. Non-Federal interests shall share the costs assigned to each purpose in accord with the cost sharing in effect at the time of initial project construction: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of the Interior shall recover costs assigned to irrigation in accordance with repayment provisions of <ref>Public Law 98–404</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Repayment under this subsection, with the exception of costs assigned to irrigation, may be made, with interest, over a period of not more than thirty years from the date of completion of the work. The interest rate used shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration average market yields on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the applicable reimbursable period during the month preceding the fiscal year in which the costs are incurred, plus a premium of one-eighth of one percentage point for transaction costs. To the extent that more than one interest rate is determined pursuant to the preceding sentence, the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish an interest rate at the weighted average of the rates so determined.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section affects the authority of the Secretary to perform work pursuant to <ref>Public Law 84–99</ref>, as amended (<ref>33 U.S.C. 701n</ref>) or cost sharing for such work.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XII, § 1203</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 467o.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1132(e)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3024</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>