<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 55—</num>
<heading>SAVE OUR SEAS 2.0</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4201.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Circular economy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “circular economy” means an economy that uses a systems-focused approach and involves industrial processes and economic activities that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are restorative or regenerative by design;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enable resources used in such processes and activities to maintain their highest values for as long as possible; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> aim for the elimination of waste through the superior design of materials, products, and systems (including business models).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> EPA Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “EPA Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given the term “Indian tribe” in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>, without regard to capitalization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency Marine Debris Coordinating Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Interagency Marine Debris Coordinating Committee” means the Interagency Marine Debris Coordinating Committee established under <ref>section 1954 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Marine debris</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “marine debris” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1956 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Marine debris event</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “marine debris event” means an event or related events that affects or may imminently affect the United States involving—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> marine debris caused by a natural event, including a tsunami, flood, landslide, hurricane, or other natural source;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> distinct, nonrecurring marine debris, including derelict vessel groundings and container spills, that have immediate or long-term impacts on habitats with high ecological, economic, or human-use values; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> marine debris caused by an intentional or grossly negligent act or acts that causes substantial economic or environmental harm.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “non-Federal funds” means funds provided by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian Tribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a territory of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> one or more units of local governments or Tribal organizations (as defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a foreign government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a private for-profit entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a nonprofit organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a private individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “nonprofit organization” means an organization that is described in <ref>section 501(c) of title 26</ref> and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Post-consumer materials management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “post-consumer materials management” means the systems, operation, supervision, and long-term management of processes and equipment used for post-use material (including packaging, goods, products, and other materials), including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transport;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> safe disposal of waste that cannot be recovered, reused, recycled, repaired, or refurbished; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> systems and processes related to post-use materials that can be recovered, reused, recycled, repaired, or refurbished.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian Tribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a territory or possession of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any political subdivision of an entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Under Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Under Secretary” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COMBATING MARINE DEBRIS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Marine Debris Foundation</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4211.</num>
<heading> Establishment and purposes of Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the Marine Debris Foundation (in this subchapter referred to as the “Foundation”). The Foundation is a charitable and nonprofit organization and is not an agency or establishment of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the Foundation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to encourage, accept, and administer private gifts of property for the benefit of, or in connection with, the activities and services of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration under the Marine Debris Program established under <ref>section 1952 of this title</ref>, and other relevant programs and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to undertake and conduct such other activities as will augment efforts of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to assess, prevent, reduce, and remove marine debris and address the adverse impacts of marine debris on the economy of the United States, the marine environment, and navigation safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to participate with, and otherwise assist, State, local, and Tribal governments, foreign governments, entities, and individuals in undertaking and conducting activities to assess, prevent, reduce, and remove marine debris and address the adverse impacts of marine debris and its root causes on the economy of the United States, the marine environment (including waters in the jurisdiction of the United States, the high seas, and waters in the jurisdiction of other countries), and navigation safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> subject to an agreement with the Secretary of Commerce, administer the Genius Prize for Save Our Seas Innovation as described in title II; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002157">1</ref> and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to support other Federal actions to reduce marine debris.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1075</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4212.</num>
<heading> Board of Directors of the Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Foundation shall have a governing Board of Directors (in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”), which shall consist of the Under Secretary and 12 additional Directors appointed in accordance with subsection (b) from among individuals who are United States citizens.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation of diverse points of view</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the maximum extent practicable, the membership of the Board shall represent diverse points of view relating to the assessment, prevention, reduction, and removal of marine debris.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Not Federal employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Appointment as a Director of the Foundation shall not constitute employment by, or the holding of an office of, the United States for the purpose of any Federal law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and terms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), after consulting with the EPA Administrator, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and considering the recommendations submitted by the Board, the Under Secretary shall appoint 12 Directors who meet the criteria established by subsection (a), of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at least 4 shall be educated or experienced in the assessment, prevention, reduction, or removal of marine debris, which may include an individual with expertise in post-consumer materials management or a circular economy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least 2 shall be educated or experienced in the assessment, prevention, reduction, or removal of marine debris outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at least 2 shall be educated or experienced in ocean and coastal resource conservation science or policy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> at least 2 shall be educated or experienced in international trade or foreign policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any Director appointed after the initial appointments are made under subparagraph (B) (other than the Under Secretary), shall be appointed for a term of 6 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial appointments to new member positions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Of the Directors appointed by the Under Secretary under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall appoint, not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-12-18">December 18, 2020</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 4 Directors for a term of 6 years;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 4 Directors for a term of 4 years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 4 Directors for a term of 2 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Under Secretary shall fill a vacancy on the Board.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of appointments to fill unexpired terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An individual appointed to fill a vacancy that occurs before the expiration of the term of a Director shall be appointed for the remainder of the term.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reappointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An individual shall not serve more than 2 consecutive terms as a Director, excluding any term of less than 6 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation before removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Under Secretary may remove a Director from the Board only after consultation with the Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the EPA Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman shall be elected by the Board from its members for a 2-year term.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A majority of the current membership of the Board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall meet at the call of the Chairman at least once a year. If a Director misses 3 consecutive regularly scheduled meetings, that individual may be removed from the Board and that vacancy filled in accordance with subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Board shall serve without pay, but may be reimbursed for the actual and necessary traveling and subsistence expenses incurred by them in the performance of the duties of the Foundation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General powers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Board may complete the organization of the Foundation by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appointing officers and employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adopting a constitution and bylaws consistent with the purposes of the Foundation and the provisions of this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> undertaking of other such acts as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The following limitations apply with respect to the appointment of officers and employees of the Foundation:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Officers and employees may not be appointed until the Foundation has sufficient funds to pay them for their service. Officers and employees of the Foundation shall be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The first officer or employee appointed by the Board shall be the Secretary of the Board who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall serve, at the direction of the Board, as its chief operating officer; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be knowledgeable and experienced in matters relating to the assessment, prevention, reduction, and removal of marine debris.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1075</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4213.</num>
<heading> Rights and obligations of the Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Foundation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall have perpetual succession;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may conduct business throughout the several States, territories, and possessions of the United States and abroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall at all times maintain a designated agent authorized to accept service of process for the Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The serving of notice to, or service of process upon, the agent required under subsection (a)(3), or mailed to the business address of such agent, shall be deemed as service upon or notice to the Foundation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To carry out its purposes under <ref>section 4211 of this title</ref>, the Foundation shall have, in addition to the powers otherwise given it under this subchapter, the usual powers of a corporation acting as a trustee in the District of Columbia, including the power—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to accept, receive, solicit, hold, administer, and use any gift, devise, or bequest, either absolutely or in trust, of real or personal property or any income therefrom or other interest therein;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to acquire by purchase or exchange any real or personal property or interest therein;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to invest any funds provided to the Foundation by the Federal Government in obligations of the United States or in obligations or securities that are guaranteed or insured by the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to deposit any funds provided to the Foundation by the Federal Government into accounts that are insured by an agency or instrumentality of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to make use of any interest or investment income that accrues as a consequence of actions taken under subparagraph (C) or (D) to carry out the purposes of the Foundation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to use Federal funds to make payments under cooperative agreements to provide substantial long-term benefits for the assessment, prevention, reduction, and removal of marine debris;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> unless otherwise required by the instrument of transfer, to sell, donate, lease, invest, reinvest, retain or otherwise dispose of any property or income therefrom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> to borrow money and issue bonds, debentures, or other debt instruments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to sue and be sued, and complain and defend itself in any court of competent jurisdiction, except that the Directors of the Foundation shall not be personally liable, except for gross negligence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> to enter into contracts or other arrangements with, or provide financial assistance to, public agencies and private organizations and persons and to make such payments as may be necessary to carry out its functions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> to do any and all acts necessary and proper to carry out the purposes of the Foundation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal contributions to the fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A gift, devise, or bequest may be accepted by the Foundation without regard to whether the gift, devise, or bequest is encumbered, restricted, or subject to beneficial interests of private persons if any current or future interest in the gift, devise, or bequest is for the benefit of the Foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to Members of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation may not make a grant of Federal funds in an amount greater than $100,000 unless, by not later than 15 days before the grant is made, the Foundation provides notice of the grant to the Member of Congress for the congressional district in which the project to be funded with the grant will be carried out.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of international efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any efforts of the Foundation carried out in a foreign country, and any grants provided to an individual or entity in a foreign country, shall be made only with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, in consultation, as appropriate, with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation With NOAA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation shall consult with the Under Secretary during the planning of any restoration or remediation action using funds resulting from judgments or settlements relating to the damage to trust resources of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4214.</num>
<heading> Administrative services and support</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary may provide personnel, facilities, and other administrative services to the Foundation, including reimbursement of expenses, not to exceed the current Federal Government per diem rates, for a period of up to 5 years beginning on <date date="2020-12-18">December 18, 2020</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall require reimbursement from the Foundation for any administrative service provided under subsection (a). The Under Secretary shall deposit any reimbursement received under this subsection into the Treasury to the credit of the appropriations then current and chargeable for the cost of providing such services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4215.</num>
<heading> Volunteer status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce may accept, without regard to the civil service classification laws, rules, or regulations, the services of the Foundation, the Board, and the officers and employees of the Board, without compensation from the Department of Commerce, as volunteers in the performance of the functions authorized in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4216.</num>
<heading> Report requirements; petition of Attorney General for equitable relief</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Foundation shall, as soon as practicable after the end of each fiscal year, transmit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describing the proceedings and activities of the Foundation during that fiscal year, including a full and complete statement of its receipts, expenditures, and investments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> including a detailed statement of the recipient, amount, and purpose of each grant made by the Foundation in the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief with respect to certain Foundation acts or failure to act</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Foundation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> engages in, or threatens to engage in, any act, practice, or policy that is inconsistent with its purposes set forth in <ref>section 4211(b) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> refuses, fails, or neglects to discharge its obligations under this subchapter, or threatens to do so,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Attorney General may petition in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for such equitable relief as may be necessary or appropriate.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4217.</num>
<heading> United States release from liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States shall not be liable for any debts, defaults, acts, or omissions of the Foundation nor shall the full faith and credit of the United States extend to any obligation of the Foundation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4218.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Commerce to carry out this subchapter $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2024.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of appropriated funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (3), amounts made available under paragraph (1) shall be provided to the Foundation to match contributions (whether in currency, services, or property) made to the Foundation, or to a recipient of a grant provided by the Foundation, by private persons and State and local government agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on use for administrative expenses</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no Federal funds made available under paragraph (1) may be used by the Foundation for administrative expenses of the Foundation, including for salaries, travel and transportation expenses, and other overhead expenses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may allow the use of Federal funds made available under paragraph (1) to pay for salaries during the 18-month period beginning on <date date="2020-12-18">December 18, 2020</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authorization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the amounts made available under subsection (a), the Foundation may accept Federal funds from a Federal agency under any other Federal law for use by the Foundation to further the assessment, prevention, reduction, and removal of marine debris in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds accepted from Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal funds provided to the Foundation under paragraph (1) shall be used by the Foundation for matching, in whole or in part, contributions (whether in currency, services, or property) made to the Foundation by private persons and State and local government agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on use of grant amounts for litigation and lobbying expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts provided as a grant by the Foundation shall not be used for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any expense related to litigation consistent with Federal-wide cost principles; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any activity the purpose of which is to influence legislation pending before Congress consistent with Federal-wide cost principles.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 118</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4219.</num>
<heading> Termination of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the Foundation under this part shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the establishment of the Foundation, unless the Foundation is reauthorized by an Act of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Genius Prize for Save Our Seas Innovations</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4231.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prize competition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “prize competition” means the competition for the award of the Genius Prize for Save Our Seas Innovations established under <ref>section 4232 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4232.</num>
<heading> Genius Prize for Save Our Seas Innovations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-18">December 18, 2020</date>, the Secretary shall establish under <ref>section 3719 of title 15</ref> a prize competition—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to encourage technological innovation with the potential to reduce plastic waste, and associated and potential pollution, and thereby prevent marine debris; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to award 1 or more prizes biennially for projects that advance human understanding and innovation in removing and preventing plastic waste, in one of the categories described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Categories for projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The categories for projects are:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Advancements in materials used in packaging and other products that, if such products enter the coastal or ocean environment, will fully degrade without harming the environment, wildlife, or human health.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Innovations in production and packaging design that reduce the use of raw materials, increase recycled content, encourage reusability and recyclability, and promote a circular economy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Improvements in marine debris detection, monitoring, and cleanup technologies and processes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Improvements or improved strategies to increase solid waste collection, processing, sorting, recycling, or reuse.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> New designs or strategies to reduce overall packaging needs and promote reuse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The prize competition established under subsection (a) shall be known as the “Genius Prize for Save Our Seas Innovations”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In selecting awards for the prize competition, priority shall be given to projects that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have a strategy, submitted with the application or proposal, to move the new technology, process, design, material, or other product supported by the prize to market-scale deployment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> support the concept of a circular economy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> promote development of materials that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> can fully degrade in the ocean without harming the environment, wildlife, or human health; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are to be used in fishing gear or other maritime products that have an increased likelihood of entering the coastal or ocean environment as unintentional waste.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4233.</num>
<heading> Agreement with the Marine Debris Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may offer to enter into an agreement, which may include a grant or cooperative agreement, under which the Marine Debris Foundation established under title I <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002158">1</ref> may administer the prize competition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall comply with the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Marine Debris Foundation shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advertise the prize competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> solicit prize competition participants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> administer funds relating to the prize competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> receive Federal and non-Federal funds—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to administer the prize competition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to award a cash prize;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> carry out activities to generate contributions of non-Federal funds to offset, in whole or in part—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the administrative costs of the prize competition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the costs of a cash prize;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> in the design and award of the prize, consult, as appropriate with experts from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Federal agencies with jurisdiction over the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> State agencies with jurisdiction over the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> State, regional, or local conservation or post-consumer materials management organizations, the mission of which relates to the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> conservation groups, technology companies, research institutions, scientists (including those with expertise in marine environments) institutions of higher education, industry, or individual stakeholders with an interest in the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> experts in the area of standards development regarding the degradation, breakdown, or recycling of polymers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> other relevant experts of the Board’s choosing;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> in consultation with, and subject to final approval by, the Secretary, develop criteria for the selection of prize competition winners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> provide advice and consultation to the Secretary on the selection of judges under <ref>section 4234 of this title</ref> based on criteria developed in consultation with, and subject to the final approval of, the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> announce 1 or more annual winners of the prize competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (2), award 1 or more cash prizes biennially of not less than $100,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> protect against unauthorized use or disclosure by the Marine Debris Foundation of any trade secret or confidential business information of a prize competition participant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional cash prizes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Marine Debris Foundation may award more than 1 cash prize in a year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the initial cash prize referred to in paragraph (1)(J) and any additional cash prizes are awarded using only non-Federal funds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consisting of an amount determined by the Under Secretary after the Secretary is notified by the Marine Debris Foundation that non-Federal funds are available for an additional cash prize.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Solicitation of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Marine Debris Foundation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may request and accept Federal funds and non-Federal funds for a cash prize or administration of the prize competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may accept a contribution for a cash prize in exchange for the right to name the prize; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall not give special consideration to any Federal agency or non-Federal entity in exchange for a donation for a cash prize awarded under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4234.</num>
<heading> Judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall appoint not fewer than 3 judges who shall, except as provided in subsection (b), select the 1 or more annual winners of the prize competition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by the Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The judges appointed under subsection (a) shall not select any annual winner of the prize competition if the Secretary makes a determination that, in any fiscal year, none of the technological advancements entered into the prize competition merits an award.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4235.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the date on which a cash prize is awarded under this subchapter, the Secretary shall post on a publicly available website a report on the prize competition that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the Secretary has entered into an agreement under <ref>section 4233 of this title</ref>, a statement by the Marine Debris Foundation that describes the activities carried out by the Marine Debris Foundation relating to the duties described in <ref>section 4233 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement by 1 or more of the judges appointed under <ref>section 4234 of this title</ref> that explains the basis on which the winner of the cash prize was selected.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4236.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized under <ref>section 4218(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Commerce shall use up to $1,000,000 to carry out this part.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4237.</num>
<heading> Termination of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The prize program will terminate after 5 prize competition cycles have been completed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Pilot Projects</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4251.</num>
<heading> Incentive for fishermen to collect and dispose of plastic found at sea</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall establish a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing incentives, such as grants, to fishermen based in the United States who incidentally capture marine debris while at sea—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to track or keep the debris on board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to dispose of the debris properly on land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support for collection and removal of derelict gear</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall encourage United States efforts, such as the Fishing for Energy net disposal program, that support—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> collection and removal of derelict fishing gear and other fishing waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disposal or recycling of such gear and waste; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prevention of the loss of such gear.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title I, § 137</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ENHANCED GLOBAL ENGAGEMENT TO COMBAT MARINE DEBRIS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4261.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy on international cooperation to combat marine debris</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to partner, consult, and coordinate with foreign governments (at the national and subnational levels), civil society, international organizations, international financial institutions, subnational coastal communities, commercial and recreational fishing industry leaders, and the private sector, in a concerted effort—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to increase knowledge and raise awareness about—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the linkages between the sources of plastic waste, mismanaged waste and post-consumer materials, and marine debris; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the upstream and downstream causes and effects of plastic waste, mismanaged waste and post-consumer materials, and marine debris on marine environments, marine wildlife, human health, and economic development;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> strengthening systems for reducing the generation of plastic waste and recovering, managing, reusing, and recycling plastic waste, marine debris, and microfiber pollution in the world’s oceans, emphasizing upstream post-consumer materials management solutions—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to decrease plastic waste at its source; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to prevent leakage of plastic waste into the environment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> advancing the utilization and availability of safe and affordable reusable alternatives to disposable plastic products in commerce, to the extent practicable, and with consideration for the potential impacts of such alternatives, and other efforts to prevent marine debris;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> deployment of and access to advanced technologies to capture value from post-consumer materials and municipal solid waste streams through mechanical and other recycling systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> access to information on best practices in post-consumer materials management, options for post-consumer materials management systems financing, and options for participating in public-private partnerships; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> implementation of management measures to reduce derelict fishing gear, the loss of fishing gear, and other sources of pollution generated from marine activities and to increase proper disposal and recycling of fishing gear; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to work cooperatively with international partners—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> on establishing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> measurable targets for reducing marine debris, lost fishing gear, and plastic waste from all sources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> action plans to achieve those targets with a mechanism to provide regular reporting;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to promote consumer education, awareness, and outreach to prevent marine debris;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to reduce marine debris by improving advance planning for marine debris events and responses to such events; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to share best practices in post-consumer materials management systems to prevent the entry of plastic waste into the environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4262.</num>
<heading> Prioritization of efforts and assistance to combat marine debris and improve plastic waste management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, as appropriate, and the officials specified in subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> lead and coordinate efforts to implement the policy described in <ref>section 4261 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> develop strategies and implement programs that prioritize engagement and cooperation with foreign governments, subnational and local stakeholders, and the private sector to expedite efforts and assistance in foreign countries—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to partner with, encourage, advise and facilitate national and subnational governments on the development and execution, where practicable, of national projects, programs and initiatives to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> improve the capacity, security, and standards of operations of post-consumer materials management systems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> monitor and track how well post-consumer materials management systems are functioning nationwide, based on uniform and transparent standards developed in cooperation with municipal, industrial, and civil society stakeholders;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> identify the operational challenges of post-consumer materials management systems and develop policy and programmatic solutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> end intentional or unintentional incentives for municipalities, industries, and individuals to improperly dispose of plastic waste; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> conduct outreach campaigns to raise public awareness of the importance of proper waste disposal and the reduction of plastic waste;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to facilitate the involvement of municipalities and industries in improving solid waste reduction, collection, disposal, and reuse and recycling projects, programs, and initiatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> to partner with and provide technical assistance to investors, and national and local institutions, including private sector actors, to develop new business opportunities and solutions to specifically reduce plastic waste and expand solid waste and post-consumer materials management best practices in foreign countries by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> maximizing the number of people and businesses, in both rural and urban communities, receiving reliable solid waste and post-consumer materials management services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> improving and expanding the capacity of foreign industries to responsibly employ post-consumer materials management practices;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> improving and expanding the capacity and transparency of tracking mechanisms for marine debris to reduce the impacts on the marine environment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> eliminating incentives that undermine responsible post-consumer materials management practices and lead to improper waste disposal practices and leakage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> building the capacity of countries—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to reduce, monitor, regulate, and manage waste, post-consumer materials and plastic waste, and pollution appropriately and transparently, including imports of plastic waste from the United States and other countries;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to encourage private investment in post-consumer materials management and reduction; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> to encourage private investment, grow opportunities, and develop markets for recyclable, reusable, and repurposed plastic waste and post-consumer materials, and products with high levels of recycled plastic content, at both national and local levels; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> promoting safe and affordable reusable alternatives to disposable plastic products, to the extent practicable; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to research, identify, and facilitate opportunities to promote collection and proper disposal of damaged or derelict fishing gear.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Officials specified</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The officials specified in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States Trade Representative.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The EPA Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director of the Trade and Development Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The President and the Board of Directors of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation or the Chief Executive Officer and the Board of Directors of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Chief Executive Officer and the Board of Directors of the Millennium Challenge Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Commandant of the Coast Guard, with respect to pollution from ships.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The heads of such other agencies as the Secretary of State considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the officials specified in subsection (b) shall prioritize assistance to countries with, and regional organizations in regions with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> rapidly developing economies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> rivers and coastal areas that are the most severe sources of marine debris, as identified by the best available science.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effectiveness measurement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In prioritizing and expediting efforts and assistance under this section, the officials specified in subsection (b) shall use clear, accountable, and metric-based targets to measure the effectiveness of guarantees and assistance in achieving the policy described in <ref>section 4261 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the modification of or the imposition of limits on the portfolios of any agency or institution led by an official specified in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4263.</num>
<heading> United States leadership in international FORA</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In implementing the policy described in <ref>section 4261 of this title</ref>, the President shall direct the United States representatives to appropriate international bodies and conferences (including the United Nations Environment Programme, the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation, the Group of 7, the Group of 20, the Organization for Economic Co-Operation and Development (OECD), and the Our Ocean Conference) to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States, consistent with the broad foreign policy goals of the United States, to advocate that each such body—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> commit to significantly increasing efforts to promote investment in well-designed post-consumer materials management and plastic waste elimination and mitigation projects and services that increase access to safe post-consumer materials management and mitigation services, in partnership with the private sector and consistent with the constraints of other countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> address the post-consumer materials management needs of individuals and communities where access to municipal post-consumer materials management services is historically impractical or cost-prohibitive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> enhance coordination with the private sector—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to increase access to solid waste and post-consumer materials management services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to utilize safe and affordable alternatives to disposable plastic products, to the extent practicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to encourage and incentivize the use of recycled content; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to grow economic opportunities and develop markets for recyclable, compostable, reusable, and repurposed plastic waste materials and post-consumer materials and other efforts that support the circular economy;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> provide technical assistance to foreign regulatory authorities and governments to remove unnecessary barriers to investment in otherwise commercially-viable projects related to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> post-consumer materials management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of safe and affordable alternatives to disposable plastic products; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> beneficial reuse of solid waste, plastic waste, post-consumer materials, plastic products, and refuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> use clear, accountable, and metric-based targets to measure the effectiveness of such projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> engage international partners in an existing multilateral forum (or, if necessary, establish through an international agreement a new multilateral forum) to improve global cooperation on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> creating tangible metrics for evaluating efforts to reduce plastic waste and marine debris;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> developing and implementing best practices at the national and subnational levels of foreign countries, particularly countries with little to no solid waste or post-consumer materials management systems, facilities, or policies in place for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> collecting, disposing, recycling, and reusing plastic waste and post-consumer materials, including building capacity for improving post-consumer materials management; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> integrating alternatives to disposable plastic products, to the extent practicable;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> encouraging the development of standards and practices, and increasing recycled content percentage requirements for disposable plastic products;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> integrating tracking and monitoring systems into post-consumer materials management systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> fostering research to improve scientific understanding of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> how microfibers and microplastics may affect marine ecosystems, human health and safety, and maritime activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> changes in the amount and regional concentrations of plastic waste in the ocean, based on scientific modeling and forecasting;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the role rivers, streams, and other inland waterways play in serving as conduits for mismanaged waste traveling from land to the ocean;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> effective means to eliminate present and future leakages of plastic waste into the environment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> other related areas of research the United States representatives deem necessary;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> encouraging the World Bank and other international finance organizations to prioritize efforts to reduce plastic waste and combat marine debris;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> collaborating on technological advances in post-consumer materials management and recycled plastics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> growing economic opportunities and developing markets for recyclable, compostable, reusable, and repurposed plastic waste and post-consumer materials and other efforts that support the circular economy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> advising foreign countries, at both the national and subnational levels, on the development and execution of regulatory policies, services, including recycling and reuse of plastic, and laws pertaining to reducing the creation and the collection and safe management of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> solid waste;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> post-consumer materials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> plastic waste; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> marine debris.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1089</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4264.</num>
<heading> Enhancing international outreach and partnership of United States agencies involved in marine debris activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress recognizes the success of the marine debris program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Trash-Free Waters program of the Environmental Protection Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of efforts to build foreign partnerships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary and the EPA Administrator shall work with the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to build partnerships, as appropriate, with the governments of foreign countries and to support international efforts to combat marine debris.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1091</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4265.</num>
<heading> Consideration of marine debris in negotiating international agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In negotiating any relevant international agreement with any country or countries after <date date="2020-12-18">December 18, 2020</date>, the President shall, as appropriate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consider the impact of land-based sources of plastic waste and other solid waste from that country on the marine and aquatic environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the agreement strengthens efforts to eliminate land-based sources of plastic waste and other solid waste from that country that impact the marine and aquatic environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1091</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>IMPROVING DOMESTIC INFRASTRUCTURE TO PREVENT MARINE DEBRIS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4281.</num>
<heading> Strategy for improving post-consumer materials management and water management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-18">December 18, 2020</date>, the EPA Administrator shall, in consultation with stakeholders, develop a strategy to improve post-consumer materials management and infrastructure for the purpose of reducing plastic waste and other post-consumer materials in waterways and oceans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On development of the strategy under subsection (a), the EPA Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> distribute the strategy to States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> make the strategy publicly available, including for use by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for-profit private entities involved in post-consumer materials management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other nongovernmental entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1092</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4282.</num>
<heading> Grant programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Post-consumer materials management infrastructure grant program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The EPA Administrator may provide grants to States to implement the strategy developed under <ref>section 4281(a) of this title</ref> and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to support improvements to local post-consumer materials management, including municipal recycling programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to assist local waste management authorities in making improvements to local waste management systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), the applicant State shall submit to the EPA Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the EPA Administrator may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of applications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing application requirements, the EPA Administrator shall consider requesting that a State applicant provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a description of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the project or projects to be carried out using grant funds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how the project or projects would result in the generation of less plastic waste;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of how the funds will support disadvantaged communities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an explanation of any limitations, such as flow control measures, that restrict access to reusable or recyclable materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2023-01-01">January 1, 2023</date>, the EPA Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the activities carried out under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> estimates as to how much plastic waste was prevented from entering the oceans and other waterways as a result of activities funded pursuant to this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a recommendation on the utility of evolving the grant program into a new waste management State revolving fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drinking water infrastructure grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The EPA Administrator may provide competitive grants to units of local government, Indian Tribes, and public water systems (as defined in <ref>section 300f of title 42</ref>) to support improvements in reducing and removing plastic waste and post-consumer materials, including microplastics and microfibers, from drinking water or sources of drinking water, including planning, design, construction, technical assistance, and planning support for operational adjustments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an applicant shall submit to the EPA Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the EPA Administrator may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wastewater infrastructure grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The EPA Administrator may provide grants to municipalities (as defined in section 502 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1362</ref>)) or Indian Tribes that own and operate treatment works (as such term is defined in section 212 of such Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1292</ref>)) for the construction of improvements to reduce and remove plastic waste and post-consumer materials, including microplastics and microfibers, from wastewater.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an applicant shall submit to the EPA Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the EPA Administrator may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trash-free waters grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The EPA Administrator may provide grants to units of local government, Indian Tribes, and nonprofit organizations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to support projects to reduce the quantity of solid waste in bodies of water by reducing the quantity of waste at the source, including through anti-litter initiatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to enforce local post-consumer materials management ordinances;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to implement State or local policies relating to solid waste;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to capture post-consumer materials at stormwater inlets, at stormwater outfalls, or in bodies of water;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to provide education and outreach about post-consumer materials movement and reduction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to monitor or model flows of post-consumer materials, including monitoring or modeling a reduction in trash as a result of the implementation of best management practices for the reduction of plastic waste and other post-consumer materials in sources of drinking water.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an applicant shall submit to the EPA Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the EPA Administrator may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of Federal law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The EPA Administrator shall ensure that all laborers and mechanics employed on projects funded directly, or assisted in whole or in part, by a grant established by this section shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a character similar in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of chapter 31 of part A of subtitle II of title 40.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to the labor standards specified in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (<ref>64 Stat. 1267</ref>; 5 U.S.C. App.) and <ref>section 3145 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The requirements of section 608 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1388</ref>) shall apply to the construction of a project carried out, in whole or in part, with assistance made available under this section in the same manner as the requirements of such section apply with respect to funds made available pursuant to title VI of such Act [<ref>33 U.S.C. 1381</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A grant under this section may not be used (directly or indirectly) as a source of payment (in whole or in part) of, or security for, an obligation the interest on which is excluded from gross income under <ref>section 103 of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the program described <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002159">1</ref> subsection (a), $55,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for each of the programs described <sup>1</sup> subsections (b), (c), and (d), $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–224, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1092</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>