<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 50—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL OCEAN ACIDIFICATION RESEARCH AND MONITORING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3701.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> development coordination <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002149">1</ref> and implementation of a comprehensive interagency plan to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> monitor and conduct research on the processes and consequences of ocean acidification and coastal acidification on marine organisms and ecosystems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintain and advise an interagency research, monitoring, and public outreach program on ocean acidification and coastal acidification;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintenance of an ocean acidification program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assessment and consideration of regional and national ecosystem and socioeconomic impacts of increased ocean acidification and coastal acidification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> research adaptation strategies and mitigating the impacts of ocean and coastal acidification and related co-stressors on marine ecosystems.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12402</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10642</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coastal acidification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “coastal acidification” means the decrease in pH and changes in the water chemistry of coastal oceans, estuaries, and Great Lakes from atmospheric pollution, freshwater inputs, and excess nutrient run-off from land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ocean acidification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “ocean acidification” means the decrease in pH and changes in the water chemistry of the Earth’s oceans, coastal estuaries, marine waterways, and Great Lakes caused by carbon dioxide from the atmosphere and the breakdown of organic matter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subcommittee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Subcommittee” means the National Science and Technology Council Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12403</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10643</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3703.</num>
<heading> Interagency working group</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Subcommittee shall coordinate Federal activities on ocean and coastal acidification and establish and maintain an interagency working group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The interagency working group on ocean acidification shall be comprised of senior representatives from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Science Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the United States Geological Survey, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of State, the Department of Energy, the Department of the Navy, the National Park Service, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Smithsonian Institution, and such other Federal agencies as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The interagency working group shall be chaired by the representative from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Subcommittee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop the strategic research and monitoring plan to guide Federal research on ocean acidification required under <ref>section 3704 of this title</ref> and oversee the implementation of the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> oversee the development of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of the potential impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification on marine organisms and marine ecosystems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adaptation and mitigation strategies to conserve marine organisms and ecosystems exposed to ocean acidification and coastal acidification;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitate communication and outreach opportunities with nongovernmental organizations and members of the stakeholder community with interests in marine resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordinate the United States Federal research and monitoring program with research and monitoring programs and scientists from other nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish or designate, and contribute to as appropriate, an Ocean Acidification Information Exchange to make information on ocean acidification and coastal acidification developed through or utilized by the interagency ocean acidification program accessible through electronic means, including information which would be useful to policymakers, researchers, and other stakeholders in mitigating or adapting to the impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002150">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chair of the Subcommittee shall establish an Ocean Acidification Advisory Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Advisory Board shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> maintain a process for reviewing and making recommendations to the Subcommittee on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the biennial report specified in subsection (d)(2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the strategic research plan in subsection (d)(3);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide ongoing advice to the Subcommittee and the interagency working group on matters related to Federal activities on ocean and coastal acidification, including impacts and mitigation of ocean and coastal acidification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> advise the Subcommittee and the interagency working group on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> efforts to coordinate research and monitoring activities related to ocean acidification and coastal acidification; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the best practices for the standards developed for data archiving under <ref>section 3705(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Advisory Board shall consist of 25 members as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Two representatives of the shellfish, lobster, or crab industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> One representative of the finfish industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> One representative of seafood processors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Three representatives from academia, including both natural and social sciences.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> One representative of recreational fishing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> One representative of a relevant nongovernmental organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Six representatives from relevant State and local governments with policy or regulatory authorities related to ocean acidification and coastal acidification.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> One representative from the Alaska Ocean Acidification Network or a subsequent entity that represents the same geographical region and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> One representative from the California Current Acidification Network or a subsequent entity that represents the same geographical region and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> One representative from the Northeast Coastal Acidification Network or a subsequent entity that represents the same geographical region and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> One representative from the Southeast Coastal Acidification Network or a subsequent entity that represents the same geographical region and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> One representative from the Gulf of Mexico Coastal Acidification Network or a subsequent entity that represents the same geographical region and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> One representative from the Mid-Atlantic Coastal Acidification Network or a subsequent entity that represents the same geographical region and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> One representative from the Pacific Islands Ocean Observing System or a subsequent entity that represents the island territories and possessions of the United States in the Pacific Ocean, and the State of Hawaii and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> One representative from the Caribbean Regional Association for Coastal Ocean Observing or a subsequent entity that represents Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands and has a similar purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> One representative from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Olympic Coast Ocean Acidification Sentinel Site or a subsequent entity that represents the same geographical representation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> One representative from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall serve as an ex-officio member of the Advisory Board without a vote.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Chair of the Subcommittee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> appoint members to the Advisory Board (taking into account the geographical interests of each individual to be appointed as a member of the Advisory Board to ensure that an appropriate balance of geographical interests are represented by the members of the Advisory Board) who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> represent the interest group for which each seat is designated;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> demonstrate expertise on ocean acidification or coastal acidification and its scientific, economic, industry, cultural, and community impacts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> have a record of distinguished service with respect to ocean acidification or coastal acidification, and such impacts;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> give consideration to nominations and recommendations from the members of the interagency working group and the public for such appointments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensure that an appropriate balance of scientific, industry, State and local resource managers, and geographical interests are represented by the members of the Advisory Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each member of the Advisory Board—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be appointed for a 5-year term; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may be appointed to no more than two terms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chair of the Subcommittee shall appoint one member of the Advisory Board to serve as the Chair of the Advisory Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less than once each calendar year, the Advisory Board shall meet at such times and places as may be designated by the Chair of the Advisory Board, in consultation with the Chair of the Subcommittee and the Chair of the interagency working group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chair of the Advisory Board shall brief the Subcommittee and the interagency working group on the progress of the Advisory Board as necessary or at the request of the Subcommittee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal government engagement and coordination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Advisory Board shall maintain mechanisms for coordination, and engagement with Tribal governments.</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Nothing in subparagraph (A) may be construed as affecting any requirement to consult with Indian Tribes under Executive Order 13175 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> note; relating to consultation and coordination with Tribal governments) or any other applicable law or policy.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Advisory Committee Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act shall not apply to the Advisory Board for 10 years from <date date="2022-08-09">August 9, 2022</date>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002151">2</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prize competitions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any Federal agency with a representative serving on the interagency working group established under this section may, either individually or in cooperation with one or more agencies, carry out a program to award prizes competitively under <ref>section 3719 of title 15</ref>. An agency seeking to carry out such a program shall carry out such program in coordination with the chair of such interagency working group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any prize competition carried out under this subsection shall be for the purpose of stimulating innovation to advance our Nation’s ability to understand, research, or monitor ocean acidification or its impacts, or to develop management or adaptation options for responding to ocean and coastal acidification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Priority shall be given to establishing programs under this section that address communities, environments, or industries that are in distress due to the impacts of ocean and coastal acidification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2009-03-30">March 30, 2009</date>, the Subcommittee shall transmit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science and Technology and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes a summary of federally funded ocean acidification research and monitoring activities, including the budget for each of these activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describes the progress in developing the plan required under <ref>section 3704 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Biennial report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after the delivery of the initial report under paragraph (1) and every 2 years thereafter until 2032, the Subcommittee shall transmit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science and Technology and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and to the Office of Management and Budget, that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of federally funded ocean acidification research and monitoring activities, including the budget for each of these activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an analysis of the progress made toward achieving the goals and priorities for interagency strategic research plan developed by the Subcommittee under <ref>section 3704 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic research plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2009-03-30">March 30, 2009</date>, the Subcommittee shall transmit the strategic research plan developed under <ref>section 3704 of this title</ref> to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science and Technology and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives. A revised plan shall be submitted at least once every 5 years until 2031 thereafter.<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic vulnerability report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, and every 6 years thereafter until 2032, the Subcommittee shall transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is named the “Ocean Chemistry Coastal Community Vulnerability Assessment”;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> identifies gaps in ocean acidification monitoring by public, academic, and private assets in the network of regional coastal observing systems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> identifies geographic areas which have gaps in ocean acidification research;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> identifies United States coastal communities, including island communities, fishing communities, low-population rural communities, tribal and subsistence communities, and island communities, that may be impacted by ocean acidification;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> identifies impacts of changing ocean carbonate chemistry on the communities described in clause (iv), including impacts from changes in ocean and coastal marine resources that are not managed by the Federal Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> identifies gaps in understanding of the impacts of ocean acidification on economically or commercially important species, particularly those which support United States commercial, recreational, and tribal fisheries and aquaculture;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> identifies habitats that may be particularly vulnerable to corrosive sea water, including areas experiencing multiple stressors such as hypoxia, sedimentation, and harmful algal blooms;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> identifies areas in which existing National Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System assets, including unmanned maritime systems, may be leveraged as platforms for the deployment of new sensors or other applicable observing technologies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<chapeau> is written in collaboration with Federal agencies responsible for carrying out this chapter, including representatives of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the National Marine Fisheries Service and the Office for Coastal Management of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> regional coastal observing systems established under <ref>section 3603(c)(4) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> regional ocean acidification networks; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> sea grant programs (as defined in <ref>section 1122 of this title</ref>); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> is written in consultation with experts, including subsistence users, academia, and stakeholders familiar with the economic, social, ecological, geographic, and resource concerns of coastal communities in the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of report</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The initial report required under subparagraph (A) shall include the information described in clauses (i) through (viii) of that subparagraph on a national level.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Each report required under subparagraph (A) after the initial report—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> may describe the information described in clauses (i) through (viii) of that subparagraph on a national level; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> may consist of separate reports for each region of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the Subcommittee opts to prepare a report required under subparagraph (A) as separate regional reports under clause (ii)(II), the Subcommittee shall submit a report for each region of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration not less frequently than once during each 6-year reporting period.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph and in paragraph (5), the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring prioritization plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the date of the submission of the initial report under paragraph (4)(A), the Subcommittee shall transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that develops a plan to deploy new sensors or other applicable observing technologies such as unmanned maritime systems—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> based on such initial report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> prioritized by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the threat to coastal economies and ecosystems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> gaps in data; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> research needs; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that leverage existing platforms, where possible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12404</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–271, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10644</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3704.</num>
<heading> Strategic research plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2009-03-30">March 30, 2009</date>, and not later than every 5 years following the publication of each subsequent strategic research plan until 2035, the Subcommittee shall develop a strategic plan for Federal research and monitoring on ocean acidification and coastal acidification that will provide for an assessment of the impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification on marine organisms and ecosystems and the development of adaptation and mitigation strategies to address the socioeconomic impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification and to conserve marine organisms and ecosystems. In developing the plan, the Subcommittee shall consider and use information, reports, and studies of ocean acidification and coastal acidification that have identified research and monitoring needed to better understand ocean acidification and coastal acidification and its potential impacts, and recommendations made by the Advisory Board established in <ref>section 3703(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of the plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The plan shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for interdisciplinary research among the ocean sciences and social sciences, and coordinated research and activities to improve the understanding of ocean chemistry that will affect marine ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> establish, for the 10-year period beginning in the year the plan is submitted, the goals and priorities for Federal research and monitoring which will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advance understanding of ocean acidification and its physical, chemical, and biological impacts on marine organisms and marine ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assess the short-term and long-term socioeconomic impacts of ocean acidification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> provide information for the development of adaptation and mitigation strategies to address—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> socioeconomic impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> conservation of marine organisms and ecosystems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> assessment of the effectiveness of such adaptation and mitigation strategies; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> improve research on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ocean acidification and coastal acidification;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the interactions between and effects of ocean and coastal acidification and multiple combined stressors including changes in water chemistry, changes in sediment delivery, hypoxia, and harmful algal blooms, on ocean acidification and coastal acidification; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the effect or effects of clauses (i) and (ii) on marine resources and ecosystems;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> describe specific activities, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> efforts to determine user needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> research activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> monitoring activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> technology and methods development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> data collection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> data management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> modeling activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> assessment of ocean acidification impacts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> participation in international research efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> assessment of adaptation and mitigation strategies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> education and outreach activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identify relevant programs and activities of the Federal agencies that contribute to the interagency program directly and indirectly and ensure an appropriate balance of contribution in establishing the role of each Federal agency in implementing the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consider and utilize, as appropriate, the best available peer-reviewed scientific reports and studies conducted by Federal agencies, the National Research Council, or other entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> make recommendations for the coordination of the ocean acidification and coastal acidification research and monitoring activities within the United States with such activities of other nations and international organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> outline budget requirements for Federal ocean acidification research and monitoring and assessment activities to be conducted by each agency under the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> identify the monitoring systems and sampling programs currently employed in collecting data relevant to ocean acidification and coastal acidification and prioritize additional monitoring systems that may be needed to ensure adequate data collection and monitoring of ocean acidification and coastal acidification and their impacts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> describe specific activities designed to facilitate outreach and data and information exchange with stakeholder communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> make recommendations for research to be conducted, including in the social sciences and economics, to address the key knowledge gaps identified in the Ocean Chemistry Coastal Community Vulnerability Assessment conducted under section 3703(c)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002152">1</ref> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> describe monitoring needs necessary to support potentially affected industry members, coastal stakeholders, fishery management councils and commissions, Tribal governments, non-Federal resource managers, and scientific experts on decision-making and adaptation related to ocean acidification and coastal acidification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> describe the extent to which the Subcommittee incorporated feedback from the Advisory Board established in <ref>section 3703(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The plan shall include at a minimum the following program elements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Monitoring of ocean chemistry and biological impacts associated with ocean acidification at selected coastal and open-ocean monitoring stations, including satellite-based monitoring to characterize—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> marine ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> changes in marine productivity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> changes in ocean chemistry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Research to understand the species specific physiological responses of marine organisms to ocean acidification and coastal acidification, impacts on marine food webs of ocean acidification and coastal acidification, and to develop environmental and ecological indices that track marine ecosystem responses to ocean acidification and coastal acidification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Modeling to predict changes in the ocean carbon cycle as a function of carbon dioxide and atmosphere-induced changes in temperature, ocean circulation, biogeochemistry, ecosystem and terrestrial inputs, modeling to determine impacts on marine ecosystems, marine food webs, and individual marine organisms, and modeling that supports fisheries management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Technology development and standardization of carbonate chemistry measurements on moorings and autonomous floats.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Assessment of socioeconomic impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification and development of adaptation and mitigation strategies to conserve marine organisms and marine ecosystems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Research to understand the combined impact of changes in ocean chemistry and other stressors, including sediment delivery, hypoxia, and harmful algal blooms, on each other and on living marine resources, including aquaculture and coastal ecosystems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Applied research to identify adaptation strategies for species impacted by changes in ocean chemistry including vegetation-based systems, shell recycling, species and genetic diversity, applied technologies, aquaculture methodologies, and management recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Research to understand related and cumulative stressors and other biogeochemical processes occurring in conjunction with ocean acidification and coastal acidification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Concurrent with the submission of the plan to Congress, the Subcommittee shall publish the plan on a public website.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12405</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–271, title I, § 110(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3343</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10645</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3705.</num>
<heading> NOAA ocean acidification activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and maintain an ocean acidification program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to conduct research, monitoring, coordination, and other activities consistent with the strategic research and implementation plan developed by the Subcommittee under <ref>section 3704 of this title</ref> that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> interdisciplinary research among the ocean and atmospheric sciences, and coordinated research and activities to improve understanding of ocean acidification and coastal acidification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the establishment of a long-term monitoring program of ocean acidification and coastal acidification utilizing existing global and national ocean observing assets, including leveraging, as appropriate, the Integrated Ocean Observing System and the ocean observing assets of other Federal, State, and Tribal agencies, and adding instrumentation and sampling stations as appropriate to the aims of the research program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> prioritization of the location of monitoring instruments, assets, and projects to maximize the efficiency of resources and agency and department missions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an optimization of understanding of socioeconomic impacts and ecosystem health <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002153">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> research to identify and develop adaptation and mitigation strategies and techniques for effectively conserving marine ecosystems as they cope with increased ocean acidification and coastal acidification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> technical assistance to socioeconomically vulnerable States, local governments, Tribal governments, communities, and industries impacted by ocean and coastal acidification to support their development of ocean and coastal acidification mitigation strategies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> as an integral part of the research programs described in this chapter, educational opportunities that encourage an interdisciplinary and international approach to exploring the impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> as an integral part of the research programs described in this chapter, national public outreach activities to improve the understanding of current scientific knowledge of ocean acidification and coastal acidification and their respective impacts on marine resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> coordination of ocean acidification and coastal acidification research, monitoring, and adaptation and mitigation strategies with other appropriate international ocean science bodies such as the International Oceanographic Commission, the International Council for the Exploration of the Sea, the North Pacific Marine Science Organization, and others;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> research to improve understanding of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the impact of ocean acidification and coastal acidification; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how multiple environmental stressors may contribute to and exacerbate ocean and coastal acidification on living marine resources and coastal ecosystems; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> research to support the development of adaptation and mitigation strategies to address the socioeconomic impacts of ocean and coastal acidification on coastal communities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides grants for critical research, education, and outreach projects that explore and communicate the effects of ocean acidification and coastal acidification on ecosystems and the socioeconomic impacts of increased ocean acidification and coastal acidification that are relevant to the goals and priorities of the strategic research plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> incorporates a competitive merit-based process for awarding grants that may be conducted jointly with other participating agencies or under the National Oceanographic Partnership Program under <ref>section 8931 of title 10</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> includes an ongoing mechanism that allows industry members, coastal stakeholders, fishery management councils and commissions, non-Federal resource managers, community acidification networks, indigenous knowledge groups, and scientific experts to provide input on monitoring needs that are necessary to support on the ground management, decision making, and adaptation related to ocean acidification and its impacts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In conducting the Program, the Secretary may enter into and perform such contracts, leases, grants, or cooperative agreements as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter on such terms as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to interagency working group</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall serve as the lead Federal agency responsible for coordinating the Federal response to ocean and coastal acidification. The Administration may enter into Memoranda of Understanding to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate monitoring and research efforts among Federal agencies in cooperation with State, local, and Tribal governments and international partners; this may include analysis and synthesis of the results of monitoring and research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> maintain an Ocean Acidification Information Exchange described under <ref>section 3703(b)(5) of this title</ref> to allow for information to be electronically accessible, including information—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on ocean acidification developed through or used by the ocean acidification program described under subsection (a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that would be useful to State governments, local governments, Tribal governments, resource managers, policymakers, researchers, and other stakeholders in mitigating or adapting to the impacts of ocean acidification and coastal acidification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establishing and maintaining the data archive system under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data archive system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in coordination with the members of the interagency working group, shall support the long-term stewardship of, and access to, data relating to ocean and coastal acidification through providing the data on a publicly accessible data archive system. To the extent possible, this data archive system shall collect and provide access to ocean and coastal acidification data—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> from relevant federally funded research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provided by a Federal, State, or local government, academic scientist, citizen scientist, or industry organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> voluntarily submitted by Tribes or Tribal governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> from existing global or national data assets that are currently maintained within Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary to, the extent possible, shall ensure all such data adheres to data and metadata standards to support the public findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability of such data.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12406</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1843</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–271, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3343</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10646</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3706.</num>
<heading> NSF ocean acidification activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall continue to carry out research activities on ocean acidification and coastal acidification which shall support competitive, merit-based, peer-reviewed proposals for research, observation, and monitoring of ocean acidification and coastal acidification and their respective impacts, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> impacts on marine organisms, including species cultured for aquaculture, and marine ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> impacts on ocean, coastal, and estuarine biogeochemistry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the development of methodologies and technologies to evaluate ocean acidification and coastal acidification and their respective impacts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> impacts of multiple stressors on ecosystems exhibiting hypoxia, harmful algal blooms, or sediment delivery, combined with changes in ocean chemistry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> adaptation and mitigation strategies to address socioeconomic effects of ocean acidification and coastal acidification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The research activities shall be consistent with the strategic research plan developed by the Subcommittee under <ref>section 3704 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall encourage coordination of the Foundation’s ocean acidification and coastal acidification activities with such activities of other nations and international organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Recipients of grants from the National Science Foundation under this chapter that collect data described under <ref>section 3705(d) of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> collect data in accordance with the standards, protocols, or procedures established pursuant to <ref>section 3705(d) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit such data to the Director and the Secretary after publication, in accordance with any rules promulgated by the Director or the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12407</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–271, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3344</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10647</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3707.</num>
<heading> NASA ocean acidification activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ocean acidification activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, in coordination with other relevant agencies, shall ensure that space-based monitoring assets are used in as productive a manner as possible for monitoring of ocean acidification and coastal acidification and their respective impacts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program consistency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that the Agency’s research and monitoring activities on ocean acidification and coastal acidification are carried out in a manner consistent with the strategic research plan developed by the Subcommittee under <ref>section 3704 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall encourage coordination of the Agency’s ocean acidification and coastal acidification activities with such activities of other nations and international organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Researchers from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration under this subtitle that collect data described under <ref>section 3705(d) of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> collect such data in accordance with the standards, protocols, or procedures established pursuant to <ref>section 3705(d) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit such data to the Administrator and the Secretary, in accordance with any rules promulgated by the Administrator or the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12408</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10648</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3708.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NOAA</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $20,500,000 for fiscal year 2023;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $22,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $24,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $26,000,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $28,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NSF</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Science Foundation to carry out the purposes of this chapter, $20,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12409</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10649</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>