<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 48—</num>
<heading>OCEAN AND COASTAL MAPPING INTEGRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3501.</num>
<heading> Establishment of program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President, in coordination with the Interagency Working Group on Ocean and Coastal Mapping under <ref>section 3502 of this title</ref> and affected coastal states, shall establish and maintain a program to coordinate comprehensive Federal ocean and coastal mapping efforts for the Great Lakes and coastal state waters, the territorial sea, the exclusive economic zone, and the continental shelf of the United States that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhances ecosystem approaches in decisionmaking for natural resource and habitat management restoration and conservation, emergency response, and coastal resilience and adaptation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establishes research and mapping priorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> supports the siting of research and other platforms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> advances ocean and coastal science.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program parameters</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In maintaining such a program, the President, through the Working Group, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify all Federal and federally-funded programs conducting shoreline delineation and ocean or coastal mapping, noting geographic coverage, frequency, spatial coverage, resolution, and subject matter focus of the data and location of data archives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> facilitate cost-effective, cooperative mapping efforts that incorporate policies for contracting with non-governmental entities among all Federal agencies conducting ocean and coastal mapping and for leveraging existing Federal geospatial services capacities and contract vehicles for efficiencies, by increasing data sharing, developing appropriate data acquisition and metadata standards, and facilitating the interoperability of in situ data collection systems, data processing, archiving, and distribution of data products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitate the adaptation of existing technologies as well as foster expertise in new ocean and coastal mapping technologies, including through research, development, and training conducted among Federal agencies and in cooperation with non-governmental entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop standards and protocols for testing innovative experimental mapping technologies and transferring new technologies between the Federal Government, coastal state, and non-governmental entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide for the archiving, management, and distribution of data sets through a national registry as well as provide mapping products and services to the general public in service of statutory requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> develop data standards and protocols consistent with standards developed by the Federal Geographic Data Committee for use by Federal, coastal state, and other entities in mapping and otherwise documenting locations of federally permitted activities, living and nonliving coastal and marine resources, marine ecosystems, sensitive habitats, submerged cultural resources, undersea cables, offshore aquaculture projects, offshore energy projects, and any areas designated for purposes of environmental protection or conservation and management of living and nonliving coastal and marine resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> identify the procedures to be used for coordinating the collection and integration of Federal ocean and coastal mapping data with mapping programs, in conjunction with Federal and State agencies, Tribal governments, private industry, academia, and nongovernmental organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> facilitate, to the extent practicable, the collection of tide data and water-level data and the development and dissemination of hydrodynamic models for coastal areas to allow for the application of V-datum tools that will facilitate the seamless integration of onshore and offshore maps and charts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> establish a plan for the acquisition and collection of ocean and coastal mapping data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> set forth a timetable for completion and implementation of the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Ocean Science and Technology Subcommittee of the Ocean Policy Committee established under <ref>section 8932(c) of title 10</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council established under section 5405 of the National Ocean Exploration Act.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002139">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12202</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1421</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(a)</ref>, (b)(1)(A), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3974</ref>, 3975.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3502.</num>
<heading> Interagency Working Group on Ocean and Coastal Mapping</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of the National Ocean Exploration Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002140">1</ref> shall use the Interagency Working Group on Ocean and Coastal Mapping in existence as of the date of the enactment of such Act to implement <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Working Group shall be comprised of senior-level representatives from Federal agencies with ocean and coastal mapping and surveying responsibilities. Membership shall include senior-level representatives from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Department of the Navy, the United States Geological Survey, the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management of the Department of the Interior, the Office of the Assistant Secretary, Fish and Wildlife and Parks of the Department of the Interior, the National Science Foundation, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the United States Army Corps of Engineers, the Coast Guard, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and other appropriate Federal agencies involved in ocean and coastal mapping.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Co-Chairs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Working Group shall be co-chaired by one representative from each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Department of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subordinate groups</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The co-chairs may establish such permanent or temporary subordinate groups as determined appropriate by the Working Group.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Working Group shall meet on a quarterly basis, but each subordinate group shall meet on an as-needed basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Working Group shall coordinate activities when appropriate, with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> other Federal efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> international mapping activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coastal States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coastal Indian Tribes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> data acquisition and user groups through workshops, partnerships, and other appropriate mechanisms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> representatives of nongovernmental entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Working Group shall support the National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council established under section 5405 of the National Ocean Exploration Act <sup>1</sup> and the Ocean Science and Technology Subcommittee of the Ocean Policy Committee established under <ref>section 8932(c) of title 10</ref> on ocean mapping activities and associated technology development across the Federal Government, State governments, coastal Indian Tribes, private industry, nongovernmental organizations, and academia.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12203</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)–(9), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3975</ref>, 3976.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3503.</num>
<heading> Biennial reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of the National Ocean Exploration Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref> and biennially thereafter until 2040, the co-chairs of the Working Group, in coordination with the National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council established under section 5405 of such Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref> shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, a report detailing progress made in implementing this chapter, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an inventory of ocean and coastal mapping data, including the data maintained by the National Centers for Environmental Information of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, within the territorial sea and the exclusive economic zone and throughout the Continental Shelf of the United States, noting the age and source of the survey and the spatial resolution (metadata) of the data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identification of priority areas in need of survey coverage using present technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a resource plan that identifies when priority areas in need of modern ocean and coastal mapping surveys can be accomplished, including a plan to map the coasts of the United States on a requirements-based cycle, with mapping agencies and partners coordinating on a unified approach that factors in recent related studies, meets multiple user requirements, and identifies gaps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the status of efforts to produce integrated digital maps of ocean and coastal areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of any products resulting from coordinated mapping efforts under this chapter that improve public understanding of the coasts and oceans, or regulatory decisionmaking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> documentation of minimum and desired standards for data acquisition and integrated metadata;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a statement of the status of Federal efforts to leverage mapping technologies, coordinate mapping activities, share expertise, and exchange data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a statement of resource requirements for organizations to meet the goals of the program, including technology needs for data acquisition, processing, and distribution systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> a statement of the status of efforts to declassify data gathered by the Navy, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, and other agencies to the extent possible without jeopardizing national security, and make it available to partner agencies and the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the status of efforts to coordinate Federal programs with international, coastal State, and local government and nongovernmental mapping programs and leverage those programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> a description of efforts of Federal agencies to streamline and expand contracting with nongovernmental entities for the purpose of fulfilling Federal mapping and charting responsibilities, plans, and strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> an inventory and description of any new Federal or federally funded programs conducting shoreline delineation and ocean or coastal mapping since the previous reporting cycle;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> a progress report on the development of new and innovative technologies and applications through research and development, including cooperative or other agreements with joint or cooperative research institutes and centers and other nongovernmental entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> a description of best practices in data processing and distribution and leveraging opportunities among agencies represented on the Working Group and with coastal States, coastal Indian Tribes, and nongovernmental entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> an identification of any training, technology, or other requirements for enabling Federal mapping programs, vessels, and aircraft to support a coordinated ocean and coastal mapping program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> a timetable for implementation and completion of the plan described in paragraph (3), including recommendations for integrating new approaches into the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12204</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3977</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3504.</num>
<heading> NOAA joint ocean and coastal mapping centers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator may maintain and operate up to three joint ocean and coastal mapping centers, including a joint hydrographic center, which shall each be co-located with an institution of higher education. The centers shall serve as hydrographic centers of excellence and may conduct activities necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> research and development of innovative ocean and coastal mapping technologies, equipment, and data products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> mapping of the United States Outer Continental Shelf and other regions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> data processing for nontraditional data and uses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> advancing the use of remote sensing and uncrewed technologies, for related issues, including mapping and assessment of essential fish habitat and of coral resources, ocean observations, and ocean exploration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> providing graduate education and training in ocean and coastal mapping sciences for members of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps, personnel of other agencies with ocean and coastal mapping programs, and civilian personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12205</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1424</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(d)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3978</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3504a.</num>
<heading> Ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding opportunity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the National Ocean Exploration Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002142">1</ref> the Administrator shall develop an integrated ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity, to be known as the “Brennan Ocean Mapping Fund” in memory of Rear Admiral Richard T. Brennan, within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with Federal, State, Tribal, local, nonprofit, private industry, or academic partners in order to increase the coordinated acquisition, processing, stewardship, and archival of new ocean and coastal mapping data in United States waters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall develop administrative and procedural rules for the ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity developed under subsection (a), to include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specific and detailed criteria that must be addressed by an applicant, such as geographic overlap with preestablished priorities, number and type of project partners, benefit to the applicant, coordination with other funding opportunities, and benefit to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determination of the appropriate funding match amounts and mechanisms to use, such as grants, agreements, or contracts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other funding award criteria as are necessary or appropriate to ensure that evaluations of proposals and decisions to award funding under this section are based on objective standards applied fairly and equitably to those proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geospatial services and contract vehicles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity developed under subsection (a) shall leverage Federal expertise and capacities for geospatial services and Federal geospatial contract vehicles using the private sector for acquisition efficiencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12206</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3978</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3504b.</num>
<heading> Agreements and financial assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the head of a Federal agency that is represented on the Interagency Committee on Ocean and Coastal Mapping may enter into agreements with any other agency that is so represented to provide, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, facilities, equipment, services, personnel, and other support services to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may make financial assistance awards (grants of cooperative agreements) to any State or subdivision thereof or any public or private organization or individual to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12207</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3979</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3505.</num>
<heading> Effect on other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to supersede or alter the existing authorities of any Federal agency with respect to ocean and coastal mapping.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12208</ref>, formerly § 12206, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1426</ref>; renumbered § 12208, <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3978</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3506.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the amounts authorized by <ref>section 892d of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this chapter $45,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint ocean and coastal mapping centers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a), the following amounts shall be used to carry out section 3504(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002143">1</ref> of this title $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding opportunity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of amounts authorized pursuant to subsection (a), $20,000,000 is authorized to carry out <ref>section 3504a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12209</ref>, formerly § 12207, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1426</ref>; renumbered § 12209 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(e)(1)</ref>, (f), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3978</ref>, 3979.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3507.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator’ ” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002144">1</ref> means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coastal state</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “coastal state” has the meaning given that term by <ref>section 1453(4) of title 16</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Working Group</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Working Group” means the Interagency Working Group on Ocean and Coastal Mapping under <ref>section 3502 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusive economic zone</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “exclusive economic zone” means the exclusive economic zone of the United States established by Presidential Proclamation No. 5030, of <date date="1983-03-10">March 10, 1983</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ocean and coastal mapping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “ocean and coastal mapping” means the acquisition, processing, management, maintenance, interpretation, certification, and dissemination of physical, biological, geological, chemical, and archaeological characteristics and boundaries of ocean and coastal areas, resources, and sea beds through the use of acoustics, satellites, aerial photogrammetry, light and imaging, direct sampling, and other mapping technologies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Territorial sea</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “territorial sea” means the belt of sea measured from the baseline of the United States determined in accordance with international law, as set forth in Presidential Proclamation Number 5928, dated <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nongovernmental entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “nongovernmental entities” includes nongovernmental organizations, members of the academic community, and private sector organizations that provide products and services associated with measuring, locating, and preparing maps, charts, surveys, aerial photographs, satellite imagines,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002145">2</ref> or other graphical or digital presentations depicting natural or manmade physical features, phenomena, and legal boundaries of the Earth.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outer Continental Shelf</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Outer Continental Shelf” means all submerged lands lying seaward and outside of lands beneath navigable waters (as that term is defined in <ref>section 1301 of title 43</ref>), and of which the subsoil and seabed appertain to the United States and are subject to its jurisdiction and control.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coastal Indian Tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “coastal Indian Tribe” means an “Indian Tribe”, as defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>, the land of which is located in a coastal State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12210</ref>, formerly § 12208, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1426</ref>; renumbered § 12210 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(b)(1)(C)</ref>, (e)(1), (g), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3976</ref>, 3978, 3979.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>