<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2—</num>
<heading>OFFICE AND COMPENSATION OF PRESIDENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Commencement of term of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term of four years for which a President and Vice President shall be elected, shall, in all cases, commence on the 20th day of January next succeeding the day on which the votes of the electors have been given.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Compensation of the President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall receive in full for his services during the term for which he shall have been elected compensation in the aggregate amount of $400,000 a year, to be paid monthly, and in addition an expense allowance of $50,000 to assist in defraying expenses relating to or resulting from the discharge of his official duties. Any unused amount of such expense allowance shall revert to the Treasury pursuant to <ref>section 1552 of title 31</ref>, United States Code. No amount of such expense allowance shall be included in the gross income of the President. He shall be entitled also to the use of the furniture and other effects belonging to the United States and kept in the Executive Residence at the White House.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref>Jan. 19, 1949, ch. 2, § 1(a)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 4</ref>; <ref>Oct. 20, 1951, ch. 521</ref>, title VI, § 619(a), <ref>65 Stat. 569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–1, § 1</ref>, <date date="1969-01-17">Jan. 17, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 3</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–58, title VI, § 644(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. F, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Traveling expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There may be expended for or on account of the traveling expenses of the President of the United States such sum as Congress may from time to time appropriate, not exceeding $100,000 per annum, such sum when appropriated to be expended in the discretion of the President and accounted for on his certificate solely.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 104.</num>
<heading> Salary of the Vice President</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The per annum rate of salary of the Vice President of the United States shall be the rate determined for such position under chapter 11 of title 2, as adjusted under this section. Subject to subsection (b), effective at the beginning of the first month in which an adjustment takes effect under <ref>section 5303 of title 5</ref> in the rates of pay under the General Schedule, the salary of the Vice President shall be adjusted by an amount, rounded to the nearest multiple of $100 (or if midway between multiples of $100, to the nearest higher multiple of $100), equal to the percentage of such per annum rate which corresponds to the most recent percentage change in the ECI (relative to the date described in the next sentence), as determined under section 704(a)(1) of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989. The appropriate date under this sentence is the first day of the fiscal year in which such adjustment in the rates of pay under the General Schedule takes effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In no event shall the percentage adjustment taking effect under the second and third sentences of subsection (a) in any calendar year (before rounding) exceed the percentage adjustment taking effect in such calendar year under <ref>section 5303 of title 5</ref> in the rates of pay under the General Schedule.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref>Jan. 19, 1949, ch. 2, § 1(b)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 4</ref>; <ref>Mar. 2, 1955, ch. 9, § 4(c)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 422</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–67, § 1</ref>, <date date="1969-09-15">Sept. 15, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–82, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–257, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-10">Sept. 10, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title VII, § 704(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 101(b)(4)(I)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1440; <ref>Pub. L. 103–356, title I, § 101(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 105.</num>
<heading> Assistance and services for the President</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisons <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the President is authorized to appoint and fix the pay of employees in the White House Office without regard to any other provision of law regulating the employment or compensation of persons in the Government service. Employees so appointed shall perform such official duties as the President may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The President may, under paragraph (1) of this subsection, appoint and fix the pay of not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 25 employees at rates not to exceed the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level II of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 25 employees at rates not to exceed the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level III of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 50 employees at rates not to exceed the maximum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–18 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such number of other employees as he may determine to be appropriate at rates not to exceed the minimum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the President is authorized to appoint and fix the pay of employees in the Executive Residence at the White House without regard to any other provision of law regulating the employment or compensation of persons in the Government service. Employees so appointed shall perform such official duties as the President may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The President may, under paragraph (1) of this subsection, appoint and fix the pay of not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 3 employees at rates not to exceed the maximum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–18 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such number of other employees as he may determine to be appropriate at rates not to exceed the minimum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The President is authorized to procure for the White House Office and the Executive Residence at the White House, as provided in appropriation Acts, temporary or intermittent services of experts and consultants, as described in and in accordance with the first two sentences of <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of the White House Office, at respective daily rates of pay for individuals which are not more than the daily equivalent of the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level II of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of the Executive Residence, at respective daily rates of pay for individuals which are not more than the daily equivalent of the maximum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–18 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding such section 3109(b), temporary services of any expert or consultant described in such section 3109(b) may be procured for a period in excess of one year if the President determines such procurement is necessary.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> There are authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year to the President such sums as may be necessary for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the care, maintenance, repair, alteration, refurnishing, improvement, air-conditioning, heating, and lighting (including electric power and fixtures) of the Executive Residence at the White House;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the official expenses of the White House Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the official entertainment expenses of the President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the official entertainment expenses for allocation within the Executive Office of the President; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the subsistence expenses of persons in the Government service while traveling on official business in connection with the travel of the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Sums appropriated under this subsection for expenses described in paragraphs (1), (3), and (5) may be expended as the President may determine, notwithstanding the provisions of any other law. Such sums shall be accounted for solely on the certificate of the President, except that, with respect to such expenses, the Comptroller General may inspect all necessary books, documents, papers, and records relating to any such expenditures solely for the purpose of verifying that all such expenditures related to expenses in paragraph (1), (3), or (5). The Comptroller General shall certify to Congress the fact of such verification, and shall report any such expenses not expended for such purpose.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Assistance and services authorized pursuant to this section to the President are authorized to be provided to the spouse of the President in connection with assistance provided by such spouse to the President in the discharge of the President’s duties and responsibilities. If the President does not have a spouse, such assistance and services may be provided for such purposes to a member of the President’s family whom the President designates.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref>Oct. 15, 1949, ch. 695, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 880</ref>; <ref>July 31, 1956, ch. 804</ref>, title I, § 109, <ref>70 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–367, title III, § 303(h)</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 794</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 304(b)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 422</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–222, title I, § 111(c)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-23">Dec. 23, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2445</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 106.</num>
<heading> Assistance and services for the Vice President</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In order to enable the Vice President to provide assistance to the President in connection with the performance of functions specially assigned to the Vice President by the President in the discharge of executive duties and responsibilities, the Vice President is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> without regard to any other provision of law regulating the employment or compensation of persons in the Government service, to appoint and fix the pay of not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 5 employees at rates not to exceed the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level II of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 3 employees at rates not to exceed the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level III of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 3 employees at rates not to exceed the maximum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–18 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such number of other employees as he may determine to be appropriate at rates not to exceed the minimum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to procure, as provided in appropriation Acts, temporary or intermittent services of experts and consultants, as described in and in accordance with the first two sentences of <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, at respective daily rates of pay for individuals which are not more than the daily equivalent of the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level II of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding such section 3109(b), temporary services of any expert or consultant described in such section 3109(b) may be procured under paragraph (2) of this subsection for a period in excess of one year if the Vice President determines such procurement is necessary.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In order to carry out the executive duties and responsibilities referred to in subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year to the Vice President such sums as may be necessary for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the official expenses of the Office of the Vice President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the official entertainment expenses of the Vice President; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the subsistence expenses of persons in the Government service while traveling on official business in connection with the travel of the Vice President.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Sums appropriated under this subsection for expenses described in paragraphs (2) and (3) may be expended as the Vice President may determine, notwithstanding the provisions of any other law. Such sums shall be accounted for solely on the certificate of the Vice President, except that, with respect to such expenses, the Comptroller General may inspect all necessary books, documents, papers, and records relating to any such expenditures solely for the purpose of verifying that all such expenditures related to expenses in paragraph (2) or (3). The Comptroller General shall certify to Congress the fact of such verification, and shall report any such expenses not expended for such purpose.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Assistance and services authorized pursuant to this section to the Vice President are authorized to be provided to the spouse of the Vice President in connection with assistance provided by such spouse to the Vice President in the discharge of the Vice President’s executive duties and responsibilities. If the Vice President does not have a spouse, such assistance and services may be provided for such purposes to a member of the Vice President’s family whom the Vice President designates.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref>Oct. 15, 1949, ch. 695, § 2(b)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 107.</num>
<heading> Domestic Policy Staff and Office of Administration; personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In order to enable the Domestic Policy Staff to perform its functions, the President (or his designee) is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> without regard to any other provision of law regulating the employment or compensation of persons in the Government service, to appoint and fix the pay of not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 6 employees at rates not to exceed the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level III of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 18 employees at rates not to exceed the maximum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–18 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such number of other employees as he may determine to be appropriate at rates not to exceed the minimum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to procure, as provided in appropriation Acts, temporary or intermittent services of experts and consultants, as described in and in accordance with the first two sentences of <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, at respective daily rates of pay for individuals which are not more than the daily equivalent of the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level III of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In order to enable the Office of Administration to perform its functions, the President (or his designee) is authorized—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> without regard to such other provisions of law as the President may specify which regulate the employment and compensation of persons in the Government service, to appoint and fix the pay of not more than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 5 employees at rates not to exceed the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level III of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>; and in addition</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 5 employees at rates not to exceed the maximum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–18 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to procure, as provided in appropriation Acts, temporary or intermittent services of experts and consultants, as described in and in accordance with the first two sentences of <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, at respective daily rates of pay for individuals which are not more than the daily equivalent of the maximum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–18 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In addition to any authority granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the President (or his designee) is authorized to employ individuals in the Office of Administration in accordance with <ref>section 3101 of title 5</ref> and provisions relating thereto. Any individual so employed under the authority granted under such section 3101 shall be subject to the limitation specified in <ref>section 114 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary for the official expenses of the Domestic Policy Staff and the Office of Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 108.</num>
<heading> Assistance to the President for unanticipated needs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated to the President an amount not to exceed $1,000,000 each fiscal year to enable the President, in his discretion, to meet unanticipated needs for the furtherance of the national interest, security, or defense, including personnel needs and needs for services described in <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, and administrative expenses related thereto, without regard to any provision of law regulating the employment or compensation of persons in the Government service or regulating expenditures of Government funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President shall transmit a report to each House of the Congress for each fiscal year beginning on or after the effective date of this subsection which sets forth the purposes for which expenditures were made under this section for such fiscal year and the amount expended for each such purpose. Each such report shall be transmitted no later than 60 days after the close of the fiscal year covered by such report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An individual may not be paid under the authority of this section at a rate of pay in excess of the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level II of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 109.</num>
<heading> Public property in and belonging to the Executive Residence at the White House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The steward, housekeeper, or such other employee of the Executive Residence at the White House as the President may designate, shall under the direction of the President, have the charge and custody of and be responsible for the plate, furniture, and public property therein. A complete inventory, in proper books, shall be made annually in the month of June, under the direction of the Director of the National Park Service, of all the public property in and belonging to the Executive Residence at the White House, showing when purchased, its cost, condition, and final disposition. This inventory shall be submitted to the President for his approval, and shall then be kept for reference in the office of the Director of the National Park Service, which shall furnish a copy thereof to the steward, housekeeper, or other employee responsible for the property.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 679</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 202</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 5(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110.</num>
<heading> Furniture for the Executive Residence at the White House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All furniture purchased for the use of the Executive Residence at the White House shall be, as far as practicable, of domestic manufacture. With a view to conserving in the Executive Residence at the White House the best specimens of the early American furniture and furnishings, and for the purpose of maintaining the interior of the Executive Residence at the White House in keeping with its original design, the Director of the National Park Service is authorized and directed, with the approval of the President, to accept donations of furniture and furnishings for use in the Executive Residence at the White House, all such articles thus donated to become the property of the United States and to be accounted for as such. The said Director of the National Park Service is further authorized and directed, with the approval of the President, to appoint a temporary committee composed of one representative of the American Federation of Arts, one representative of the National Commission of Fine Arts, one representative of the National Academy of Design, one member of the American Institute of Architects, and five members representing the public at large; the said committee to have full power to select and pass on the articles in question and to recommend the same for acceptance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 679</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 111.</num>
<heading> Expense allowance of Vice President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be paid to the Vice President in equal monthly installments an expense allowance of $20,000 per annum to assist in defraying expenses relating to or resulting from the discharge of his official duties, for which no accounting, other than for income tax purposes, shall be made by him.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Jan. 19, 1949, ch. 2, § 1(c)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 4</ref>; amended <ref>Oct. 20, 1951, ch. 521</ref>, title VI, § 619(b), <ref>65 Stat. 570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112.</num>
<heading> Detail of employees of executive departments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of any department, agency, or independent establishment of the executive branch of the Government may detail, from time to time, employees of such department, agency, or establishment to the White House Office, the Executive Residence at the White House, the Office of the Vice President, the Domestic Policy Staff, and the Office of Administration. Any such office to which an employee has been detailed for service to such office shall reimburse the detailing department, agency, or establishment for the pay of each employee thereof—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who is so detailed, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> who is performing services which have been or would otherwise be performed by an employee of such office,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">for any period occurring during any fiscal year after 180 calendar days after the employee is detailed in such year.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 113.</num>
<heading> Personnel report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall transmit to each House of the Congress, and make available to the public, reports containing information described in subsection (b) for each fiscal year beginning on or after the effective date of this section. Each such report shall be transmitted no later than 60 days after the close of the fiscal year covered by such report and shall contain a statement of such information for such year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each report required under subsection (a) shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of employees who are paid at a rate of basic pay equal to or greater than the rate of basic pay then currently paid for level V of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5316 of title 5</ref> and who are employed in the White House Office, the Executive Residence at the White House, the Office of the Vice President, the Domestic Policy Staff, or the Office of Administration, and the aggregate amount paid to such employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of employees employed in such offices who are paid at a rate of basic pay which is equal to or greater than the minimum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> but which is less than the rate then currently paid for level V of the Executive Schedule of section 5316 of title V <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref> and the aggregate amount paid to such employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of employees employed in such offices who are paid at a rate of basic pay which is less than the minimum rate then currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule of section 5332 of title V <sup>1</sup>, and the aggregate amount paid to such employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of individuals detailed under <ref>section 112 of this title</ref> for more than 30 days to each such office, the number of days in excess of 30 each individual was detailed, and the aggregate amount of reimbursement made as provided by the provisions of <ref>section 112 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the number of individuals whose services as experts or consultants are procured under this chapter for service in any such office, the total number of days employed, and the aggregate amount paid to procure such services.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The information required under this subsection to be in any report shall be shown both in the aggregate and by office involved.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 114.</num>
<heading> General pay limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of law, other than the provisions of this chapter, no employee of the White House Office, the Executive Residence at the White House, the Domestic Policy Staff, or the Office of Administration, nor any employee under the Vice President appointed under <ref>section 106 of this title</ref>, may be paid at a rate of basic pay in excess of the minimum rate of basic pay then currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–570, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 115.</num>
<heading> Veterans’ preference</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (b), appointments under sections 105, 106, and 107 shall be made in accordance with section 2108, and sections 3309 through 3312, of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) shall not apply to any appointment to a position the rate of basic pay for which is at least equal to the minimum rate established for positions in the Senior Executive Service under <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref> and the duties of which are comparable to those described in section 3132(a)(2) of such title or to any other position if, with respect to such position, the President makes certification—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> that such position is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a confidential or policy-making position; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a position for which political affiliation or political philosophy is otherwise an important qualification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that any individual selected for such position is expected to vacate the position at or before the end of the President’s term (or terms) of office.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each individual appointed to a position described in the preceding sentence as to which the expectation described in paragraph (2) applies shall be notified as to such expectation, in writing, at the time of appointment to such position.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–339, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>