<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 22—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL DRUG CONTROL POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agency” has the meaning given the term “executive agency” in <ref>section 102 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any submission to Congress shall mean submission to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demand reduction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “demand reduction” means any activity conducted by a National Drug Control Program agency, other than an enforcement activity, that is intended to reduce or prevent the use of drugs or support, expand, or provide treatment and recovery efforts, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> education about the dangers of illicit drug use;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> services, programs, or strategies to prevent substance use disorder, including evidence-based education campaigns, community-based prevention programs, collection and disposal of unused prescription drugs, and services to at-risk populations to prevent or delay initial use of an illicit drug;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> substance use disorder treatment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> support for long-term recovery from substance use disorders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> drug-free workplace programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> drug testing, including the testing of employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> interventions for illicit drug use and dependence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> expanding availability of access to health care services for the treatment of substance use disorders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> international drug control coordination and cooperation with respect to activities described in this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> pre- and post-arrest criminal justice interventions such as diversion programs, drug courts, and the provision of evidence-based treatment to individuals with substance use disorders who are arrested or under some form of criminal justice supervision, including medication assisted treatment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> other coordinated and joint initiatives among Federal, State, local, and Tribal agencies to promote comprehensive drug control strategies designed to reduce the demand for, and the availability of, illegal drugs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> international illicit drug use education, prevention, treatment, recovery, research, rehabilitation activities, and interventions for illicit drug use and dependence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> research related to illicit drug use and any of the activities described in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of National Drug Control Policy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drug</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “drug” has the meaning given the term “controlled substance” in <ref>section 802(6) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drug control</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “drug control” means any activity conducted by a National Drug Control Program agency involving supply reduction or demand reduction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emerging drug threat</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “emerging drug threat” means the occurrence of a new and growing trend in the use of an illicit drug or class of drugs, including rapid expansion in the supply of or demand for such drug.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Illicit drug use; illicit drugs; illegal drugs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “illicit drug use”, “illicit drugs”, and “illegal drugs” include the illegal or illicit use of prescription drugs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “law enforcement” or “drug law enforcement” means all efforts by a Federal, State, local, or Tribal government agency to enforce the drug laws of the United States or any State, including investigation, arrest, prosecution, and incarceration or other punishments or penalties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Drug Control Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Drug Control Program” means programs, policies, and activities undertaken by National Drug Control Program agencies pursuant to the responsibilities of such agencies under the National Drug Control Strategy, including any activities involving supply reduction, demand reduction, or State, local, and tribal <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002181">1</ref> affairs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Drug Control Program agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Drug Control Program agency” means any agency (or bureau, office, independent agency, board, division, commission, subdivision, unit, or other component thereof) that is responsible for implementing any aspect of the National Drug Control Strategy, including any agency that receives Federal funds to implement any aspect of the National Drug Control Strategy, but does not include any agency that receives funds for drug control activity solely under the National Intelligence Program or the Joint Military Intelligence Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Drug Control Strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Drug Control Strategy” or “Strategy” means the strategy developed and submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1705 of this title</ref>, including any report, plan, or strategy required to be incorporated into or issued concurrently with such strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “nonprofit organization” means an organization that is described in <ref>section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Office” means the Office of National Drug Control Policy established under <ref>section 1702(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State, local, and Tribal affairs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State, local, and Tribal affairs” means domestic activities conducted by a National Drug Control Program agency that are intended to reduce the availability and use of illegal drugs, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordination and enhancement of Federal, State, local, and Tribal law enforcement drug control efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordination and enhancement of efforts among National Drug Control Program agencies and State, local, and Tribal demand reduction and supply reduction agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordination and enhancement of Federal, State, local, and Tribal law enforcement initiatives to gather, analyze, and disseminate information and law enforcement intelligence relating to drug control among domestic law enforcement agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other coordinated and joint initiatives among Federal, State, local, and Tribal agencies to promote comprehensive drug control strategies designed to reduce the demand for, and the availability of, illegal drugs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substance use disorder treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “substance use disorder treatment” means an evidence-based, professionally directed, deliberate, and planned regimen including evaluation, observation, medical monitoring, and rehabilitative services and interventions such as pharmacotherapy, behavioral therapy, and individual and group counseling, on an inpatient or outpatient basis, to help patients with substance use disorder reach recovery.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supply reduction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “supply reduction” means any activity or program conducted by a National Drug Control Program agency that is intended to reduce the availability or use of illegal drugs in the United States or abroad, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> law enforcement outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> domestic law enforcement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> source country programs, including economic development programs primarily intended to reduce the production or trafficking of illicit drugs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> activities to control international trafficking in, and availability of, illegal drugs, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> accurate assessment and monitoring of international drug production and interdiction programs and policies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> coordination and promotion of compliance with international treaties relating to the production, transportation, or interdiction of illegal drugs;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> activities to conduct and promote international law enforcement programs and policies to reduce the supply of drugs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> activities to facilitate and enhance the sharing of domestic and foreign intelligence information among National Drug Control Program agencies, relating to the production and trafficking of drugs in the United States and in foreign countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> activities to prevent the diversion of drugs for their illicit use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> research related to any of the activities described in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 702, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–670</ref>, 2681–693; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title I, § 101</ref>, title VI, § 602, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3503</ref>, 3533; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), (b)(2), 8216, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4117; <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1702.</num>
<heading> Office of National Drug Control Policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established in the Executive Office of the President an Office of National Drug Control Policy, which shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> lead the national drug control effort, including coordinating with the National Drug Control Program agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate and oversee the implementation of the national drug control policy, including the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assess and certify the adequacy of National Drug Control Programs and the budget for those programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> evaluate the effectiveness of national drug control policy efforts, including the National Drug Control Program Agencies’ <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002182">1</ref> programs, by developing and applying specific goals and performance measurements and monitoring the agencies’ program-level spending;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> identify and respond to emerging drug threats related to illicit drug use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> administer the Drug-Free Communities Program, the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program, and other grant programs directly authorized to be administered by the Office in furtherance of the National Drug Control Strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> facilitate broad-scale information sharing and data standardization among Federal, State, and local entities to support the national drug control efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8222(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4142</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access by Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The location of the Office in the Executive Office of the President shall not be construed as affecting access by Congress, or any committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, to any—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information, document, or study in the possession of, or conducted by or at the direction of the Director; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> personnel of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of National Drug Control Policy Gift Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund for the receipt of gifts, both real and personal, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Office under <ref>section 1703(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office may accept, hold, and administer contributions to the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts deposited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts deposited in the Fund are authorized to be appropriated, to remain available until expended for authorized purposes at the discretion of the Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ethics guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall establish written guidelines setting forth the criteria to be used in determining whether a gift or donation should be declined under this subsection because the acceptance of the gift or donation would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reflect unfavorably upon the ability of the Director or the Office, or any employee of the Office, to carry out responsibilities or official duties under this chapter in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compromise the integrity or the appearance of integrity of programs or services provided under this chapter or of any official involved in those programs or services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registry of gifts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall maintain a list of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the source and amount of each gift or donation accepted by the Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the source and amount of each gift or donation accepted by a contractor to be used in its performance of a contract for the Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall include in the annual assessment under <ref>section 1705(g) of this title</ref> a copy of the registry maintained under paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 703, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–672</ref>, 2681–693; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title I, § 102</ref>, title VI, § 602, title XI, § 1120, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3505</ref>, 3533, 3548; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), (b)(2), 8217(a), (b), 8222(1), <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4119, 4142; <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, (4), <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1703.</num>
<heading> Appointment and duties of Director and Deputy Directors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">There shall be at the head of the Office a Director who shall hold the same rank and status as the head of an executive department listed in <ref>section 101 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Director shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall serve at the pleasure of the President.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deputy Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">There shall be a Deputy Director who shall report directly to the Director, and who shall be appointed by the President, and shall serve at the pleasure of the President.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinators</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The following coordinators shall be appointed by the Director:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Performance Budget Coordinator, as described in subsection (c)(5).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Interdiction Coordinator, as described in <ref>section 1710 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator, as described in <ref>section 1708 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> State, Local, and Tribal Affairs Coordinator, to carry out the activities described in subsection (j).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Demand Reduction Coordinator, as described in subparagraph (D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demand Reduction Coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall designate or appoint a United States Demand Reduction Coordinator to be responsible for the activities described in <ref>section 1701(3) of this title</ref>. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Deputy Director of National Drug Control Policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Deputy Director of National Drug Control Policy shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve as the Director in the absence of the Director or during any period in which the office of the Director is vacant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acting Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Director dies, resigns, or is otherwise unable to perform the functions and duties of the office, the Deputy Director shall perform the functions and duties of the Director temporarily in an acting capacity pursuant to subchapter III of chapter 33 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No person shall serve as Director or a Deputy Director while serving in any other position in the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on political campaigning</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any officer or employee of the Office who is appointed to that position by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, may not participate in Federal election campaign activities, except that such officer or employee is not prohibited by this paragraph from making contributions to individual candidates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on the use of funds for ballot initiatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No funds authorized under this chapter may be obligated for the purpose of expressly advocating the passage or defeat of a State or local ballot initiative.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall assist the President in the establishment of policies, goals, objectives, and priorities for the National Drug Control Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall promulgate the National Drug Control Strategy under <ref>section 1705(a) of this title</ref> and each report under section 1705(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002183">1</ref> of this title in accordance with <ref>section 1705 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall coordinate and oversee the implementation by the National Drug Control Program agencies of the policies, goals, objectives, and priorities established under paragraph (1) and the fulfillment of the responsibilities of such agencies under the National Drug Control Strategy and make recommendations to National Drug Control Program agency heads with respect to implementation of Federal counter-drug programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall make such recommendations to the President as the Director determines are appropriate regarding changes in the organization, management, and budgets of National Drug Control Program agencies, and changes in the allocation of personnel to and within those departments and agencies, to implement the policies, goals, priorities, and objectives established under paragraph (1) and the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> shall consult with and assist State and local governments with respect to the formulation and implementation of National Drug Control Policy and their relations with the National Drug Control Program agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> shall appear before duly constituted committees and subcommittees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate to represent the drug policies of the executive branch;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> shall notify any National Drug Control Program agency if its policies are not in compliance with the responsibilities of the agency under the National Drug Control Strategy, transmit a copy of each such notification to the President and the appropriate congressional committees, and maintain a copy of each such notification;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> shall provide, by July 1 of each year, budget recommendations, including requests for specific initiatives that are consistent with the priorities of the President under the National Drug Control Strategy, to the heads of departments and agencies with responsibilities under the National Drug Control Program, which recommendations shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> apply to the next budget year scheduled for formulation under chapter 11 of title 31, and each of the 4 subsequent fiscal years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> address funding priorities developed in the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> may serve as representative of the President in appearing before Congress on all issues relating to the National Drug Control Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> shall, in any matter affecting national security interests, work in conjunction with the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> may serve as spokesperson of the Administration on drug issues;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> shall ensure that no Federal funds appropriated to the Office of National Drug Control Policy shall be expended for any study or contract relating to the legalization (for a medical use or any other use) of a substance listed in schedule I of <ref>section 812 of this title</ref> and take such actions as necessary to oppose any attempt to legalize the use of a substance (in any form) that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is listed in schedule I of <ref>section 812 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has not been approved for use for medical purposes by the Food and Drug Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8221(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4142</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<chapeau> shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees on an annual basis, not later than 60 days after the date of the last day of the applicable period, a summary of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each of the evaluations received by the Director under <ref>section 1705(g)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the progress of each National Drug Control Program agency toward the drug control program goals of the agency using the performance measures for the agency developed under section 1705(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002184">2</ref> of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> shall ensure that drug prevention and drug treatment research and information is effectively disseminated by National Drug Control Program agencies to State and local governments and nongovernmental entities involved in demand reduction by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encouraging formal consultation between any such agency that conducts or sponsors research, and any such agency that disseminates information in developing research and information product development agendas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encouraging such agencies (as appropriate) to develop and implement dissemination plans that specifically target State and local governments and nongovernmental entities involved in demand reduction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> supporting the substance abuse information clearinghouse administered by the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration and established in <ref>section 290aa(d)(16) of title 42</ref> by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> encouraging all National Drug Control Program agencies to provide all appropriate and relevant information; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> supporting the dissemination of information to all interested entities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> shall coordinate with the private sector to promote private research and development of medications to treat addiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8221(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4142</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> shall monitor and evaluate the allocation of resources among Federal law enforcement agencies in response to significant local and regional drug trafficking and production threats;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> shall submit an annual report to Congress detailing how the Office of National Drug Control Policy has consulted with and assisted State, local, and tribal governments with respect to the formulation and implementation of the National Drug Control Strategy and other relevant issues;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> shall, within 1 year after <date date="2006-12-29">December 29, 2006</date>, report to Congress on the impact of each Federal drug reduction strategy upon the availability, addiction rate, use rate, and other harms of illegal drugs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<chapeau> in order to formulate the national drug control policies, goals, objectives, and priorities—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall consult with and assist—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> State and local governments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> National Drug Control Program agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> each committee, working group, council, or other entity established under this chapter, as appropriate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the public;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> appropriate congressional committees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any other person in the discretion of the Director; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> establish advisory councils;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> acquire data from agencies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> request data from any other entity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Drug Control Program budget</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of National Drug Control Program agencies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For each fiscal year, the head of each department, agency, or program of the Federal Government with responsibilities under the National Drug Control Program Strategy shall transmit to the Director a copy of the proposed drug control budget request of the department, agency, or program at the same time as that budget request is submitted to their superiors (and before submission to the Office of Management and Budget) in the preparation of the budget of the President submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of drug control budget requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The head of each National Drug Control Program agency shall ensure timely development and submission to the Director of each proposed drug control budget request transmitted pursuant to this paragraph, in such format as may be designated by the Director with the concurrence of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content of drug control budget requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A drug control budget request submitted by a department, agency, or program under this paragraph shall include all requests for funds for any drug control activity undertaken by that department, agency, or program, including demand reduction, supply reduction, and State, local, and tribal affairs, including any drug law enforcement activities. If an activity has both drug control and nondrug control purposes or applications, the department, agency, or program shall estimate by a documented calculation the total funds requested for that activity that would be used for drug control, and shall set forth in its request the basis and method for making the estimate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Drug Control Program budget proposal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For each fiscal year, following the transmission of proposed drug control budget requests to the Director under paragraph (1), the Director shall, in consultation with the head of each National Drug Control Program agency and the head of each major national organization that represents law enforcement officers, agencies, or associations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> develop a consolidated National Drug Control Program budget proposal designed to implement the National Drug Control Strategy and to inform Congress and the public about the total amount proposed to be spent on all supply reduction, demand reduction, State, local, and tribal affairs, including any drug law enforcement, and other drug control activities by the Federal Government, which shall conform to the content requirements set forth in paragraph (1)(C) and include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the funding level for each National Drug Control Program agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> alternative funding structures that could improve progress on achieving the goals of the National Drug Control Strategy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit the consolidated budget proposal to the President and Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and certification of budget requests and budget submissions of National Drug Control Program agencies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall review each drug control budget request submitted to the Director under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of budget requests</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inadequate requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the Director concludes that a budget request submitted under paragraph (1) is inadequate, in whole or in part, to implement the objectives of the National Drug Control Strategy with respect to the department, agency, or program at issue for the year for which the request is submitted, the Director shall submit to the head of the applicable National Drug Control Program agency a written description of funding levels and specific initiatives that would, in the determination of the Director, make the request adequate to implement those objectives.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adequate requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the Director concludes that a budget request submitted under paragraph (1) is adequate to implement the objectives of the National Drug Control Strategy with respect to the department, agency, or program at issue for the year for which the request is submitted, the Director shall submit to the head of the applicable National Drug Control Program agency a written statement confirming the adequacy of the request.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Director shall maintain a record of each description submitted under clause (i) and each statement submitted under clause (ii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific requests</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall not confirm the adequacy of any budget request that requests a level of funding that will not enable achievement of the goals of the National Drug Control Strategy, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> requests funding for Federal law enforcement activities that do not adequately compensate for transfers of drug enforcement resources and personnel to law enforcement and investigation activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> requests funding for law enforcement activities on the borders of the United States that do not adequately direct resources to drug interdiction and enforcement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> requests funding for substance use disorder prevention and treatment activities that do not provide adequate results and accountability measures; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> requests funding for drug treatment activities that do not adequately support and enhance Federal drug treatment programs and capacity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency response</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The head of a National Drug Control Program agency that receives a description under subparagraph (B)(i) shall include the funding levels and initiatives described by the Director in the budget submission for that agency to the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Impact statement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The head of a National Drug Control Program agency that has altered its budget submission under this subparagraph shall include as an appendix to the budget submission for that agency to the Office of Management and Budget an impact statement that summarizes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the changes made to the budget under this subparagraph; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the impact of those changes on the ability of that agency to perform its other responsibilities, including any impact on specific missions or programs of the agency.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The head of a National Drug Control Program agency shall submit a copy of any impact statement under clause (ii) to the Senate and the House of Representatives and the appropriate congressional committees, at the time the budget for that agency is submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of budget submissions</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">At the time a National Drug Control Program agency submits its budget request to the Office of Management and Budget, the head of the National Drug Control Program agency shall submit a copy of the budget request to the Director.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Director shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> review each budget submission submitted under clause (i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> based on the review under subclause (I), make a determination as to whether the budget submission of a National Drug Control Program agency includes the funding levels and initiatives described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<chapeau> a written statement that either—</chapeau>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(AA)</num>
<content> certifies that the budget submission includes sufficient funding; or</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(BB)</num>
<content> decertifies the budget submission as not including sufficient funding;</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> a copy of the description made under subparagraph (B); and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> the budget recommendations made under subsection (b)(8).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reprogramming and transfer requests</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No National Drug Control Program agency shall submit to Congress a reprogramming or transfer request with respect to any amount of appropriated funds in an amount exceeding $5,000,000 or 10 percent of a specific program or account that is included in the National Drug Control Program budget unless the request has been approved by the Director. If the Director has not responded to a request for reprogramming subject to this subparagraph within 30 days after receiving notice of the request having been made, the request shall be deemed approved by the Director under this subparagraph and forwarded to Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The head of any National Drug Control Program agency may appeal to the President any disapproval by the Director of a reprogramming or transfer request under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance-Budget Coordinator</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall designate or appoint a United States Performance-Budget Coordinator to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ensure the Director has sufficient information necessary to analyze the performance of each National Drug Control Program agency, the impact Federal funding has had on the goals in the Strategy, and the likely contributions to the goals of the Strategy based on funding levels of each National Drug Control Program agency, to make an independent assessment of the budget request of each agency under this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> advise the Director on agency budgets, performance measures and targets, and additional data and research needed to make informed policy decisions under this section and <ref>section 1705 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other duties as may be determined by the Director with respect to measuring or assessing performance or agency budgets.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of position</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of carrying out subparagraph (A), the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget estimate or request submission to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever the Director submits any budget estimate or request to the President or the Office of Management and Budget, the Director shall concurrently transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed statement of the budgetary needs of the Office to execute its mission based on the good-faith assessment of the Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers of the Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (b), the Director may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> select, appoint, employ, and fix compensation of such officers and employees of the Office as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Office under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (e)(3), request the head of a department or agency, or program of the Federal Government to place department, agency, or program personnel who are engaged in drug control activities on temporary detail to another department, agency, or program in order to implement the National Drug Control Strategy, and the head of the department or agency shall comply with such a request;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use for administrative purposes, on a reimbursable basis, the available services, equipment, personnel, and facilities of Federal, State, and local agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, relating to appointments in the Federal Service, at rates of compensation for individuals not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate of pay payable under level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5311 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> accept and use gifts and donations of property from Federal, State, and local government agencies, and from the private sector, as authorized in <ref>section 1702(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> use the mails in the same manner as any other department or agency of the executive branch;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> monitor implementation of the National Drug Control Program, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conducting program and performance audits and evaluations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requesting assistance from the Inspector General of the relevant agency in such audits and evaluations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> transfer funds made available to a National Drug Control Program agency for National Drug Control Strategy programs and activities to another account within such agency or to another National Drug Control Program agency for National Drug Control Strategy programs and activities, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the authority under this paragraph may be limited in an annual appropriations Act or other provision of Federal law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Director may exercise the authority under this paragraph only with the concurrence of the head of each affected agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of an interagency transfer, the total amount of transfers under this paragraph may not exceed 3 percent of the total amount of funds made available for National Drug Control Strategy programs and activities to the agency from which those funds are to be transferred;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> funds transferred to an agency under this paragraph may only be used to increase the funding for programs or activities authorized by law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> the Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> submit to the appropriate congressional committees and any other applicable committees of jurisdiction, a reprogramming or transfer request in advance of any transfer under this paragraph in accordance with the regulations of the affected agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> annually submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the effect of all transfers of funds made pursuant to this paragraph or subsection (c)(4) during the 12-month period preceding the date on which the report is submitted; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> funds may only be used for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> expansion of demand reduction activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> interdiction of illicit drugs on the high seas, in United States territorial waters, and at United States ports of entry by officers and employees of National Drug Control Program agencies and domestic and foreign law enforcement officers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> accurate assessment and monitoring of international drug production and interdiction programs and policies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> activities to facilitate and enhance the sharing of domestic and foreign intelligence information among National Drug Control Program agencies related to the production and trafficking of drugs in the United States and foreign countries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> research related to any of these activities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> issue to the head of a National Drug Control Program agency a fund control notice described in subsection (f) to ensure compliance with the National Drug Control Program Strategy and notify the appropriate congressional committees of any fund control notice issued in accordance with subsection (f)(5); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> participate in the drug certification process pursuant to <ref>section 2291j of title 22</ref> and <ref>section 2291j–1 of title 22</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel detailed to Office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 43 of title 5, the Director shall perform the evaluation of the performance of any employee detailed to the Office for purposes of the applicable performance appraisal system established under such chapter for any rating period, or part thereof, that such employee is detailed to such office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bonus payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Director may provide periodic bonus payments to any employee detailed to the Office.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An amount paid under this paragraph to an employee for any period—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not be greater than 20 percent of the basic pay paid or payable to such employee for such period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be in addition to the basic pay of such employee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggregate amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The aggregate amount paid during any fiscal year to an employee detailed to the Office as basic pay, awards, bonuses, and other compensation shall not exceed the annual rate payable at the end of such fiscal year for positions at level III of the Executive Schedule.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum number of detailees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The maximum number of personnel who may be detailed to another department or agency (including the Office) under subsection (d)(2) during any fiscal year is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the Department of Defense, 50; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for any other department or agency, 10.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund control notices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A fund control notice may direct that all or part of an amount appropriated to the National Drug Control Program agency account be obligated by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> months, fiscal year quarters, or other time periods; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> activities, functions, projects, or object classes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unauthorized obligation or expenditure prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An officer or employee of a National Drug Control Program agency shall not make or authorize an expenditure or obligation contrary to a fund control notice issued by the Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disciplinary action for violation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a violation of paragraph (2) by an officer or employee of a National Drug Control Program agency, the head of the agency, upon the request of and in consultation with the Director, may subject the officer or employee to appropriate administrative discipline, including, when circumstances warrant, suspension from duty without pay or removal from office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A copy of each fund control notice shall be transmitted to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall not issue a fund control notice to direct that all or part of an amount appropriated to the National Drug Control Program agency account be obligated, modified, or altered in any manner contrary, in whole or in part, to a specific appropriation or statute.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability to certain programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not apply to the National Intelligence Program, the Joint Military Intelligence Program, and Tactical and Related Activities, unless such program or an element of such program is designated as a National Drug Control Program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by the President; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> jointly by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of the National Intelligence Program, the Director and the Director of National Intelligence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of the Joint Military Intelligence Program and Tactical and Related Activities, the Director, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as derogating the authorities and responsibilities of the Director of National Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency contained in the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref>50 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.], the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref>50 U.S.C. 3501</ref> et seq.], or any other law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Model acts program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall provide for or shall enter into an agreement with a nonprofit organization to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advise States on establishing laws and policies to address illicit drug use issues; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> revise such model State drug laws and draft supplementary model State laws to take into consideration changes in illicit drug use issues in the State involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $1,250,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State, Local, and Tribal Affairs Coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall designate or appoint a United States State, Local, and Tribal Affairs Coordinator to perform the duties of the Office outlined in this section and <ref>section 1705 of this title</ref> and such other duties as may be determined by the Director with respect to coordination of drug control efforts between agencies and State, local, and Tribal governments. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Harm reduction programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When developing the national drug control policy, any policy of the Director, including policies relating to syringe exchange programs for intravenous drug users, shall be based on the best available medical and scientific evidence regarding the effectiveness of such policy in promoting individual health and preventing the spread of infectious disease and the impact of such policy on drug addiction and use. In making any policy relating to harm reduction programs, the Director shall consult with the National Institutes of Health and the National Academy of Sciences.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 704, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–672</ref>, 2681–693; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title I</ref>, §§ 103(a)–(e), (f)(3), 105, title VI, § 602, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3506</ref>, 3507, 3510, 3511, 3533; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(t)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), (b)(2), 8217(c)–(f), 8221(b)(1), 8222(2), <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4120–4122, 4142; <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (2), (5), <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1704.</num>
<heading> Coordination with National Drug Control Program agencies in demand reduction, supply reduction, and State and local affairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Upon the request of the Director, the head of any National Drug Control Program agency shall cooperate with and provide to the Director any statistics, studies, reports, and other information prepared or collected by the agency concerning the responsibilities of the agency under the National Drug Control Strategy that relate to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> drug control; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the manner in which amounts made available to that agency for drug control are being used by that agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection of intelligence information</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The authorities conferred on the Office and the Director by this chapter shall be exercised in a manner consistent with provisions of the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref>50 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.]. The Director of National Intelligence shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to protect information provided pursuant to this chapter regarding intelligence sources and methods.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director of National Intelligence and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall, to the maximum extent practicable in accordance with subparagraph (A), render full assistance and support to the Office and the Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required reports</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than July 1 of each year, the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior shall jointly submit to the Director and the appropriate congressional committees an assessment of the quantity of illegal drug cultivation and manufacturing in the United States on lands owned or under the jurisdiction of the Federal Government for the preceding year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of Homeland Security</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than July 1 of each year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Director and the appropriate congressional committees information for the preceding year regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number and type of seizures of drugs by each component of the Department of Homeland Security seizing drugs, as well as statistical information on the geographic areas of such seizures; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of air and maritime patrol hours primarily dedicated to drug supply reduction missions undertaken by each component of the Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Defense shall, by July 1 of each year, submit to the Director and the appropriate congressional committees information for the preceding year regarding the number of air and maritime patrol hours primarily dedicated to drug supply reduction missions undertaken by each component of the Department of Defense.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Attorney General shall, by July 1 of each year, submit to the Director and the appropriate congressional committees information for the preceding year regarding the number and type of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> arrests for drug violations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> prosecutions for drug violations by United States Attorneys; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> seizures of drugs by each component of the Department of Justice seizing drugs, as well as statistical information on the geographic areas of such seizures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of policy changes to Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the head of a National Drug Control Program agency shall, unless exigent circumstances require otherwise, notify the Director in writing regarding any proposed change in policies relating to the activities of that agency under the National Drug Control Program prior to implementation of such change. The Director shall promptly review such proposed change and certify to the head of that agency in writing whether such change is consistent with the National Drug Control Strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If prior notice of a proposed change under paragraph (1) is not practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the head of the National Drug Control Program agency shall notify the Director of the proposed change as soon as practicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon such notification, the Director shall review the change and certify to the head of that agency in writing whether the change is consistent with the National Drug Control Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General Services Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Director, on a reimbursable basis, such administrative support services as the Director may request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounting of funds expended</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than February 1 of each year, in accordance with guidance issued by the Director, the head of each National Drug Control Program agency shall submit to the Director a detailed accounting of all funds expended by the agency for National Drug Control Program activities during the previous fiscal year and shall ensure such detailed accounting is authenticated for the previous fiscal year by the Inspector General for such agency prior to the submission to the Director as frequently as determined by the Inspector General but not less frequently than every 3 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall submit to Congress not later than April 1 of each year the information submitted to the Director under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drug court training and technical assistance program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director may make a grant to a nonprofit organization for the purpose of providing training and technical assistance to drug courts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tracking system for federally funded grant programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director, or the head of an agency designated by the Director, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall track federally-funded grant programs to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> ensure the public has electronic access to information identifying:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all drug control grants and pertinent identifying information for each grant; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any available performance metrics, evaluations, or other information indicating the effectiveness of such programs;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitate efforts to identify duplication, overlap, or gaps in funding to provide increased accountability of Federally-funded grants for substance use disorder treatment, prevention, and enforcement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identify barriers that may impede applicants in the grant application process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Drug Control Program Agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The head of each National Drug Control Program agency shall provide to the Director a complete list of all drug control program grant programs and any other relevant information for inclusion in the system developed under paragraph (1) and annually update such list.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updating existing systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director may meet the requirements of this subsection by utilizing, updating, or improving existing Federal information systems to ensure they meet the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2018-10-24">October 24, 2018</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report examining implementation of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 705, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–680</ref>, 2681–693; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title I, § 104</ref>, title VI, § 602, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3510</ref>, 3533; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), (b)(2), 8207, 8217(g), <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4113, 4124; <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (6), <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1155</ref>, 1156.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1705.</num>
<heading> Development, submission, implementation, and assessment of National Drug Control Strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of drug policy priorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall release a statement of drug control policy priorities in the calendar year of a Presidential inauguration following the inauguration, but not later than April 1.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Drug Control Strategy submitted by the President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than the first Monday in February following the year in which the term of the President commences, and every 2 years thereafter, the President shall submit to Congress a National Drug Control Strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of the National Drug Control Strategy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall promulgate the National Drug Control Strategy, which shall set forth a comprehensive plan to reduce illicit drug use and the consequences of such illicit drug use in the United States by limiting the availability of and reducing the demand for illegal drugs and promoting prevention, early intervention, treatment, and recovery support for individuals with substance use disorders.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local commitment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall seek the support and commitment of State, local, and Tribal officials in the formulation and implementation of the National Drug Control Strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy based on evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall ensure the National Drug Control Strategy is based on the best available evidence regarding the policies that are most effective in reducing the demand for and supply of illegal drugs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Process for development and submission of National Drug Control Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing and effectively implementing the National Drug Control Strategy, the Director—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall consult with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the heads of the National Drug Control Program agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each Coordinator listed in <ref>section 1703 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Interdiction Committee and the Emerging Threats Committee;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the appropriate congressional committees and any other committee of jurisdiction;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> State, local, and Tribal officials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> private citizens and organizations, including community and faith-based organizations, with experience and expertise in demand reduction;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> private citizens and organizations with experience and expertise in supply reduction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> appropriate representatives of foreign governments; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in satisfying the requirements of subparagraph (A), shall ensure, to the maximum extent possible, that State, local, and Tribal officials and relevant private organizations commit to support and take steps to achieve the goals and objectives of the National Drug Control Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of the National Drug Control Strategy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The National Drug Control Strategy submitted under subsection (a)(2) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A mission statement detailing the major functions of the National Drug Control Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Comprehensive, research-based, long-range, quantifiable goals for reducing illicit drug use, and the consequences of illicit drug use in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Annual quantifiable and measurable objectives and specific targets to accomplish long-term quantifiable goals that the Director determines may be achieved during each year beginning on the date on which the National Drug Control Strategy is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A 5-year projection for the National Drug Control Program and budget priorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A review of international, State, local, and private sector drug control activities to ensure that the United States pursues coordinated and effective drug control at all levels of government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> A description of how each goal established under subparagraph (B) will be achieved, including for each goal—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a list of each relevant National Drug Control Program agency and each such agency’s related programs, activities, and available assets and the role of each such program, activity, and asset in achieving such goal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a list of relevant stakeholders and each such stakeholder’s role in achieving such goal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an estimate of Federal funding and other resources needed to achieve such goal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a list of each existing or new coordinating mechanism needed to achieve such goal; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a description of the Office’s role in facilitating the achievement of such goal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> For each year covered by the Strategy, a performance evaluation plan for each goal established under subparagraph (B) for each National Drug Control Program agency, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> specific performance measures for each National Drug Control Program agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> annual and, to the extent practicable, quarterly objectives and targets for each performance measure; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an estimate of Federal funding and other resources needed to achieve each performance objective and target.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A list identifying existing data sources or a description of data collection needed to evaluate performance, including a description of how the Director will obtain such data.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> A list of any anticipated challenges to achieving the National Drug Control Strategy goals and planned actions to address such challenges.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> A description of how each goal established under subparagraph (B) was determined, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of each required consultation and a description of how such consultation was incorporated; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> data, research, or other information used to inform the determination to establish the goal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> A description of the current prevalence of illicit drug use in the United States, including both the availability of illicit drugs and the prevalence of substance use disorders.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Such other statistical data and information as the Director considers appropriate to demonstrate and assess trends relating to illicit drug use, the effects and consequences of illicit drug use (including the effects on children), supply reduction, demand reduction, drug-related law enforcement, and the implementation of the National Drug Control Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<chapeau> A systematic plan for increasing data collection to enable real time surveillance of drug control threats, developing analysis and monitoring capabilities, and identifying and addressing policy questions related to the National Drug Control Strategy and Program, which shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a list of policy-relevant questions for which the Director and each National Drug Control Program agency intends to develop evidence to support the National Drug Control Program and Strategy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a list of data the Director and each National Drug Control Program agency intends to collect, use, or acquire to facilitate the use of evidence in drug control policymaking and monitoring;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a list of methods and analytical approaches that may be used to develop evidence to support the National Drug Control Program and Strategy and related policy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a list of any challenges to developing evidence to support policymaking, including any barriers to accessing, collecting, or using relevant data;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a description of the steps the Director and the head of each National Drug Control Program agency will take to effectuate the plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any other relevant information as determined by the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<chapeau> A plan to expand treatment of substance use disorders, which shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify unmet needs for treatment for substance use disorders and a strategy for closing the gap between available and needed treatment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> describe the specific roles and responsibilities of the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies for implementing the plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> identify the specific resources required to enable the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies to implement that strategy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> identify the resources, including private sources, required to eliminate the unmet need for evidence-based substance use disorder treatment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing the plan required under paragraph (1)(M), the Director shall consult with the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The public.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any evaluation or analysis units and personnel of the Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Office officials responsible for implementing privacy policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Office officials responsible for data governance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any other individual or entity as determined by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional strategies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall include in the National Drug Control Strategy the additional strategies described under this paragraph and shall comply with the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Provide a copy of the additional strategies to the appropriate congressional committees and to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Issue the additional strategies in consultation with the head of each relevant National Drug Control Program agency, any relevant official of a State, local, or Tribal government, and the government of other relevant countries.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Not change any existing agency authority or construe any strategy described under this paragraph to amend or modify any law governing interagency relationship but may include recommendations about changes to such authority or law.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Present separately from the rest of any strategy described under this paragraph any information classified under criteria established by an Executive order, or whose public disclosure, as determined by the Director or the head of any relevant National Drug Control Program agency, would be detrimental to the law enforcement or national security activities of any Federal, State, local, or Tribal agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for Southwest Border Counternarcotics Strategy</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Southwest Border Counternarcotics Strategy shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> set forth the Government’s strategy for preventing the illegal trafficking of drugs across the international border between the United States and Mexico, including through ports of entry and between ports of entry on that border;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> state the specific roles and responsibilities of the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies for implementing that strategy; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> identify the specific resources required to enable the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies to implement that strategy.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific content related to drug tunnels between the United States and Mexico</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Southwest Border Counternarcotics Strategy shall include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a strategy to end the construction and use of tunnels and subterranean passages that cross the international border between the United States and Mexico for the purpose of illegal trafficking of drugs across such border; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> recommendations for criminal penalties for persons who construct or use such a tunnel or subterranean passage for such a purpose.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for Northern Border Counternarcotics Strategy</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Northern Border Counternarcotics Strategy shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> set forth the strategy of the Federal Government for preventing the illegal trafficking of drugs across the international border between the United States and Canada, including through ports of entry and between ports of entry on the border;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> state the specific roles and responsibilities of each relevant National Drug Control Program agency for implementing the strategy;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> identify the specific resources required to enable the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies to implement the strategy;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> be designed to promote, and not hinder, legitimate trade and travel; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> reflect the unique nature of small communities along the international border between the United States and Canada, ongoing cooperation and coordination with Canadian law,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002185">1</ref> enforcement authorities, and variations in the volumes of vehicles and pedestrians crossing through ports of entry along the international border between the United States and Canada.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific content related to cross-border Indian reservations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Northern Border Counternarcotics Strategy shall include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a strategy to end the illegal trafficking of drugs to or through Indian reservations on or near the international border between the United States and Canada; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> recommendations for additional assistance, if any, needed by Tribal law enforcement agencies relating to the strategy, including an evaluation of Federal technical and financial assistance, infrastructure capacity building, and interoperability deficiencies.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classified information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any contents of the National Drug Control Strategy that involve information properly classified under criteria established by an Executive order shall be presented to Congress separately from the rest of the National Drug Control Strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of data and information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In selecting data and information for inclusion in the Strategy, the Director shall ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the inclusion of data and information that will permit analysis of current trends against previously compiled data and information where the Director believes such analysis enhances long-term assessment of the National Drug Control Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the inclusion of data and information to permit a standardized and uniform assessment of the effectiveness of drug treatment programs in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of revised Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may submit to Congress a revised National Drug Control Strategy that meets the requirements of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at any time, upon a determination of the President, in consultation with the Director, that the National Drug Control Strategy in effect is not sufficiently effective; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if a new President or Director takes office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure of Director to Submit National Drug Control Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Director does not submit a National Drug Control Strategy to Congress in accordance with subsection (a)(2), not later than five days after the first Monday in February following the year in which the term of the President commences, the Director shall send a notification to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> explaining why the Strategy was not submitted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specifying the date by which the Strategy will be submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drug Control Data Dashboard</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall collect and disseminate, as appropriate, such information as the Director determines is appropriate, but not less than the information described in this subsection. The data shall be publicly available in a machine-readable format on the online portal of the Office, and to the extent practicable on the Drug Control Data Dashboard.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall publish to the online portal of the Office in a machine-readable, sortable, and searchable format, or to the extent practicable, establish and maintain a data dashboard on the online portal of the Office to be known as the “Drug Control Data Dashboard”. To the extent practicable, when establishing the Drug Control Dashboard, the Director shall ensure the user interface of the dashboard is constructed with modern design standards. To the extent practicable, the data made available on the dashboard shall be publicly available in a machine-readable format and searchable by year, agency, drug, and location.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The data included in the Drug Control Data Dashboard shall be updated quarterly to the extent practicable, but not less frequently than annually and shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For each substance identified by the Director as having a significant impact on the prevalence of illicit drug use—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> data sufficient to show the quantities of such substance available in the United States, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total amount seized and disrupted in the calendar year and each of the previous 3 calendar years, including to the extent practicable the amount seized by State, local, and Tribal governments;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the known and estimated flows into the United States from all sources in the calendar year and each of the previous 3 calendar years;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the total amount of known flows that could not be interdicted or disrupted in the calendar year and each of the previous 3 calendar years;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the known and estimated levels of domestic production in the calendar year and each of the previous three calendar years, including the levels of domestic production if the drug is a prescription drug, as determined under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.], for which a listing is in effect under <ref>section 812 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> the average street price for the calendar year and the highest known street price during the preceding 10-year period; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, related prosecutions by State, local, and Tribal governments; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002186">2</ref></content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> data sufficient to show the frequency of use of such substance, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> use of such substance in the workplace and productivity lost by such use;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> use of such substance by arrestees, probationers, and parolees;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> crime and criminal activity related to such substance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, related prosecutions by State, local, and Tribal governments.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> For the calendar year and each of the previous three years data sufficient to show, disaggregated by State and, to the extent feasible, by region within a State, county, or city, the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The number of fatal and non-fatal overdoses caused by each drug identified under subparagraph (A)(i).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The prevalence of substance use disorders.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The number of individuals who have received substance use disorder treatment, including medication assisted treatment, for a substance use disorder, including treatment provided through publicly-financed health care programs.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The extent of the unmet need for substance use disorder treatment, including the unmet need for medication-assisted treatment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Data sufficient to show the extent of prescription drug diversion, trafficking, and misuse in the calendar year and each of the previous 3 calendar years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any quantifiable measures the Director determines to be appropriate to detail progress toward the achievement of the goals of the National Drug Control Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of an annual national drug control assessment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than the first Monday in February of each year, the Director shall submit to the President, Congress, and the appropriate congressional committees, a report assessing the progress of each National Drug Control Program agency toward achieving each goal, objective, and target contained in the National Drug Control Strategy applicable to the prior fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Process for development of the annual assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than November 1 of each year, the head of each National Drug Control Program agency shall submit, in accordance with guidance issued by the Director, to the Director an evaluation of progress by the agency with respect to the National Drug Control Strategy goals using the performance measures for the agency developed under this chapter, including progress with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> success in achieving the goals of the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> success in reducing domestic and foreign sources of illegal drugs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> success in expanding access to and increasing the effectiveness of substance use disorder treatment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> success in protecting the borders of the United States (and in particular the Southwestern border of the United States) from penetration by illegal narcotics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> success in reducing crime associated with drug use in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> success in reducing the negative health and social consequences of drug use in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> implementation of evidence-based substance use disorder treatment and prevention programs in the United States and improvements in the adequacy and effectiveness of such programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> success in increasing the prevention of illicit drug use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of the annual assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall include in the annual assessment required under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of each evaluation received by the Director under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the progress of each National Drug Control Program agency toward the National Drug Control Strategy goals of the agency using the performance measures for the agency developed under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the effectiveness of each National Drug Control Program agency and program in achieving the National Drug Control Strategy for the previous year, including a specific evaluation of whether the applicable goals, measures, objectives, and targets for the previous year were met; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the assessments required under this subsection shall be based on the Performance Measurement System.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002187">3</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance measurement system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than February 1 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress as part of the National Drug Control Strategy, a description of a national drug control performance measurement system, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develops 2-year and 5-year performance measures and targets for each National Drug Control Strategy goal and objective established for reducing drug use, availability, and the consequences of drug use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describes the sources of information and data that will be used for each performance measure incorporated into the performance measurement system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identifies major programs and activities of the National Drug Control Program agencies that support the goals and annual objectives of the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> evaluates the contribution of demand reduction and supply reduction activities as defined in <ref>section 1701 of this title</ref> implemented by each National Drug Control Program agency in support of the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> monitors consistency between the drug-related goals and objectives of the National Drug Control Program agencies and ensures that each agency’s goals and budgets support and are fully consistent with the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> coordinates the development and implementation of national drug control data collection and reporting systems to support policy formulation and performance measurement, including an assessment of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the quality of current drug use measurement instruments and techniques to measure supply reduction and demand reduction activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the adequacy of the coverage of existing national drug use measurement instruments and techniques to measure the illicit drug user population, and groups that are at risk for illicit drug use;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the adequacy of the coverage of existing national treatment outcome monitoring systems to measure the effectiveness of drug abuse treatment in reducing illicit drug use and criminal behavior during and after the completion of substance abuse treatment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the actions the Director shall take to correct any deficiencies and limitations identified pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> develops performance measures and targets for the National Drug Control Strategy for supplemental strategies (the Southwest Border, Northern Border, and Caribbean Border Counternarcotics Strategies) to effectively evaluate region-specific goals, to the extent the performance measurement system does not adequately measure the effectiveness of the strategies, as determined by the Director, such strategies may evaluate interdiction efforts at and between ports of entry, interdiction technology, intelligence sharing, diplomacy, and other appropriate metrics, specific to each supplemental strategies region, as determined by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A description of any modifications made during the preceding year to the national drug performance measurement system described in subsection (c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002188">4</ref> shall be included in each report submitted under subsection (b).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002189">5</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 706, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–681</ref>, 2681–693; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title II</ref>, §§ 201, 202, title VI, § 602, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3513</ref>, 3517, 3533; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), (b)(2), 8221(a), <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4134; <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (2), (c)(1)(B), (d), <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1155</ref>, 1158; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIII, § 5302</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3249</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1706.</num>
<heading> High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Office a program to be known as the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The purpose of the Program is to reduce drug trafficking and drug production in the United States by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> facilitating cooperation among Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies to share information and implement coordinated enforcement activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enhancing law enforcement intelligence sharing among Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> providing reliable law enforcement intelligence to law enforcement agencies needed to design effective enforcement strategies and operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> supporting coordinated law enforcement strategies which maximize use of available resources to reduce the supply of illegal drugs in designated areas and in the United States as a whole.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, heads of the National Drug Control Program agencies, and the Governor of each applicable State, may designate any specified area of the United States as a high intensity drug trafficking area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After making a designation under paragraph (1) and in order to provide Federal assistance to the area so designated, the Director may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> obligate such sums as are appropriated for the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> direct the temporary reassignment of Federal personnel to such area, subject to the approval of the head of the department or agency that employs such personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take any other action authorized under <ref>section 1703 of this title</ref> to provide increased Federal assistance to those areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> coordinate activities under this section (specifically administrative, recordkeeping, and funds management activities) with State, local, and tribal officials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petitions for designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall establish regulations under which a coalition of interested law enforcement agencies from an area may petition for designation as a high intensity drug trafficking area. Such regulations shall provide for a regular review by the Director of the petition, including a recommendation regarding the merit of the petition to the Director by a panel of qualified, independent experts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors for consideration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In considering whether to designate an area under this section as a high intensity drug trafficking area, the Director shall consider, in addition to such other criteria as the Director considers to be appropriate, the extent to which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the area is a significant center of illegal drug production, manufacturing, importation, or distribution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies have committed resources to respond to the drug trafficking problem in the area, thereby indicating a determination to respond aggressively to the problem;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> drug-related activities in the area are having a significant harmful impact in the area, and in other areas of the country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a significant increase in allocation of Federal resources is necessary to respond adequately to drug-related activities in the area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organization of high intensity drug trafficking areas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Board and officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible for funds appropriated under this section, each high intensity drug trafficking area shall be governed by an Executive Board. The Executive Board shall designate a chairman, vice chairman, and any other officers to the Executive Board that it determines are necessary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Executive Board of a high intensity drug trafficking area shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing direction and oversight in establishing and achieving the goals of the high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> managing the funds of the high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> reviewing and approving all funding proposals consistent with the overall objective of the high intensity drug trafficking area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> reviewing and approving all reports to the Director on the activities of the high intensity drug trafficking area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">None of the funds appropriated under this section may be expended for any high intensity drug trafficking area, or for a partnership or region of a high intensity drug trafficking area, if the Executive Board for such area, region, or partnership, does not apportion an equal number of votes between representatives of participating Federal agencies and representatives of participating State, local, and tribal agencies. Where it is impractical for an equal number of representatives of Federal agencies and State, local, and tribal agencies to attend a meeting of an Executive Board in person, the Executive Board may use a system of proxy votes or weighted votes to achieve the voting balance required by this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No agency relationship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The eligibility requirements of this section are intended to ensure the responsible use of Federal funds. Nothing in this section is intended to create an agency relationship between individual high intensity drug trafficking areas and the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall ensure that not more than a total of 5 percent of Federal funds appropriated for the Program are expended for substance use disorder treatment programs and drug prevention programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Counterterrorism activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director may authorize use of resources available for the Program to assist Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies in investigations and activities related to terrorism and prevention of terrorism, especially but not exclusively with respect to such investigations and activities that are also related to drug trafficking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that assistance provided under paragraph (1) remains incidental to the purpose of the Program to reduce drug availability and carry out drug-related law enforcement activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that significant resources of the Program are not redirected to activities exclusively related to terrorism, except on a temporary basis under extraordinary circumstances, as determined by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Role of Drug Enforcement Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall ensure that a representative of the Drug Enforcement Administration is included in the Intelligence Support Center for each high intensity drug trafficking area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual HIDTA Program budget submissions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As part of the documentation that supports the President’s annual budget request for the Office, the Director shall submit to Congress a budget justification that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount proposed for each high intensity drug trafficking area, conditional upon a review by the Office of the request submitted by the HIDTA and the performance of the HIDTA, with supporting narrative descriptions and rationale for each request;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed justification that explains—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reasons for the proposed funding level; how such funding level was determined based on a current assessment of the drug trafficking threat in each high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> how such funding will ensure that the goals and objectives of each such area will be achieved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> how such funding supports the National Drug Control Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount of HIDTA funds used to investigate and prosecute organizations and individuals trafficking in methamphetamine in the prior calendar year, and a description of how those funds were used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emerging threat response fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Director may expend up to 10 percent of the amounts appropriated under this section on a discretionary basis, to respond to any emerging drug trafficking threat in an existing high intensity drug trafficking area, or to establish a new high intensity drug trafficking area or expand an existing high intensity drug trafficking area, in accordance with the criteria established under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of impact</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In allocating funds under this subsection, the Director shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the impact of activities funded on reducing overall drug traffic in the United States, or minimizing the probability that an emerging drug trafficking threat will spread to other areas of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other criteria as the Director considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2006-12-29">December 29, 2006</date>, the Director shall, after consulting with the Executive Boards of each designated high intensity drug trafficking area, submit a report to Congress that describes, for each designated high intensity drug trafficking area—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the specific purposes for the high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the specific long-term and short-term goals and objectives for the high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the measurements that will be used to evaluate the performance of the high intensity drug trafficking area in achieving the long-term and short-term goals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the reporting requirements needed to evaluate the performance of the high intensity drug trafficking area in achieving the long-term and short-term goals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of HIDTA Program as part of National Drug Control Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For each designated high intensity drug trafficking area, the Director shall submit, as part of the annual National Drug Control Strategy report, a report that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> describes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the specific purposes for the high intensity drug trafficking area; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the specific long-term and short-term goals and objectives for the high intensity drug trafficking area; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes an evaluation of the performance of the high intensity drug trafficking area in accomplishing the specific long-term and short-term goals and objectives identified under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of drug enforcement task forces in high intensity drug trafficking areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2006-12-29">December 29, 2006</date>, and as part of each subsequent annual National Drug Control Strategy report, the Director shall submit to Congress a report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assessing the number and operation of all federally funded drug enforcement task forces within each high intensity drug trafficking area; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each Federal, State, local, and tribal drug enforcement task force operating in the high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> how such task forces coordinate with each other, with any high intensity drug trafficking area task force, and with investigations receiving funds from the Organized Crime and Drug Enforcement Task Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> what steps, if any, each such task force takes to share information regarding drug trafficking and drug production with other federally funded drug enforcement task forces in the high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the role of the high intensity drug trafficking area in coordinating the sharing of such information among task forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the nature and extent of cooperation by each Federal, State, local, and tribal participant in ensuring that such information is shared among law enforcement agencies and with the high intensity drug trafficking area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the nature and extent to which information sharing and enforcement activities are coordinated with joint terrorism task forces in the high intensity drug trafficking area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any recommendations for measures needed to ensure that task force resources are utilized efficiently and effectively to reduce the availability of illegal drugs in the high intensity drug trafficking areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of law enforcement intelligence sharing in High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-12-29">December 29, 2006</date>, and as part of each subsequent annual National Drug Control Strategy report, the Director, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to Congress a report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluating existing and planned law enforcement intelligence systems supported by each high intensity drug trafficking area, or utilized by task forces receiving any funding under the Program, including the extent to which such systems ensure access and availability of law enforcement intelligence to Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies within the high intensity drug trafficking area and outside of it;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the extent to which Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies participating in each high intensity drug trafficking area are sharing law enforcement intelligence information to assess current drug trafficking threats and design appropriate enforcement strategies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the measures needed to improve effective sharing of information and law enforcement intelligence regarding drug trafficking and drug production among Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement participating in a high intensity drug trafficking area, and between such agencies and similar agencies outside the high intensity drug trafficking area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of Law enforcement intelligence sharing with Organized Crime Drug Enforcement Task Force program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall ensure that any drug enforcement intelligence obtained by the Intelligence Support Center for each high intensity drug trafficking area is shared, on a timely basis, with the drug intelligence fusion center operated by the Organized Crime Drug Enforcement Task Force of the Department of Justice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds to combat methamphetamine trafficking</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As part of the documentation that supports the President’s annual budget request for the Office, the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing the use of HIDTA funds to investigate and prosecute organizations and individuals trafficking in methamphetamine in the prior calendar year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of methamphetamine manufacturing facilities discovered through HIDTA-funded initiatives in the previous fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amounts of methamphetamine or listed chemicals (as that term is defined in <ref>section 802(33) of this title</ref>) seized by HIDTA-funded initiatives in the area during the previous year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> law enforcement intelligence and predictive data from the Drug Enforcement Administration showing patterns and trends in abuse, trafficking, and transportation in methamphetamine and listed chemicals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before the Director awards any funds to a high intensity drug trafficking area, the Director shall certify that the law enforcement entities participating in that HIDTA are providing laboratory seizure data to the national clandestine laboratory database at the El Paso Intelligence Center.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Office of National Drug Control Policy to carry out this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $240,000,000 for fiscal year 2007;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $250,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $260,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $270,000,000 for fiscal year 2010;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $280,000,000 for each of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002190">1</ref> fiscal year 2011; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> $280,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(q)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall ensure that, of the amounts appropriated for a fiscal year for the Program, at least $7,000,000 is used in high intensity drug trafficking areas with severe neighborhood safety and illegal drug distribution problems.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The funds used under paragraph (1) shall be used to ensure the safety of neighborhoods and the protection of communities, including the prevention of the intimidation of witnesses of illegal drug distribution and related activities and the establishment of, or support for, programs that provide protection or assistance to witnesses in court proceedings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Best practice models</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall work with HIDTAs to develop and maintain best practice models to assist State, local, and Tribal governments in addressing witness safety, relocation, financial and housing assistance, or any other services related to witness protection or assistance in cases of illegal drug distribution and related activities. The Director shall ensure dissemination of the best practice models to each HIDTA.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(r)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drug overdose response strategy implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director may use funds appropriated to carry out this section to implement a drug overdose response strategy in high intensity drug trafficking areas on a nationwide basis by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinating multi-disciplinary efforts to prevent, reduce, and respond to drug overdoses, including the uniform reporting of fatal and non-fatal overdoses to public health and safety officials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increasing data sharing among public safety and public health officials concerning drug-related abuse trends, including new psychoactive substances, and related crime; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enabling collaborative deployment of prevention, intervention, and enforcement resources to address substance use addiction and narcotics trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(s)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplemental grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director is authorized to use not more than $10,000,000 of the amounts otherwise appropriated to carry out this section to provide supplemental competitive grants to high intensity drug trafficking areas that have experienced high seizures of fentanyl and new psychoactive substances for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> purchasing portable equipment to test for fentanyl and other substances;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> training law enforcement officers and other first responders on best practices for handling fentanyl and other substances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> purchasing protective equipment, including overdose reversal drugs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 707, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–686</ref>, 2681–693; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title III</ref>, §§ 301, § 302(c), title VI, § 602, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3518</ref>, 3525, 3533; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), 8202(b)(2), 8205, 8208, 8209, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4113, 4114; <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1707.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8222(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4143</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1708.</num>
<heading> Emerging Threats Committee, plan, and media campaign</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall designate or appoint a United States Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator to perform the duties of that position described in this section and such other duties as may be determined by the Director. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emerging Threats Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Emerging Threats Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> monitor evolving and emerging drug threats in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify and discuss evolving and emerging drug trends in the United States using the criteria required to be established under paragraph (6);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist in the formulation of and oversee implementation of any plan described in subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide such other advice to the Coordinator and Director concerning strategy and policies for emerging drug threats and trends as the Committee determines to be appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> disseminate and facilitate the sharing with Federal, State, local, and Tribal officials and other entities as determined by the Director of pertinent information and data relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> recent trends in drug supply and demand;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> fatal and nonfatal overdoses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> demand for and availability of evidence-based substance use disorder treatment, including the extent of the unmet treatment need, and treatment admission trends;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> recent trends in drug interdiction, supply, and demand from State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> other subject matter as determined necessary by the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall designate one of the members of the Emerging Threats Committee to serve as Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall appoint other members of the Committee, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> representatives from National Drug Control Program agencies or other agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> representatives from State, local, and Tribal governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> representatives from other entities as designated by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The members of the Emerging Threats Committee shall meet, in person and not through any delegate or representative, not less frequently than once per calendar year, before June 1. At the call of the Director or the Chairperson, the Emerging Threats Committee may hold additional meetings as the members may choose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract, agreement, and other authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director may award contracts, enter into interagency agreements, manage individual projects, and conduct other activities in support of the identification of emerging drug threats and in support of the development, implementation, and assessment of any Emerging Threat Response Plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria to identify emerging drug threats</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Committee first meets, the Committee shall develop and recommend to the Director criteria to be used to identify an emerging drug threat or the termination of an emerging drug threat designation based on information gathered by the Committee, statistical data, and other evidence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director, in consultation with the Coordinator, the Committee, and the head of each National Drug Control Program agency, may designate an emerging drug threat in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards for designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director, in consultation with the Coordinator, shall promulgate and make publicly available standards by which a designation under paragraph (1) and the termination of such designation may be made. In developing such standards, the Director shall consider the recommendations of the committee and other criteria the Director considers to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public statement required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall publish a public written statement on the portal of the Office explaining the designation of an emerging drug threat or the termination of such designation and shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the availability of such statement when a designation or termination of such designation has been made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after making a designation under subsection (c), the Director shall publish and make publicly available an Emerging Threat Response Plan and notify the President and the appropriate congressional committees of such plan’s availability.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Concurrently with the annual submissions under <ref>section 1705(g) of this title</ref>, the Director shall update the plan and report on implementation of the plan, until the Director issues the public statement required under subsection (c)(3) to terminate the emerging drug threat designation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of an emerging threat response plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall include in the plan required under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a comprehensive strategic assessment of the emerging drug threat, including the current availability of, demand for, and effectiveness of evidence-based prevention, treatment, and enforcement programs and efforts to respond to the emerging drug threat;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> comprehensive, research-based, short- and long-term, quantifiable goals for addressing the emerging drug threat, including for reducing the supply of the drug designated as the emerging drug threat and for expanding the availability and effectiveness of evidence-based substance use disorder treatment and prevention programs to reduce the demand for the emerging drug threat;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> performance measures pertaining to the plan’s goals, including quantifiable and measurable objectives and specific targets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the level of funding needed to implement the plan, including whether funding is available to be reprogrammed or transferred to support implementation of the plan or whether additional appropriations are necessary to implement the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an implementation strategy for the media campaign under subsection (f), including goals as described under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph and performance measures, objectives, and targets, as described under subparagraph (C) of this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any other information necessary to inform the public of the status, progress, or response to an emerging drug threat.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 120 days after the date on which a designation is made under subsection (c), the Director, in consultation with the President, the appropriate congressional committees, and the head of each National Drug Control Program agency, shall issue guidance on implementation of the plan described in this subsection to the National Drug Control Program agencies and any other relevant agency determined to be necessary by the Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinator’s responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> direct the implementation of the plan among the agencies identified in the plan, State, local, and Tribal governments, and other relevant entities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> facilitate information-sharing between agencies identified in the plan, State, local, and Tribal governments, and other relevant entities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> monitor implementation of the plan by coordinating the development and implementation of collection and reporting systems to support performance measurement and adherence to the plan by agencies identified in the plan, where appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after the date on which a designation is made under subsection (c) and in accordance with subparagraph (A), the head of each agency identified in the plan shall submit to the Coordinator a report on implementation of the plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of media campaign</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon designation of an emerging drug threat, the Director shall evaluate whether a media campaign would be appropriate to address that threat.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National anti-drug media campaign</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall, to the extent feasible and appropriate, conduct a national anti-drug media campaign (referred to in this subsection as the “national media campaign”) in accordance with this subsection for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preventing substance abuse among people in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> educating the public about the dangers and negative consequences of substance use and abuse, including patient and family education about the characteristics and hazards of substance abuse and methods to safeguard against substance use, to include the safe disposal of prescription medications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> supporting evidence-based prevention programs targeting the attitudes, perception, and beliefs of persons concerning substance use and intentions to initiate or continue such use;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> encouraging individuals affected by substance use disorders to seek treatment and providing such individuals with information on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> how to recognize addiction issues;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> what forms of evidence-based treatment options are available; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> how to access such treatment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> combating the stigma of addiction and substance use disorders, including the stigma of treating such disorders with medication-assisted treatment therapies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> informing the public about the dangers of any drug identified by the Director as an emerging drug threat as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Amounts made available to carry out this subsection for the national media campaign may only be used for the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The purchase of media time and space, including the strategic planning for, tracking, and accounting of, such purchases.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Creative and talent costs, consistent with subparagraph (B)(i).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Advertising production costs, which may include television, radio, internet, social media, and other commercial marketing venues.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Testing and evaluation of advertising.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Evaluation of the effectiveness of the national media campaign.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Costs of contracts to carry out activities authorized by this subsection.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Partnerships with professional and civic groups, community-based organizations, including faith-based organizations, and government organizations related to the national media campaign.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> Entertainment industry outreach, interactive outreach, media projects and activities, public information, news media outreach, and corporate sponsorship and participation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> Operational and management expenses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific requirements</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Creative services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In using amounts for creative and talent costs under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Director shall use creative services donated at no cost to the Government wherever feasible and may only procure creative services for advertising—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> responding to high-priority or emergent campaign needs that cannot timely be obtained at no cost; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> intended to reach a minority, ethnic, or other special audience that cannot reasonably be obtained at no cost.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Testing and evaluation of advertising</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In using amounts for testing and evaluation of advertising under subparagraph (A)(iv), the Director shall test all advertisements prior to use in the national media campaign to ensure that the advertisements are effective with the target audience and meet industry-accepted standards. The Director may waive this requirement for advertisements using no more than 10 percent of the purchase of advertising time purchased under this subsection in a fiscal year and no more than 10 percent of the advertising space purchased under this subsection in a fiscal year, if the advertisements respond to emergent and time-sensitive campaign needs or the advertisements will not be widely utilized in the national media campaign.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For the planning of the campaign under paragraph (1), the Director may consult with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the head of any appropriate National Drug Control Program agency;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> experts on the designated drug;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> State, local, and Tribal government officials and relevant agencies;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> communications professionals;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> the public; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of effectiveness of national media campaign</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In using amounts for the evaluation of the effectiveness of the national media campaign under subparagraph (A)(v), the Director shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> designate an independent entity to evaluate by April 20 of each year the effectiveness of the national media campaign based on data from—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the Monitoring the Future Study published by the Department of Health and Human Services;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the National Survey on Drug Use and Health; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> other relevant studies or publications, as determined by the Director, including tracking and evaluation data collected according to marketing and advertising industry standards; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ensure that the effectiveness of the national media campaign is evaluated in a manner that enables consideration of whether the national media campaign has contributed to changes in attitude or behaviors among the target audience with respect to substance use and such other measures of evaluation as the Director determines are appropriate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advertising</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out this subsection, the Director shall ensure that sufficient funds are allocated to meet the stated goals of the national media campaign.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities and functions under the program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall determine the overall purposes and strategy of the national media campaign.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Director shall approve—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the strategy of the national media campaign;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> all advertising and promotional material used in the national media campaign; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the plan for the purchase of advertising time and space for the national media campaign.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Director shall be responsible for implementing a focused national media campaign to meet the purposes set forth in paragraph (1) and shall ensure—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> information disseminated through the campaign is accurate and scientifically valid; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> the campaign is designed using strategies demonstrated to be the most effective at achieving the goals and requirements of paragraph (1), which may include—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> a media campaign, as described in paragraph (2);</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> local, regional, or population specific messaging;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> the development of websites to publicize and disseminate information;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> conducting outreach and providing educational resources for parents;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ee)</num>
<content> collaborating with law enforcement agencies; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ff)</num>
<content> providing support for school-based public health education classes to improve teen knowledge about the effects of substance use.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">None of the amounts made available under paragraph (2) may be obligated or expended for any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To supplant current anti-drug community-based coalitions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To supplant pro bono public service time donated by national and local broadcasting networks for other public service campaigns.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For partisan political purposes, or to express advocacy in support of or to defeat any clearly identified candidate, clearly identified ballot initiative, or clearly identified legislative or regulatory proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To fund advertising that features any elected officials, persons seeking elected office, cabinet level officials, or other Federal officials employed pursuant to section 213 of Schedule C of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> To fund advertising that does not contain a primary message intended to reduce or prevent substance use.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> To fund advertising containing a primary message intended to promote support for the national media campaign or private sector contributions to the national media campaign.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Amounts made available under paragraph (2) for media time and space shall be matched by an equal amount of non-Federal funds for the national media campaign, or be matched with in-kind contributions of the same value.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No-cost match advertising direct relationship requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall ensure that not less than 85 percent of no-cost match advertising directly relates to substance abuse prevention consistent with the specific purposes of the national media campaign.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No-cost match advertising not directly related</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall ensure that no-cost match advertising that does not directly relate to substance abuse prevention consistent with the purposes of the national media campaign includes a clear anti-drug message. Such message is not required to be the primary message of the match advertising.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial and performance accountability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall cause to be performed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> audits and reviews of costs of the national media campaign pursuant to <ref>section 4706 of title 41</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an audit to determine whether the costs of the national media campaign are allowable under chapter 43 of title 41.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall submit on an annual basis a report to Congress that describes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the strategy of the national media campaign and whether specific objectives of the national media campaign were accomplished;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> steps taken to ensure that the national media campaign operates in an effective and efficient manner consistent with the overall strategy and focus of the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> plans to purchase advertising time and space;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> policies and practices implemented to ensure that Federal funds are used responsibly to purchase advertising time and space and eliminate the potential for waste, fraud, and abuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> all contracts entered into with a corporation, partnership, or individual working on behalf of the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the results of any financial audit of the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a description of any evidence used to develop the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> specific policies and steps implemented to ensure compliance with this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a detailed accounting of the amount of funds obligated during the previous fiscal year for carrying out the national media campaign, including each recipient of funds, the purpose of each expenditure, the amount of each expenditure, any available outcome information, and any other information necessary to provide a complete accounting of the funds expended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> a review and evaluation of the effectiveness of the national media campaign strategy for the past year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required notice for communication from the Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any communication, including an advertisement, paid for or otherwise disseminated by the Office directly or through a contract awarded by the Office shall include a prominent notice informing the audience that the communication was paid for by the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Office to carry out this section, $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 709, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–688</ref>, 2681–693; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, title VI, § 602, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3527</ref>, 3533; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), (b)(2), 8218(a), <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4125; <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (2), (8), <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1155</ref>, 1157.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1708a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–74, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1157</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1709.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title XI, § 1101(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3539</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1710.</num>
<heading> Drug Interdiction Coordinator and Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Interdiction Coordinator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent) as the United States Interdiction Coordinator to perform the duties of that position described in paragraph (2) and such other duties as may be determined by the Director with respect to coordination of efforts to interdict illicit drugs from entering the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The United States Interdiction Coordinator shall be responsible to the Director for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinating the interdiction activities of the National Drug Control Program agencies to ensure consistency with the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on behalf of the Director, developing and issuing, on or before September 1 of each year and in accordance with paragraph (4), a National Interdiction Command and Control Plan to ensure the coordination and consistency described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assessing the sufficiency of assets committed to illicit drug interdiction by the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> advising the Director on the efforts of each National Drug Control Program agency to implement the National Interdiction Command and Control Plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall assign such permanent staff of the Office as he considers appropriate to assist the United States Interdiction Coordinator to carry out the responsibilities described in paragraph (2), and may request that appropriate National Drug Control Program agencies detail or assign staff to assist in carrying out such responsibilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Interdiction Command and Control Plan</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The National Interdiction Command and Control Plan shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> set forth the Government’s strategy for drug interdiction;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> state the specific roles and responsibilities of the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies for implementing that strategy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> identify the specific resources required to enable the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies to implement that strategy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Before submission of the National Drug Control Strategy or annual assessment required under <ref>section 1705 of this title</ref>, as applicable, the United States Interdiction Coordinator shall issue the National Interdiction Command and Control Plan in consultation with the other members of the Interdiction Committee described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">On or before September 1 of each year, the Director, acting through the United States Interdiction Coordinator, shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees, to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate a report that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a copy of that year’s National Interdiction Command and Control Plan, including information about how each National Drug Control Program agency conducting drug interdiction activities is engaging with relevant international partners;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> information for the previous 10 years regarding the number and type of seizures of drugs by each National Drug Control Program agency conducting drug interdiction activities and statistical information on the geographic areas of such seizures; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> information for the previous 10 years regarding the number of air and maritime patrol hours undertaken by each National Drug Control Program agency conducting drug interdiction activities and statistical information on the geographic areas in which such patrol hours took place; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may include recommendations for changes to existing agency authorities or laws governing interagency relationships.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classified annex</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each report required to be submitted under subparagraph (C) shall be in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interdiction Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Interdiction Committee shall meet to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> discuss and resolve issues related to the coordination, oversight and integration of international, border, and domestic drug interdiction efforts in support of the National Drug Control Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> review the annual National Interdiction Command and Control Plan, and provide advice to the Director and the United States Interdiction Coordinator concerning that plan and how to strengthen international partnerships to better achieve the goals of that plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide such other advice to the Director concerning drug interdiction strategy and policies as the committee determines is appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall designate one of the members of the Interdiction Committee to serve as Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The members of the Interdiction Committee shall meet, in person and not through any delegate or representative, at least once per calendar year, before June 1. At the call of the Director or the Chairperson, the Interdiction Committee may hold additional meetings, which shall be attended by the members in person, or through such delegates or representatives as the members may choose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than September 30 of each year, the Chairperson of the Interdiction Committee shall submit to the Director and to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the results of the meetings and any significant findings of the Committee during the previous 12 months. The report required under this paragraph shall be in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may facilitate international drug control coordination efforts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII, § 711</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title I, § 103(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3507</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII, § 715</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–693</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8202(a), (b)(2), 8219, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>, 4132.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1710a.</num>
<heading> Requirement for disclosure of Federal sponsorship of all Federal advertising or other communication materials</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each advertisement or other communication paid for by the Office, either directly or through a contract awarded by the Office, shall include a prominent notice informing the target audience that the advertisement or other communication is paid for by the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advertisement or other communication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “advertisement or other communication” includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an advertisement disseminated in any form, including print or by any electronic means; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a communication by an individual in any form, including speech, print, or by any electronic means.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII, § 712</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title XI, § 1118</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3546</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C</ref>. title VII, § 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–693</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8202(a)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1711.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter except activities otherwise specified, to remain available until expended, $18,400,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII</ref>, §§ 714, 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–693</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title VI</ref>, §§ 601, 602, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8202</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1712.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1713.</num>
<heading> Authorization of use of environmentally-approved herbicides to eliminate illicit narcotics crops</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency are authorized to support the development and use of environmentally-approved herbicides to eliminate illicit narcotics crops, including coca, cannabis, and opium poppy, both in the United States and in foreign countries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VIII, § 834</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1714.</num>
<heading> Awards for demonstration programs by local partnerships to coerce abstinence in chronic hard-drug users under community supervision through the use of drug testing and sanctions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Awards required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall make competitive awards to fund demonstration programs by eligible partnerships for the purpose of reducing the use of illicit drugs by chronic hard-drug users living in the community while under the supervision of the criminal justice system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of award amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Award amounts received under this section shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support the efforts of the agencies, organizations, and researchers included in the eligible partnership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to develop and field a drug testing and graduated sanctions program for chronic hard-drug users living in the community under criminal justice supervision; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to assist individuals described in subsection (a) by strengthening rehabilitation efforts through such means as job training, drug treatment, or other services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible partnership defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “eligible partnership” means a working group whose application to the Director—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> identifies the roles played, and certifies the involvement of, two or more agencies or organizations, which may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State, local, or tribal agencies (such as those carrying out police, probation, prosecution, courts, corrections, parole, or treatment functions);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Federal agencies (such as the Drug Enforcement Agency, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, and United States Attorney offices); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> community-based organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes a qualified researcher;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> includes a plan for using judicial or other criminal justice authority to administer drug tests to individuals described in subsection (a) at least twice a week, and to swiftly and certainly impose a known set of graduated sanctions for non-compliance with community-release provisions relating to drug abstinence (whether imposed as a pre-trial, probation, or parole condition or otherwise);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> includes a strategy for responding to a range of substance use and abuse problems and a range of criminal histories;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> includes a plan for integrating data infrastructure among the agencies and organizations included in the eligible partnership to enable seamless, real-time tracking of individuals described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> includes a plan to monitor and measure the progress toward reducing the percentage of the population of individuals described in subsection (a) who, upon being summoned for a drug test, either fail to show up or who test positive for drugs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2009-06-01">June 1, 2009</date>, the Director shall submit to Congress a report that identifies the best practices in reducing the use of illicit drugs by chronic hard-drug users, including the best practices identified through the activities funded under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2010-06-01">June 1, 2010</date>, the Director shall submit to Congress a report on the demonstration programs funded under this section, including on the matters specified in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $4,900,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2009.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title VII, § 716</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title XI, § 1119</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3547</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. C</ref>. title VII, § 715, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–693</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–469, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8202(a)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1715.</num>
<heading> GAO audit</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 4 years after <date date="2018-10-24">October 24, 2018</date>, and every 4 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> conduct an audit relating to the programs and operations of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Office; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002191">1</ref> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> certain programs within the Office,<sup>1</sup> including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Drug-Free Communities Program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the campaign under <ref>section 1708(f) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the Director <sup>1</sup> and the appropriate congressional committees <sup>1</sup> a report containing an evaluation of and recommendations on the—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> policies and activities of the programs and operations subject to the audit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in the administration of the reviewed programs and operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> policy or management changes needed to prevent and detect fraud and abuse in such programs and operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8220</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>