<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 28A—</num>
<heading>FENTANYL ERADICATION AND NARCOTICS DETERRENCE OFF FENTANYL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2341.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “foreign person”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any citizen or national of a foreign country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any entity not organized under the laws of the United States or a jurisdiction within the United States; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include the government of a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowingly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “knowingly”, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “trafficking”, with respect to fentanyl, fentanyl precursors, or other related opioids, has the meaning given the term “opioid trafficking” in <ref>section 2302(8) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transnational criminal organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “transnational criminal organization” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any organization designated as a significant transnational criminal organization under part 590 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any of the organizations known as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Sinaloa Cartel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Jalisco New Generation Cartel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Gulf Cartel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Los Zetas Cartel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Juarez Cartel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the Tijuana Cartel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the Beltran-Leyva Cartel; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> La Familia Michoacana; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any successor organization to an organization described in subparagraph (B) or as otherwise determined by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “United States person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any person in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, § 3003</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>SANCTIONS IN RESPONSE TO NATIONAL EMERGENCY RELATING TO FENTANYL TRAFFICKING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2351.</num>
<heading> Finding; policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress finds that international trafficking of fentanyl, fentanyl precursors, or other related opioids constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and is a national emergency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the policy of the United States to apply economic and other financial sanctions to those who engage in the international trafficking of fentanyl, fentanyl precursors, or other related opioids to protect the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title I, § 3101</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 936</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2352.</num>
<heading> Use of national emergency authorities; reporting</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 1702 and 1704 of title 50 to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on actions taken by the executive branch pursuant to this subchapter and any national emergency declared with respect to the trafficking of fentanyl and trade in other illicit drugs, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the issuance of any new or revised regulations, policies, or guidance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the imposition of sanctions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the collection of relevant information from outside parties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the issuance or closure of general licenses, specific licenses, and statements of licensing policy by the Office of Foreign Assets Control;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of any pending enforcement cases; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the implementation of mitigation procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include the matters required under subparagraphs (C), (D), (E), and (F) of such paragraph in a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title I, § 3102</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 936</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2353.</num>
<heading> Imposition of sanctions with respect to fentanyl trafficking by transnational criminal organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person the President determines—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is knowingly involved in the significant trafficking of fentanyl, fentanyl precursors, or other related opioids, including such trafficking by a transnational criminal organization; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> otherwise is knowingly involved in significant activities of a transnational criminal organization relating to the trafficking of fentanyl, fentanyl precursors, or other related opioids.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.), may block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on actions taken by the executive branch with respect to the foreign persons identified under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title I, § 3103</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 936</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2354.</num>
<heading> Penalties; waivers; exceptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this subchapter or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this subchapter shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 1705 of title 50</ref> to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National security waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may waive the application of sanctions under this subchapter with respect to a foreign person if the President determines that such waiver is in the national security interest of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for intelligence activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subchapter shall not apply with respect to activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for compliance with international obligations and law enforcement activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sanctions under this subchapter shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success on <date date="1947-06-26">June 26, 1947</date>, and entered into force <date date="1947-11-21">November 21, 1947</date>, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out or assist law enforcement activity of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Humanitarian exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may not impose sanctions under this subchapter with respect to any person for conducting or facilitating a transaction for the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices or for the provision of humanitarian assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title I, § 3104</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 937</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2355.</num>
<heading> Treatment of forfeited property of transnational criminal organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of forfeited property to forfeiture funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any covered forfeited property shall be deposited into the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund established under <ref>section 9705 of title 31</ref> or the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund established under <ref>section 524(c) of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on any deposits made under paragraph (1) during the 180-day period preceding submission of the report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered forfeited property defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “covered forfeited property” means property—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> forfeited to the United States under chapter 46 or <ref>section 1963 of title 18</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> that belonged to or was possessed by an individual affiliated with or connected to a transnational criminal organization subject to sanctions under—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Fentanyl Sanctions Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 2301</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Executive Order 14059 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to imposing sanctions on foreign persons involved in the global illicit drug trade).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Blocked Assets Under Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter may be construed to affect the treatment of blocked assets of a terrorist party described in section 201(a) of the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 (<ref>28 U.S.C. 1610</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title I, § 3105</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ANTI-MONEY LAUNDERING MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2361.</num>
<heading> Treatment of transnational criminal organizations in suspicious transactions reports of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing instructions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>, the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall issue guidance or instructions to United States financial institutions for filing reports on suspicious transactions required under section 1010.320 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, related to suspected fentanyl trafficking by transnational criminal organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization of reports relating to fentanyl trafficking or transnational criminal organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall prioritize research into reports described in subsection (a) that indicate a connection to trafficking of fentanyl or related synthetic opioids or financing of suspected transnational criminal organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title II, § 3202</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>EXCEPTION RELATING TO IMPORTATION OF GOODS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2371.</num>
<heading> Exception relating to importation of goods</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority or a requirement to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property under this chapter shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “good” means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title III, § 3301</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>