<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 83—</num>
<heading>CORAL REEF CONSERVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6401.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to conserve and restore the condition of United States coral reef ecosystems challenged by natural and human-accelerated changes, including increasing ocean temperatures, changing ocean chemistry, coral bleaching, coral diseases, water quality degradation, invasive species, and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote the science-based management and sustainable use of coral reef ecosystems to benefit local communities and the Nation, including through improved integration and cooperation among Federal and non-Federal stakeholders responsible for managing coral reef resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to develop sound scientific information on the condition of coral reef ecosystems, continuing and emerging threats to such ecosystems, and the efficacy of innovative tools, technologies, and strategies to mitigate stressors and restore such ecosystems, including evaluation criteria to determine the effectiveness of management interventions, and accurate mapping for coral reef restoration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to assist in the preservation of coral reefs by supporting science-based, consensus-driven, and community-based coral reef management by covered States and covered Native entities, including monitoring, conservation, and restoration projects that empower local communities, small businesses, and nongovernmental organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide financial resources, technical assistance, and scientific expertise to supplement, complement, and strengthen community-based management programs and conservation and restoration projects of non-Federal reefs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to establish a formal mechanism for collecting and allocating monetary donations from the private sector to be used for coral reef conservation and restoration projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> to support rapid, effective, and science-based assessment and response to exigent circumstances that pose immediate and long-term threats to coral reefs, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coral disease outbreaks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> invasive or nuisance species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coral bleaching;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> natural disasters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> industrial or mechanical disasters, including vessel groundings, hazardous spills, and coastal construction accidents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to serve as a model for advancing similar international efforts to monitor, conserve, and restore coral reef ecosystems.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 202</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3931</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6402.</num>
<heading> Federal coral reef management and restoration activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator, the Secretary of the Interior, or the Secretary of Commerce may conduct activities described in subsection (b) to conserve and restore coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems that are consistent with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all applicable laws governing resource management in Federal and State waters, including this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coral reef action plans in effect under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Activities described in this subsection are activities to conserve, research, monitor, assess, and restore coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems in waters managed under the jurisdiction of a Federal agency specified in subsection (c) or in coordination with a State in waters managed under the jurisdiction of such State, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> developing, including through the collection of requisite in situ and remotely sensed data, high-quality and digitized maps reflecting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> current and historical live coral cover data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coral reef habitat quality data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> priority areas for coral reef conservation to maintain biodiversity and ecosystem structure and function, including the reef matrix, that benefit coastal communities and living marine resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> priority areas for coral reef restoration to enhance biodiversity and ecosystem structure and function, including the reef matrix, to benefit coastal communities and living marine resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> areas of concern that may require enhanced monitoring of coral health and cover;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> enhancing compliance with Federal laws that prohibit or regulate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the taking of coral products or species associated with coral reefs; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use and management of coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> long-term ecological monitoring of coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> implementing species-specific recovery plans for listed coral species consistent with the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> restoring degraded coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> reducing land-based stressors to coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> promoting ecologically sound navigation and anchorages, including through navigational aids and expansion of reef-safe anchorages and mooring buoy systems, to enhance recreational access while preventing or minimizing the likelihood of vessel impacts or other physical damage to coral reefs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> monitoring and responding to severe bleaching or mortality events, disease outbreaks, invasive species outbreaks, and significant maritime accidents, including hazardous spill cleanup and the removal of grounded vessels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> conducting scientific research that contributes to the understanding, sustainable use, and long-term conservation of coral reefs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> enhancing public awareness, understanding, and appreciation of coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems and their ecological and socioeconomic value; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> centrally archiving, managing, and distributing on a public website data sets and coral reef ecosystem assessments, including the data repositories of the Coral Reef Conservation Program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agencies specified</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A Federal agency specified in this subsection is one of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The National Park Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Office of Insular Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3932</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6403.</num>
<heading> National coral reef resilience strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than 2 years after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, develop a national coral reef resilience strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> review and revise the strategy—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less frequently than once every 15 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less frequently than once every 5 years, in the case of guidance on best practices under subsection (b)(4); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A discussion addressing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> continuing and emerging threats to the resilience of United States coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> remaining gaps in coral reef ecosystem research, monitoring, and assessment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the status of management cooperation and integration among Federal reef managers and covered reef managers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the status of efforts to manage and disseminate critical information, and enhance interjurisdictional data sharing, related to research, reports, data sets, and maps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> areas of special focus, which may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> improving natural coral recruitment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> preventing avoidable losses of corals and their habitat;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> enhancing the resilience of coral populations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> supporting a resilience-based management approach;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> developing, coordinating, and implementing watershed management plans;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> building and sustaining watershed management capacity at the local level;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> providing data essential for coral reef fisheries management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> building capacity for coral reef fisheries management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> increasing understanding of coral reef ecosystem services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> educating the public on the importance of coral reefs, threats and solutions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> evaluating intervention efficacy;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the status of conservation efforts, including the use of marine protected areas to serve as replenishment zones developed consistent with local practices and traditions and in cooperation with, and with respect for the scientific, technical, and management expertise and responsibilities of, covered reef managers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> science-based adaptive management and restoration efforts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> management of coral reef emergencies and disasters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A statement of national goals and objectives designed to guide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> future Federal coral reef management and restoration activities authorized under <ref>section 6402 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conservation and restoration priorities for grants awarded under <ref>section 6410 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> research priorities for the reef research coordination institutes designated under section 6412(b)(1)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002824">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A designation of priority areas for conservation, and priority areas for restoration, to support the review and approval of grants under <ref>section 6410(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Technical assistance in the form of general templates for use by covered reef managers and Federal reef managers to guide the development of coral reef action plans under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>, including guidance on the best science-based practices to respond to coral reef emergencies that can be included in coral reef action plans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing all elements of the strategy required by subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with the Secretary of the Interior, the Task Force, covered States, and covered Native entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consult with the Secretary of Defense, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> engage stakeholders, including covered States, coral reef stewardship partnerships, reef research institutes and research centers described in section 6412 <sup>1</sup> of this title, and recipients of grants under <ref>section 6410 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> solicit public review and comment regarding scoping and the draft strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress; publication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> submit the strategy required by subsection (a) and any revisions to the strategy to the appropriate congressional committees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> publish the strategy and any such revisions on public websites of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Coral Reef Conservation Program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Task Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3933</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6404.</num>
<heading> Coral reef action plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plans prepared by Federal reef managers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and 2 years after the date of publication of each National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy, each Federal reef manager shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prepare a coral reef action plan to guide management and restoration activities to be undertaken within the responsibilities and jurisdiction of the manager; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a reef under the jurisdiction of a Federal reef manager for which there is an action plan in effect as of <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, update that plan to comply with the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A plan prepared under paragraph (1) by a Federal reef manager shall include a discussion of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Short- and medium-term coral reef conservation and restoration objectives within the jurisdiction of the manager.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A current adaptive management framework to inform research, monitoring, and assessment needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Tools, strategies, and partnerships necessary to identify, monitor, and address pollution, water quality, and other negative impacts to coral reef ecosystems within the jurisdiction of the manager.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The status of efforts to improve coral reef ecosystem management cooperation and integration between Federal reef managers and covered reef managers, including the identification of existing research and monitoring activities that can be leveraged for coral reef status and trends assessments within the jurisdiction of the manager.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Estimated budgetary and resource considerations necessary to carry out the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Contingencies for response to and recovery from emergencies and disasters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> In the case of an updated plan, annual records of significant management and restoration actions taken under the previous plan, cash and noncash resources used to undertake the actions, and the source of such resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Documentation by the Federal reef manager that the plan is consistent with the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> A data management plan to ensure data, assessments, and accompanying information are appropriately preserved, curated, publicly accessible, and broadly reusable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Task Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Federal reef manager shall submit a plan prepared under paragraph (1) to the Task Force.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of Administrative Procedure Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each plan prepared under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the requirements of subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5 (commonly known as the “Administrative Procedure Act”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plans prepared by covered reef managers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A covered reef manager may elect to prepare, submit to the Task Force, and maintain a coral reef action plan to guide management and restoration activities to be undertaken within the responsibilities and jurisdiction of the manager.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A plan prepared under this subsection shall remain in effect for 5 years, or until an updated plan is submitted to the Task Force, whichever occurs first.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A plan prepared under paragraph (1) by a covered reef manager—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall contain a discussion of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> short- and medium-term coral reef conservation and restoration objectives within the jurisdiction of the manager;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> estimated budgetary and resource considerations necessary to carry out the plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of an updated plan, annual records of significant management and restoration actions taken under the previous plan, cash and noncash resources used to undertake the actions, and the source of such resources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> contingencies for response to and recovery from emergencies and disasters; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> may contain a discussion of—</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the status of efforts to improve coral reef ecosystem management cooperation and integration between Federal reef managers and covered reef managers, including the identification of existing research and monitoring activities that can be leveraged for coral reef status and trends assessments within the jurisdiction of the manager;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a current adaptive management framework to inform research, monitoring, and assessment needs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> tools, strategies, and partnerships necessary to identify, monitor, and address pollution and water quality impacts to coral reef ecosystems within the jurisdiction of the manager; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a data management plan to ensure data, assessments, and accompanying information are appropriately preserved, curated, publicly accessible, and broadly reusable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator and the Task Force shall make reasonable efforts to provide technical assistance upon request by a Federal reef manager or covered reef manager developing a coral reef action plan under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall publish each coral reef action plan prepared and submitted to the Task Force under this section on the public website of the Coral Reef Conservation Program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 205</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6405.</num>
<heading> Coral reef stewardship partnerships</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To further community-based stewardship of coral reefs, coral reef stewardship partnerships for Federal and non-Federal coral reefs may be established in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards and procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall develop and adopt—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> standards for identifying individual coral reefs and ecologically significant units of coral reefs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> processes for adjudicating multiple applicants for stewardship of the same coral reef or ecologically significant unit of a reef to ensure no geographic overlap in representation among stewardship partnerships authorized by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership for Federal coral reefs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A coral reef stewardship partnership that has identified, as the subject of its stewardship activities, a coral reef or ecologically significant unit of a coral reef that is fully or partially under the management jurisdiction of any Federal agency specified in <ref>section 6402(c) of this title</ref> shall, at a minimum, include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That Federal agency, a representative of which shall serve as chairperson of the coral reef stewardship partnership.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A State or county’s resource management agency to the extent that such partnership covers a reef within such States or county’s jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A coral reef research center designated under <ref>section 6411(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A nongovernmental organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A covered Native entity culturally affiliated with the subject reef or ecologically significant unit, if any.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Such other members as the partnership considers appropriate, such as interested stakeholder groups and covered Native entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership for non-Federal coral reefs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A coral reef stewardship partnership that has identified, as the subject of its stewardship activities, a coral reef or ecologically significant component of a coral reef that is not under the management jurisdiction of any Federal agency specified in <ref>section 6402(c) of this title</ref> shall, at a minimum, include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A State or county’s resource management agency or a covered Native entity, a representative of which shall serve as the chairperson of the coral reef stewardship partnership.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A coral reef research center designated under <ref>section 6411(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A nongovernmental organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Such other members as the partnership considers appropriate, such as interested stakeholder groups.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional members</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), a coral reef stewardship partnership described in paragraph (1) may also include representatives of one or more Federal agencies.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests; approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A representative of a Federal agency described in subparagraph (A) may become a member of a coral reef stewardship partnership described in paragraph (1) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the representative submits a request to become a member to the chairperson of the partnership referred to in paragraph (1)(A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the chairperson consents to the request.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002825">1</ref> shall not apply to coral reef stewardship partnerships under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 206</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3937</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6406.</num>
<heading> Block grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In each fiscal year beginning in fiscal year 2023 and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall provide block grants of financial assistance of not less than $500,000 to each covered State to support management and restoration activities and further the implementation of coral reef action plans in effect under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref> by covered States and non-Federal coral reef stewardship partnerships in accordance with this section. The Administrator shall review each covered State’s application for block grant funding to ensure that applications are consistent with applicable action plans and the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of the Administrator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator is responsible for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> providing guidance on the proper documentation of expenditures authorized under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issuing annual solicitations to covered States for awards under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> determining the appropriate allocation of additional amounts among covered States in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of covered States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each covered State is responsible for documenting and reporting—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such State’s use of Federal funds received under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such expenditures of non-Federal funds made in furtherance of coral reef management and restoration as the Administrator determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator may seek to enter into a cooperative agreement with a covered State to fund coral reef conservation and restoration activities in waters managed under the jurisdiction of such covered State that are consistent with the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy and any applicable action plan under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> All Islands Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may enter into a cooperative agreement with the All Islands Committee of the Task Force to provide support for its activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 207</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6407.</num>
<heading> Coral Reef Stewardship Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (in this section referred to as the “Foundation”), authorizing the Foundation to receive, hold, and administer funds received under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Foundation shall establish an account, which shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be known as the “Coral Reef Stewardship Fund” (in this section referred to as the “Fund”); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve as the successor to the account known before <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, as the Coral Reef Conservation Fund and administered through a public-private partnership with the Foundation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Foundation shall deposit funds received under this section into the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund shall be available solely to support coral reef stewardship activities that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> further the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> are consistent with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> coral reef action plans in effect, if any, under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref> covering a coral reef or ecologically significant component of a coral reef to be impacted by such activities, if applicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment of amounts</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Foundation shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not required to meet current withdrawals in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest and proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of performance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall conduct a continuing review of all deposits into, and disbursements from, the Fund. Each review shall include a written assessment concerning the extent to which the Foundation has implemented the goals and requirements of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to solicit donations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Pursuant to an agreement entered into under subsection (a), the Foundation may accept, receive, solicit, hold, administer, and use any gift (including, notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, donations of services) to further the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits in Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, any funds received as a gift shall be deposited and maintained in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under an agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (a), and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator may transfer funds appropriated for such purposes to carry out this chapter to the Foundation. Amounts received by the Foundation under this subsection may be used for matching, in whole or in part, contributions (whether in money, services, or property) made to the Foundation by private persons, State or local government agencies, or covered Native entities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 208</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3939</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6408.</num>
<heading> Emergency assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, from funds appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under <ref>section 6414 of this title</ref>, the Administrator may provide emergency assistance to any covered State or coral reef stewardship partnership to respond to immediate harm to coral reefs or coral reef ecosystems arising from any of the exigent circumstances described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral reef exigent circumstances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall develop a list of, and criteria for, circumstances that pose an exigent threat to coral reefs, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> new and ongoing outbreaks of disease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> new and ongoing outbreaks of invasive or nuisance species;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> new and ongoing coral bleaching events;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> natural disasters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> industrial or mechanical incidents, such as vessel groundings, hazardous spills, or coastal construction accidents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> such other circumstances as the Administrator determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report on exigent circumstances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On February 1 of each year, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes locations with exigent circumstances described in subsection (b) that were considered but declined for emergency assistance, and the rationale for the decision; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to each instance in which emergency assistance under this section was provided—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the location and a description of the exigent circumstances that prompted the emergency assistance, the entity that received the assistance, and the current and expected outcomes from the assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that were curtailed as a result of providing the emergency assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of whether further action is needed to restore the affected coral reef, recommendations for such restoration, and a cost estimate to implement such recommendations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 209</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3940</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6409.</num>
<heading> Coral Reef Disaster Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (in this section referred to as the “Foundation”), authorizing the Foundation to receive, hold, and administer funds received under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Foundation shall establish an account, to be known as the “Coral Reef Disaster Fund” (in this section referred to as the “Fund”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Foundation shall deposit funds received under this section into the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Fund shall be available solely to support the long-term recovery of coral reefs from exigent circumstances described in <ref>section 6408(b) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in partnership with non-Federal stakeholders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in a manner that is consistent with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> coral reef action plans in effect, if any, under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment of amounts</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Foundation shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not required to meet current withdrawals in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest and proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The interest on, and the proceeds from, the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of performance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall conduct continuing reviews of all deposits into, and disbursements from, the Fund. Each such review shall include a written assessment concerning the extent to which the Foundation has implemented the goals and requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to solicit donations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Pursuant to an agreement entered into under subsection (a), the Foundation may accept, receive, solicit, hold, administer, and use any gift (including, notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, donations of services) to further the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits in Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, any funds received as a gift shall be deposited and maintained in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 210</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6410.</num>
<heading> Ruth D. Gates Coral Reef Conservation Grant Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall establish a program (to be known as the “Ruth D. Gates Coral Reef Conservation Grant Program”) to provide grants for projects for the conservation and restoration of coral reef ecosystems (in this section referred to as “coral reef projects”) pursuant to proposals approved by the Administrator in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirements for grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), Federal funds for any coral reef project for which a grant is provided under subsection (a) may not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The non-Federal share of the cost of a coral reef project may be provided by in-kind contributions and other noncash support.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator may waive all or part of the matching requirement under paragraph (1) if the Administrator determines that no reasonable means are available through which an applicant can meet the matching requirement with respect to a coral reef project and the probable benefit of the project outweighs the public interest in the matching requirement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An entity described in paragraph (2) may submit to the Administrator a proposal for a coral reef project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entities described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An entity described in this paragraph is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a covered reef manager or a covered Native entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a regional fishery management council established under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a coral reef stewardship partnership seeking to implement a coral reef action plan in effect under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a coral reef research center designated under <ref>section 6411(b) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a nongovernmental organization or research institution with demonstrated expertise in the conservation or restoration of coral reefs in practice or through significant contributions to the body of existing scientific research on coral reefs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project proposals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each proposal for a grant under this section for a coral reef project shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The name of the individual or entity responsible for conducting the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the qualifications of the individual or entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A succinct statement of the purposes of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An estimate of the funds and time required to complete the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Evidence of support for the project by appropriate representatives of States or other government jurisdictions in which the project will be conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Information regarding the source and amount of matching funding available to the applicant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> A description of how the project meets one or more of the criteria under subsection (e)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In the case of a proposal submitted by a coral reef stewardship partnership, a description of how the project aligns with the applicable coral reef action plan in effect under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Any other information the Administrator considers to be necessary for evaluating the eligibility of the project for a grant under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project review and approval</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall review each coral reef project proposal submitted under this section to determine if the project meets the criteria set forth in subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization of conservation projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall prioritize the awarding of funding for projects that meet the criteria for approval described in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subparagraphs (A) through (G) of subsection (f)(2) that are proposed to be conducted within priority areas identified for coral reef conservation by the Administrator under the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subparagraphs (E) through (L) of subsection (f)(2) that are proposed to be conducted within priority areas identified for coral reef restoration by the Administrator under the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review; approval or disapproval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after receiving a proposal for a coral reef project under this section, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> request and consider written comments on the proposal from each Federal agency, State government, covered Native entity, or other government jurisdiction, including the relevant regional fishery management councils established under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), or any National Marine Sanctuary or Marine National Monument, with jurisdiction or management authority over coral reef ecosystems in the area where the project is to be conducted, including the extent to which the project is consistent with locally established priorities, unless such entities were directly involved in the development of the project proposal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for the merit-based peer review of the proposal and require standardized documentation of that peer review;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> after considering any written comments and recommendations based on the reviews under subparagraphs (A) and (B), approve or disapprove the proposal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide written notification of that approval or disapproval, with summaries of all written comments, recommendations, and peer reviews, to the entity that submitted the proposal, and each of those States, covered Native entity, and other government jurisdictions that provided comments under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator may not approve a proposal for a coral reef project under this section unless the project—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> is consistent with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any Federal or non-Federal coral reef action plans in effect under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref> covering a coral reef or ecologically significant unit of a coral reef to be affected by the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> will enhance the conservation and restoration of coral reefs by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> addressing conflicts arising from the use of environments near coral reefs or from the use of corals, species associated with coral reefs, and coral products, including supporting consensus-driven and community-based planning and management initiatives for the protection of coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improving compliance with laws that prohibit or regulate the taking of coral products or species associated with coral reefs or regulate the use and management of coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> designing and implementing networks of real-time water quality monitoring along coral reefs, including data collection related to turbidity, nutrient availability, harmful algal blooms, and plankton assemblages, with an emphasis on coral reefs impacted by agriculture and urban development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promoting ecologically sound navigation and anchorages, including mooring buoy systems to promote enhanced recreational access, near coral reefs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> furthering the goals and objectives of coral reef action plans in effect under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> mapping the location and distribution of coral reefs and potential coral reef habitat;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> stimulating innovation to advance the ability of the United States to understand, research, or monitor coral reef ecosystems, or to develop management or adaptation options to conserve and restore coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> implementing research to ensure the population viability of coral species in United States waters listed as threatened or endangered under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.] as detailed in the population-based recovery criteria included in species-specific recovery plans established under such Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> developing and implementing cost-effective methods to restore degraded coral reef ecosystems or to create geographically appropriate coral reef ecosystems in suitable waters, including by improving habitat or promoting success of keystone species, with an emphasis on novel restoration strategies and techniques to advance coral reef recovery and growth near population centers threatened by rising sea levels and storm surge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> translating and applying coral genetics research to coral reef ecosystem restoration, including research related to traits that promote resilience to increasing ocean temperatures, changing ocean chemistry, coral bleaching, coral diseases, and invasive species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> developing and maintaining in situ native coral propagation sites; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<chapeau> developing and maintaining ex situ coral propagation nurseries and land-based coral gene banks to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conserve or augment genetic diversity of native coral populations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> support captive breeding of rare coral species; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> enhance resilience of native coral populations to increasing ocean temperatures, changing ocean chemistry, coral bleaching, and coral diseases through selective breeding, conditioning, or other approaches that target genes, gene expression, phenotypic traits, or phenotypic plasticity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To the extent practicable based upon proposals for coral reef projects submitted to the Administrator, the Administrator shall ensure that funding for grants awarded under this section during a fiscal year is distributed as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not less than 40 percent of funds available shall be awarded for projects in areas of the Pacific Ocean subject to the jurisdiction or control of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not less than 40 percent of the funds available shall be awarded for projects in areas of the Atlantic Ocean, the Gulf of Mexico, or the Caribbean Sea subject to the jurisdiction or control of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent there are viable applications made by eligible coral reef stewardship partners, not more than 67 percent of funds distributed in each region in accordance with paragraphs (1) and (2) may be made exclusively available to projects that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submitted by a coral reef stewardship partnership; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consistent with the coral reef action plan in effect under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref> by such a partnership.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Of the funds distributed to support projects in accordance with paragraph (3), not less than 20 percent and not more than 33 percent shall be awarded for projects submitted by a Federal coral reef stewardship partnership, to the extent there are viable applications made by eligible Federal coral reef stewardship partnerships.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Task Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may consult with the Secretary of the Interior and the Task Force to obtain guidance in establishing priorities and evaluating proposals for coral reef projects under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 211</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6411.</num>
<heading> Coral reef research</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reef research coordination institutes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall designate 2 reef research coordination institutes for the purpose of advancing and sustaining essential capabilities in coral reef research, one each in the Atlantic and Pacific basins, to be known as the “Atlantic Reef Research Coordination Institute” and the “Pacific Reef Research Coordination Institute”, respectively.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each institute designated under paragraph (1) shall be housed within a single coral reef research center designated by the Administrator under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The institutes designated under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct federally directed research to fill national and regional coral reef ecosystem research gaps and improve understanding of, and responses to, continuing and emerging threats to the resilience of United States coral reef ecosystems consistent with the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> support ecological research and monitoring to study the effects of conservation and restoration activities funded by this chapter on promoting more effective coral reef management and restoration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> through agreements—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> collaborate directly with States, covered Native entities, covered coral reef managers, nonprofit organizations, and other coral reef research centers designated under subsection (b);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> assist in the development and implementation of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> coral reef action plans under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> build capacity within non-Federal governmental resource management agencies to establish research priorities and translate and apply research findings to management and restoration practices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> conduct public education and awareness programs for policymakers, resource managers, and the general public on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> best practices for coral reef ecosystem management and restoration;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the value of coral reefs; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the threats to the sustainability of coral reef ecosystems.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral reef research centers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> periodically solicit applications for designation of qualifying institutions in covered States as coral reef research centers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> designate all qualifying institutions in covered States as coral reef research centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), an institution is a qualifying institution if the Administrator determines that the institution—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is operated by an institution of higher education or nonprofit marine research organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has established management-driven national or regional coral reef research or restoration programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has demonstrated abilities to coordinate closely with appropriate Federal and State agencies, and other academic and nonprofit organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> maintains significant local community engagement and outreach programs related to coral reef ecosystems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 212</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6412.</num>
<heading> Coral reef prize competitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the head of any Federal agency with a representative serving on the United States Coral Reef Task Force established by <ref>section 6451 of this title</ref>, may, individually or in cooperation with one or more agencies, carry out a program to award prizes competitively under <ref>section 3719 of title 15</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any program carried out under this section shall be for the purpose of stimulating innovation to advance the ability of the United States to understand, research, or monitor coral reef ecosystems, or to develop management or adaptation options to preserve, sustain, and restore coral reef ecosystems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Priority shall be given to establishing programs under this section that address communities, environments, or industries that are in distress as a result of the decline or degradation of coral reef ecosystems, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> scientific research and monitoring that furthers the understanding of causes behind coral reef decline and degradation and the generally slow recovery following disturbances, including changing ocean chemistry, temperature-related bleaching, disease, and their associated impacts on coral physiology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development of monitoring or management options for communities or industries that are experiencing significant financial hardship;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the development of adaptation options to alleviate economic harm and job loss caused by damage to coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the development of measures to help vulnerable communities or industries, with an emphasis on rural communities and businesses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the development of adaptation and management options for impacted tourism industries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 213</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3946</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6413.</num>
<heading> Reports on administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the committees specified in subsection (b) a report on the administration of this chapter during the 2-year period preceding submission of the report, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of all activities undertaken to implement the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement of all funds obligated under the authorities of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a summary, disaggregated by State, of Federal and non-Federal contributions toward the costs of each project or activity funded, in full or in part, under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committees specified</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The committees specified in this subsection are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, Committee on Environment and Public Works, Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 214</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6414.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $45,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out this chapter which shall remain available until expended. Of such amounts, there is authorized to be appropriated for each such fiscal year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $12,000,000 to carry out <ref>section 6406 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $3,500,000 for activities authorized under <ref>section 6410 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $4,500,000 to be provided to the cooperative institutes designated under <ref>section 6411(a) of this title</ref> to carry out the functions described in such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 10 percent of the amounts appropriated under subsection (a) may be used for program administration or overhead costs incurred by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or the Department of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 215</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6415.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alaska Native Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Alaska Native Corporation” has the meaning given the term “Native Corporation” in <ref>section 1602 of title 43</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “conservation” means the use of methods and procedures necessary to preserve or sustain native corals and associated species as diverse, viable, and self-perpetuating coral reef ecosystems with minimal impacts from invasive species, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all activities associated with resource management, such as monitoring, assessment, protection, restoration, sustainable use, management of habitat, and maintenance or augmentation of genetic diversity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mapping;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> scientific expertise and technical assistance in the development and implementation of management strategies for marine protected areas and marine resources required by Federal law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> law enforcement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> conflict resolution initiatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> community outreach and education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> promotion of safe and ecologically sound navigation and anchoring.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “coral” means species of the phylum Cnidaria, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all species of the orders Antipatharia (black corals), Scleractinia (stony corals), Alcyonacea (soft corals, organ pipe corals, gorgonians), and Helioporacea (blue coral), of the class Anthozoa; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all species of the order Anthoathecata (fire corals and other hydrocorals) of the class Hydrozoa.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “coral products” means any living or dead specimens, parts, or derivatives, or any product containing specimens, parts, or derivatives, of any species of coral.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral reef</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “coral reef” means calcium carbonate structures in the form of a reef or shoal, composed in whole or in part by living coral, skeletal remains of coral, crustose coralline algae, and other associated sessile marine plants and animals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral reef ecosystem</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “coral reef ecosystem” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> corals and other geographically and ecologically associated marine communities of other reef organisms (including reef plants and animals) associated with coral reef habitat; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the biotic and abiotic factors and processes that control or significantly affect coral calcification rates, tissue growth, reproduction, recruitment, abundance, coral-algal symbiosis, and biodiversity in such habitat.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral reef ecosystem services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “coral reef ecosystem services” means the attributes and benefits provided by coral reef ecosystems including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protection of coastal beaches, structures, and infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> habitat for organisms of economic, ecological, biomedical, medicinal, and cultural value;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> serving as centers for the promulgation, performance, and training of cultural practices representative of traditional ecological knowledge; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> aesthetic value.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered Native entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “covered Native entity” means a Native entity with interests in a coral reef ecosystem.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered reef manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered reef manager” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a management unit of a covered State with jurisdiction over a coral reef ecosystem;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a covered State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a coral reef stewardship partnership under <ref>section 6405 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “covered State” means Florida, Hawaii, and the territories of American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, Puerto Rico, and the United States Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal reef manager</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “Federal reef manager” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a management unit of a Federal agency specified in subparagraph (B) with lead management jurisdiction over a coral reef ecosystem; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a coral reef stewardship partnership under <ref>section 6405(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agencies specified</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A Federal agency specified in this subparagraph is one of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The National Park Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The Office of Insular Affairs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interested stakeholder groups</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “interested stakeholder groups” means any of the following with interest in an applicable coral reef or ecologically significant unit of a coral reef:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A business.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A commercial or recreational fisherman.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A recreationalist.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A Federal, State, Tribal, or local government unit with related jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An institution of higher education (as such term is defined in <ref>section 1001(a) of title 20</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002826">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A nongovernmental organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy” means the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy in effect under <ref>section 6403 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Native entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Native entity” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An Indian Tribe (as defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An Alaska Native Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Department of Hawaiian Home Lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Office of Hawaiian Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A Native Hawaiian organization (as defined in <ref>section 7517 of title 20</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “nonprofit organization” means any corporation, trust, association, cooperative, or other organization, not including an institution of higher education, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is operated primarily for scientific, educational, service, charitable, or similar purposes in the public interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not organized primarily for profit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> uses net proceeds to maintain, improve, or expand the operations of the organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(19)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restoration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “restoration” means the use of methods and procedures necessary to enhance, rehabilitate, recreate, or create a functioning coral reef or coral reef ecosystem, in whole or in part, within suitable waters of the historical geographic range of such ecosystems, to provide ecological, economic, cultural, or coastal resiliency services associated with healthy coral reefs and benefit native populations of coral reef organisms.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(20)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resilience</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “resilience” means the capacity for corals within their native range, coral reefs, or coral reef ecosystems to resist and recover from natural and human disturbances, and maintain structure and function to provide coral reef ecosystem services, as determined by clearly identifiable, measurable, and science-based standards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(21)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(22)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any State of the United States that contains a coral reef ecosystem within its seaward boundaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, Puerto Rico, or the United States Virgin Islands; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other territory or possession of the United States or separate sovereign in free association with the United States that contains a coral reef ecosystem within its seaward boundaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(23)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stewardship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “stewardship”, with respect to a coral reef, includes conservation, restoration, and public outreach and education.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(24)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Task Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Task Force” means the United States Coral Reef Task Force established under <ref>section 6451 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title II, § 216</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>