<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 30—</num>
<heading>WILD HORSES AND BURROS: PROTECTION, MANAGEMENT, AND CONTROL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1331.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress finds and declares that wild free-roaming horses and burros are living symbols of the historic and pioneer spirit of the West; that they contribute to the diversity of life forms within the Nation and enrich the lives of the American people; and that these horses and burros are fast disappearing from the American scene. It is the policy of Congress that wild free-roaming horses and burros shall be protected from capture, branding, harassment, or death; and to accomplish this they are to be considered in the area where presently found, as an integral part of the natural system of the public lands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1332.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior when used in connection with public lands administered by him through the Bureau of Land Management and the Secretary of Agriculture in connection with public lands administered by him through the Forest Service;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> “wild free-roaming horses and burros” means all unbranded and unclaimed horses and burros on public lands of the United States;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> “range” means the amount of land necessary to sustain an existing herd or herds of wild free-roaming horses and burros, which does not exceed their known territorial limits, and which is devoted principally but not necessarily exclusively to their welfare in keeping with the multiple-use management concept for the public lands;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> “herd” means one or more stallions and his mares; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002619">1</ref></content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> “public lands” means any lands administered by the Secretary of the Interior through the Bureau of Land Management or by the Secretary of Agriculture through the Forest Service.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002620">2</ref></content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> “excess animals” means wild free-roaming horses or burros (1) which have been removed from an area by the Secretary pursuant to applicable law or, (2) which must be removed from an area in order to preserve and maintain a thriving natural ecological balance and multiple-use relationship in that area.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–514, § 14(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-25">Oct. 25, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1333.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction; management; ranges; ecological balance objectives; scientific recommendations; forage allocation adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All wild free-roaming horses and burros are hereby declared to be under the jurisdiction of the Secretary for the purpose of management and protection in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The Secretary is authorized and directed to protect and manage wild free-roaming horses and burros as components of the public lands, and he may designate and maintain specific ranges on public lands as sanctuaries for their protection and preservation, where the Secretary after consultation with the wildlife agency of the State wherein any such range is proposed and with the Advisory Board established in <ref>section 1337 of this title</ref> deems such action desirable. The Secretary shall manage wild free-roaming horses and burros in a manner that is designed to achieve and maintain a thriving natural ecological balance on the public lands. He shall consider the recommendations of qualified scientists in the field of biology and ecology, some of whom shall be independent of both Federal and State agencies and may include members of the Advisory Board established in <ref>section 1337 of this title</ref>. All management activities shall be at the minimal feasible level and shall be carried out in consultation with the wildlife agency of the State wherein such lands are located in order to protect the natural ecological balance of all wildlife species which inhabit such lands, particularly endangered wildlife species. Any adjustments in forage allocations on any such lands shall take into consideration the needs of other wildlife species which inhabit such lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inventory and determinations; consultation; overpopulation; research study: submittal to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall maintain a current inventory of wild free-roaming horses and burros on given areas of the public lands. The purpose of such inventory shall be to: make determinations as to whether and where an overpopulation exists and whether action should be taken to remove excess animals; determine appropriate management levels of wild free-roaming horses and burros on these areas of the public lands; and determine whether appropriate management levels should be achieved by the removal or destruction of excess animals, or other options (such as sterilization, or natural controls on population levels). In making such determinations the Secretary shall consult with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, wildlife agencies of the State or States wherein wild free-roaming horses and burros are located, such individuals independent of Federal and State government as have been recommended by the National Academy of Sciences, and such other individuals whom he determines have scientific expertise and special knowledge of wild horse and burro protection, wildlife management and animal husbandry as related to rangeland management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Where the Secretary determines on the basis of (i) the current inventory of lands within his jurisdiction; (ii) information contained in any land use planning completed pursuant to <ref>section 1712 of title 43</ref>; (iii) information contained in court ordered environmental impact statements as defined in <ref>section 1902 of title 43</ref>; and (iv) such additional information as becomes available to him from time to time, including that information developed in the research study mandated by this section, or in the absence of the information contained in (i–iv) above on the basis of all information currently available to him, that an overpopulation exists on a given area of the public lands and that action is necessary to remove excess animals, he shall immediately remove excess animals from the range so as to achieve appropriate management levels. Such action shall be taken, in the following order and priority, until all excess animals have been removed so as to restore a thriving natural ecological balance to the range, and protect the range from the deterioration associated with overpopulation:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall order old, sick, or lame animals to be destroyed in the most humane manner possible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall cause such number of additional excess wild free-roaming horses and burros to be humanely captured and removed for private maintenance and care for which he determines an adoption demand exists by qualified individuals, and for which he determines he can assure humane treatment and care (including proper transportation, feeding, and handling): <i>Provided</i>, That, not more than four animals may be adopted per year by any individual unless the Secretary determines in writing that such individual is capable of humanely caring for more than four animals, including the transportation of such animals by the adopting party; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall cause additional excess wild free-roaming horses and burros for which an adoption demand by qualified individuals does not exist to be destroyed in the most humane and cost efficient manner possible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purpose of furthering knowledge of wild horse and burro population dynamics and their interrelationship with wildlife, forage and water resources, and assisting him in making his determination as to what constitutes excess animals, the Secretary shall contract for a research study of such animals with such individuals independent of Federal and State government as may be recommended by the National Academy of Sciences for having scientific expertise and special knowledge of wild horse and burro protection, wildlife management and animal husbandry as related to rangeland management. The terms and outline of such research study shall be determined by a research design panel to be appointed by the President of the National Academy of Sciences. Such study shall be completed and submitted by the Secretary to the Senate and House of Representatives on or before <date date="1983-01-01">January 1, 1983</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Title of transferee to limited number of excess animals adopted for requisite period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where excess animals have been transferred to a qualified individual for adoption and private maintenance pursuant to this chapter and the Secretary determines that such individual has provided humane conditions, treatment and care for such animal or animals for a period of one year, the Secretary is authorized upon application by the transferee to grant title to not more than four animals to the transferee at the end of the one-year period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loss of status as wild free-roaming horses and burros; exclusion from coverage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Wild free-roaming horses and burros or their remains shall lose their status as wild free-roaming horses or burros and shall no longer be considered as falling within the purview of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upon passage of title pursuant to subsection (c) except for the limitation of subsection (c)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002621">1</ref> of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if they have been transferred for private maintenance or adoption pursuant to this chapter and die of natural causes before passage of title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> upon destruction by the Secretary or his designee pursuant to subsection (b) of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> if they die of natural causes on the public lands or on private lands where maintained thereon pursuant to <ref>section 1334 of this title</ref> and disposal is authorized by the Secretary or his designee; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> upon destruction or death for purposes of or incident to the program authorized in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of excess animals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any excess animal or the remains of an excess animal shall be sold if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the excess animal is more than 10 years of age; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the excess animal has been offered unsuccessfully for adoption at least 3 times.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Method of sale</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An excess animal that meets either of the criteria in paragraph (1) shall be made available for sale without limitation, including through auction to the highest bidder, at local sale yards or other convenient livestock selling facilities, until such time as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all excess animals offered for sale are sold; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the appropriate management level, as determined by the Secretary, is attained in all areas occupied by wild free-roaming horses and burros.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Funds generated from the sale of excess animals under this subsection shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> credited as an offsetting collection to the Management of Lands and Resources appropriation for the Bureau of Land Management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used for the costs relating to the adoption of wild free-roaming horses and burros, including the costs of marketing such adoption.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any excess animal sold under this provision shall no longer be considered to be a wild free-roaming horse or burro for purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–514, § 14(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-25">Oct. 25, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. E, title I, § 142(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3070</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1334.</num>
<heading> Private maintenance; numerical approximation; strays on private lands: removal; destruction by agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If wild free-roaming horses or burros stray from public lands onto privately owned land, the owners of such land may inform the nearest Federal marshall or agent of the Secretary, who shall arrange to have the animals removed. In no event shall such wild free-roaming horses and burros be destroyed except by the agents of the Secretary. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a private landowner from maintaining wild free-roaming horses or burros on his private lands, or lands leased from the Government, if he does so in a manner that protects them from harassment, and if the animals were not willfully removed or enticed from the public lands. Any individuals who maintain such wild free-roaming horses or burros on their private lands or lands leased from the Government shall notify the appropriate agent of the Secretary and supply him with a reasonable approximation of the number of animals so maintained.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 4</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1335.</num>
<heading> Recovery rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person claiming ownership of a horse or burro on the public lands shall be entitled to recover it only if recovery is permissible under the branding and estray laws of the State in which the animal is found.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 5</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1336.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements; regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with other landowners and with the State and local governmental agencies and may issue such regulations as he deems necessary for the furtherance of the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 6</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1337.</num>
<heading> Joint advisory board; appointment; membership; functions; qualifications; reimbursement limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture are authorized and directed to appoint a joint advisory board of not more than nine members to advise them on any matter relating to wild free-roaming horses and burros and their management and protection. They shall select as advisers persons who are not employees of the Federal or State Governments and whom they deem to have special knowledge about protection of horses and burros, management of wildlife, animal husbandry, or natural resources management. Members of the board shall not receive reimbursement except for travel and other expenditures necessary in connection with their services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 7</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1338.</num>
<heading> Criminal provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations; penalties; trial</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> willfully removes or attempts to remove a wild free-roaming horse or burro from the public lands, without authority from the Secretary, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> converts a wild free-roaming horse or burro to private use, without authority from the Secretary, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> maliciously causes the death or harassment of any wild free-roaming horse or burro, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> except as provided in <ref>section 1333(e) of this title</ref>, processes or permits to be processed into commercial products the remains of a wild free-roaming horse or burro, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> sells, directly or indirectly, a wild free-roaming horse or burro maintained on private or leased land pursuant to <ref>section 1334 of this title</ref>, or the remains thereof, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> willfully violates a regulation issued pursuant to this chapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be subject to a fine of not more than $2,000, or imprisonment for not more than one year, or both. Any person so charged with such violation by the Secretary may be tried and sentenced by any United States commissioner or magistrate judge designated for that purpose by the court by which he was appointed, in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as provided for in <ref>section 3401 of title 18</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arrest; appearance for examination or trial; warrants: issuance and execution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employee designated by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture shall have power, without warrant, to arrest any person committing in the presence of such employee a violation of this chapter or any regulation made pursuant thereto, and to take such person immediately for examination or trial before an officer or court of competent jurisdiction, and shall have power to execute any warrant or other process issued by an officer or court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this chapter or regulations made pursuant thereto. Any judge of a court established under the laws of the United States, or any United States magistrate judge may, within his respective jurisdiction, upon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause, issue warrants, in all such cases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 8</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. E, title I, § 142(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1338a.</num>
<heading> Transportation of captured animals; procedures and prohibitions applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In administering this chapter, the Secretary may use or contract for the use of helicopters or, for the purpose of transporting captured animals, motor vehicles. Such use shall be undertaken only after a public hearing and under the direct supervision of the Secretary or of a duly authorized official or employee of the Department. The provisions of <ref>section 47(a) of title 18</ref> shall not be applicable to such use. Such use shall be in accordance with humane procedures prescribed by the Secretary. Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to limit the authority of the Secretary in the management of units of the National Park System, and the Secretary may, without regard either to the provisions of this chapter, or the provisions of <ref>section 47(a) of title 18</ref>, use motor vehicles, fixed-wing aircraft, or helicopters, or to contract for such use, in furtherance of the management of the National Park System, and <ref>section 47(a) of title 18</ref> shall be applicable to such use.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2775</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–333, div. I, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-11-12">Nov. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4186</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1339.</num>
<heading> Limitation of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to relocate wild free-roaming horses or burros to areas of the public lands where they do not presently exist.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 10</ref>, formerly § 9, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 651</ref>, renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1340.</num>
<heading> Joint report to Congress; consultation and coordination of implementation, enforcement, and departmental activities; studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After the expiration of thirty calendar months following <date date="1971-12-15">December 15, 1971</date>, and every twenty-four calendar months thereafter, the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture will submit to Congress a joint report on the administration of this chapter, including a summary of enforcement and/or other actions taken thereunder, costs, and such recommendations for legislative or other actions as he might deem appropriate.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with respect to the implementation and enforcement of this chapter and to the maximum feasible extent coordinate the activities of their respective departments and in the implementation and enforcement of this chapter. The Secretaries are authorized and directed to undertake those studies of the habits of wild free-roaming horses and burros that they may deem necessary in order to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–195, § 11</ref>, formerly § 10, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 651</ref>, renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>