<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 97—</num>
<heading>CONVENTION ON THE CONSERVATION AND MANAGEMENT OF HIGH SEAS FISHERY RESOURCES IN THE SOUTH PACIFIC</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7801.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1982 Convention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “1982 Convention” means the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea of 10 December 1982.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the Commission of the South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organization established in accordance with the South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Convention Area</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Convention Area” means the area to which the Convention on the Conservation and Management of High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean applies under Article 5 of such Convention.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Council” means the Western Pacific Regional Fishery Management Council.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusive economic zone</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “exclusive economic zone” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to the United States, the zone established by Presidential Proclamation Numbered 5030 of <date date="1983-03-10">March 10, 1983</date> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1453</ref> note); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to a foreign country, a designated zone similar to the zone referred to in subparagraph (A) for that country, consistent with international law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fishery resources</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fishery resources” means all fish, mollusks, crustaceans, and other marine species, and any products thereof, caught by a fishing vessel within the Convention Area, but excluding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sedentary species insofar as they are subject to the national jurisdiction of coastal States pursuant to Article 77 paragraph 4 of the 1982 Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> highly migratory species listed in Annex I of the 1982 Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> anadromous and catadromous species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> marine mammals, marine reptiles and sea birds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fishing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fishing”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> except as provided in subparagraph (B), means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the actual or attempted searching for, catching, taking, or harvesting of fishery resources;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> engaging in any activity that can reasonably be expected to result in the locating, catching, taking or harvesting of fishery resources for any purpose;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> transshipment and any operation at sea, in support of, or in preparation for, any activity described in this subparagraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the use of any vessel, vehicle, aircraft, or hovercraft in relation to any activity described in this subparagraph; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include any operation related to emergencies involving the health and safety of crew members or the safety of a fishing vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fishing vessel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “fishing vessel” means any vessel used or intended to be used for fishing, including any fish processing vessel support ship, carrier vessel, or any other vessel directly engaged in fishing operations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” means any individual (whether or not a citizen or national of the United States); any corporation, partnership, association, or other entity (whether or not organized or existing under the laws of any State); and any Federal, State, local, or foreign government or any entity of any such government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention” means the Convention on the Conservation and Management of the High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean (including any annexes, amendments, or protocols that are in force, or have come into force, for the United States), which was adopted at Auckland, New Zealand, on <date date="2009-11-14">November 14, 2009</date>, by the International Consultations on the Proposed South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7802.</num>
<heading> Appointment or designation of United States Commissioners</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States shall be represented on the Commission by not more than 3 Commissioners. In making each appointment, the President shall select a Commissioner from among individuals who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning fishery resources in the South Pacific Ocean.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">At least 1 of the Commissioners shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> serving at the pleasure of the President, an officer or employee of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Department of Commerce;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Department of State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Coast Guard; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the chairperson or designee of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternate Commissioners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary, may designate from time to time and for periods of time considered appropriate an alternate Commissioner to the Commission. An alternate Commissioner may exercise all powers and duties of a Commissioner in the absence of a Commissioner appointed under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative matters</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An individual serving as a Commissioner, or as an alternate Commissioner, other than an officer or employee of the United States Government, shall not be considered a Federal employee, except for the purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An individual serving as a Commissioner or an alternate Commissioner, although an officer of the United States while so serving, shall receive no compensation for the individual’s services as such Commissioner or alternate Commissioner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of State shall pay the necessary travel expenses of a Commissioner or an alternate Commissioner in accordance with the Federal Travel Regulations and sections 5701, 5702, 5704 through 5708, and 5731 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may reimburse the Secretary of State for amounts expended by the Secretary of State under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of permanent Advisory Committee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">There is established an advisory committee which shall be composed of 7 members appointed by the Secretary as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A member engaging in commercial fishing in the management area of the Council.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Two members from the indigenous population of the Pacific, including a Native Hawaiian and a native-born inhabitant of any State in the Pacific.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A member that is a marine fisheries scientist and a member of the Council’s Scientific and Statistical Committee.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> A member representing a non-governmental organization active in fishery issues in the Pacific.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> A member nominated by the Governor of the State of Hawaii.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> A member designated by the Council.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and privileges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each member of the Advisory Committee shall serve for a term of 2 years and shall be eligible for reappointment for not more than 3 consecutive terms. The Commissioners shall notify the Advisory Committee in advance of each meeting of the Commissioners. The Advisory Committee may attend each meeting and may examine and be heard on all proposed programs, investigations, reports, recommendations, and regulations of the Commissioners.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Advisory Committee shall determine its organization and prescribe its practices and procedures for carrying out its functions under this chapter, the South Pacific Fisheries Convention, and the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability of procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Advisory Committee shall publish and make available to the public a statement of its organization, practices, and procedures.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A majority of the members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum to conduct business.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Meetings of the Advisory Committee, except when in executive session, shall be open to the public. Prior notice of each non-executive meeting shall be made public in a timely fashion. The Advisory Committee shall not be subject to the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002867">1</ref></p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost savings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In order to reduce the cost of Advisory Committee meetings, the Advisory Committee shall, to the extent practicable, utilize teleconferences and webinars for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary and the Secretary of State shall furnish the Advisory Committee with relevant information concerning fishery resources and international fishery agreements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative matters</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall provide to the Advisory Committee in a timely manner such administrative and technical support services as are necessary to function effectively.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation; status; expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An individual appointed to serve as a member of the Advisory Committee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall serve without pay; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not be considered a Federal employee, except for the purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7803.</num>
<heading> Authority and responsibility of the Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receive and transmit, on behalf of the United States, reports, requests, recommendations, proposals, decisions, and other communications of and to the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Secretary, act upon, or refer to other appropriate authority, any communication pursuant to paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with the concurrence of the Secretary, and in accordance with the South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention, object to decisions of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7804.</num>
<heading> Responsibility of the Secretary and rulemaking authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administer this chapter and any regulations issued under this chapter, except to the extent otherwise provided for in this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issue permits to vessels subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and to owners and operators of such vessels, to fish in the Convention Area, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if recommended by the United States Commissioners, assess and collect fees, not to exceed 3 percent of the ex-vessel value of fisheries resources harvested by vessels of the United States in fisheries conducted in the Convention Area, to recover the actual costs to the United States to carry out the functions of the Secretary under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgation of regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, may promulgate such regulations as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out the international obligations of the United States under the South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention and this chapter, including decisions adopted by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Regulations promulgated under this subsection shall be applicable only to a person or fishing vessel that is or has engaged in fishing, and fishery resources covered by the Convention on the Conservation and Management of High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency with other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure the consistency, to the extent practicable, of fishery management programs administered under this chapter, the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), the Tuna Conventions Act of 1950 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.), the South Pacific Tuna Act of 1988 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 973</ref> et seq.), <ref>section 401 of Public Law 108–219</ref> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1821</ref> note) (relating to Pacific albacore tuna), the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1992 (<ref>Public Law 102–567</ref>) and the amendments made by that Act, and <ref>Public Law 100–629</ref> (<ref>102 Stat. 3286</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review of regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Regulations promulgated by the Secretary under this chapter shall be subject to judicial review to the extent authorized by, and in accordance with, chapter 7 of title 5 if a petition for such review is filed not later than 30 days after the date on which the regulations are promulgated or the action is published in the Federal Register, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall file a response to any petition filed in accordance with paragraph (1) not later than 30 days after the date the Secretary is served with that petition, except that the appropriate court may extend the period for filing such a response upon a showing by the Secretary of good cause for that extension.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Copies of administrative record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A response of the Secretary under paragraph (2) shall include a copy of the administrative record for the regulations that are the subject of the petition.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon a motion by the person who files a petition under this subsection, the appropriate court shall assign the matter for hearing at the earliest possible date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7805.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter, and any regulations or permits issued under this chapter, shall be enforced by the Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. Such Secretaries shall, and the head of any Federal or State agency that has entered into an agreement with either such Secretary under this section may (if the agreement so provides), authorize officers to enforce this chapter or any regulation promulgated under this chapter. Any officer so authorized may enforce this chapter in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though section 311 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1861</ref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall prevent any person from violating this chapter in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though sections 308 through 311 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1858</ref> through 1861) were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter. Any person that violates this chapter shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.) in the same manner and by the same means as though sections 308 through 311 of that Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1858</ref> through 1861) were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> District court jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over any actions arising under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hawaii and Pacific insular areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (b), for the purpose of this section, for Hawaii or any possession of the United States in the Pacific Ocean, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of Hawaii, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of Guam and Wake Island, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of Guam; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of the Northern Mariana Islands, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each violation shall be a separate offense and the offense is deemed to have been committed not only in the district where the violation first occurred, but also in any other district as authorized by law. Any offenses not committed in any district are subject to the venue provisions of <ref>section 3238 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7806.</num>
<heading> Prohibited acts.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to violate any provision of this chapter or of any regulation promulgated or permit issued under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to use any fishing vessel to engage in fishing without a valid permit or after the revocation, or during the period of suspension, of an applicable permit pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to refuse to permit any officer authorized to enforce this chapter to board a fishing vessel subject to such person’s control for the purposes of conducting any investigation or inspection in connection with the enforcement of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, or interfere with any such authorized officer in the conduct of any search, investigation, or inspection in connection with the enforcement of this chapter or any regulation promulgated or permit issued under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to resist a lawful arrest for any act prohibited by this chapter or any regulation promulgated or permit issued under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to ship, transport, offer for sale, sell, purchase, import, export, or have custody, control, or possession of, any fishery resources taken or retained in violation of this chapter or any regulation or permit referred to in paragraph (1) or (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to interfere with, delay, or prevent, by any means, the apprehension or arrest of another person, knowing that such other person has committed any act prohibited by this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to submit to the Secretary false information, regarding any matter that the Secretary is considering in the course of carrying out this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, sexually harass, bribe, or interfere with any observer on a vessel pursuant to the requirements of this chapter, or any data collector employed by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or under contract to any person to carry out responsibilities under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to fail to make, keep, or furnish any catch returns, statistical records, or other reports as are required by regulations adopted pursuant to this chapter to be made, kept, or furnished;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> to fail to stop a vessel upon being hailed and instructed to stop by a duly authorized official of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> to import, in violation of any regulation promulgated under this chapter, any fishery resources in any form of those species subject to regulation pursuant to a decision of the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> to make or submit any false record, account, or label for, or any false identification of, any fishery resources that have been or are intended to be imported, exported, transported, sold, offered for sale, purchased, or received in interstate or foreign commerce; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> to refuse to authorize and accept boarding by a duly authorized inspector pursuant to procedures adopted by the Commission for the boarding and inspection of fishing vessels in the Convention Area.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7807.</num>
<heading> Cooperation in carrying out the Convention</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal and State agencies; private institutions and organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may cooperate with agencies of the United States Government, any public or private institutions or organizations within the United States or abroad, and, through the Secretary of State, the duly authorized officials of the government of any party to the South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention, in carrying out responsibilities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scientific and other programs; facilities and personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All Federal agencies may, upon the request of the Secretary, cooperate in the conduct of scientific and other programs and to furnish facilities and personnel for the purpose of assisting the Commission in carrying out its duties under the South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctioned fishing operations and biological experiments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter, or in the laws or regulations of any State, prevents the Secretary or the Commission from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conducting or authorizing the conduct of fishing operations and biological experiments at any time for purposes of scientific investigation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> discharging any other duties prescribed by the South Pacific Fishery Resources Convention.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State jurisdiction not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to diminish or to increase the jurisdiction of any State in the territorial sea of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7808.</num>
<heading> Territorial participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall ensure participation in the Commission and its subsidiary bodies by American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands to the extent allowed under United States law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7809.</num>
<heading> Exclusive economic zone notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Masters of commercial fishing vessels of countries fishing under the management authority of the South Pacific Fisheries Convention that do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with United States enforcement authorities shall, before or as soon as reasonably possible after, entering and transiting the exclusive economic zone bounded by the Convention Area, ensure that all fishing gear on board the vessel is stowed below deck or otherwise removed from the place it is normally used for fishing activities and placed where it is not readily available for fishing activities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7810.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated out of funds made available to the Secretary and the Secretary of State $300,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 to carry out this chapter and to pay the United States contribution to the Commission under Article 15 of the South Pacific Fisheries Convention.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International cooperation and assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the limits of available appropriations and consistent with applicable law, the Secretary or the Secretary of State may provide appropriate assistance, including grants, to developing nations and international organizations of which such nations are members to assist those nations in meeting their obligations under the South Pacific Fisheries Convention.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the limits of available appropriations and consistent with other applicable law, the Secretary and the Secretary of State are authorized to transfer funds to any foreign government and any international, non-governmental, or international organization, including the Commission, for purposes of carrying out the international responsibilities under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>