<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 65—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL FORESTRY COOPERATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4501.</num>
<heading> Forestry and related natural resource assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Focus of activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To achieve the maximum impact from activities undertaken under the authority of this chapter, the Secretary shall focus such activities on the key countries which could have a substantial impact on emissions of greenhouse gases related to global warming.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for international forestry activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In support of forestry and related natural resource activities outside of the United States and its territories and possessions, the Secretary of Agriculture may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> provide assistance that promotes sustainable development and global environmental stability, including assistance for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conservation and sustainable management of forest land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> forest plantation technology and tree improvement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> rehabilitation of cutover lands, eroded watersheds, and areas damaged by wildfires or other natural disasters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> prevention and control of insects, diseases, and other damaging agents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> preparedness planning, training, and operational assistance to combat natural disasters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> more complete utilization of forest products leading to resource conservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> range protection and enhancement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> wildlife and fisheries habitat protection and improvement;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> share technical, managerial, extension, and administrative skills related to public and private natural resource administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide education and training opportunities to promote the transfer and utilization of scientific information and technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> engage in scientific exchange and cooperative research with foreign governmental, educational, technical and research institutions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> cooperate with domestic and international organizations that further international programs for the management and protection of forests, rangelands, wildlife and fisheries, and related natural resource activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall undertake the activities described in subsection (b), in countries that receive assistance from the Agency for International Development only at the request, or with the concurrence, of the Administrator of the Agency for International Development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2070</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4596</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4502.</num>
<heading> Tropical deforestation assessment and assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In support of the Tropical Forestry Action Plan and to specifically address tropical deforestation and degradation, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> support and actively participate in global and regional meetings that seek to reform such Plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> together with the United States Agency for International Development,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002797">1</ref> and other Federal agencies, provide technical assistance to tropical countries for the formulation of national forestry sector development strategies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> cooperate with tropical countries on research, training, and technical programs aimed at implementing national forestry sector development strategies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4502a.</num>
<heading> Tropical forestry research and assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To promote sound management and conservation of tropical forests of the United States and to promote the development and transfer of technical, managerial, educational, and administrative skills to managers of tropical forests within or outside the United States, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to provide assistance through the Forest Service to eligible entities in States with tropical forests to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop, promote, and demonstrate sustainable harvesting of native woods and other forest products on a sustainable yield basis in balance with natural resource conservation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promote habitat preservation and species protection or recovery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> protect indigenous plant and animal species and essential watersheds from non-native animals, plants, and pathogens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish biological control agents for non-native species that threaten natural ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish a monitoring system in tropical forests to identify baseline conditions and determine detrimental changes or improvements over time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> detect and appraise stresses affecting tropical forests caused by insect infestations, diseases, pollution, fire, and non-native animal and plant species, and by the influence of people;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> determine the causes of changes that are detected through experimentation, intensive monitoring, and data collection at affected tropical forest sites; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> engage in research, demonstration, education, training, and outreach that furthers the objectives of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assistance provided to eligible entities under this section may be in the form of grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means a State forester or equivalent State official, State, political subdivision of a State, Federal agency, private organization, corporation, or other private person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the 50 States, Guam, American Samoa, the Republic of Palau (until the Compact of Free Association enters into effect), Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4596</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503.</num>
<heading> Institute of Tropical Forestry in Puerto Rico</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expansion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall expand the capabilities of and construct additional facilities at the Caribbean National Forest and Institute of Tropical Forestry in Puerto Rico, as the Secretary determines necessary to support the purpose of this chapter, and as funds are appropriated for such expansion and construction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tropical forestry plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives, a tropical forestry plan for the expansion and construction of additional facilities under subsection (a). Such plan shall include provisions for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the construction or acquisition of a major center for education, interpretation, and appreciation of the benefits and methods of the intelligent management of tropical forests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the acquisition or construction of facilities for housing and classroom instruction near the Caribbean National Forest/Luguillo Experimental Forest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the acquisition or construction of facilities for the study and recovery of endangered tropical wildlife, fish and plant species.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2071</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4596</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503a.</num>
<heading> Institute of Pacific Islands Forestry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expansion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall expand the capabilities of and construct additional facilities, as funds are appropriated for the expansion and construction, at—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Institute of Pacific Islands Forestry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> tropical forests in the State of Hawaii.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tropical forestry plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after the date of receipt by the Secretary of the action plan required by section 5(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002798">1</ref> of the Hawaii Tropical Forest Recovery Act, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, and to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate, a tropical forestry plan to expand the capabilities of and construct additional facilities under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The plan shall provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the establishment of a model center for research, demonstration, education, training, and outreach activities suitable for transferring scientific, technical, managerial, and administrative assistance to governmental and non-governmental organizations seeking to address problems associated with tropical forests within and outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the acquisition or construction of facilities for research, classroom instruction, and housing near an experimental tropical forest in the State of Hawaii;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the acquisition or construction of facilities for the study and recovery of endangered tropical wildlife, fish, and plant species and the restoration of their habitats;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the study of biological control of non-native species that degrade or destroy native forest ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> achieving a better understanding of global climate change and the significance of achieving a reduction of greenhouse gases through research associated with the unique atmospheric conditions found in Hawaii and the Pacific Ocean;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a review of the extent to which existing Federal forestry programs can be utilized to achieve the purposes of the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the establishment of experimental tropical forests in the State of Hawaii as authorized by <ref>section 4503b of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In preparing elements of the plan that address paragraph (2)(F), the Secretary shall identify the capability of the plan—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to promote a greater understanding of tropical forest ecosystem processes, conservation biology, and biodiversity management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to demonstrate the various benefits of maintaining a tropical forest reserve system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to promote sound watershed and forest management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to develop compatible land uses adjacent to protected natural areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to develop new methods of reclaiming and restoring degraded lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 605</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4593</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(42)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503b.</num>
<heading> Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Forest” means the Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Governor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Governor” means the Governor of Hawaii.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “lands” means lands, waters, and interests in lands and waters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means the State of Hawaii.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">At the request of the Governor, the Secretary shall establish and administer within the State a Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest. The Forest shall be managed as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a model of quality tropical forest management where harvesting on a sustainable yield basis can be demonstrated in balance with natural resource conservation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a site for research on tropical forestry, conservation biology, and natural resource management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a center for demonstration, education, training, and outreach on tropical forestry, conservation biology, and natural resources research and management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delineation of location of Forest</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Governor and the Secretary shall identify one or more suitable sites for the Forest in lands within the State. The identification of each site shall be based on scientific, ecological, administrative, and such other factors as the Governor and Secretary consider to be necessary or desirable to achieve the purposes of this section. Each site identified pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be of sufficient size and located so that the site can be effectively managed for Forest purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exterior boundaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The exterior boundaries of the Forest, including the boundaries of all sites identified for Forest purposes, shall be delineated on an official map. The map shall be available for public inspection in the office of the Administrator of the Division of Forestry and Wildlife of the Department of Land and Natural Resources of the State. The Governor and the Secretary may from time to time, by mutual agreement, amend the official map to modify the boundaries of the Forest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities of Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of this section, the Secretary is authorized—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to administer the Forest in cooperation with the Governor and affected State agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to make grants and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with the Federal Government, the government of the State, local governments, corporations, nonprofit organizations and individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to exercise existing authority with respect to cooperative forestry and research for Forest purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> to issue necessary rules and regulations or apply existing rules and regulations applicable to areas administered by the Forest Service that are necessary or desirable to administer the Forest—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for the purposes described in subsection (b);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to protect persons within the Forest; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to preserve and protect the resources in the Forest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Land acquisition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority in <ref>section 1643 of this title</ref> shall be available to the Secretary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section is intended to affect the jurisdiction of the State, both civil and criminal, over any person within the Forest by reason of the establishment of the Forest under this section, except in the case of a penalty for an offense against the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 606</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503c.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503d.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter (unless the context otherwise requires):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institutes of Tropical Forestry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Institutes of Tropical Forestry” means the Institute of Tropical Forestry in Puerto Rico and the Institute of Pacific Islands Forestry established under <ref>section 6706 of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the 50 States, Guam, American Samoa, the Republic of Palau (until the Compact of Free Association enters into effect), Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 608</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4504.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate all activities outside of the United States under this chapter with other Federal officials, departments, agencies, and international organizations, as the President may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may provide assistance, as determined appropriate by the Secretary to carry out this chapter, including technical and financial assistance, equipment, and facilities without reimbursement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 609</ref>, formerly § 605, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2072</ref>; renumbered § 609, <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4505.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 610</ref>, formerly § 606, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2072</ref>; renumbered § 610, <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>