<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3B—</num>
<heading>SOIL CONSERVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 590a.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is recognized that the wastage of soil and moisture resources on farm, grazing, and forest lands of the Nation, resulting from soil erosion, is a menace to the national welfare and that it is declared to be the policy of Congress to provide permanently for the control and prevention of soil erosion to preserve soil, water, and related resources, promote soil and water quality, control floods, prevent impairment of reservoirs, and maintain the navigability of rivers and harbors, protect public health, public lands and relieve unemployment, and the Secretary of Agriculture, from now on, shall coordinate and direct all activities with relation to soil erosion and in order to effectuate this policy is authorized, from time to time—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To conduct surveys, investigations, and research relating to the character of soil erosion and the preventive measures needed, to publish the results of any such surveys, investigations, or research, to disseminate information concerning such methods, and to conduct demonstrational projects in areas subject to erosion by wind or water;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To carry out preventive measures, including, but not limited to, engineering operations, methods of cultivation, the growing of vegetation, and changes in use of land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To cooperate or enter into agreements with, or to furnish financial or other aid to, any agency, governmental or otherwise, or any person, subject to such conditions as he may deem necessary, for the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To acquire lands, or rights or interests therein, by purchase, gift, condemnation, or otherwise, whenever necessary for the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 163</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title II, § 2802(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1085</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title II, § 2802(a)(1), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1813.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590b.</num>
<heading> Lands on which preventive measures may be taken</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The acts authorized in section 590a(1) and (2) of this title may be performed—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> On lands owned or controlled by the United States or any of its agencies, with the cooperation of the agency having jurisdiction thereof; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> On any other lands, upon obtaining proper consent or the necessary rights or interests in such lands.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 2</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590c.</num>
<heading> Conditions under which benefits of law extended to nongovernment controlled lands</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As a condition to the extending of any benefits under this chapter to any lands not owned or controlled by the United States or any of its agencies, the Secretary of Agriculture may, insofar as he may deem necessary for the purposes of this chapter, require the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The enactment and reasonable safeguards for the enforcement of State and local laws imposing suitable permanent restrictions on the use of such lands and otherwise providing for the prevention of soil erosion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Agreements or covenants as to the permanent use of such lands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Contributions in money, services, materials, or otherwise, to any operations conferring such benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The payment of user fees for conservation planning technical assistance if the Secretary determines that the fees, subject to subparagraph (B), are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reasonable and appropriate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assessed for conservation planning technical assistance resulting in the development of a conservation plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> assessed based on the size of the land or the complexity of the resource issues involved.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Fees under subparagraph (A) may not exceed $150 per conservation plan for which technical assistance is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may waive fees otherwise required under subparagraph (A) in the case of conservation planning technical assistance provided—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to beginning farmers or ranchers (as defined in <ref>section 1991(a) of title 7</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to limited resource farmers or ranchers (as defined by the Secretary);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers (as defined in <ref>section 2003(e) of title 7</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to qualify for an exemption from ineligibility under <ref>section 3812 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> to comply with Federal, State, or local regulatory requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 3</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 163</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title VII, § 705(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590d.</num>
<heading> Cooperation of governmental agencies; officers and employees, appointment and compensation; expenditures for personal services and supplies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary of Agriculture may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Secure the cooperation of any governmental agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, appoint and fix compensation of such officers and employees as he may deem necessary, except for a period not to exceed eight months from <date date="1935-04-27">April 27, 1935</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture may make appointments and may continue employees of the organization heretofore established for the purpose of administering those provisions of the National Industrial Recovery Act which relate to the prevention of soil erosion, without regard to the civil-service laws or regulations and the Classification Act, as amended; and any persons with technical or practical knowledge may be employed and compensated under this chapter on a basis to be determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Make expenditures for personal services and rent in the District of Columbia and elsewhere, for the purchase of law books and books of reference, for printing and binding, for the purchase, operation, and maintenance of passenger-carrying vehicles, and perform such acts, and prescribe such regulations, as he may deem proper to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 4</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 164</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3784</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 246(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3225</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 590e–1, 590e–2.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590f.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations and conservation technical assistance funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of this chapter such sums as Congress may from time to time determine to be necessary.</p>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations for carrying out this chapter allocated for the production or procurement of nursery stock by any Federal agency, or funds appropriated to any Federal agency for allocation to cooperating States for the production or procurement of nursery stock, shall remain available for expenditure for not more than three fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation Technical Assistance Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Conservation Technical Assistance Fund” (referred to in this subsection as the “Fund”), to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An amount equal to the amounts collected as fees under <ref>section 590c(4) of this title</ref> and late payments, interest, and such other amounts as are authorized to be collected pursuant to <ref>section 3717 of title 31</ref> shall be deposited in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Amounts in the Fund shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> only be available to the extent and in the amount provided in advance in appropriations Acts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be used for the costs of carrying out this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 6</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 164</ref>; <ref>Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title III, § 302(a), <ref>58 Stat. 738</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title VII, § 705(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 1193</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590g.</num>
<heading> Additional policies and purposes of chapter</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes enumerated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is hereby declared to be the policy of this chapter also to secure, and the purposes of this chapter shall also include, (1) preservation and improvement of soil and water quality and related resources; (2) promotion of the economic use and conservation of land; (3) diminution of exploitation and wasteful and unscientific use of national soil resources; (4) the protection of rivers and harbors against the results of soil erosion in aid of maintaining the navigability of waters and water courses and in aid of flood control; (5) reestablishment, at as rapid a rate as the Secretary of Agriculture determines to be practicable and in the general public interest, of the ratio between the purchasing power of the net income per person on farms and that of the income per person not on farms that prevailed during the five-year period August 1909–July 1914, inclusive, as determined from statistics available in the United States Department of Agriculture, and the maintenance of such ratio; (6) prevention and abatement of agricultural-related pollution,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002459">1</ref> and (7) the promotion of energy and water conservation through dry land farming. The powers conferred under this section and sections 590h, 590i, and 590j to 590n of this title shall be used to assist voluntary action calculated to effectuate the purposes specified in this section. Such powers shall not be used to discourage the production of supplies of foods and fibers sufficient to maintain normal domestic human consumption as determined by the Secretary from the records of domestic human consumption in the years 1920 to 1929, inclusive, taking into consideration increased population, quantities of any commodity that were forced into domestic consumption by decline in exports during such period, current trends in domestic consumption and exports of particular commodities, and the quantities of substitutes available for domestic consumption within any general class of food commodities. In carrying out the purposes of this section due regard shall be given to the maintenance of a continuous and stable supply of agricultural commodities adequate to meet consumer demand at prices fair to both producers and consumers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (g) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 101(1)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 605</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1148</ref>; amended <ref>June 28, 1937, ch. 395, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 329</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 101(1)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 605</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–419, title VI, § 606(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 676</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XII, § 1253</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1517</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title II, § 2802(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1085</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title II, § 2802(a)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1813.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 590g–1, 590g–2.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590h.</num>
<heading> Payments and grants of aid</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 101(2)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 605</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation and environmental assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental quality incentives program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide technical assistance, cost-share payments, and incentive payments to operators through the environmental quality incentives program in accordance with subchapter A of chapter 4 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 3839aa</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (4) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(A)(i)(I)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1004</ref></heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State, county, and area committees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of State committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall appoint in each State a State committee composed of not fewer than 3 nor more than 5 members who are fairly representative of the farmers in the State. The members of a State committee shall serve at the pleasure of the Secretary for such term as the Secretary may establish.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and elections for county, area, or local committees</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">In each county or area in which activities are carried out under this section, the Secretary shall establish a county or area committee.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local administrative areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Secretary may designate local administrative areas within a county or a larger area under the jurisdiction of a committee established under subclause (I).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition of county, area, or local committees</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">Except as provided in subclause (II), a committee established under clause (i) shall consist of not fewer than 3 nor more than 5 members that—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> are fairly representative of the agricultural producers within the area covered by the county, area, or local committee; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> are elected by the agricultural producers that participate or cooperate in programs administered within the area under the jurisdiction of the county, area, or local committee.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Combination or consolidation of areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">A committee established by combining or consolidating 2 or more county or area committees shall consist of not fewer than 3 nor more than 11 members that—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> are fairly representative of the agricultural producers within the area covered by the county, area, or local committee; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> are elected by the agricultural producers that participate or cooperate in programs administered within the area under the jurisdiction of the county, area, or local committee.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation of socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Secretary shall develop procedures to maintain representation of socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers on combined or consolidated committees.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(IV)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Notwithstanding any other producer eligibility requirements for service on county or area committees, if a county or area is consolidated or combined, a producer shall be eligible to serve only as a member of the county or area committee that the producer elects to administer the farm records of the producer.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elections</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Subject to subclauses (II) through (V), the Secretary shall establish procedures for nominations and elections to county, area, or local committees.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondiscrimination statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Each solicitation of nominations for, and notice of elections of, a county, area, or local committee shall include the nondiscrimination statement used by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nominations</heading>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">To be eligible for nomination and election to the applicable county, area, or local committee, as determined by the Secretary, an agricultural producer shall be located within the area under the jurisdiction of a county, area, or local committee, and participate or cooperate in programs administered within that area.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(bb)</num>
<heading> Outreach</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">In addition to such nominating procedures as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary shall solicit and accept nominations from organizations representing the interests of socially disadvantaged groups (as defined in section 355(e)(1) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2003(e)(1)</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002460">1</ref></p>
</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(IV)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Opening of ballots</heading>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading> Public notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">At least 10 days before the date on which ballots are to be opened and counted, a county, area, or local committee shall announce the date, time, and place at which election ballots will be opened and counted.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(bb)</num>
<heading> Opening of ballots</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">Election ballots shall not be opened until the date and time announced under item (aa).</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(cc)</num>
<heading> Observation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">Any person may observe the opening and counting of the election ballots.</p>
</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(V)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report of election</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">Not later than 20 days after the date on which an election is held, a county, area, or local committee shall file an election report with the Secretary and the State office of the Farm Service Agency that includes—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the number of eligible voters in the area covered by the county, area, or local committee;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the number of ballots cast in the election by eligible voters (including the percentage of eligible voters that cast ballots);</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> the number of ballots disqualified in the election;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> the percentage that the number of ballots disqualified is of the number of ballots received;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ee)</num>
<content> the number of nominees for each seat up for election;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ff)</num>
<content> the race, ethnicity, and gender of each nominee, as provided through the voluntary self-identification of each nominee; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(gg)</num>
<content> the final election results (including the number of ballots received by each nominee).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(VI)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the first election of a county, area, or local committee that occurs after <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, is held, the Secretary shall complete a report that consolidates all the election data reported to the Secretary under subclause (V).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(VII)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election reform</heading>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading> Analysis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">If determined necessary by the Secretary after analyzing the data contained in the report under subclause (VI), the Secretary shall promulgate and publish in the Federal Register proposed uniform guidelines for conducting elections for members and alternate members of county, area, and local committees not later than 1 year after the date of completion of the report.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(bb)</num>
<heading> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">The procedures promulgated by the Secretary under item (aa) shall ensure fair representation of socially disadvantaged groups described in subclause (III)(bb) in an area covered by the county, area, or local committee, in cases in which those groups are underrepresented on the county, area, or local committee for that area.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(cc)</num>
<heading> Methods of inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">Notwithstanding clause (ii), the Secretary may ensure inclusion of socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers through provisions allowing for appointment of 1 additional voting member to a county, area, or local committee or through other methods.</p>
</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term of office for a member of a county, area, or local committee shall not exceed 3 years.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability and report to Congress</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Secretary shall maintain and make readily available to the public, via website and otherwise in electronic and paper form, all data required to be collected and computed under <ref>section 2279–1(c) of title 7</ref> and clause (iii)(V) collected annually since the most recent Census of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">After each Census of Agriculture, the Secretary shall report to Congress the rate of loss or gain in participation by each socially disadvantaged group, by race, ethnicity, and gender, since the previous Census.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination or combination of committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may not terminate a county or area committee or combine or consolidate two or more county or area committees unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary first notifies the committee or committees involved of the proposed action; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the State committee of the State in which the affected counties are located approves of such action in a vote taken after the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date the notification is received.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall use the services of such committees in carrying out programs under this section and the agricultural credit programs under the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1921</ref> et seq.) and in considering administrative appeals as provided by <ref>section 6932(d) of title 7</ref>. The Secretary may use the services of such committees in carrying out programs under other authorities administered by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary considers necessary relating to the selection and exercise of the functions of the respective committees, and to the administration through such committees of the programs described in subparagraph (D). Pursuant to such regulations, each county and area committee shall select an executive director for the area or county. Such selection shall be made in the same manner as provided for the selection of the county executive director under section 7.21(b)(2) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>. Regulations governing payments or grants under this subsection shall be as simple and direct as possible, and, whenever practicable, they shall be classified on the following two bases:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Soil-depleting practices.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Soil-building practices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory duties of Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> insofar as practicable, protect the interests of tenants and sharecroppers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> accord such encouragement to producer-owned and producer-controlled cooperative associations as will be in harmony with the policy toward cooperative associations set forth in Federal laws and as will tend to promote efficient methods of marketing and distribution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in every practicable manner, protect the interests of small producers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> in every practical way, encourage and provide for soil-conserving and soil-rebuilding practices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary authorities of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out this section, the Secretary may use other approved agencies.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(H)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall not have the authority to acquire any land or any right or interest in land.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apportionment of acreage allotments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In apportioning acreage allotments under this section in the case of wheat and corn, the National and State allotments and the allotments to counties shall be apportioned annually on the basis of the acreage seeded for the production of the commodity during the ten calendar years immediately preceding the calendar year in which the national acreage allotment is determined (plus, in applicable years, the acreage diverted under previous agricultural adjustment and conservation programs), with adjustments for abnormal weather conditions and trends in acreage during the applicable period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of wheat, the allotment to any county shall be apportioned annually by the Secretary, through the local committees, among the farms within such county on the basis of tillable acres, crop-rotation practices, type of soil, and topography. Not more than 3 per centum of such county allotment shall be apportioned to farms on which wheat has not been planted during any of the three marketing years immediately preceding the marketing year in which the allotment is made. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the allotments established, or which would have been established, for any farm acquired in 1940 or thereafter by the United States for national-defense purposes shall be placed in an allotment pool and shall be used only to establish allotments for other farms owned or acquired by the owner of the farm so acquired by the United States. The allotments so made for any farm, including a farm on which wheat has not been planted during any of the three marketing years preceding the marketing year in which the allotment is made, shall compare with the allotments established for other farms in the same area which are similar except for the past acreage of wheat.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of corn, the allotment to any county shall be apportioned annually by the Secretary, through the local committees, among the farms within such county on the basis of tillable acreage, type of soil, topography, and crop rotation practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Apr. 10, 1939, ch. 48</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 573</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In determining normal yield per acre for any county under this section in the case of wheat or corn, the normal yield shall be the average yield per acre therein for such commodity during the ten calendar years immediately preceding the calendar year in which such yield is determined, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions and trends in yields. If for any reason there is no actual yield, or the data therefor are not available for any year, then an appraised yield for such year, determined in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, shall be used. If, on account of drought, flood, insect pests, plant disease, or other uncontrollable natural cause, the yield in any year of such ten-year period is less than 75 per centum of the average (computed without regard to such year), such year shall be eliminated in calculating the normal yield per acre. Such normal yield per acre for any county need be redetermined only when the actual average yield for the ten calendar years immediately preceding the calendar year in which such yield is being reconsidered differs by at least 5 per centum from the actual average yield for the ten years upon which the existing normal yield per acre for the county was based.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In determining normal yield per acre for any farm under this section in the case of wheat or corn, the normal yield shall be the average yield per acre thereon for such commodity during the ten calendar years immediately preceding the calendar year in which such yield is determined, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions and trends in yields. If for any such year the data are not available, or there is no actual yield, then the normal yield for the farm shall be appraised in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, taking into consideration abnormal weather conditions, the normal yield for the county, and the yield in years for which data are available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (f) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1004</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A payment that may be made to a producer under this section may be assigned only in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary. This subsection shall not authorize any suit against or impose any liability on the Secretary, any disbursing agent, or any agency of the United States if payment is made to the producer without regard to the existence of any such assignment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1149</ref>; amended <ref>June 28, 1937, ch. 395, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 329</ref>; <ref>Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title I, §§ 101, 102, 103, <ref>52 Stat. 31</ref>, 34, 35; <ref>Apr. 7, 1938, ch. 107</ref>, §§ 16–18, <ref>52 Stat. 204</ref>, 205; <ref>Apr. 10, 1939, ch. 48</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 573</ref>; <ref>May 14, 1940, ch. 200</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref>July 2, 1940, ch. 521, § 2</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>June 21, 1941, ch. 217</ref>, <ref>55 Stat. 257</ref>; <ref>Dec. 26, 1941, ch. 626, § 1</ref>, <ref>55 Stat. 860</ref>; <ref>Feb. 6, 1942, ch. 44, § 4</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 53</ref>; <ref>Sept. 29, 1942, ch. 568</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 761</ref>; <ref>Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref>58 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref>July 25, 1946, ch. 642</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 663</ref>; <ref>July 3, 1948, ch. 827</ref>, title I, § 4, <ref>62 Stat. 1250</ref>; <ref>Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 997</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 978</ref>; <ref>May 26, 1952, ch. 335</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title V, § 501, <ref>68 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref>Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 624</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Apr. 6, 1956, ch. 186</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>July 24, 1956, ch. 668</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–553</ref>, <date date="1958-07-25">July 25, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 414</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 13(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 101(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 605</ref>, 606; <ref>Pub. L. 88–534, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–742</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1167</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–419, title VI</ref>, §§ 605, 606(2)–(5), <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 676</ref>, 677; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XV, § 1501(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1019</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 259</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII</ref>, §§ 1711(a), 1712, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1635</ref>, 1636; <ref>Pub. L. 99–253, § 3</ref>, <date date="1986-02-28">Feb. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 36</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(a) [title VI, § 645]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783</ref>, 1783–36, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(a) [title VI, § 645]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341</ref>, 3341–36; <ref>Pub. L. 99–641, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XI, § 1146</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 227(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10708(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 522</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1615</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1021</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1615, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1749; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2301(d)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 590h–1, 590h–2.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590h–3.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 88–534, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 743</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590h–4.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(2)(G)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1006</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590i.</num>
<heading> Surveys and investigations; publication of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to conduct surveys, investigations, and research relating to the conditions and factors affecting, and methods of accomplishing most effectively, the policy and purposes of <ref>section 590g(a) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding any provision of existing law, the Secretary is authorized to make public such information as he deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1150</ref>; amended <ref>June 28, 1937, ch. 395, § 2</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 329</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–375, title I, § 103(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590i–1.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590i–2.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590j.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural commodity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “agricultural commodity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an agricultural commodity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any regional or market classification, type, or grade of an agricultural commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “technical assistance” means technical expertise, information, and tools necessary for the conservation of natural resources on land active in agricultural, forestry, or related uses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “technical assistance” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> technical services provided directly to farmers, ranchers, and other eligible entities, such as conservation planning, technical consultation, and assistance with design and implementation of conservation practices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> technical infrastructure, including activities, processes, tools, and agency functions needed to support delivery of technical services, such as technical standards, resource inventories, training, data, technology, monitoring, and effects analyses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 10</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1150</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title II, § 2802(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1085</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title II, § 2802(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1813.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590k.</num>
<heading> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All funds available for carrying out this chapter shall be available for allotment to the bureaus and offices of the Department of Agriculture and for transfer to such other agencies of the Federal or State Governments, or to local public agencies, as the Secretary may request to cooperate or assist in carrying out this chapter, and for payments to committees or associations of producers in any region or regions to cover the estimated administrative expenses to be incurred by any such committee or association in cooperating in carrying out this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary may prescribe that all or part of such estimated expenses of any such committee or association may be deducted pro rata from the payments or grants made to the members thereof: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary may make such payments in advance of determination of performance. Funds so transferred may be placed in a single account for each State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 11</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1150</ref>; amended <ref>June 24, 1936, ch. 767</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1915</ref>; <ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 950, § 6(c)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1033</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1005</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590l.</num>
<heading> Expansion of domestic and foreign markets for agricultural commodities; advances for crop insurance; transfer of funds to corporation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Market expansion and surplus disposition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary finds that the exercise of the powers conferred in this section will tend to carry out the purpose specified in clause (5) of <ref>section 590g(a) of this title</ref>, or will tend to provide for and maintain a continuous and stable supply of agricultural commodities adequate to meet consumer demand at prices fair to both producers and consumers, or both, he shall use such part as he deems necessary of the sums appropriated to carry out this chapter for the expansion of domestic and foreign markets or for seeking new or additional markets for agricultural commodities or the products thereof or for the removal or disposition of surpluses of such commodities or the products thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advances for premiums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make advances to producers for the purpose of assisting them to insure their crops with the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation. The Secretary shall remit the amount of any such advances to a producer directly to such Corporation in payment of the premium on the insurance for which the producer has made application. Advances shall only be made to producers who are participating or who agree to participate in a program formulated pursuant to <ref>section 590h of this title</ref>. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the terms and conditions of such advances shall be fixed by the Secretary. In carrying out the provisions of this subsection, the Secretary may transfer to the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, prior to the execution of applications for insurance or requests for advances by producers, the funds estimated as necessary to cover the advances which will be requested for the payment of premiums under a crop-insurance program, and any portion of such funds not used for advances to producers under such program shall be returned to the Secretary by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 12</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1151</ref>; amended <ref>Mar. 25, 1939, ch. 15</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 550</ref>; <ref>July 2, 1940, ch. 521, § 1</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590m.</num>
<heading> Execution of powers of Secretary by Production and Marketing Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this chapter, the Secretary is authorized and directed to provide for the execution by the Production and Marketing Administration of such powers conferred upon him under sections 590g, 590h, 590i, and 590j to 590n of this title as he deems may be appropriately exercised by such Administration, and for such purposes the provisions of law applicable to the appointment and compensation of persons employed by the Production and Marketing Administration shall apply.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 13</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1151</ref>; amended 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 501, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7877, <ref>60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590n.</num>
<heading> Payments reviewable only by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The facts constituting the bases for any payment or grant or the amount thereof authorized to be made under <ref>section 590g of this title</ref>, when officially determined in conformity with rules or regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture, shall be reviewable only by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1151</ref>; amended <ref>Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 950, § 6(a)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1033</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1005</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590o.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations; distribution of appropriated funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To enable the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 590g of this title</ref> there is authorized to be appropriated for any fiscal year not exceeding $500,000,000. The amount appropriated shall be available until expended. The Secretary shall distribute the funds available for financial assistance among the several States in accordance with their conservation needs, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 15</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1151</ref>; amended <ref>Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title I, § 104, <ref>52 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title V, § 502, <ref>68 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–419, title VI, § 606(6)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XV, § 1501(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1020</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1005</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590p.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1006</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590p–1.</num>
<heading> Limitation on wetlands drainage assistance to aid wildlife preservation; termination of limitation; redetermination of need for assistance upon change of ownership of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall not enter into an agreement in the States of North Dakota, South Dakota, and Minnesota to provide financial or technical assistance for wetland drainage on a farm under authority of this chapter, if the Secretary of the Interior has made a finding that wildlife preservation will be materially harmed on that farm by such drainage and that preservation of such land in its undrained status will materially contribute to wildlife preservation and such finding, identifying specifically the farm and the land on that farm with respect to which the finding was made, has been filed with the Secretary of Agriculture within ninety days after the filing of the application for drainage assistance: <i>Provided</i>, That the limitation against furnishing such financial or technical assistance shall terminate (1) at such time as the Secretary of the Interior notifies the Secretary of Agriculture that such limitation should not be applicable, (2) one year after the date on which the adverse finding of the Secretary of the Interior was filed unless during that time an offer has been made by the Secretary of the Interior or a State government agency to lease or to purchase the wetland area from the owner thereof as a waterfowl resource, or (3) five years after the date on which such adverse finding was filed if such an offer to lease or to purchase such wetland area has not been accepted by the owner thereof: <i>Provided further</i>, That upon any change in the ownership of the land with respect to which such adverse finding was filed, the eligibility of such land for such financial or technical assistance shall be redetermined in accordance with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 16A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 87–732</ref>, <date date="1962-10-02">Oct. 2, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590q.</num>
<heading> Coverage; “State” defined; short title</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> This chapter shall apply to the States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Virgin Islands, and, as used in this chapter, the term “State” includes Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This chapter may be cited as the “Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 17</ref>, as added <ref>Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1151</ref>; amended <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 339, § 2</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 494</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 13(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624</ref>. § 8(b), <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–454, title VI, § 601(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590q–1.</num>
<heading> Sale and distribution of supplies, materials, and equipment to other Government agencies; reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Soil Conservation Service subject to applicable regulations under chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3306(f), 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4104, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 may sell and distribute supplies, materials, and equipment to other Government activities, the cost of such supplies and materials or the value of such equipment (including the cost of transportation and handling) to be reimbursed to appropriations current at the time additional supplies, materials, or equipment are procured from the appropriations chargeable with the cost or value of such supplies, materials, or equipment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title III, § 302(b), <ref>58 Stat. 738</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 2(12)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590q–2.</num>
<heading> Voluntary relinquishment of allotments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may provide for the reduction or cancellation of any allotment or base when the owner of the farm states in writing that he has no further use of such allotment or base.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–524, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1970-11-30">Nov. 30, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 590q–3.</num>
<heading> Critical lands resource conservation program in Great Plains area</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization for program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to formulate and carry out a program with owners and operators of land in the Great Plains area as described in section 590p(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002461">1</ref> of this title to reduce runoff, soil and water erosion, and otherwise to promote the conservation of soil and water resources in such area through the conversion of cropland from soil depleting uses to conserving uses including the production of soil conserving cover crops.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of agreements with owners or operators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To effectuate the purposes of the program, the Secretary may enter into an agreement for a two-year period with an owner or operator as described in subsection (a) whereby the owner or operator shall agree to devote to a soil conserving cover crop a specifically designated acreage of cropland on the farm up to 50 per centum of the acreage which had been planted to any soil depleting crop or crops in any of the two years preceding the date of the agreement. The agreement shall be renewable for annual periods thereafter subject to the mutual agreement of the owner or operator and the Secretary. In such agreement, the owner or operator shall agree (1) to plant a legume, or if not adapted to such area, an annual, biennial, or a perennial cover crop, as specified in the agreement; (2) to divert from production such portion of one or more crops designated by the Secretary as the Secretary determines necessary to effectuate the purpose of the program; (3) not to harvest any crop from or graze the designated acreage during the agreement period, unless the Secretary determines that it is necessary to permit grazing or harvesting in order to alleviate damage, hardship, or suffering caused by severe drought, flood, or other natural disaster, and consents to such grazing or harvesting subject to an appropriate reduction in the rate of payment; (4) to give adequate assurance, as specified by the Secretary, that the land was not acquired for the purpose of placing it in the program: <i>Provided</i>, That the foregoing provision shall not prohibit the continuation of an agreement by a new owner if an agreement has once been entered into under this section nor prevent an owner or operator from placing a farm in the program if the farm was acquired by the owner to replace an eligible farm from which he was displaced because of its acquisition by any Federal, State, or other agency having the right of eminent domain; (5) to forfeit all rights to further payments under the agreement and refund to the United States all payments received thereunder upon his violation of the agreement at any stage during the time he has control of the land if the Secretary determines that such violation is of such a nature as to warrant termination of the agreement, or to make refunds or accept such payment adjustments as the Secretary may deem appropriate if the Secretary determines that the violation by the owner or operator does not warrant termination of the agreement; (6) upon transfer of his right and interest in the farm, during the agreement period, to forfeit all rights to further payments under the agreement and refund to the United States all payments received thereunder unless the transferee of any such land agrees with the Secretary to assume all obligations of the agreement; (7) not to adopt any practice specified by the Secretary in the agreement as a practice which would tend to defeat the purposes of the agreement; and (8) to such additional provisions as the Secretary determines are desirable to effectuate the purposes of the program or to facilitate the practical administration of the program, including such measures as the Secretary may deem appropriate to keep the designated acreage from eroding and free from weeds and rodents in accordance with good conservation systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual adjustment payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In consideration for such agreement, the Secretary shall make annual adjustment payments to the owner or operator for the period of the agreement at such rate or rates not in excess of $30 per acre as the Secretary determines to be fair and reasonable. The Secretary may use an advertising and bid procedure in determining the lands in any area to be covered by agreements and the payment rate therefor. The Secretary and the owner or operator may agree that the annual adjustment payments for the agreement period shall be made either upon approval of the agreement or in such installments as they may agree to be desirable: <i>Provided</i>, That for each year any annual adjustment payment is made in advance of performance, the annual adjustment payment shall be reduced by 5 per centum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may terminate any agreement under the program, by mutual agreement with the owner or operator, if the Secretary determines that such termination would be in the public interest, and may agree with the owner or operator to such modification of agreements as the Secretary may determine to be desirable to carry out the purposes of the program or facilitate its administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation of cropland, crop acreage, and allotment history</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, to the extent the Secretary deems it desirable, provide by appropriate regulations for preservation of cropland, crop acreage, and allotment history applicable to acreage diverted from the production of crops to establish vegetative cover for the purpose of any Federal program under which such history is used as a basis for an allotment or other limitation or for participation in such program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of Federal and non-Federal offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall utilize the services of local, county, and State committees established under <ref>section 590h of this title</ref> and the technical services of the Soil Conservation Service and soil and water conservation districts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In case any producer who is entitled to any payment under the program dies, becomes incompetent, or disappears before receiving such payment, or is succeeded by another who renders or completes the required performance, the payment shall, without regard to any other provisions of law, be made as the Secretary may determine to be fair and reasonable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tenants and sharecroppers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide adequate safeguards to protect the interests of tenants and sharecroppers, including provision for sharing, on a fair and equitable basis, in payments under the program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations; utilization of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for the period beginning <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>, and ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, such sums as may be necessary to carry out the program provided for in this section. The Secretary is authorized to utilize the facilities, services, and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation in discharging the Secretary’s functions and responsibilities under the program, including payment of costs of administration: <i>Provided</i>, That the Commodity Credit Corporation shall not make any expenditures for such purposes unless the Corporation has received funds to cover such expenditures from appropriations made to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–113, title XV, § 1511</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>