<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 41—</num>
<heading>COOPERATIVE FORESTRY ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2101.</num>
<heading> Findings, purpose, and policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> most of the productive forest land of the United States is in private, State, and local governmental ownership, and the capacity of the United States to produce renewable forest resources is significantly dependent on such non-Federal forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adequate supplies of timber and other forest resources are essential to the United States, and adequate supplies are dependent on efficient methods for establishing, managing, and harvesting trees and processing, marketing, and using wood and wood products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> nearly one-half of the wood supply of the United States comes from nonindustrial private timberlands and such percentage could rise with expanded assistance programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> managed forest lands provide habitats for fish and wildlife, as well as aesthetics, outdoor recreation opportunities, and other forest resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the soil, water, and air quality of the United States can be maintained and improved through good stewardship of privately held forest resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> insects and diseases affecting trees occur and sometimes create emergency conditions on all land, whether Federal or non-Federal, and efforts to prevent and control such insects and diseases often require coordinated action by both Federal and non-Federal land managers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> fires in rural areas threaten human lives, property, forests and other resources, and Federal-State cooperation in forest fire protection has proven effective and valuable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> trees and forests are of great environmental and economic value to urban areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> managed forests contribute to improving the quality, quantity, and timing of water yields that are of broad benefit to society;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> over half the forest lands of the United States are in need of some type of conservation treatment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> forest landowners are being faced with increased pressure to convert their forest land to development and other purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> increased population pressures and user demands are being placed on private, as well as public, landholders to provide a wide variety of products and services, including fish and wildlife habitat, aesthetic quality, and recreational opportunities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> stewardship of privately held forest resources requires a long-term commitment that can be fostered through local, State, and Federal governmental actions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the Department of Agriculture, through the coordinated efforts of its agencies with forestry responsibilities, cooperating with other Federal agencies, State foresters, and State political subdivisions, has the expertise and experience to assist private landowners in achieving individual goals and public benefits regarding forestry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> the products and services resulting from nonindustrial private forest land stewardship provide income and employment that contribute to the economic health and diversity of rural communities; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002708">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> sustainable agroforestry systems and tree planting in semiarid lands can improve environmental quality and maintain farm yields and income; and <sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002709">2</ref> the same forest resource supply, protection, and management issues that exist in the United States are also present on an international scale, and the forest and rangeland renewable resources of the world are threatened by deforestation due to conversion to agriculture of lands better suited to other purposes, over-grazing, over-harvesting, and other causes which pose a direct adverse threat to people, the global environment, and the world economy.<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Secretary”), with respect to non-Federal forest lands in the United States, and forest lands in foreign countries, of the United States, to assist in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the establishment of a coordinated and cooperative Federal, State, and local forest stewardship program for management of the non-Federal forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the encouragement of the production of timber;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the prevention and control of insects and diseases affecting trees and forests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the prevention and control of rural fires;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the efficient utilization of wood and wood residues, including the recycling of wood fiber;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the improvement and maintenance of fish and wildlife habitat;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the planning and conduct of urban forestry programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> broadening existing forest management, fire protection, and insect and disease protection programs on non-Federal forest lands to meet the multiple use objectives of landowners in an environmentally sensitive manner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> providing opportunities to private landowners to protect ecologically valuable and threatened non-Federal forest lands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> strengthening educational, technical, and financial assistance programs that provide assistance to owners of non-Federal forest lands in the United States, and forest lands in foreign countries,.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002710">3</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In allocating funds appropriated or otherwise made available under this chapter, the Secretary shall focus on the following national private forest conservation priorities, notwithstanding other priorities specified elsewhere in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Conserving and managing working forest landscapes for multiple values and uses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Protecting forests from threats, including catastrophic wildfires, hurricanes, tornados, windstorms, snow or ice storms, flooding, drought, invasive species, insect or disease outbreak, or development, and restoring appropriate forest types in response to such threats.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Enhancing public benefits from private forests, including air and water quality, soil conservation, biological diversity, carbon storage, forest products, forestry-related jobs, production of renewable energy, wildlife, wildlife corridors and wildlife habitat, and recreation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2011-09-30">September 30, 2011</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing how funds were used under this chapter, and through other programs administered by the Secretary, to address the national priorities specified in subsection (c) and the outcomes achieved in meeting the national priorities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of Congress that it is in the national interest for the Secretary to work through and in cooperation with State foresters, or equivalent State officials, nongovernmental organizations, and the private sector in implementing Federal programs affecting non-Federal forest lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall be construed to complement the policies and direction under the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1600</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 365</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 611(b)(1)</ref>, (2), formerly § 607(b)(1), (2), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2072</ref>, renumbered § 611(b)(1), (2), <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1212</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8001</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8001, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2041.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2101a.</num>
<heading> State-wide assessment and strategies for forest resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment and strategies for forest resources</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For a State to be eligible to receive funds under the authorities of this chapter, the State forester of that State or equivalent State official shall develop and submit to the Secretary, not later than two years after the date of enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A State-wide assessment of forest resource conditions, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the conditions and trends of forest resources in that State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the threats to forest lands and resources in that State consistent with the national priorities specified in <ref>section 2101(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any areas or regions of that State that are a priority; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any multi-State areas that are a regional priority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A long-term State-wide forest resource strategy, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> strategies for addressing threats to forest resources in the State outlined in the assessment required by paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the resources necessary for the State forester or equivalent State official from all sources to address the State-wide strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updating</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At such times as the Secretary determines to be necessary, the State forester or equivalent State official shall update and resubmit to the Secretary the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing or updating the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a), the State Forester or equivalent State official shall coordinate with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the State Forest Stewardship Coordinating Committee established for the State under <ref>section 2113(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the State wildlife agency, with respect to strategies contained in the State wildlife action plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the State Technical Committee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> applicable Federal land management agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> as feasible, appropriate military installations where the voluntary participation and management of private or State-owned or other public forestland is able to support, promote, and contribute to the missions of such installations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> for purposes of the Forest Legacy Program under <ref>section 2103c of this title</ref>, the State lead agency designated by the Governor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incorporation of other plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing or updating the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a), the State forester or equivalent State official shall incorporate any forest management plan of the State, including community wildfire protection plans and State wildlife action plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sufficiency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Once approved by the Secretary, a State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy developed under subsection (a) shall be deemed to be sufficient to satisfy all relevant State planning and assessment requirements under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section up to $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional funding sources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the funds appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in paragraph (1) to carry out this section, the Secretary may use any other funds made available for planning under this chapter to carry out this section, except that the total amount of combined funding used to carry out this section may not exceed $10,000,000 in any fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report on use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The State forester or equivalent State official shall submit to the Secretary an annual report detailing how funds made available to the State under this chapter are being used.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 2A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8002</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1280</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8002, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2041; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8101</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8101</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102.</num>
<heading> Rural forestry assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to forest landowners and others</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may provide financial, technical, educational, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials, and State extension directors, to enable such officials to provide technical information, advice, and related assistance to private forest land owners and managers, vendors, forest resource operators, forest resource professionals, public agencies, and individuals to enable such persons to carry out activities that are consistent with the purposes of this chapter, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> protecting, maintaining, enhancing, restoring, and preserving forest lands and the multiple values and uses that depend on such lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identifying, protecting, maintaining, enhancing, and preserving wildlife and fish species, including threatened and endangered species, and their habitats;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> implementing forest management technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> selecting, producing, and marketing alternative forest crops, products and services from forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> protecting forest land from damage caused by fire, insects, disease, and damaging weather;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> managing the rural-land and urban-land interface to balance the use of forest resources in and adjacent to urban and community areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> identifying and managing recreational forest land resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> identifying and protecting the aesthetic character of forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> protecting forest land from conversion to alternative uses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> the management of resources of forest lands, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the harvesting, processing, and marketing of timber and other forest resources and the marketing and utilization of wood and wood products;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the conversion of wood to energy for domestic, industrial, municipal, and other uses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the planning, management, and treatment of forest land, including site preparation, reforestation, thinning, prescribed burning, and other silvicultural activities designed to increase the quantity and improve the quality of timber and other forest resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ensuring that forest regeneration or reforestation occurs if needed to sustain long-term resource productivity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> protecting and improving forest soil fertility and the quality, quantity, and timing of water yields; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> encouraging the investment of a portion of the proceeds from the sale of timber or other forest resources in stewardship activities that preserve, protect, maintain, and enhance their forest land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State forestry assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to provide financial, technical, and related assistance to State foresters, or equivalent State officials, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop genetically improved tree seeds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop and contract for the development of field arboretums, greenhouses, and tree nurseries, in cooperation with a State, to facilitate production and distribution of tree seeds and seedlings in States where the Secretary determines that there is an inadequate capacity to carry out present and future reforestation needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> procure, produce, and distribute tree seeds and trees for the purpose of establishing forests, windbreaks, shelterbelts, woodlots, and other plantings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> plant tree seeds and seedlings on non-Federal forest lands that are suitable for the production of timber, recreation, and for other benefits associated with the growing of trees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> plan, organize, and implement measures on non-Federal forest lands, including thinning, prescribed burning, and other silvicultural activities designed to increase the quantity and improve the quality of trees and other vegetation, fish and wildlife habitat, and water yielded therefrom; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> protect or improve soil fertility on non-Federal forest lands and the quality, quantity, and timing of water yields therefrom.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this section, the Secretary shall cooperate with other Federal, State, and local natural resource management agencies, universities and the private sector.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 366</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1213</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8001(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103a.</num>
<heading> Forest Stewardship Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, shall establish a Forest Stewardship Program (hereafter referred to in this section as the “Program”) to encourage the long-term stewardship of nonindustrial private forest lands by assisting owners of such lands to more actively manage their forest and related resources by utilizing existing State, Federal, and private sector resource management expertise and assistance programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Goal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The goal of the Program shall be to enter at least 25,000,000 acres of nonindustrial private forest lands in the Program by <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Nonindustrial private forest lands” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “nonindustrial private forest lands” means rural, as determined by the Secretary, lands with existing tree cover, or suitable for growing trees, and owned by any private individual, group, association, corporation, Indian tribe, or other private legal entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the Program the Secretary, in consultation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, shall provide financial, technical, educational, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials, including assistance to help such State foresters or equivalent officials to provide financial assistance to other State and local natural resource entities, both public and private, and land-grant universities for the delivery of information and professional assistance to owners of nonindustrial private forest lands. Such information and assistance shall be directed to help such owners understand and evaluate alternative actions they might take, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> managing and enhancing the productivity of timber, fish and wildlife habitat, water quality, wetlands, recreational resources, and the aesthetic value of forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> investing in practices to protect, maintain, and enhance the resources identified in paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensuring that afforestation, reforestation, improvement of poorly stocked stands, timber stand improvement, practices necessary to improve seedling growth and survival, and growth enhancement practices occur where needed to enhance and sustain the long-term productivity of timber and nontimber forest resources to help meet future public demand for all forest resources and provide the environmental benefits that result; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> protecting their forests from damage caused by fire, insects, disease, and damaging weather.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All nonindustrial private forest lands that are not in management under Federal, State, or private sector financial and technical assistance programs existing on <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, are eligible for assistance under the Program. Nonindustrial private forest lands that are managed under such existing programs are eligible for assistance under the Program if forest management activities are expanded and enhanced and the landowner agrees to meet the requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of owners</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To enter forest land into the Program, landowners shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> prepare and submit to the State forester or equivalent State official a forest stewardship plan that meets the requirements of this section and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is prepared by a professional resource manager;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identifies and describes actions to be taken by the landowner to protect soil, water, range, aesthetic quality, recreation, timber, water, and fish and wildlife resources on such land in a manner that is compatible with the objectives of the landowner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is approved by the State forester, or equivalent State official; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> agree that all activities conducted on such land shall be consistent with the stewardship plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stewardship recognition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, is encouraged to develop an appropriate recognition program for landowners who practice stewardship management on their lands, with an appropriate, special recognition symbol and title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1991 through 1995, and such sums as may be necessary thereafter, to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1215(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1018(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8002</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103c.</num>
<heading> Forest Legacy Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the Forest Legacy Program, in cooperation with appropriate State, regional, and other units of government for the purposes of ascertaining and protecting environmentally important forest areas that are threatened by conversion to nonforest uses and, through the use of conservation easements and other mechanisms, for promoting forest land protection and other conservation opportunities. Such purposes shall also include the protection of important scenic, cultural, fish, wildlife, and recreational resources, riparian areas, and other ecological values.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and regional forest legacy programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall exercise the authority under subsection (a) in conjunction with State or regional programs that the Secretary deems consistent with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interests in land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the authorities granted under <ref>section 515 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 2268a(a) of title 7</ref>, the Secretary may acquire from willing landowners lands and interests therein, including conservation easements and rights of public access, for Forest Legacy Program purposes. The Secretary shall not acquire conservation easements with title held in common ownership with any other entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Lands and interests therein acquired under subsection (c) may be held in perpetuity for program and easement administration purposes as the Secretary may provide. In administering lands and interests therein under the program, the Secretary shall identify the environmental values to be protected by entry of the lands into the program, management activities which are planned and the manner in which they may affect the values identified, and obtain from the landowner other information determined appropriate for administration and management purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1991-11-28">November 28, 1991</date>, the Secretary shall establish a regional program in furtherance of the Northern Forest Lands Study in the States of New York, New Hampshire, Vermont, and Maine under <ref>Public Law 100–446</ref>. The Secretary shall establish additional programs in each of the Northeast, Midwest, South, and Western regions of the United States, and the Pacific Northwest (including the State of Washington), on the preparation of an assessment of the need for such programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1991-11-28">November 28, 1991</date>, and in consultation with State Forest Stewardship Coordinating Committees established under <ref>section 2113(b) of this title</ref> and similar regional organizations, the Secretary shall establish eligibility criteria for the designation of forest areas from which lands may be entered into the Forest Legacy Program and subsequently select such appropriate areas. To be eligible, such areas shall have significant environmental values or shall be threatened by present or future conversion to nonforest uses. Of land proposed to be included in the Forest Legacy Program, the Secretary shall give priority to lands which can be effectively protected and managed, and which have important scenic or recreational values; riparian areas; fish and wildlife values, including threatened and endangered species; or other ecological values.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For areas included in the Forest Legacy Program, an owner of lands or interests in lands who wishes to participate may prepare and submit an application at such time in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may prescribe. The Secretary shall give reasonable advance notice for the submission of all applications to the State forester, equivalent State official, or other appropriate State or regional natural resource management agency. If applications exceed the ability of the Secretary to fund them, priority shall be given to those forest areas having the greatest need for protection pursuant to the criteria described in subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where a State has not approved the acquisition of land under <ref>section 515 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall not acquire lands or interests therein under authority granted by this section outside an area of that State designated as a part of a program established under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest management activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Conservation easements or deed reservations acquired or reserved pursuant to this section may allow forest management activities, including timber management, on areas entered in the Forest Legacy Program insofar as the Secretary deems such activities consistent with the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment of responsibilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For Forest Legacy Program areas, the Secretary may delegate or assign management and enforcement responsibilities over federally owned lands and interests in lands only to another governmental entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of owners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under the terms of a conservation easement or other property interest acquired under subsection (b),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002711">1</ref> the landowner shall be required to manage property in a manner that is consistent with the purposes for which the land was entered in the Forest Legacy Program and shall not convert such property to other uses. Hunting, fishing, hiking, and similar recreational uses shall not be considered inconsistent with the purposes of this program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation and cost sharing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall pay the fair market value of any property interest acquired under this section. Payments under this section shall be in accordance with Federal appraisal and acquisition standards and procedures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with terms and conditions that the Secretary shall prescribe, costs for the acquisition of lands or interests therein or project costs shall be shared among participating entities including regional organizations, State and other governmental units, landowners, corporations, or private organizations. Such costs may include, but are not limited to, those associated with planning, administration, property acquisition, and property management. To the extent practicable, the Federal share of total program costs shall not exceed 75 percent, including any in-kind contribution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Easements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reserved interest deeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As used in this section, the term “conservation easement” includes an easement utilizing a reserved interest deed where the grantee acquires all rights, title, and interests in a property, except those rights, title, and interests that may run with the land that are expressly reserved by a grantor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibitions on limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding any provision of State law, no conservation easement held by the United States or its successors or assigns under this section shall be limited in duration or scope or be defeasible by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the conservation easement being in gross or appurtenant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the management of the conservation easement having been delegated or assigned to a non-Federal entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any requirement under State law for re-recordation or renewal of the easement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any future disestablishment of a Forest Legacy Program area or other Federal project for which the conservation easement was originally acquired.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any provision of State law, conservation easements shall be construed to effect the Federal purposes for which they were acquired and, in interpreting their terms, there shall be no presumption favoring the conservation easement holder or fee owner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Optional State grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall, at the request of a participating State, provide a grant to the State to carry out the Forest Legacy Program in the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a State elects to receive a grant under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall use a portion of the funds made available under subsection (m), as determined by the Secretary, to provide a grant to the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the State shall use the grant to carry out the Forest Legacy Program in the State, including the acquisition by the State of lands and interests in lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of Forest Legacy Program land—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to any terms and conditions that the Secretary may require (including the requirements described in subparagraph (B)), the Secretary may, at the request of the State of Vermont, convey to the State, by quitclaim deed, without consideration, any land or interest in land acquired in the State under the Forest Legacy Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In conveying land or an interest in land under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may require that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the deed conveying the land or interest in land include requirements for the management of the land in a manner that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> conserves the land or interest in land; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is consistent with any other Forest Legacy Program purposes for which the land or interest in land was acquired;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if the land or interest in land is subsequently sold, exchanged, or otherwise disposed of by the State of Vermont, the State shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> reimburse the Secretary in an amount that is based on the current market value of the land or interest in land in proportion to the amount of consideration paid by the United States for the land or interest in land; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> convey to the Secretary land or an interest in land that is equal in value to the land or interest in land conveyed.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Amounts received by the Secretary under subparagraph (B)(ii) shall be credited to the Wildland Fire Management account, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1217</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3528</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1018(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 374</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1015</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–108, title III, § 336</ref>, <date date="2003-11-10">Nov. 10, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103d.</num>
<heading> Community forest and open space conservation program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means a local governmental entity, Indian tribe, or nonprofit organization that owns or acquires a parcel under the program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local governmental entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “local governmental entity” includes any municipal government, county government, or other local government body with jurisdiction over local land use decisions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “nonprofit organization” means any organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is described in <ref>section 170(h)(3) of title 26</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operates in accordance with 1 or more of the purposes specified in <ref>section 170(h)(4)(A) of title 26</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the community forest and open space conservation program established under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the “community forest and open space conservation program”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to acquire private forest land,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002712">1</ref> to be owned in fee simple, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are threatened by conversion to nonforest uses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> provide public benefits to communities, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> economic benefits through sustainable forest management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> environmental benefits, including clean water and wildlife habitat;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> benefits from forest-based educational programs, including vocational education programs in forestry;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> benefits from serving as models of effective forest stewardship for private landowners; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> recreational benefits, including hunting and fishing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal cost share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible entity may receive a grant under the Program in an amount equal to not more than 50 percent of the cost of acquiring 1 or more parcels, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition of receipt of the grant, an eligible entity that receives a grant under the Program shall provide, in cash, donation, or in kind, a non-Federal matching share in an amount that is at least equal to the amount of the grant received.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appraisal of parcels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To determine the non-Federal share of the cost of a parcel of privately-owned forest land under paragraph (2), an eligible entity shall require appraisals of the land that comply with the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions developed by the Interagency Land Acquisition Conference.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An eligible entity that seeks to receive a grant under the Program shall submit to the State forester or equivalent official (or in the case of an Indian tribe, an equivalent official of the Indian tribe) an application that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the land to be acquired;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a forest plan that provides—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of community benefits to be achieved from the acquisition of the private forest land; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an explanation of the manner in which any private forest land to be acquired using funds from the grant will be managed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such other relevant information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on trust land</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall not provide a grant under the Program for any project on land held in trust by the United States (including Indian reservations and allotment land).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquired land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No land acquired using a grant provided under the Program shall be converted to land held in trust by the United States on behalf of any Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications to Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State forester or equivalent official (or in the case of an Indian tribe, an equivalent official of the Indian tribe) shall submit to the Secretary a list that includes a description of each project submitted by an eligible entity at such times and in such form as the Secretary shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of eligible entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An eligible entity shall provide public access to, and manage, forest land acquired with a grant under this section in a manner that is consistent with the purposes for which the land was acquired under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited uses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), an eligible entity that acquires a parcel under the Program shall not sell the parcel or convert the parcel to nonforest use.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible entity that sells or converts to nonforest use a parcel acquired under the Program shall pay to the Federal Government an amount equal to the greater of the current sale price, or current appraised value, of the parcel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loss of eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible entity that sells or converts a parcel acquired under the Program shall not be eligible for additional grants under the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State administration and technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may allocate not more than 10 percent of all funds made available to carry out the Program for each fiscal year to State foresters or equivalent officials (including equivalent officials of Indian tribes) for Program administration and technical assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 7A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8003(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1281</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8003(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2043.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104.</num>
<heading> Forest health protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may protect trees and forests and wood products, stored wood, and wood in use directly on the National Forest System and, in cooperation with others, on other lands in the United States, from natural and man-made causes, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhance the growth and maintenance of trees and forests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promote the stability of forest-related industries and employment associated therewith through the protection of forest resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> aid in forest fire prevention and control;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conserve forest cover on watersheds, shelterbelts, and windbreaks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> protect outdoor recreation opportunities and other forest resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> extend timber supplies by protecting wood products, stored wood, and wood in use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsections (c), (d), and (e) and to such other conditions the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may, directly on the National Forest System, in cooperation with other Federal departments on other Federal lands, and in cooperation with State foresters, or equivalent State officials, subdivisions of States, agencies, institutions, organizations, or individuals on non-Federal lands—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct surveys to detect and appraise insect infestations and disease conditions and man-made stresses affecting trees and establish a monitoring system throughout the forests of the United States to determine detrimental changes or improvements that occur over time, and report annually concerning such surveys and monitoring;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determine the biological, chemical, and mechanical measures necessary to prevent, retard, control, or suppress incipient, potential, threatening, or emergency insect infestations and disease conditions affecting trees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> plan, organize, direct, and perform measures the Secretary determines necessary to prevent, retard, control, or suppress incipient, potential, threatening, or emergency insect infestations and disease epidemics affecting trees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide technical information, advice, and related assistance on the various techniques available to maintain a healthy forest and in managing and coordinating the use of pesticides and other toxic substances applied to trees and other vegetation, and to wood products, stored wood, and wood in use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop applied technology and conduct pilot tests of research results prior to the full-scale application of such technology in affected forests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> promote the implementation of appropriate silvicultural or management techniques that may improve or protect the health of the forests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> take any other actions the Secretary determines necessary to accomplish the objectives and purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent of entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Operations under this section to prevent, retard, control, or suppress insects or diseases affecting forests and trees on land not controlled or administered by the Secretary shall not be conducted without the consent, cooperation, and participation of the entity having ownership of or jurisdiction over the affected land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contribution by entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No money appropriated to implement this section shall be expended to prevent, retard, control, or suppress insects or diseases affecting trees on non-Federal land until the entity having ownership of or jurisdiction over the affected land contributes, or agrees to contribute, to the work to be done in the amount and in the manner determined appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allotments to other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, in the Secretary’s discretion, and out of any money appropriated to implement this section, make allocations to Federal agencies having jurisdiction over lands held or owned by the United States in the amounts the Secretary determines necessary to prevent, retard, control, or suppress insect infestations and disease epidemics affecting trees on those lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removing dead trees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No amounts appropriated shall be used to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pay the cost of felling and removing dead or dying trees unless the Secretary determines that such actions are necessary to prevent the spread of a major insect infestation or disease epidemic severely affecting trees; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compensate for the value of any property injured, damaged, or destroyed by any cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insects and diseases affecting trees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may procure materials and equipment necessary to prevent, retard, control, or suppress insects and diseases affecting trees without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>, under whatever procedures the Secretary may prescribe, if the Secretary determines that such action is necessary and in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, by contract or cooperative agreement, may provide financial assistance through the Forest Service to State foresters or equivalent State officials, and private forestry and other organizations, to monitor forest health and protect the forest lands of the United States. The Secretary shall require contribution by the non-Federal entity in the amount and in the manner determined appropriate. Such non-Federal share may be in the form of cash, services, or equipment, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated annually such sums as may be necessary to carry out subsections (a) through (g).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated pest management</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (e), the Secretary shall, in cooperation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, subdivisions of States, or other entities on non-Federal lands (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the “cooperator”)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide cost-share assistance to such cooperators who have established an acceptable integrated pest management strategy, as determined by the Secretary, that will prevent, retard, control, or suppress gypsy moth, southern pine beetle, spruce budworm infestations, or other major insect infestations in an amount no less than 50 percent nor greater than 75 percent of the cost of implementing such strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon request, assist the cooperator in the development of such integrated pest management strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually $10,000,000 to implement this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 8</ref>, formerly § 5, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 368</ref>; renumbered § 8 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1215(1), 1218, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>, 3531.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104a.</num>
<heading> Pest and Disease Revolving Loan Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized equipment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “authorized equipment” means any equipment necessary for the management of forest land.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “authorized equipment” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> cherry pickers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> equipment necessary for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the construction of staging and marshalling areas;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the planting of trees; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the surveying of forest land;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> vehicles capable of transporting harvested trees;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> wood chippers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any other appropriate equipment, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Fund” means the Pest and Disease Revolving Loan Fund established by subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Deputy Chief of the State and Private Forestry organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund, to be known as the “Pest and Disease Revolving Loan Fund”, consisting of such amounts as are appropriated to the Fund under subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures from Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), on request by the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the Fund to the Secretary such amounts as the Secretary determines are necessary to provide loans under subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An amount not exceeding 10 percent of the amounts in the Fund shall be available for each fiscal year to pay the administrative expenses necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers of amounts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amounts required to be transferred to the Fund under this section shall be transferred at least monthly from the general fund of the Treasury to the Fund on the basis of estimates made by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Proper adjustment shall be made in amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were in excess of or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uses of Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loans</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall use amounts in the Fund to provide loans to eligible units of local government to finance purchases of authorized equipment to monitor, remove, dispose of, and replace infested trees that are located—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on land under the jurisdiction of the eligible units of local government; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> within the borders of quarantine areas infested by plant pests.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The maximum amount of a loan that may be provided by the Secretary to an eligible unit of local government under this subsection shall be the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount that the eligible unit of local government has appropriated to finance purchases of authorized equipment in accordance with subparagraph (A); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $5,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The interest rate on any loan made by the Secretary under this paragraph shall be a rate equal to 2 percent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after the date on which an eligible unit of local government receives a loan provided by the Secretary under subparagraph (A), the eligible unit of local government shall submit to the Secretary a report that describes each purchase made by the eligible unit of local government using assistance provided through the loan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan repayment schedule</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To be eligible to receive a loan from the Secretary under paragraph (1), in accordance with each requirement described in subparagraph (B), an eligible unit of local government shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary to establish a loan repayment schedule relating to the repayment of the loan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements relating to loan repayment schedule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A loan repayment schedule established under subparagraph (A) shall require the eligible unit of local government—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> to repay to the Secretary of the Treasury, not later than 1 year after the date on which the eligible unit of local government receives a loan under paragraph (1), and semiannually thereafter, an amount equal to the quotient obtained by dividing—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the principal amount of the loan (including interest); by</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the total quantity of payments that the eligible unit of local government is required to make during the repayment period of the loan; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not later than 20 years after the date on which the eligible unit of local government receives a loan under paragraph (1), to complete repayment to the Secretary of the Treasury of the loan made under this section (including interest).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title X, § 10205</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1344</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title X, § 10205, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2106.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2105.</num>
<heading> Urban and community forestry assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the health of forests in urban areas and communities, including cities, their suburbs, and towns, in the United States is on the decline;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> forest lands, shade trees, and open spaces in urban areas and communities improve the quality of life for residents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> forest lands and associated natural resources enhance the economic value of residential and commercial property in urban and community settings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> urban trees are 15 times more effective than forest trees at reducing the buildup of carbon dioxide and aid in promoting energy conservation through mitigation of the heat island effect in urban areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> tree plantings and ground covers such as low growing dense perennial turfgrass sod in urban areas and communities can aid in reducing carbon dioxide emissions, mitigating the heat island effect, and reducing energy consumption, thus contributing to efforts to reduce global warming trends;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> efforts to encourage tree plantings and protect existing open spaces in urban areas and communities can contribute to the social well-being and promote a sense of community in these areas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> strengthened research, education, technical assistance, and public information and participation in tree planting and maintenance programs for trees and complementary ground covers for urban and community forests are needed to provide for the protection and expansion of tree cover and open space in urban areas and communities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this section are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve understanding of the benefits of preserving existing tree cover in urban areas and communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage owners of private residences and commercial properties to maintain trees and expand forest cover on their properties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide education programs and technical assistance to State and local organizations (including community associations and schools) in maintaining forested lands and individual trees in urban and community settings and identifying appropriate tree species and sites for expanding forest cover;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide assistance through competitive matching grants awarded to local units of government, approved organizations that meet the requirements of <ref>section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref>, or other local community tree volunteer groups, for urban and community forestry projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> implement a tree planting program to complement urban and community tree maintenance and open space programs and to reduce carbon dioxide emissions, conserve energy, and improve air quality in addition to providing other environmental benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> promote the establishment of demonstration projects in selected urban and community settings to illustrate the benefits of maintaining and creating forest cover and trees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> enhance the technical skills and understanding of sound tree maintenance and arboricultural practices including practices involving the cultivation of trees, shrubs and complementary ground covers, of individuals involved in the planning, development, and maintenance of urban and community forests and trees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> expand existing research and educational efforts intended to improve understanding of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> tree growth and maintenance, tree physiology and morphology, species adaptations, and forest ecology,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the value of integrating trees and ground covers,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the economic, environmental, social, and psychological benefits of trees and forest cover in urban and community environments, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the role of urban trees in conserving energy and mitigating the urban heat island.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to provide financial, technical, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials for the purpose of encouraging States to provide information and technical assistance to units of local government and others that will encourage cooperative efforts to plan urban forestry programs and to plant, protect, and maintain, and utilize wood from, trees in open spaces, greenbelts, roadside screens, parks, woodlands, curb areas, and residential developments in urban areas. In providing such assistance, the Secretary is authorized to cooperate with interested members of the public, including nonprofit private organizations. The Secretary is also authorized to cooperate directly with units of local government and others in implementing this section whenever the Secretary and the affected State forester or equivalent State official agree that direct cooperation would better achieve the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program of education and technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, in cooperation with State foresters and State extension directors or equivalent State officials and interested members of the public, including nonprofit private organizations, shall implement a program of education and technical assistance for urban and community forest resources. The program shall be designed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assist urban areas and communities in conducting inventories of their forest resources, including inventories of the species, number, location, and health of trees in urban areas and communities, identifying opportunities for the establishment of plantings for the purposes of conserving energy, and determining the status of related resources (including fish and wildlife habitat, water resources, and trails);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist State and local organizations (including community associations and schools) in organizing and conducting urban and community forestry projects and programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> improve education and technical support in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> selecting tree species appropriate for planting in urban and community environments and for promotion of energy conservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing for proper tree planting, maintenance, and protection in urban areas and communities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> protecting individual trees and preserving existing open spaces with or without tree cover; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identifying opportunities for expanding tree cover in urban areas and communities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assist in the development of State and local management plans for trees and associated resources in urban areas and communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> increase public understanding of the energy conservation, economic, social, environmental, and psychological values of trees and open space in urban and community environments and expand knowledge of the ecological relationships and benefits of trees and related resources in these environments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement of plant materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in cooperation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, shall assist in identifying sources of plant materials and may procure or otherwise obtain such plant materials from public or private sources and may make such plant materials available to urban areas and communities for the purpose of reforesting open spaces, replacing dead and dying urban trees, promoting energy conservation, and providing other environmental benefits through expanding tree cover in urban areas and communities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Challenge cost-share program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish an urban and community forestry challenge cost-share program. Funds or other support shall be provided under such program to eligible communities and organizations, on a competitive basis, for urban and community forestry projects. The Secretary shall annually make awards under the program in accordance with criteria developed in consultation with, and after consideration of recommendations received from, the National Urban and Community Forestry Advisory Council established under subsection (g). Each State forester or equivalent State official may make recommendations to the Secretary for awards under the program for project proposals in their State which meet such criteria. Awards shall be consistent with the cost-share requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal share of support for a project provided under this subsection may not exceed 50 percent of the support for that project and shall be provided on a matching basis. The non-Federal share of such support may be in the form of cash, services, or in-kind contributions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forestry Advisory Council</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a National Urban and Community Forestry Advisory Council (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Council”) for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> developing a national urban and community forestry action plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> evaluating the implementation of that plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> developing criteria for, and submitting recommendations with respect to, the urban and community forestry challenge cost-share program under subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition and operation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Council shall be composed of 15 members appointed by the Secretary, as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 2 members representing national nonprofit forestry and conservation citizen organizations,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 3 members, 1 each representing State, county, and city and town governments,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 1 member representing the forest products, nursery, or related industries,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> 1 member representing urban forestry, landscape, or design consultants,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> 2 members representing academic institutions with an expertise in urban and community forestry activities,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> 1 member representing State forestry agencies or equivalent State agencies,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> 1 member representing a professional renewable natural resource or arboricultural society,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> 1 member from the National Institute of Food and Agriculture,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> 1 member from the Forest Service, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> 2 members who are not officers or employees of any governmental body, 1 of whom is a resident of a community with a population of less than 50,000 as of the most recent census and both of whom have expertise and have been active in urban and community forestry.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A vacancy in the Council shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall select 1 member, from members appointed to the Council, who is not an officer or employee of the United States nor any State, county, city, or town government, who shall serve as the chairperson of the Council.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in clauses (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, members shall be appointed for terms of 3 years, and no member may serve more than 2 consecutive terms on the Council.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staggered terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Of the members first appointed—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 5, including the chairperson and 2 governmental employees, shall be appointed for a term of 3 years,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 5, including 2 governmental employees, shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> 5, including 2 governmental employees, shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, as designated by the Secretary at the time of appointment.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term of the member’s predecessor shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term. A member may serve after the expiration of the member’s term until the member’s successor has taken office.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), members of the Council shall serve without pay, but may be reimbursed for reasonable costs incurred while in the actual performance of duties vested in the Council.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal officers and employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Members of the Council who are full-time officers or employees of the United States shall receive no additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Council.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial and administrative support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall provide financial and administrative support for the Council.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Urban and Community Forestry Action Plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Within 1 year after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, and every 10 years thereafter, the Council shall prepare a National Urban and Community Forestry Action Plan. The plan shall include (but not be limited to) the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An assessment of the current status of urban forest resources in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A review of urban and community forestry programs and activities in the United States, including education and technical assistance activities conducted by the Department of Agriculture, and other Federal agencies, the State forestry organizations, private industry, private nonprofit organizations, community and civic organizations and interested others.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Recommendations for improving the status of the Nation’s urban and community forest resources, including education and technical assistance and modifications required in existing programs and policies of relevant Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> A review of urban and community forestry research, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a review of all ongoing research associated with urban and community forests, arboricultural practices, and the economic, social, and psychological benefits of trees and forest cover in urban and community environments being conducted by the Forest Service, other Federal agencies, and associated land grant colleges and universities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recommendations for new and expanded research efforts directed toward urban and community forestry concerns; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a summary of research priorities and an estimate of the funds needed to implement such research, on an annual basis, for the next 10 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Proposed criteria for evaluating proposed projects under the urban and community forestry challenge cost share program under subsection (f), with special emphasis given to projects that would demonstrate the benefits of improved forest management (including the maintenance and establishment of forest cover and trees) in urban areas and communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> An estimate of the resources needed to implement the National Urban and Community Forestry Action Plan for the succeeding 10 fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendment of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The plan may be amended by a majority of the Council members. Such amendments shall be incorporated into the Council’s annual review of the plan submitted to the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Council shall submit the plan to the Secretary and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate upon its completion. Beginning no later than one year after the plan is submitted and annually thereafter, the Council shall submit a review of the plan to the Secretary no later than December 31. The review shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Council’s assessment of prior year accomplishments in research, education, technical assistance, and related activities in urban and community forestry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Council’s recommendations for research, education, technical assistance, and related activities in the succeeding year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Council’s recommendations for the urban and community forestry challenge cost share projects to be funded during the succeeding year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The review submitted to the Secretary shall be incorporated into the annual report required under subsection (e) of <ref>section 1601 of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon request of the Council, the Secretary is authorized to detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the Department of Agriculture to the Council to assist the Council in carrying out its duties under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Council” means the National Urban and Community Forestry Advisory Council established under subsection (g);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “plan” means the National Urban and Community Forestry Action Plan developed under subsection (g)(3); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “urban and community area” includes cities, their suburbs, and towns.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1991 through 1995, and such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year thereafter, for the implementation of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 9</ref>, formerly § 6, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 369</ref>; renumbered § 9 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1215(1), 1219(a), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>, 3533; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1018(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(36)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(c)(36), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2032; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. G, title III, § 70302(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106.</num>
<heading> Rural fire prevention and control</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> significant accomplishments have been made by the Secretary and cooperating States in the prevention and control of fires on forest lands and on nonforested watersheds for more than fifty years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> progress is being made by the Secretary and cooperating States and rural communities in the protection of human lives, agricultural crops and livestock, property and other improvements, and natural resources from fires in rural areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> notwithstanding the accomplishments and progress that have been made, fire prevention and control on rural lands and in rural communities are of continuing high priority to protect human lives, agricultural crops and livestock, property and other improvements, and natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the effective cooperative relationships between the Secretary and the States regarding fire prevention and control on rural lands and in rural communities should be retained and improved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> efforts in fire prevention and control in rural areas should be coordinated among Federal, State, and local agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> in addition to providing assistance to State and local rural fire prevention and control programs, the Secretary should provide prompt and adequate assistance whenever a rural fire emergency overwhelms, or threatens to overwhelm, the firefighting capability of the affected State or rural area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 2201</ref> et seq.] the Secretary is authorized, under whatever conditions the Secretary may prescribe, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> cooperate with State foresters or equivalent State officials in developing systems and methods for the prevention, control, suppression, and prescribed use of fires on rural lands and in rural communities that will protect human lives, agricultural crops and livestock, property and other improvements, and natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide financial, technical, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials, and through them to other agencies and individuals, for the prevention, control, suppression, and prescribed use of fires on non-Federal forest lands and other non-Federal lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide financial, technical, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials in cooperative efforts to organize, train, and equip local firefighting forces, including those of Indian tribes or other native groups, to prevent, control, and suppress fires threatening human lives, crops, livestock, farmsteads or other improvements, pastures, orchards, wildlife, rangeland, woodland, and other resources in rural areas. As used herein, the term “rural areas” shall have the meaning set out in the first clause of section 1926(a)(7) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002713">1</ref> of title 7; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide financial, technical, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials, and through them to other agencies and individuals, including rural volunteer fire departments, to conduct preparedness and mobilization activities, including training, equipping, and otherwise enabling State and local firefighting agencies to respond to requests for fire suppression assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Encouragement of use of excess personal property by State and local fire forces receiving assistance; cooperation and assistance of Administrator of General Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, with the cooperation and assistance of the Administrator of General Services, shall encourage the use of excess personal property (within the meaning of chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41) by State and local fire forces receiving assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of assistance with assistance of Secretary of Commerce under Federal fire prevention and control provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To promote maximum effectiveness and economy, the Secretary shall seek to coordinate the assistance the Secretary provides under this section with the assistance provided by the Secretary of Commerce under the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 2201</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for implementation of provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually such sums as may be needed to implement paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> There are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually $70,000,000 to carry out subsection (b)(4). Of the total amount appropriated to carry out subsection (b)(4)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one-half shall be available only for State foresters or equivalent State officials, and through them to other agencies and individuals, of which not less than $100,000 shall be made available to each State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one-half shall be available only for rural volunteer fire departments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Federal share of the cost of any activity carried out with funds made available pursuant to this paragraph may not exceed 50 percent of the cost of that activity. The non-Federal share for such activity may be in the form of cash, services, or in kind contributions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rural fire disaster fund; establishment, appropriations, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be established in the Treasury a special rural fire disaster fund that shall be immediately available to and used by the Secretary to supplement any other money available to carry out this section with respect to rural fire emergencies, as determined by the Secretary. The Secretary shall determine that State and local resources are fully used or will be fully used before expending money in the disaster fund to assist a State in which one or more rural fire emergencies exist. There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be needed to establish and replenish the disaster fund established by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “rural volunteer fire department” means any organized, not for profit, fire protection organization that provides service primarily to a community or city with a population of 10,000 or less or to a rural area, as defined by the Secretary, whose firefighting personnel is 80 percent or more volunteer, and that is recognized as a fire department by the laws of the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “mobilization” means any activity in which one firefighting organization assists another that has requested assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 10</ref>, formerly § 7, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 370</ref>; renumbered § 10 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1215(1), 1220, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>, 3539; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1018(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106a.</num>
<heading> Emergency reforestation assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to provide assistance under this section to eligible landowners who suffer destruction of 35 percent or more of a commercial tree stand due to damaging weather, related condition, or wildfire.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The assistance, if any, provided by the Secretary under this section shall consist of either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reimbursement of up to 65 percent of the cost of reestablishing such tree stand damaged by the damaging weather, related condition, or wildfire in excess of 35 percent mortality; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at the discretion of the Secretary, provision of sufficient tree seedlings to reestablish such tree stand.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No person may receive an amount in excess of $25,000 in any fiscal year, or an equivalent value in tree seedlings, under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A person who has qualifying gross revenues in excess of $2,000,000 annually, as determined by the Secretary, shall not be eligible to receive any disaster payment or other benefits under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In implementing this section, the Secretary shall issue regulations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> defining the term “person” for the purposes of this section that shall conform, to the extent practicable, to the regulations defining the term “person” issued under section 1308 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002714">1</ref> of title 7 (before the amendment made by section 1603(a) of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prescribing such rules as the Secretary determines necessary to ensure a fair and reasonable application of the limitations established under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensuring that no person receives duplicative payments or assistance under this section, the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.), and the environmental quality incentives program established under subchapter A of chapter 4 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 3839aa</ref> et seq.], or other Federal program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “damaging weather” includes drought, hail, excessive moisture, freeze, tornado, hurricane, excessive wind, or any combination thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “eligible landowner” means a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> produces annual crops from trees for commercial purposes and owns 500 acres or less of such trees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> owns 1,000 acres or less of private forest land; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> owns more than 1,000 acres but less than 5,000 acres of private forest land if the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, determines the person eligible;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “qualifying gross revenues” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if a majority of the person’s annual income is received from farming, ranching, and forestry operations, the gross revenue from the person’s farming, ranching, and forestry operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if less than a majority of the person’s annual income is received from farming, ranching, and forestry operations, the person’s gross revenue from all sources;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “related condition” includes insect infestations, disease, or other deterioration of a tree stand that is accelerated or exacerbated by damaging weather;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “reestablish” includes site preparation, reforestation of a damaged stand, and timber stand improvement practices, including thinning, prescribed burning, and other practices approved by the Secretary for reforestation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “wildfire” means any forest or range fire.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retroactive assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall use funds provided under this section to reimburse landowners for approved reforestation practices that were implemented before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>. The Secretary shall not make reimbursements for reforestation practices that were implemented prior to <date date="1989-09-01">September 1, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1271</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3557</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1018(f)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1603(g)(5)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1603(g)(5), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1740; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1609(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2301(d)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106b.</num>
<heading> Use of money collected from States for fire suppression assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any money collected from the States for fire suppression assistance rendered by the Forest Service on non-Federal lands not in the vicinity of National Forest System lands shall on and after <date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date>, be used to reimburse the applicable appropriation and shall remain available until expended as the Secretary may direct in conducting activities authorized by <ref>16 U.S.C. 2101</ref> note, 2101–2110, 1606, and 2111.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–273.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106c.</num>
<heading> Enhanced community fire protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative management related to wildfire threats</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may cooperate with State foresters and equivalent State officials in the management of lands in the United States for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Aid in wildfire prevention and control.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Protect communities from wildfire threats.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Enhance the growth and maintenance of trees and forests that promote overall forest health.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Ensure the continued production of all forest resources, including timber, outdoor recreation opportunities, wildlife habitat, and clean water, through conservation of forest cover on watersheds, shelterbelts, and windbreaks.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a Community and Private Land Fire Assistance program (in this subsection referred to as the “Program”)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to focus the Federal role in promoting optimal firefighting efficiency at the Federal, State, and local levels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to augment Federal projects that establish landscape level protection from wildfires;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to expand outreach and education programs to homeowners and communities about fire prevention; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to establish space around homes and property of private landowners that is defensible against wildfires.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Program shall be administered by the Forest Service and implemented through State foresters or equivalent State officials.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Components</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In coordination with existing authorities under this chapter, the Secretary, in consultation with the State forester or equivalent State official, may undertake on non-Federal lands—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fuel hazard mitigation and prevention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> invasive species management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> multiresource wildfire planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> community protection planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> community and landowner education enterprises, including the program known as FIREWISE;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> market development and expansion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> improved wood utilization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> special restoration projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Program activities undertaken by the Secretary on non-Federal lands shall be undertaken only with the consent of the owner of the lands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall use persons in the local community wherever possible to carry out projects under the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the heads of other Federal agencies, as necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2007; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such sums as are necessary for fiscal years thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 10A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VIII, § 8003(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 473</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2107.</num>
<heading> Financial, technical, and related assistance to States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of State organizations for protection and management of non-Federal forest lands; scope of assistance; request by officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To aid in achieving maximum effectiveness in the programs and activities conducted under this chapter, the Secretary is authorized to provide financial, technical, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials for the development of stronger and more efficient State organizations that will enable them to fulfill better their responsibilities for the protection and management of non-Federal forest lands. Assistance under this subsection may include, but will not be limited to, assistance in matters related to organization management, program planning and management, budget and fiscal accounting services, personnel training and management, information services, and recordkeeping. Assistance under this subsection may be extended only upon request by State foresters or equivalent State officials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assembly, analysis, display, and reporting of State forest resources data, resources planning, etc.; scope of assistance; other statutory provisions unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To ensure that data regarding forest lands are available for and effectively presented in State and Federal natural resources planning, the Secretary is authorized to provide financial, technical, and related assistance to State foresters or equivalent State officials in the assembly, analysis, display, and reporting of State forest resources data, in the training of State forest resources planners, and in participating in natural resources planning at the State and Federal levels. The Secretary shall restrict assistance under this subsection to the implementation of the forestry aspects of State and Federal natural resources planning conducted under other laws. This subsection shall not be construed, in any way whatsoever, as extending, limiting, amending, repealing, or otherwise affecting any other law or authority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technology implementation program; scope of program; availability of funds; use of forest resources planning committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To ensure that new technology is introduced, new information is integrated into existing technology, and forest resources research findings are promptly made available to State forestry personnel, private forest landowners and managers, vendors, forest operators, wood proc­essors, public agencies, and individuals, the Secretary is authorized to carry out a program of technology implementation.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In implementing this subsection, the Secretary is authorized to work through State foresters or equivalent State officials, and, if the State forester or equivalent State official is unable to deliver these services, the Secretary is authorized to act through appropriate United States Department of Agriculture agencies, subdivisions of States, agencies, institutions, organizations, or individuals to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> strengthen technical assistance and service programs of cooperators participating in programs under this chapter by applying research results and conducting pilot projects and field tests of management and utilization practices, equipment, and technologies, related to programs and activities authorized under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> study the effects of tax laws, methods, and practices on forest management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> develop and maintain technical information systems in support of programs and activities authorized under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> test, evaluate, and seek registration of chemicals for use in implementing the programs and activities authorized under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> conduct other activities, including training of State forestry personnel whom the Secretary deems necessary to ensure that the programs and activities authorized under this chapter are responsive to special problems, unique situations, and changing conditions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may make funds available to cooperators under this chapter without regard to the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31, which prohibits advances of public money.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall use forest resources planning committees at National and State levels in implementing this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually such sums as may be needed to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 11</ref>, formerly § 8, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 371</ref>; renumbered § 11, <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1215(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2108.</num>
<heading> Consolidation of payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request by State; excluded funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To provide flexibility in funding activities authorized under this chapter, the Secretary may, upon the request of any State, consolidate the annual financial assistance payments to that State under this chapter, in lieu of functional cost sharing mechanisms, formulas, or agreements. However, consolidated payments shall not include money appropriated under section 2103 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002715">1</ref> of this title or money from any special Treasury fund established under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State forest resources programs as basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Consolidation of payments made under this section shall be based upon State forest resources programs developed by State foresters or equivalent State officials, and reviewed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Consolidated payments to any State during any fiscal year shall not exceed the total amount of non-Federal funds expended within the State during that year to implement its State forest resources program. However, the Secretary may make payments that exceed the non-Federal amount expended for selected activities under the program, if the total Federal expenditure during any fiscal year does not exceed the total non-Federal expenditure during that year under the State forest resources program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification requirement by State forester or equivalent State official for Federal payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make consolidated payments on the certificate of the State forester or equivalent State official that the conditions for Federal payment have been met.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of consolidated payments program not to adversely affect, etc., other programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer this section to ensure that the use of consolidated payments does not adversely affect or eliminate any program authorized under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Total annual amount of financial assistance to participating State; financial assistance for special projects not to be included in determining base amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to applicable appropriation Acts, the total annual amount of financial assistance to any participating State after <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, shall not be less than the base amount of financial assistance provided to that State under all the provisions of law specified in <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref> during the fiscal year in which this chapter is enacted. However, financial assistance for special projects of two years or less duration shall not be included in determining the base amount for any participating State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 12</ref>, formerly § 9, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 372</ref>; renumbered § 12 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1215(1), 1224(2), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>, 3542.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2109.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative and coordinating requirements for implementation of programs, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In implementing this chapter, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> work through, cooperate with, and assist State foresters or equivalent State officials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage cooperation and coordination between State foresters or equivalent State officials and other State agencies that manage renewable natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use and encourage cooperators under this chapter to use, private agencies, consult­ants, organizations, firms, and individuals to furnish necessary materials and services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> promote effectiveness and economy by coordinating the direct actions and assistance authorized under this chapter with related programs the Secretary administers, and with cooperative programs of other agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Money appropriated under this chapter shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation requirements for implementation of programs, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Requirements for the development of State forest resources programs and State participation in management assistance, planning assistance, and technology implementation, the apportionment of funds among States participating under this chapter, the administrative expenses in connection with activities and programs under this chapter, and the amounts to be expended by the Secretary to assist non-State cooperators under this chapter, shall be determined by the Secretary in consultation with a committee of not less than five State foresters or equivalent State officials selected by a majority of the State foresters or equivalent State officials from States participating in programs under this chapter. However, the Secretary need not consult with such committee regarding funds to be expended under emergency conditions that the Secretary may determine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms “United States” and “State” shall include each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Republic of Palau, and the territories and possessions of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “forest resources” shall include esthetics, fish and wildlife, forage, outdoor recreation opportunities, timber, and water; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “urban forestry” means the planning, establishment, protection, and management of trees and associated plants, individually, in small groups, or under forest conditions within cities, their suburbs, and towns.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may prescribe rules and regulations, as the Secretary deems appropriate, to implement the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Granting, etc., authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make grants, agreements, contracts, and other arrangements the Secretary deems necessary to implement this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of statutory provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall be construed as supplementing all other laws relating to the Department of Agriculture and shall not be construed as limiting or repealing any existing law or authority of the Secretary, except as specifically cited in <ref>section 2111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the authority provided elsewhere in this chapter, the Secretary may provide assistance to other countries with respect to the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (10) of <ref>section 2102(b) of this title</ref>, paragraphs (1) through (5) of section 2104(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002716">1</ref> of this title, and paragraphs (1) through (3) of <ref>section 2105(b) of this title</ref>. For the purposes of providing assistance to other countries under this subsection, the term “non-Federal forest land” shall mean any forest land and related renewable natural resources in such countries. In providing the assistance authorized under this subsection, the Secretary shall coordinate with other Federal officials, departments, agencies, or international organizations, as the President may direct. The references to “State foresters or equivalent State officials” in this chapter shall not apply to the assistance provided by the Secretary to other countries under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 13</ref>, formerly § 10, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 611(b)(3)</ref>, formerly § 607(b)(3), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2072</ref>, renumbered § 611(b)(3), <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4593</ref>; renumbered § 13 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1215(1), 1224(3), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>, 3542; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8004</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8004, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2045.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2109a.</num>
<heading> State and private forest landscape-scale restoration program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to encourage collaborative, science-based restoration of priority forest landscapes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonindustrial private forest land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “nonindustrial private forest land” means land that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is rural, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has existing tree cover or is suitable for growing trees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is owned by any private individual, group, association, corporation, Indian tribe, or other private legal entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State forest land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State forest land” means land that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is rural, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is under State or local governmental ownership and considered to be non-Federal forest land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with State foresters or appropriate State agencies, shall establish a competitive grant program to provide financial and technical assistance to encourage collaborative, science-based restoration of priority forest landscapes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an applicant shall submit to the Secretary, through the State forester or appropriate State agency, a State and private forest landscape-scale restoration proposal based on a restoration strategy that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is complete or substantially complete;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is for a multiyear period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> covers nonindustrial private forest land or State forest land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is accessible by wood-processing infrastructure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> is based on the best available science.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State and private forest landscape-scale restoration proposal submitted under this section shall include plans—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to reduce the risk of uncharacteristic wildfires;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to improve fish and wildlife habitats, including the habitats of threatened and endangered species;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to maintain or improve water quality and watershed function;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to mitigate invasive species, insect infestation, and disease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to improve important forest ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to measure ecological and economic benefits, including air quality and soil quality and productivity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to take other relevant actions, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to plans that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> further a statewide forest assessment and resource strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promote cross boundary landscape collaboration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> leverage public and private resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaboration and consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chief of the Forest Service, the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, and relevant stakeholders shall collaborate and consult on an ongoing basis regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administration of the program established under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identification of other applicable resources for landscape-scale restoration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching funds required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, the Secretary shall require the recipient of the grant to provide funds or in-kind support from non-Federal sources in an amount that is at least equal to the amount of Federal funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination and proximity encouraged</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making grants under this section, the Secretary may consider coordination with and proximity to other landscape-scale projects on other land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, the Secretary of the Interior, or a Governor of a State, including under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program established under <ref>section 7303 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> landscape areas designated for insect and disease treatments under <ref>section 6591a of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> good neighbor authority under section 2113 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002717">1</ref> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> stewardship end result contracting projects authorized under <ref>section 6591c of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> appropriate State-level programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other relevant programs, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate such regulations as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the status of development, execution, and administration of selected projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the accounting of program funding expenditures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specific accomplishments that have resulted from landscape-scale projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury a fund, to be known as the “State and Private Forest Landscape-Scale Restoration Fund” (referred to in this subsection as the “Fund”), to be used by the Secretary to make grants under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall consist of such amounts as are appropriated to the Fund under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $20,000,000 for each fiscal year beginning with the first full fiscal year after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, through fiscal year 2023, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 13A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8007</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1285</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8007, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2047; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8102(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2109b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8102(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4839</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2110.</num>
<heading> Statement of limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not authorize the Federal Government to regulate the use of private land or to deprive owners of land of their rights to property or to income from the sale of property, unless such property rights are voluntarily conveyed or limited by contract or other agreement. This chapter does not diminish in any way the rights and responsibilities of the States and political subdivisions of States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 14</ref>, formerly § 11, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 374</ref>; renumbered § 14 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1215(1), 1221, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>, 3540.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2111.</num>
<heading> Other Federal programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repeal of statutory authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following laws, and portions of laws, are hereby repealed:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the Act of <date date="1924-06-07">June 7, 1924</date>, known as the Clarke-McNary Act (<ref>43 Stat. 653–654</ref>, as amended; <ref>16 U.S.C. 564</ref>, 565, 566, 567);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1940-04-26">April 26, 1940</date>, known as the White Pine Blister Rust Protection Act (<ref>54 Stat. 168</ref>; <ref>16 U.S.C. 594a</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Forest Pest Control Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Cooperative Forest Management Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> section 401 of the Agricultural Act of 1956 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 568e</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> title IV of the Rural Development Act of 1972 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 2651</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> section 1009 and the proviso to section 1010 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002718">1</ref> of the Agricultural Act of 1970, as added by the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1509</ref>, 1510].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Force and effect of contracts and cooperative and other agreements under cooperative forestry programs executed under authority of repealed statutes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Contracts and cooperative and other agreements under cooperative forestry programs executed under authority of the Acts, or portions thereof, repealed under subsection (a) of this section shall remain in effect until revoked or amended by their own terms or under other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds appropriated under authority of repealed statutes for cooperative forestry assistance programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated under the authority of the Acts, or portions thereof, repealed under subsection (a) of this section shall be available for expenditure for the programs authorized under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 16</ref>, formerly § 13, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 374</ref>; renumbered § 16, <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1215(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2112.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8003</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113.</num>
<heading> Federal, State, and local coordination and cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest Resource Coordinating Committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a committee, to be known as the “Forest Resource Coordinating Committee” (in this section referred to as the “Coordinating Committee”), to coordinate nonindustrial private forestry activities within the Department of Agriculture and with the private sector.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Coordinating Committee shall be composed of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Chief of the Forest Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Director of the Farm Service Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> Non-Federal representatives appointed by the Secretary to 3 year terms, although initial appointees shall have staggered terms, including the following persons:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> At least three State foresters or equivalent State officials from geographically diverse regions of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A representative of a State fish and wildlife agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> An owner of nonindustrial private forest land.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> A forest industry representative.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> A conservation organization representative.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> A land-grant university or college representative.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> A private forestry consultant.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> A representative from a State Technical Committee established under <ref>section 3861 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Such other persons as determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief of the Forest Service shall serve as chairperson of the Coordinating Committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Coordinating Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide direction and coordination of actions within the Department of Agriculture, and coordination with State agencies and the private sector, to effectively address the national priorities specified in <ref>section 2101(c) of this title</ref>, with specific focus <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002719">1</ref> owners of nonindustrial private forest land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> clarify individual agency responsibilities of each agency represented on the Coordinating Committee concerning the national priorities specified in <ref>section 2101(c) of this title</ref>, with specific focus on nonindustrial private forest land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide advice on the allocation of funds, including the competitive funds set-aside by <ref>section 2109a of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assist the Secretary in developing and reviewing the report required by <ref>section 2101(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Coordinating Committee shall meet annually to discuss progress in addressing the national priorities specified in <ref>section 2101(c) of this title</ref> and issues regarding nonindustrial private forest land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Members of the Coordinating Committee who are full-time officers or employees of the United States shall receive no additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Coordinating Committee.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Non-federal <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002720">2</ref> members of the Coordinating Committee shall serve without pay, but may be reimbursed for reasonable costs incurred while performing their duties on behalf of the Coordinating Committee.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State Coordinating Committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary, in consultation with the State forester or equivalent State official of each State, shall establish a State Forest Stewardship Coordinating Committee (hereafter referred to in this section as the “State Coordinating Committee”) for each such State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The State Coordinating Committee shall be chaired and administered by the State forester, or equivalent State official, or the designee thereof, and shall be composed, to the extent practicable, of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> representatives from the Forest Service, Soil Conservation Service, Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, and National Institute of Food and Agriculture;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> representatives, to be appointed by the State forester or equivalent State official, representative of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> local government;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> consulting foresters;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> environmental organizations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> forest products industry;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> forest land owners;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> land-trust organizations, if applicable in the State;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> conservation organizations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VIII)</num>
<content> the State fish and wildlife agency; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IX)</num>
<content> the State Technical Committee.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any other individuals determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The members of the State Coordinating Committee appointed under subparagraph (B)(ii) shall serve 3-year terms, with the initial members serving staggered terms as determined by the State forester or equivalent State official, and may be reappointed for consecutive terms.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Existing State forestry committees may be used to complement, formulate, or replace the State Coordinating Committees to avoid duplication of efforts if such existing committees are made up of membership that is similar to that described in subparagraph (B)(ii), and if such existing committees include landowners and the general public in their memberships.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State Coordinating Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with other Department of Agriculture and State committees that address State and private forestry issues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the Secretary concerning the assignment of priorities and the coordination of responsibilities for the implementation of this chapter by the various Federal and State forest management agencies that take into consideration the mandates of each such agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the State forester or equivalent State official concerning the development of the State-wide assessment and strategy regarding forest resource conditions under <ref>section 2101a of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the Secretary concerning those forest lands that should be given priority for inclusion in the Forest Legacy Program established pursuant to <ref>section 2103c of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State Coordinating Committees shall not terminate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to compel action by any State official.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 19</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1222</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3540</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(37)</ref>, title VIII, §§ 8005, 8006, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1271</ref>, 1284, 1285; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(c)(37), title VIII, §§ 8005, 8006, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2032, 2045–2047; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8102(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2113a.</num>
<heading> Good neighbor authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized restoration services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “authorized restoration services” means similar and complementary forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services carried out—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on Federal land, non-Federal land, and land owned by an Indian tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by either the Secretary or a Governor or county, as applicable, pursuant to a good neighbor agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> County</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “county” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate executive official of an affected county; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any case in which multiple counties are affected, the appropriate executive official of a compact of the affected counties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal land</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “Federal land” means land that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> National Forest System land; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> public land (as defined in <ref>section 1702 of title 43</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> National Park System land; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> National Wildlife Refuge Land.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “Federal land” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Federal land on which the removal of vegetation is prohibited or restricted by Act of Congress or Presidential proclamation (including the applicable implementation plan); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a wilderness study area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> activities to treat insect- and disease-infected trees;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> activities to reduce hazardous fuels; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any other activities to restore or improve forest, rangeland, and watershed health, including fish and wildlife habitat.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> construction, reconstruction, repair, or restoration of paved or permanent roads or parking areas, other than the reconstruction, repair, or restoration of a National Forest System, Bureau of Land Management, National Park Service, or National Wildlife Refuge managed road that is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> necessary to carry out authorized restoration services pursuant to a good neighbor agreement; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a National Forest System road that is determined to be unneeded in accordance with section 212.5(b)(2) of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>), decommissioned in accordance with subparagraph (A)(iii)—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> in a manner that is consistent with the applicable travel management plan; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> not later than 3 years after the date on which the applicable authorized restoration services project is completed; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> construction, alteration, repair or replacement of public buildings or works.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good neighbor agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “good neighbor agreement” means a cooperative agreement or contract (including a sole source contract) entered into between the Secretary and a Governor or county, as applicable, to carry out authorized restoration services under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Governor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Governor” means the Governor or any other appropriate executive official of an affected State or Indian tribe or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Forest System road</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Forest System road” has the meaning given the term in section 212.1 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Road</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “road” has the meaning given the term in section 212.1 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to Bureau of Land Management land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good neighbor agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good neighbor agreements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may enter into a good neighbor agreement with a Governor or county to carry out authorized restoration services in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall make each good neighbor agreement available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timber sales</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subsections (d) and (g) of <ref>section 472a of this title</ref> shall not apply to services performed under a good neighbor agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of silviculture prescriptions and marking guides</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall provide or approve all silviculture prescriptions and marking guides to be applied on Federal land in all timber sale projects conducted under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of revenue</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Funds received from the sale of timber by a Governor, Indian Tribe, or county under a good neighbor agreement shall be retained and used by the Governor, Indian Tribe, or county, as applicable—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to carry out authorized restoration services on <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002721">1</ref> under the good neighbor agreement; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> if there are funds remaining after carrying out clause (i),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002722">2</ref> to carry out—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> authorized restoration services under other good neighbor agreements; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> authorized recreation services under the Good Neighbor Authority for Recreation Act.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of effectiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The authority provided under this subparagraph terminates effective <date date="2028-10-01">October 1, 2028</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retention of NEPA responsibilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any decision required to be made under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) with respect to any authorized restoration services to be provided under this section on Federal land shall not be delegated to a Governor or county.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any payment made by a county to the Secretary under a project conducted under a good neighbor agreement shall not be considered to be monies received from National Forest System, Bureau of Land Management, National Park System, or U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service land, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8206</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1073</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8624, 8704(b), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4857</ref>, 4877; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. G, title IV, § 439</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–42, div. E, title IV, § 443</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–234, title III, § 351(b)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2916</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2114.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer this chapter in accordance with regulations that the Secretary shall develop.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regulations promulgated under this chapter shall include guidelines for the administration of this chapter at the Federal and State levels and shall identify the measures and activities that are eligible for cost sharing under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing mechanisms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Existing mechanisms shall be used to the extent possible to make payments and deliver services to the landowner under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Land grant universities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, may provide assistance directly to other State and local natural resource management agencies and land grant universities in implementing this chapter in cases in which the State foresters or equivalent State officials are not able to make fund transfers to other State and local agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 20</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1223</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3542</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>