<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32—</num>
<heading>MARINE SANCTUARIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1431.</num>
<heading> Findings, purposes, and policies; establishment of system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> this Nation historically has recognized the importance of protecting special areas of its public domain, but these efforts have been directed almost exclusively to land areas above the high-water mark;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> certain areas of the marine environment possess conservation, recreational, ecological, historical, scientific, educational, cultural, archeological, or esthetic qualities which give them special national, and in some cases international, significance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> while the need to control the effects of particular activities has led to enactment of resource-specific legislation, these laws cannot in all cases provide a coordinated and comprehensive approach to the conservation and management of special areas of the marine environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> a Federal program which establishes areas of the marine environment which have special conservation, recreational, ecological, historical, cultural, archeological, scientific, educational, or esthetic qualities as national marine sanctuaries managed as the National Marine Sanctuary System will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve the conservation, understanding, management, and wise and sustainable use of marine resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enhance public awareness, understanding, and appreciation of the marine environment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> maintain for future generations the habitat, and ecological services, of the natural assemblage of living resources that inhabit these areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes and policies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes and policies of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to identify and designate as national marine sanctuaries areas of the marine environment which are of special national significance and to manage these areas as the National Marine Sanctuary System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide authority for comprehensive and coordinated conservation and management of these marine areas, and activities affecting them, in a manner which complements existing regulatory authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to maintain the natural biological communities in the national marine sanctuaries, and to protect, and, where appropriate, restore and enhance natural habitats, populations, and ecological processes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to enhance public awareness, understanding, appreciation, and wise and sustainable use of the marine environment, and the natural, historical, cultural, and archeological resources of the National Marine Sanctuary System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to support, promote, and coordinate scientific research on, and long-term monitoring of, the resources of these marine areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to facilitate to the extent compatible with the primary objective of resource protection, all public and private uses of the resources of these marine areas not prohibited pursuant to other authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to develop and implement coordinated plans for the protection and management of these areas with appropriate Federal agencies, State and local governments, Native American tribes and organizations, international organizations, and other public and private interests concerned with the continuing health and resilience of these marine areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to create models of, and incentives for, ways to conserve and manage these areas, including the application of innovative management techniques; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to cooperate with global programs encouraging conservation of marine resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the National Marine Sanctuary System, which shall consist of national marine sanctuaries designated by the Secretary in accordance with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–332, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-29">Aug. 29, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2101</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5039</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 3</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1432.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “draft management plan” means the plan described in section 1434(a)(1)(C)(v) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002644">1</ref> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Magnuson-Stevens Act” means the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “marine environment” means those areas of coastal and ocean waters, the Great Lakes and their connecting waters, and submerged lands over which the United States exercises jurisdiction, including the exclusive economic zone, consistent with international law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> “damages” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> compensation for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the cost of replacing, restoring, or acquiring the equivalent of a sanctuary resource; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the value of the lost use of a sanctuary resource pending its restoration or replacement or the acquisition of an equivalent sanctuary resource; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the value of a sanctuary resource if the sanctuary resource cannot be restored or replaced or if the equivalent of such resource cannot be acquired;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of damage assessments under <ref>section 1443(b)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the reasonable cost of monitoring appropriate to the injured, restored, or replaced resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the cost of curation and conservation of archeological, historical, and cultural sanctuary resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the cost of enforcement actions undertaken by the Secretary in response to the destruction or loss of, or injury to, a sanctuary resource;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “response costs” means the costs of actions taken or authorized by the Secretary to minimize destruction or loss of, or injury to, sanctuary resources, or to minimize the imminent risks of such destruction, loss, or injury, including costs related to seizure, forfeiture, storage, or disposal arising from liability under <ref>section 1443 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “sanctuary resource” means any living or nonliving resource of a national marine sanctuary that contributes to the conservation, recreational, ecological, historical, educational, cultural, archeological, scientific, or aesthetic value of the sanctuary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “exclusive economic zone” means the exclusive economic zone as defined in the Magnuson-Stevens Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “System” means the National Marine Sanctuary System established by <ref>section 1431 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–332, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-08-29">Aug. 29, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–375, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3217</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2102</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5040</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513</ref>, §§ 4, 19(b)(1), (2), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2382</ref>, 2392, 2393.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1433.</num>
<heading> Sanctuary designation standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may designate any discrete area of the marine environment as a national marine sanctuary and promulgate regulations implementing the designation if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the designation will fulfill the purposes and policies of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the area is of special national significance due to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> its conservation, recreational, ecological, historical, scientific, cultural, archaeological, educational, or esthetic qualities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the communities of living marine resources it harbors; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> its resource or human-use values;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> existing State and Federal authorities are inadequate or should be supplemented to ensure coordinated and comprehensive conservation and management of the area, including resource protection, scientific research, and public education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> designation of the area as a national marine sanctuary will facilitate the objectives stated in paragraph (3); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the area is of a size and nature that will permit comprehensive and coordinated conservation and management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors and consultations required in making determinations and findings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of determining if an area of the marine environment meets the standards set forth in subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the area’s natural resource and ecological qualities, including its contribution to biological productivity, maintenance of ecosystem structure, maintenance of ecologically or commercially important or threatened species or species assemblages, maintenance of critical habitat of endangered species, and the biogeographic representation of the site;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the area’s historical, cultural, archaeological, or paleontological significance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the present and potential uses of the area that depend on maintenance of the area’s resources, including commercial and recreational fishing, subsistence uses, other commercial and recreational activities, and research and education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the present and potential activities that may adversely affect the factors identified in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the existing State and Federal regulatory and management authorities applicable to the area and the adequacy of those authorities to fulfill the purposes and policies of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the manageability of the area, including such factors as its size, its ability to be identified as a discrete ecological unit with definable boundaries, its accessibility, and its suitability for monitoring and enforcement activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the public benefits to be derived from sanctuary status, with emphasis on the benefits of long-term protection of nationally significant resources, vital habitats, and resources which generate tourism;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the negative impacts produced by management restrictions on income-generating activities such as living and nonliving resources development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the socioeconomic effects of sanctuary designation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the area’s scientific value and value for monitoring the resources and natural processes that occur there;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the feasibility, where appropriate, of employing innovative management approaches to protect sanctuary resources or to manage compatible uses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> the value of the area as an addition to the System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In making determinations and findings, the Secretary shall consult with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretaries of State, Defense, Transportation, and the Interior, the Administrator, and the heads of other interested Federal agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the responsible officials or relevant agency heads of the appropriate State and local government entities, including coastal zone management agencies, that will or are likely to be affected by the establishment of the area as a national marine sanctuary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the appropriate officials of any Regional Fishery Management Council established by section 302 of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1852</ref>) that may be affected by the proposed designation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other interested persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2103</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513</ref>, §§ 5, 19(a)(1), (b)(3), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2383</ref>, 2392, 2393; <ref>Pub. L. 106–555, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1434.</num>
<heading> Procedures for designation and implementation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctuary proposal</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In proposing to designate a national marine sanctuary, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> issue, in the Federal Register, a notice of the proposal, proposed regulations that may be necessary and reasonable to implement the proposal, and a summary of the draft management plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide notice of the proposal in newspapers of general circulation or electronic media in the communities that may be affected by the proposal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> no later than the day on which the notice required under subparagraph (A) is submitted to the Office of the Federal Register, submit a copy of that notice and the draft sanctuary designation documents prepared pursuant to paragraph (2), including an executive summary, to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Governor of each State in which any part of the proposed sanctuary would be located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctuary designation documents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall prepare and make available to the public sanctuary designation documents on the proposal that include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A draft environmental impact statement pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A resource assessment that documents—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> present and potential uses of the area, including commercial and recreational fishing, research and education, minerals and energy development, subsistence uses, and other commercial, governmental, or recreational uses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> after consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, any commercial, governmental, or recreational resource uses in the areas that are subject to the primary jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> information prepared in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, on any past, present, or proposed future disposal or discharge of materials in the vicinity of the proposed sanctuary.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">Public disclosure by the Secretary of such information shall be consistent with national security regulations.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> A draft management plan for the proposed national marine sanctuary that includes the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The terms of the proposed designation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Proposed mechanisms to coordinate existing regulatory and management authorities within the area.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The proposed goals and objectives, management responsibilities, resource studies, and appropriate strategies for managing sanctuary resources of the proposed sanctuary, including interpretation and education, innovative management strategies, research, monitoring and assessment, resource protection, restoration, enforcement, and surveillance activities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> An evaluation of the advantages of cooperative State and Federal management if all or part of the proposed sanctuary is within the territorial limits of any State or is superjacent to the subsoil and seabed within the seaward boundary of a State, as that boundary is established under the Submerged Lands Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> An estimate of the annual cost to the Federal Government of the proposed designation, including costs of personnel, equipment and facilities, enforcement, research, and public education.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The proposed regulations referred to in paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Maps depicting the boundaries of the proposed sanctuary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The basis for the determinations made under <ref>section 1433(a) of this title</ref> with respect to the area.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> An assessment of the considerations under <ref>section 1433(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No sooner than thirty days after issuing a notice under this subsection, the Secretary shall hold at least one public hearing in the coastal area or areas that will be most affected by the proposed designation of the area as a national marine sanctuary for the purpose of receiving the views of interested parties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms of designation of a sanctuary shall include the geographic area proposed to be included within the sanctuary, the characteristics of the area that give it conservation, recreational, ecological, historical, research, educational, or esthetic value, and the types of activities that will be subject to regulation by the Secretary to protect those characteristics. The terms of designation may be modified only by the same procedures by which the original designation is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fishing regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide the appropriate Regional Fishery Management Council with the opportunity to prepare draft regulations for fishing within the Exclusive Economic Zone as the Council may deem necessary to implement the proposed designation. Draft regulations prepared by the Council, or a Council determination that regulations are not necessary pursuant to this paragraph, shall be accepted and issued as proposed regulations by the Secretary unless the Secretary finds that the Council’s action fails to fulfill the purposes and policies of this chapter and the goals and objectives of the proposed designation. In preparing the draft regulations, a Regional Fishery Management Council shall use as guidance the national standards of section 301(a) of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1851</ref>) to the extent that the standards are consistent and compatible with the goals and objectives of the proposed designation. The Secretary shall prepare the fishing regulations, if the Council declines to make a determination with respect to the need for regulations, makes a determination which is rejected by the Secretary, or fails to prepare the draft regulations in a timely manner. Any amendments to the fishing regulations shall be drafted, approved, and issued in the same manner as the original regulations. The Secretary shall also cooperate with other appropriate fishery management authorities with rights or responsibilities within a proposed sanctuary at the earliest practicable stage in drafting any sanctuary fishing regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committee action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After receiving the documents under subsection (a)(1)(C), the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate may each hold hearings on the proposed designation and on the matters set forth in the documents. If within the forty-five day period of continuous session of Congress beginning on the date of submission of the documents, either Committee issues a report concerning matters addressed in the documents, the Secretary shall consider this report before publishing a notice to designate the national marine sanctuary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taking effect of designations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In designating a national marine sanctuary, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the designation together with final regulations to implement the designation and any other matters required by law, and submit such notice to the Congress. The Secretary shall advise the public of the availability of the final management plan and the final environmental impact statement with respect to such sanctuary. The Secretary shall issue a notice of designation with respect to a proposed national marine sanctuary site not later than 30 months after the date a notice declaring the site to be an active candidate for sanctuary designation is published in the Federal Register under regulations issued under this Act, or shall publish not later than such date in the Federal Register findings regarding why such notice has not been published. No notice of designation may occur until the expiration of the period for Committee action under subsection (a)(6). The designation (and any of its terms not disapproved under this subsection) and regulations shall take effect and become final after the close of a review period of forty-five days of continuous session of Congress beginning on the day on which such notice is published unless, in the case of a national marine sanctuary that is located partially or entirely within the seaward boundary of any State, the Governor affected certifies to the Secretary that the designation or any of its terms is unacceptable, in which case the designation or the unacceptable term shall not take effect in the area of the sanctuary lying within the seaward boundary of the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawal of designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary considers that actions taken under paragraph (1) will affect the designation of a national marine sanctuary in a manner that the goals and objectives of the sanctuary or System cannot be fulfilled, the Secretary may withdraw the entire designation. If the Secretary does not withdraw the designation, only those terms of the designation not certified under paragraph (1) shall take effect.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In computing the forty-five-day periods of continuous session of Congress pursuant to subsection (a)(6) and paragraph (1) of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> continuity of session is broken only by an adjournment of Congress sine die; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the days on which either House of Congress is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a day certain are excluded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access and valid rights</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as terminating or granting to the Secretary the right to terminate any valid lease, permit, license, or right of subsistence use or of access that is in existence on the date of designation of any national marine sanctuary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The exercise of a lease, permit, license, or right is subject to regulation by the Secretary consistent with the purposes for which the sanctuary is designated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency cooperation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of agency actions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Federal agency actions internal or external to a national marine sanctuary, including private activities authorized by licenses, leases, or permits, that are likely to destroy, cause the loss of, or injure any sanctuary resource are subject to consultation with the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency statements required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to any regulations the Secretary may establish each Federal agency proposing an action described in subparagraph (A) shall provide the Secretary with a written statement describing the action and its potential effects on sanctuary resources at the earliest practicable time, but in no case later than 45 days before the final approval of the action unless such Federal agency and the Secretary agree to a different schedule.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary’s recommended alternatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary finds that a Federal agency action is likely to destroy, cause the loss of, or injure a sanctuary resource, the Secretary shall (within 45 days of receipt of complete information on the proposed agency action) recommend reasonable and prudent alternatives, which may include conduct of the action elsewhere, which can be taken by the Federal agency in implementing the agency action that will protect sanctuary resources.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response to recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The agency head who receives the Secretary’s recommended alternatives under paragraph (2) shall promptly consult with the Secretary on the alternatives. If the agency head decides not to follow the alternatives, the agency head shall provide the Secretary with a written statement explaining the reasons for that decision.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to follow alternative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the head of a Federal agency takes an action other than an alternative recommended by the Secretary and such action results in the destruction of, loss of, or injury to a sanctuary resource, the head of the agency shall promptly prevent and mitigate further damage and restore or replace the sanctuary resource in a manner approved by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of management plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than five years after the date of designation of any national marine sanctuary, and thereafter at intervals not exceeding five years, the Secretary shall evaluate the substantive progress toward implementing the management plan and goals for the sanctuary, especially the effectiveness of site-specific management techniques and strategies, and shall revise the management plan and regulations as necessary to fulfill the purposes and policies of this chapter. This review shall include a prioritization of management objectives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on designation of new sanctuaries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may not publish in the Federal Register any sanctuary designation notice or regulations proposing to designate a new sanctuary, unless the Secretary has published a finding that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the addition of a new sanctuary will not have a negative impact on the System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> sufficient resources were available in the fiscal year in which the finding is made to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> effectively implement sanctuary management plans for each sanctuary in the System; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> complete site characterization studies and inventory known sanctuary resources, including cultural resources, for each sanctuary in the System within 10 years after the date that the finding is made if the resources available for those activities are maintained at the same level for each fiscal year in that 10 year period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary does not submit the findings required by paragraph (1) before <date date="2004-02-01">February 1, 2004</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress before <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>, a finding with respect to whether the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) have been met by all existing sanctuaries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) does not apply to any sanctuary designation documents for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Thunder Bay National Marine Sanctuary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a Northwestern Hawaiian Islands National Marine Sanctuary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–62, § 4</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–326, § 4</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–153, § 3</ref>, <date date="1977-11-04">Nov. 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–332, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-08-29">Aug. 29, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–109</ref>, <date date="1981-12-26">Dec. 26, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3214</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2104</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 9(h)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3368</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513</ref>, §§ 6(a)–(f), 19(a)(2), (b)(4), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2383–2385</ref>, 2392, 2393; <ref>Pub. L. 106–555, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title III, § 307(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-23">Dec. 23, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1435.</num>
<heading> Application of regulations; international negotiations and cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter and the regulations issued under <ref>section 1434 of this title</ref> shall be applied in accordance with generally recognized principles of international law, and in accordance with treaties, conventions, and other agreements to which the United States is a party. No regulation shall apply to or be enforced against a person who is not a citizen, national, or resident alien of the United States, unless in accordance with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> generally recognized principles of international law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an agreement between the United States and the foreign state of which the person is a citizen; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an agreement between the United States and the flag state of a foreign vessel, if the person is a crewmember of the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negotiations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary, shall take appropriate action to enter into negotiations with other governments to make necessary arrangements for the protection of any national marine sanctuary and to promote the purposes for which the sanctuary is established.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall cooperate with other governments and international organizations in furtherance of the purposes and policies of this chapter and consistent with applicable regional and mutilateral <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002645">1</ref> arrangements for the protection and management of special marine areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 305</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2302</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2105</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5043</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1436.</num>
<heading> Prohibited activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> destroy, cause the loss of, or injure any sanctuary resource managed under law or regulations for that sanctuary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> possess, sell, offer for sale, purchase, import, export, deliver, carry, transport, or ship by any means any sanctuary resource taken in violation of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> interfere with the enforcement of this chapter by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> refusing to permit any officer authorized to enforce this chapter to board a vessel, other than a vessel operated by the Department of Defense or United States Coast Guard, subject to such person’s control for the purposes of conducting any search or inspection in connection with the enforcement of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> resisting, opposing, impeding, intimidating, harassing, bribing, interfering with, or forcibly assaulting any person authorized by the Secretary to implement this chapter or any such authorized officer in the conduct of any search or inspection performed under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully submitting false information to the Secretary or any officer authorized to enforce this chapter in connection with any search or inspection conducted under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> violate any provision of this chapter or any regulation or permit issued pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 306</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2302</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2106</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 7</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2386</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1437.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct such enforcement activities as are necessary and reasonable to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers of authorized officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any person who is authorized to enforce this chapter may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> board, search, inspect, and seize any vessel suspected of being used to violate this chapter or any regulation or permit issued under this chapter and any equipment, stores, and cargo of such vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> seize wherever found any sanctuary resource taken or retained in violation of this chapter or any regulation or permit issued under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> seize any evidence of a violation of this chapter or of any regulation or permit issued under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> execute any warrant or other process issued by any court of competent jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> exercise any other lawful authority; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> arrest any person, if there is reasonable cause to believe that such person has committed an act prohibited by <ref>section 1436(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal offenses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A person is guilty of an offense under this subsection if the person commits any act prohibited by <ref>section 1436(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Punishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any person that is guilty of an offense under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (B), shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 6 months, or both; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a person who in the commission of such an offense uses a dangerous weapon, engages in conduct that causes bodily injury to any person authorized to enforce this chapter or any person authorized to implement the provisions of this chapter, or places any such person in fear of imminent bodily injury, shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States who violates this chapter or any regulation or permit issued under this chapter shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than $100,000 for each such violation, to be assessed by the Secretary. Each day of a continuing violation shall constitute a separate violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No penalty shall be assessed under this subsection until after the person charged has been given notice and an opportunity for a hearing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In rem jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A vessel used in violating this chapter or any regulation or permit issued under this chapter shall be liable in rem for any civil penalty assessed for such violation. Such penalty shall constitute a maritime lien on the vessel and may be recovered in an action in rem in the district court of the United States having jurisdiction over the vessel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of civil penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person against whom a civil penalty is assessed under this subsection may obtain review in the United States district court for the appropriate district by filing a complaint in such court not later than 30 days after the date of such order.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty under this section after it has become a final and unappealable order, or after the appropriate court has entered final judgment in favor of the Secretary, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General, who shall recover the amount assessed in any appropriate district court of the United States. In such action, the validity and appropriateness of the final order imposing the civil penalty shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compromise or other action by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit, with or without conditions, any civil penalty which is or may be imposed under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forfeiture</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any vessel (including the vessel’s equipment, stores, and cargo) and other item used, and any sanctuary resource taken or retained, in any manner, in connection with or as a result of any violation of this chapter or of any regulation or permit issued under this chapter shall be subject to forfeiture to the United States pursuant to a civil proceeding under this subsection. The proceeds from forfeiture actions under this subsection shall constitute a separate recovery in addition to any amounts recovered as civil penalties under this section or as civil damages under <ref>section 1443 of this title</ref>. None of those proceeds shall be subject to set-off.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of the customs laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may exercise the authority of any United States official granted by any relevant customs law relating to the seizure, forfeiture, condemnation, disposition, remission, and mitigation of property in enforcing this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposal of sanctuary resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any sanctuary resource seized pursuant to this chapter may be disposed of pursuant to an order of the appropriate court, or, if perishable, in a manner prescribed by regulations promulgated by the Secretary. Any proceeds from the sale of such sanctuary resource shall for all purposes represent the sanctuary resource so disposed of in any subsequent legal proceedings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presumption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purposes of this section there is a rebuttable presumption that all sanctuary resources found on board a vessel that is used or seized in connection with a violation of this chapter or of any regulation or permit issued under this chapter were taken or retained in violation of this chapter or of a regulation or permit issued under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of storage, care, and other costs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other law, amounts received by the United States as civil penalties, forfeitures of property, and costs imposed under paragraph (2) shall be retained by the Secretary in the manner provided for in <ref>section 9607(f)(1) of title 42</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Amounts received under this section for forfeitures and costs imposed under paragraph (2) shall be used to pay the reasonable and necessary costs incurred by the Secretary to provide temporary storage, care, maintenance, and disposal of any sanctuary resource or other property seized in connection with a violation of this chapter or any regulation or permit issued under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts received under this section as civil penalties and any amounts remaining after the operation of subparagraph (B) shall be used, in order of priority, to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> manage and improve the national marine sanctuary with respect to which the violation occurred that resulted in the penalty or forfeiture;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> pay a reward to any person who furnishes information leading to an assessment of a civil penalty, or to a forfeiture of property, for a violation of this chapter or any regulation or permit issued under this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> manage and improve any other national marine sanctuary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability for costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person assessed a civil penalty for a violation of this chapter or of any regulation or permit issued under this chapter, and any claimant in a forfeiture action brought for such a violation, shall be liable for the reasonable costs incurred by the Secretary in storage, care, and maintenance of any sanctuary resource or other property seized in connection with the violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpoenas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any hearing under this section which is determined on the record in accordance with the procedures provided for under <ref>section 554 of title 5</ref>, the Secretary may issue subpoenas for the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of relevant papers, books, electronic files, and documents, and may administer oaths.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of resources of State and other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, whenever appropriate, use by agreement the personnel, services, and facilities of State and other Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, to carry out the Secretary’s responsibilities under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coast Guard authority not limited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be considered to limit the authority of the Coast Guard to enforce this or any other Federal law under section 89 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002646">1</ref> of title 14.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Injunctive relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that there is an imminent risk of destruction or loss of or injury to a sanctuary resource, or that there has been actual destruction or loss of, or injury to, a sanctuary resource which may give rise to liability under <ref>section 1443 of this title</ref>, the Attorney General, upon request of the Secretary, shall seek to obtain such relief as may be necessary to abate such risk or actual destruction, loss, or injury, or to restore or replace the sanctuary resource, or both. The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction in such a case to order such relief as the public interest and the equities of the case may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Area of application and enforceability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The area of application and enforceability of this chapter includes the territorial sea of the United States, as described in Presidential Proclamation 5928 of <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>, which is subject to the sovereignty of the United States, and the United States exclusive economic zone, consistent with international law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nationwide service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any action by the United States under this chapter, process may be served in any district where the defendant is found, resides, transacts business, or has appointed an agent for the service of process.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 307</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2302</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2107(a)</ref>–(c), (e), <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5043</ref>, 5044; <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 9(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 8</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1438.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 203(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3214</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1439.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 308</ref>, formerly § 309, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2303</ref>; renumbered § 308, <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 203(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3214</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 9</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1440.</num>
<heading> Research, monitoring, and education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct, support, or coordinate research, monitoring, evaluation, and education programs consistent with subsections (b) and (c) and the purposes and policies of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research and monitoring</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> support, promote, and coordinate research on, and long-term monitoring of, sanctuary resources and natural processes that occur in national marine sanctuaries, including exploration, mapping, and environmental and socioeconomic assessment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop and test methods to enhance degraded habitats or restore damaged, injured, or lost sanctuary resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> support, promote, and coordinate research on, and the conservation, curation, and public display of, the cultural, archeological, and historical resources of national marine sanctuaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The results of research and monitoring conducted, supported, or permitted by the Secretary under this subsection shall be made available to the public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Education</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may support, promote, and coordinate efforts to enhance public awareness, understanding, and appreciation of national marine sanctuaries and the System. Efforts supported, promoted, or coordinated under this subsection must emphasize the conservation goals and sustainable public uses of national marine sanctuaries and the System.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Educational activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Activities under this subsection may include education of the general public, teachers, students, national marine sanctuary users, and ocean and coastal resource managers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interpretive facilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may develop interpretive facilities near any national marine sanctuary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Facility requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any facility developed under this subsection must emphasize the conservation goals and sustainable public uses of national marine sanctuaries by providing the public with information about the conservation, recreational, ecological, historical, cultural, archeological, scientific, educational, or esthetic qualities of the national marine sanctuary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In conducting, supporting, and coordinating research, monitoring, evaluation, and education programs under subsection (a) and developing interpretive facilities under subsection (d), the Secretary may consult or coordinate with Federal, interstate, or regional agencies, States or local governments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 309</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 203(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3214</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2108</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 10</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1441.</num>
<heading> Special use permits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of permits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may issue special use permits which authorize the conduct of specific activities in a national marine sanctuary if the Secretary determines such authorization is necessary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish conditions of access to and use of any sanctuary resource; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote public use and understanding of a sanctuary resource.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide appropriate public notice before identifying any category of activity subject to a special use permit under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permit terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A permit issued under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall authorize the conduct of an activity only if that activity is compatible with the purposes for which the sanctuary is designated and with protection of sanctuary resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall not authorize the conduct of any activity for a period of more than 5 years unless renewed by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall require that activities carried out under the permit be conducted in a manner that does not destroy, cause the loss of, or injure sanctuary resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall require the permittee to purchase and maintain comprehensive general liability insurance, or post an equivalent bond, against claims arising out of activities conducted under the permit and to agree to hold the United States harmless against such claims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment and collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may assess and collect fees for the conduct of any activity under a permit issued under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount of a fee under this subsection shall be equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> costs incurred, or expected to be incurred, by the Secretary in issuing the permit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> costs incurred, or expected to be incurred, by the Secretary as a direct result of the conduct of the activity for which the permit is issued, including costs of monitoring the conduct of the activity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an amount which represents the fair market value of the use of the sanctuary resource.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of fees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Amounts collected by the Secretary in the form of fees under this section may be used by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for issuing and administering permits under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for expenses of managing national marine sanctuaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver or reduction of fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may accept in-kind contributions in lieu of a fee under paragraph (2)(C), or waive or reduce any fee assessed under this subsection for any activity that does not derive profit from the access to or use of sanctuary resources.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon violation of a term or condition of a permit issued under this section, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> suspend or revoke the permit without compensation to the permittee and without liability to the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assess a civil penalty in accordance with <ref>section 1437 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each person issued a permit under this section shall submit an annual report to the Secretary not later than December 31 of each year which describes activities conducted under that permit and revenues derived from such activities during the year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fishing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be considered to require a person to obtain a permit under this section for the conduct of any fishing activities in a national marine sanctuary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 310</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 203(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3214</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 11</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1442.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements, donations, and acquisitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements and grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements, contracts, or other agreements with, or make grants to, States, local governments, regional agencies, interstate agencies, or other persons to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to solicit donations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into such agreements with any nonprofit organization authorizing the organization to solicit private donations to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Donations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may accept donations of funds, property, and services for use in designating and administering national marine sanctuaries under this chapter. Donations accepted under this section shall be considered as a gift or bequest to or for the use of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may acquire by purchase, lease, or exchange, any land, facilities, or other property necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of resources of other government agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, whenever appropriate, enter into an agreement with a State or other Federal agency to use the personnel, services, or facilities of such agency on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, to assist in carrying out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to obtain grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law that prohibits a Federal agency from receiving assistance, the Secretary may apply for, accept, and use grants from other Federal agencies, States, local governments, regional agencies, interstate agencies, foundations, or other persons, to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 311</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 203(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3215</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2109</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 9(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 12</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1443.</num>
<heading> Destruction or loss of, or injury to, sanctuary resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability to United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any person who destroys, causes the loss of, or injures any sanctuary resource is liable to the United States for an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount of response costs and damages resulting from the destruction, loss, or injury; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> interest on that amount calculated in the manner described under <ref>section 2705 of title 33</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability in rem</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any vessel used to destroy, cause the loss of, or injure any sanctuary resource shall be liable in rem to the United States for response costs and damages resulting from such destruction, loss, or injury. The amount of that liability shall constitute a maritime lien on the vessel and may be recovered in an action in rem in any district court of the United States that has jurisdiction over the vessel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Defenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A person is not liable under this subsection if that person establishes that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the destruction or loss of, or injury to, the sanctuary resource was caused solely by an act of God, an act of war, or an act or omission of a third party, and the person acted with due care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the destruction, loss, or injury was caused by an activity authorized by Federal or State law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the destruction, loss, or injury was negligible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limits to liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in sections 4281–4289 of the Revised Statutes of the United States or <ref>section 30706 of title 46</ref> shall limit the liability of any person under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response actions and damage assessment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may undertake or authorize all necessary actions to prevent or minimize the destruction or loss of, or injury to, sanctuary resources, or to minimize the imminent risk of such destruction, loss, or injury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Damage assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall assess damages to sanctuary resources in accordance with <ref>section 1432(6) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil actions for response costs and damages</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General, upon request of the Secretary, may commence a civil action against any person or vessel who may be liable under subsection (a) for response costs and damages. The Secretary, acting as trustee for sanctuary resources for the United States, shall submit a request for such an action to the Attorney General whenever a person may be liable for such costs or damages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An action under this subsection may be brought in the United States district court for any district in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the defendant is located, resides, or is doing business, in the case of an action against a person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the vessel is located, in the case of an action against a vessel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the destruction of, loss of, or injury to a sanctuary resource occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of recovered amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Response costs and damages recovered by the Secretary under this section shall be retained by the Secretary in the manner provided for in <ref>section 9607(f)(1) of title 42</ref>, and used as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Amounts recovered by the United States for costs of response actions and damage assessments under this section shall be used, as the Secretary considers appropriate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to reimburse the Secretary or any other Federal or State agency that conducted those activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after reimbursement of such costs, to restore, replace, or acquire the equivalent of any sanctuary resource.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">All other amounts recovered shall be used, in order of priority—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to restore, replace, or acquire the equivalent of the sanctuary resources that were the subject of the action, including for costs of monitoring and the costs of curation and conservation of archeological, historical, and cultural sanctuary resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to restore degraded sanctuary resources of the national marine sanctuary that was the subject of the action, giving priority to sanctuary resources and habitats that are comparable to the sanctuary resources that were the subject of the action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to restore degraded sanctuary resources of other national marine sanctuaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal-State coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts recovered under this section with respect to sanctuary resources lying within the jurisdiction of a State shall be used under paragraphs (2)(A) and (B) in accordance with the court decree or settlement agreement and an agreement entered into by the Secretary and the Governor of that State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statute of limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An action for response costs or damages under subsection (c) shall be barred unless the complaint is filed within 3 years after the date on which the Secretary completes a damage assessment and restoration plan for the sanctuary resources to which the action relates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 312</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3215</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II</ref>, §§ 2107(d), 2110, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5044</ref>, 5045; <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 9(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513</ref>, §§ 13, 19(c), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2389</ref>, 2393.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1444.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to carry out this chapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $32,000,000 for fiscal year 2001;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $34,000,000 for fiscal year 2002;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> $36,000,000 for fiscal year 2003;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> $38,000,000 for fiscal year 2004;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2005; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for construction projects at national marine sanctuaries, $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, and 2005.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 313</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3221</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–605, § 10(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2111</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5046</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 3</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 14</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1445.</num>
<heading> U.S.S. Monitor artifacts and materials</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In recognition of the historical significance of the wreck of the United States ship Monitor to coastal North Carolina and to the area off the coast of North Carolina known as the Graveyard of the Atlantic, the Congress directs that a suitable display of artifacts and materials from the United States ship Monitor be maintained permanently at an appropriate site in coastal North Carolina.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclaimer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall not affect the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The responsibilities of the Secretary to provide for the protection, conservation, and display of artifacts and materials from the United States ship Monitor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority of the Secretary to designate the Mariner’s Museum, located at Newport News, Virginia, as the principal museum for coordination of activities referred to in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 314</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3222</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 15</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1445a.</num>
<heading> Advisory Councils</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may establish one or more advisory councils (in this section referred to as an “Advisory Council”) to advise and make recommendations to the Secretary regarding the designation and management of national marine sanctuaries. The Advisory Councils shall be exempt from chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Members of the Advisory Councils may be appointed from among—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> persons employed by Federal or State agencies with expertise in management of natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> members of relevant Regional Fishery Management Councils established under <ref>section 1852 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> representatives of local user groups, conservation and other public interest organizations, scientific organizations, educational organizations, or others interested in the protection and multiple use management of sanctuary resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limits on membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For sanctuaries designated after <date date="1992-11-04">November 4, 1992</date>, the membership of Advisory Councils shall be limited to no more than 15 members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staffing and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make available to an Advisory Council any staff, information, administrative services, or assistance the Secretary determines are reasonably required to enable the Advisory Council to carry out its functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public participation and procedural matters</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following guidelines apply with respect to the conduct of business meetings of an Advisory Council:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each meeting shall be open to the public, and interested persons shall be permitted to present oral or written statements on items on the agenda.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Emergency meetings may be held at the call of the chairman or presiding officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Timely notice of each meeting, including the time, place, and agenda of the meeting, shall be published locally and in the Federal Register, except that in the case of a meeting of an Advisory Council established to provide assistance regarding any individual national marine sanctuary the notice is not required to be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Minutes of each meeting shall be kept and contain a summary of the attendees and matters discussed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 315</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2112</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5046</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–283</ref>, §§ 5, 9(f), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3363</ref>, 3368; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513</ref>, §§ 16, 19(b)(5), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2391</ref>, 2393; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(112)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1445b.</num>
<heading> Enhancing support for national marine sanctuaries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may establish a program consisting of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the creation, adoption, and publication in the Federal Register by the Secretary of a symbol for the national marine sanctuary program, or for individual national marine sanctuaries or the System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the solicitation of persons to be designated as official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual national marine sanctuaries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the designation of persons by the Secretary as official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual sanctuaries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the authorization by the Secretary of the manufacture, reproduction, or other use of any symbol published under paragraph (1), including the sale of items bearing such a symbol, by official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual national marine sanctuaries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the creation, marketing, and selling of products to promote the national marine sanctuary program, and entering into exclusive or nonexclusive agreements authorizing entities to create, market or sell on the Secretary’s behalf;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the solicitation and collection by the Secretary of monetary or in-kind contributions from official sponsors for the manufacture, reproduction or use of the symbols published under paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the retention of any monetary or in-kind contributions collected under paragraphs (5) and (6) by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the expenditure and use of any monetary and in-kind contributions, without appropriation, by the Secretary to designate and manage national marine sanctuaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Monetary and in-kind contributions raised through the sale, marketing, or use of symbols and products related to an individual national marine sanctuary shall be used to support that sanctuary.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may contract with any person for the creation of symbols or the solicitation of official sponsors under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may restrict the use of the symbols published under subsection (a), and the designation of official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual national marine sanctuaries to ensure compatibility with the goals of the national marine sanctuary program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any symbol which is adopted by the Secretary and published in the Federal Register under subsection (a) is deemed to be the property of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designated as an official sponsor to influence or seek to influence any decision by the Secretary or any other Federal official related to the designation or management of a national marine sanctuary, except to the extent that a person who is not so designated may do so;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to represent himself or herself to be an official sponsor absent a designation by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to manufacture, reproduce, or otherwise use any symbol adopted by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1), including to sell any item bearing such a symbol, unless authorized by the Secretary under subsection (a)(4) or subsection (f); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to violate any regulation promulgated by the Secretary under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaborations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may authorize the use of a symbol adopted by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1) of this section by any person engaged in a collaborative effort with the Secretary to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter and to benefit a national marine sanctuary or the System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization for non-profit partner organization to solicit sponsors</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may enter into an agreement with a non-profit partner organization authorizing it to assist in the administration of the sponsorship program established under this section. Under an agreement entered into under this paragraph, the Secretary may authorize the non-profit partner organization to solicit persons to be official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary system or of individual national marine sanctuaries, upon such terms as the Secretary deems reasonable and will contribute to the successful administration of the sanctuary system. The Secretary may also authorize the non-profit partner organization to collect the statutory contribution from the sponsor, and, subject to paragraph (2), transfer the contribution to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for administrative costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under the agreement entered into under paragraph (1), the Secretary may authorize the non-profit partner organization to retain not more than 5 percent of the amount of monetary contributions it receives from official sponsors under the agreement to offset the administrative costs of the organization in soliciting sponsors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partner organization defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “partner organization” means an organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> draws its membership from individuals, private organizations, corporations, academic institutions, or State and local governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is established to promote the understanding of, education relating to, and the conservation of the resources of a particular sanctuary or 2 or more related sanctuaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 316</ref>, formerly <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2204</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5049</ref>; renumbered <ref>§ 316 of Pub. L. 92–532</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–283, § 6</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 17</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1445c.</num>
<heading> Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and administer through the National Ocean Service the Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship Program. Under the program, the Secretary shall award graduate education scholarships in oceanography, marine biology or maritime archeology, to be known as Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarships.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship Program are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to recognize outstanding scholarship in oceanography, marine biology, or maritime archeology, particularly by women and members of minority groups; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage independent graduate level research in oceanography, marine biology, or maritime archeology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be used to support graduate studies in oceanography, marine biology, or maritime archeology at a graduate level institution of higher education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be awarded in accordance with guidelines issued by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of each Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship shall be provided directly to a recipient selected by the Secretary upon receipt of certification that the recipient will adhere to a specific and detailed plan of study and research approved by a graduate level institution of higher education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amount available each fiscal year to carry out this chapter, the Secretary shall award 1 percent as Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarships.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scholarship repayment requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall require an individual receiving a scholarship under this section to repay the full amount of the scholarship to the Secretary if the Secretary determines that the individual, in obtaining or using the scholarship, engaged in fraudulent conduct or failed to comply with any term or condition of the scholarship.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maritime archeology defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section the term “maritime archeology” includes the curation, preservation, and display of maritime artifacts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 318</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–513, § 18</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2392</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1445c–1.</num>
<heading> Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall establish and administer through the National Ocean Service the Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship Program. Under the program, the Secretary shall award graduate education scholarships in marine biology, oceanography, or maritime archaeology, including the curation, preservation, and display of maritime artifacts, to be known as “Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarships”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of the Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship Program is to recognize outstanding scholarship in marine biology, oceanography, or maritime archaeology, particularly by women and members of minority groups, and encourage independent graduate level research in such fields of study.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship award—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be used to support a candidate’s graduate studies in marine biology, oceanography, or maritime archaeology at a sponsoring institution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be made available to individual candidates in accordance with guidelines issued by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of each Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarship shall be provided directly to each recipient selected by the Secretary upon receipt of certification that the recipient will adhere to a specific and detailed plan of study and research approved by the sponsoring institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make 1 percent of the amount appropriated each fiscal year to carry out the National Marine Sanctuaries Act [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.] available for Dr. Nancy Foster Scholarships.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scholarship repayment requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Repayment of the award shall be made to the Secretary in the case of fraud or noncompliance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title II, § 210]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–79.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>