<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1C—</num>
<heading>PALEONTOLOGICAL RESOURCES PRESERVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Casual collecting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “casual collecting” means the collecting of a reasonable amount of common invertebrate and plant paleontological resources for non-commercial personal use, either by surface collection or the use of non-powered hand tools resulting in only negligible disturbance to the Earth’s surface and other resources. As used in this paragraph, the terms “reasonable amount”, “common invertebrate and plant paleontological resources” and “negligible disturbance” shall be determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal land” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> land controlled or administered by the Secretary of the Interior, except Indian land; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> National Forest System land controlled or administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian Land” means land of Indian tribes, or Indian individuals, which are either held in trust by the United States or subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Paleontological resource</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “paleontological resource” means any fossilized remains, traces, or imprints of organisms, preserved in or on the earth’s crust, that are of paleontological interest and that provide information about the history of life on earth, except that the term does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any materials associated with an archaeological resource (as defined in <ref>section 470bb(1) of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002397">1</ref> or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any cultural item (as defined in <ref>section 3001 of title 25</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior with respect to land controlled or administered by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to National Forest System land controlled or administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6301</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–1.</num>
<heading> Management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall manage and protect paleontological resources on Federal land using scientific principles and expertise. The Secretary shall develop appropriate plans for inventory, monitoring, and the scientific and educational use of paleontological resources, in accordance with applicable agency laws, regulations, and policies. These plans shall emphasize interagency coordination and collaborative efforts where possible with non-Federal partners, the scientific community, and the general public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent possible, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall coordinate in the implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6302</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–2.</num>
<heading> Public awareness and education program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program to increase public awareness about the significance of paleontological resources.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6303</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–3.</num>
<heading> Collection of paleontological resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permit requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in this chapter, a paleontological resource may not be collected from Federal land without a permit issued under this chapter by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Casual collecting exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall allow casual collecting without a permit on Federal land controlled or administered by the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Forest Service, where such collection is consistent with the laws governing the management of those Federal land <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002398">1</ref> and this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Previous permit exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall affect a valid permit issued prior to <date date="2009-03-30">March 30, 2009</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for issuance of a permit</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may issue a permit for the collection of a paleontological resource pursuant to an application if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the applicant is qualified to carry out the permitted activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the permitted activity is undertaken for the purpose of furthering paleontological knowledge or for public education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the permitted activity is consistent with any management plan applicable to the Federal land concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the proposed methods of collecting will not threaten significant natural or cultural resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permit specifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A permit for the collection of a paleontological resource issued under this section shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Every permit shall include requirements that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the paleontological resource that is collected from Federal land under the permit will remain the property of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the paleontological resource and copies of associated records will be preserved for the public in an approved repository, to be made available for scientific research and public education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specific locality data will not be released by the permittee or repository without the written permission of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification, suspension, and revocation of permits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may modify, suspend, or revoke a permit issued under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for resource, safety, or other management considerations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> when there is a violation of term or condition of a permit issued pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The permit shall be revoked if any person working under the authority of the permit is convicted under <ref>section 470aaa–5 of this title</ref> or is assessed a civil penalty under <ref>section 470aaa–6 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Area closures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to protect paleontological or other resources or to provide for public safety, the Secretary may restrict access to or close areas under the Secretary’s jurisdiction to the collection of paleontological resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6304</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–4.</num>
<heading> Curation of resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any paleontological resource, and any data and records associated with the resource, collected under a permit, shall be deposited in an approved repository. The Secretary may enter into agreements with non-Federal repositories regarding the curation of these resources, data, and records.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6305</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–5.</num>
<heading> Prohibited acts; criminal penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> excavate, remove, damage, or otherwise alter or deface or attempt to excavate, remove, damage, or otherwise alter or deface any paleontological resources located on Federal land unless such activity is conducted in accordance with this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> exchange, transport, export, receive, or offer to exchange, transport, export, or receive any paleontological resource if the person knew or should have known such resource to have been excavated or removed from Federal land in violation of any provisions, rule, regulation, law, ordinance, or permit in effect under Federal law, including this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sell or purchase or offer to sell or purchase any paleontological resource if the person knew or should have known such resource to have been excavated, removed, sold, purchased, exchanged, transported, or received from Federal land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False labeling offenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person may not make or submit any false record, account, or label for, or any false identification of, any paleontological resource excavated or removed from Federal land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person who knowingly violates or counsels, procures, solicits, or employs another person to violate subsection (a) or (b) shall, upon conviction, be fined in accordance with title 18 or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both; but if the sum of the commercial and paleontological value of the paleontological resources involved and the cost of restoration and repair of such resources does not exceed $500, such person shall be fined in accordance with title 18 or imprisoned not more than 2 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple offenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a second or subsequent violation by the same person, the amount of the penalty assessed under subsection (c) may be doubled.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in subsection (a) shall apply to any person with respect to any paleontological resource which was in the lawful possession of such person prior to <date date="2009-03-30">March 30, 2009</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6306</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–6.</num>
<heading> Civil penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A person who violates any prohibition contained in an applicable regulation or permit issued under this chapter may be assessed a penalty by the Secretary after the person is given notice and opportunity for a hearing with respect to the violation. Each violation shall be considered a separate offense for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of penalty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount of such penalty assessed under paragraph (1) shall be determined under regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter, taking into account the following factors:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The scientific or fair market value, whichever is greater, of the paleontological resource involved, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The cost of response, restoration, and repair of the resource and the paleontological site involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other factors considered relevant by the Secretary assessing the penalty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple offenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a second or subsequent violation by the same person, the amount of a penalty assessed under paragraph (2) may be doubled.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of any penalty assessed under this subsection for any 1 violation shall not exceed an amount equal to double the cost of response, restoration, and repair of resources and paleontological site damage plus double the scientific or fair market value of resources destroyed or not recovered.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petition for judicial review; collection of unpaid assessments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person against whom an order is issued assessing a penalty under subsection (a) may file a petition for judicial review of the order in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the district in which the violation is alleged to have occurred within the 30-day period beginning on the date the order making the assessment was issued. Upon notice of such filing, the Secretary shall promptly file such a certified copy of the record on which the order was issued. The court shall hear the action on the record made before the Secretary and shall sustain the action if it is supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to pay</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If any person fails to pay a penalty under this section within 30 days—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> after the order making assessment has become final and the person has not filed a petition for judicial review of the order in accordance with paragraph (1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after a court in an action brought in paragraph (1) has entered a final judgment upholding the assessment of the penalty,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002399">1</ref> the Secretary may request the Attorney General to institute a civil action in a district court of the United States for any district in which the person if <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002400">2</ref> found, resides, or transacts business, to collect the penalty (plus interest at currently prevailing rates from the date of the final order or the date of the final judgment, as the case may be). The district court shall have jurisdiction to hear and decide any such action. In such action, the validity, amount, and appropriateness of such penalty shall not be subject to review. Any person who fails to pay on a timely basis the amount of an assessment of a civil penalty as described in the first sentence of this paragraph shall be required to pay, in addition to such amount and interest, attorneys fees and costs for collection proceedings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Hearings held during proceedings instituted under subsection (a) shall be conducted in accordance with <ref>section 554 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of recovered amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Penalties collected under this section shall be available to the Secretary and without further appropriation may be used only as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To protect, restore, or repair the paleontological resources and sites which were the subject of the action, and to protect, monitor, and study the resources and sites.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To provide educational materials to the public about paleontological resources and sites.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To provide for the payment of rewards as provided in <ref>section 470aaa–7 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6307</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–7.</num>
<heading> Rewards and forfeiture</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rewards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may pay from penalties collected under section 470aaa–5 or 470aaa–6 of this title or from appropriated funds—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consistent with amounts established in regulations by the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if no such regulation exists, an amount up to ½ of the penalties, to any person who furnishes information which leads to the finding of a civil violation, or the conviction of criminal violation, with respect to which the penalty was paid. If several persons provided the information, the amount shall be divided among the persons. No officer or employee of the United States or of any State or local government who furnishes information or renders service in the performance of his official duties shall be eligible for payment under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forfeiture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All paleontological resources with respect to which a violation under section 470aaa–5 or 470aaa–6 of this title occurred and which are in the possession of any person, shall be subject to civil forfeiture, or upon conviction, to criminal forfeiture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of seized resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may transfer administration of seized paleontological resources to Federal or non-Federal educational institutions to be used for scientific or educational purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6308</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–8.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Information concerning the nature and specific location of a paleontological resource shall be exempt from disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> and any other law unless the Secretary determines that disclosure would—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> further the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not create risk of harm to or theft or destruction of the resource or the site containing the resource; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be in accordance with other applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6309</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–9.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practical after <date date="2009-03-30">March 30, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are appropriate to carry out this chapter, providing opportunities for public notice and comment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6310</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–10.</num>
<heading> Savings provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> invalidate, modify, or impose any additional restrictions or permitting requirements on any activities permitted at any time under the general mining laws, the mineral or geothermal leasing laws, laws providing for minerals materials disposal, or laws providing for the management or regulation of the activities authorized by the aforementioned laws including but not limited to the Federal Land Policy Management Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1701–178</ref>4),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002401">1</ref> subchapter 3 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002402">2</ref> of chapter 1007 of title 54, the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<ref>30 U.S.C. 1201–135</ref>8) [<ref>30 U.S.C. 1201</ref> et seq.], and the Organic Administration Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 478</ref>, 482, 551);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> invalidate, modify, or impose any additional restrictions or permitting requirements on any activities permitted at any time under existing laws and authorities relating to reclamation and multiple uses of Federal land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> apply to, or require a permit for, casual collecting of a rock, mineral, or invertebrate or plant fossil that is not protected under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> affect any land other than Federal land or affect the lawful recovery, collection, or sale of paleontological resources from land other than Federal land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> alter or diminish the authority of a Federal agency under any other law to provide protection for paleontological resources on Federal land in addition to the protection provided under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> create any right, privilege, benefit, or entitlement for any person who is not an officer or employee of the United States acting in that capacity. No person who is not an officer or employee of the United States acting in that capacity shall have standing to file any civil action in a court of the United States to enforce any provision or amendment made by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6311</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 470aaa–11.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title VI, § 6312</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>