<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15C—</num>
<heading>GREAT LAKES FISH AND WILDLIFE TISSUE BANK</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 943.</num>
<heading> Tissue bank</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate existing facilities for the storage, preparation, examination, and archiving of tissues from selected Great Lakes fish and wildlife, which shall be known as the “Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Tissue Bank”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in consultation with appropriate Federal and State agencies and the Council of Great Lakes Research Managers, issue guidance, after an opportunity for public review and comment, for Great Lakes fish and wildlife tissue collection, preparation, archiving, quality control procedures, and access that will ensure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> appropriate uniform methods and standards for those activities to provide confidence in Great Lakes fish and wildlife tissue samples used for research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> documentation of procedures used for collecting, preparing, and archiving those samples; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> appropriate scientific use of the tissues in the Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Tissue Bank.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–440, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 943a.</num>
<heading> Data base</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain a central data base which provides an effective means for tracking and assessing relevant reference data on Great Lakes fish and wildlife, including data on tissues collected for and maintained in the Great Lakes Fish and Wildlife Tissue Bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish criteria, after an opportunity for public review and comment, for access to the data base which provides for appropriate use of the information by the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–440, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 943b.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Great Lakes fish and wildlife” means fauna, fish, and invertebrates dependent on Great Lakes resources, and located within the Great Lakes Basin.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–440, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 943c.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, $250,000 for each of fiscal years 1993 and 1994 to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–440, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>