<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 55—</num>
<heading>COASTAL BARRIER RESOURCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3501.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> coastal barriers along the Atlantic and Gulf coasts and along the shore areas of the Great Lakes of the United States and the adjacent wetlands, marshes, estuaries, inlets and nearshore waters provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> habitats for migratory birds and other wildlife; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> habitats which are essential spawning, nursery, nesting, and feeding areas for commercially and recreationally important species of finfish and shellfish, as well as other aquatic organisms such as sea turtles;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coastal barriers contain resources of extraordinary scenic, scientific, recreational, natural, historic, archeological, cultural, and economic importance; which are being irretrievably damaged and lost due to development on, among, and adjacent to, such barriers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coastal barriers serve as natural storm protective buffers and are generally unsuitable for development because they are vulnerable to hurricane and other storm damage and because natural shoreline recession and the movement of unstable sediments undermine manmade structures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> certain actions and programs of the Federal Government have subsidized and permitted development on coastal barriers and the result has been the loss of barrier resources, threats to human life, health, and property, and the expenditure of millions of tax dollars each year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a program of coordinated action by Federal, State, and local governments is critical to the more appropriate use and conservation of coastal barriers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Congress declares that it is the purpose of this chapter to minimize the loss of human life, wasteful expenditure of Federal revenues, and the damage to fish, wildlife, and other natural resources associated with the coastal barriers along the Atlantic and Gulf coasts and along the shore areas of the Great Lakes by restricting future Federal expenditures and financial assistance which have the effect of encouraging development of coastal barriers, by establishing the John H. Chafee Coastal Barrier Resources System, and by considering the means and measures by which the long-term conservation of these fish, wildlife, and other natural resources may be achieved.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–707, title II, § 204(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–167, § 3(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3502.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coastal barrier</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “coastal barrier” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a depositional geologic feature (such as a bay barrier, tombolo, barrier spit, bluff, or barrier island) that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is subject to wave, tidal, and wind energies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> protects landward aquatic habitats from direct wave attack; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all associated aquatic habitats including the adjacent wetlands, marshes, estuaries, inlets, and nearshore waters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Committees” means the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “financial assistance” means any form of loan, grant, guaranty, insurance, payment, rebate, subsidy, or any other form of direct or indirect Federal assistance other than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> deposit or account insurance for customers of banks, savings and loan associations, credit unions, or similar institutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the purchase of mortgages or loans by the Government National Mortgage Association, the Federal National Mortgage Association, or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> assistance for environmental studies, planning, and assessments that are required incident to the issuance of permits or other authorizations under Federal law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> assistance pursuant to programs entirely unrelated to development, such as any Federal or federally assisted public assistance program or any Federal old-age survivors or disability insurance program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Flood insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “financial assistance” includes flood insurance described in <ref>section 4028 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Great Lakes” means Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake St. Clair, Lake Michigan, and Lake Superior, to the extent that those lakes are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Otherwise Protected Area</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Otherwise Protected Area” means any unit of the System that, at the time of designation, was predominantly composed of areas established under Federal, State, or local law, or held by a qualified organization, primarily for wildlife refuge, wildlife sanctuary, recreational, or natural resource conservation purposes.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “qualified organization” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 170(h)(3) of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “System” means the John H. Chafee Coastal Barrier Resources System established under <ref>section 3503(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System unit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “System unit” means any undeveloped coastal barrier, or combination of closely-related undeveloped coastal barriers, included within the John H. Chafee Coastal Barrier Resources System established under <ref>section 3503(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Undeveloped coastal barrier</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “undeveloped coastal barrier” means a coastal barrier the features and associated habitats of which contain few manmade structures and these structures, and man’s activities on such features and within such habitats, do not significantly impede geomorphic and ecological processes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section supersedes the official maps described in <ref>section 3503(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XIV, § 14001(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 329</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–707, title II, § 204(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–591, § 2(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (c), <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–167, § 3(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–514, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–117, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3503.</num>
<heading> Establishment of John H. Chafee Coastal Barrier Resources System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established the John H. Chafee Coastal Barrier Resources System, which shall consist of those undeveloped coastal barriers and other areas located on the coasts of the United States that are identified and generally depicted as System units or Otherwise Protected Areas—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on the maps on file with the Secretary entitled “Coastal Barrier Resources System”, dated <date date="1990-10-24">October 24, 1990</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on a map described in section 201(b) of the Bolstering Ecosystems Against Coastal Harm Act; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> on a map described in paragraph (1) or (2) as such map may be replaced, modified, revised, or corrected under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subsection (f)(3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 4 of the Coastal Barrier Improvement Act of 1990 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3503</ref> note); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other provision of law enacted on or after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, that specifically replaces or authorizes the modification, revision, or correction of such a map.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System maps</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall keep the maps referred to in subsection (a) on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and in such other offices of that service as the Director considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Digital maps</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall make available to the public on the Internet web site of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service digital versions of the maps included in the set of maps referred to in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any determination as to whether a location is inside or outside the System shall be made without regard to the digital maps available under this paragraph, except that this subparagraph does not apply with respect to any printed version of such a digital map if the printed version is included in the maps referred to in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No later than 180 days after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report regarding the progress and challenges in the transition from paper to digital maps and a timetable for completion of the digitization of all maps related to the System.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Boundary review and modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At least once every 5 years, the Secretary shall review the maps referred to in subsection (a) and shall make, in consultation with the appropriate State, local, and Federal officials, such minor and technical modifications to the boundaries of System units as are necessary solely to reflect changes that have occurred in the size or location of any System unit as a result of natural forces.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additions to System</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may add a parcel of real property to the System, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the owner of the parcel requests, in writing, that the Secretary add the parcel to the System; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the parcel is an undeveloped coastal barrier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Addition of excess Federal property</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Prior to transfer or disposal of excess property under chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 that may be a coastal barrier, the Administrator of General Services shall consult with and obtain from the Secretary a determination as to whether and what portion of the property constitutes a coastal barrier. Not later than 180 days after the initiation of such consultation, the Secretary shall make and publish notice of such determination. Immediately upon issuance of a positive determination, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prepare a map depicting the coastal barrier portion of such property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> publish in the Federal Register notice of the addition of such property to the System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An area to be added to the System under this subsection shall be part of the System effective on the date on which the Secretary publishes notice in the Federal Register under paragraph (1)(B) with respect to that area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maps</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> keep a map showing the location of each boundary modification made under subsection (c) and of each parcel of real property added to the System under subsection (d) or (e) on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and in such other offices of the Service as the Director considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide a notification of the availability of the map to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State and unit of local government in which the property is located;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Federal Emergency Management Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> revise the maps referred to in subsection (a) to reflect each boundary modification under subsection (c) and each addition of real property to the System under subsection (d) or (e), after publishing in the Federal Register a notice of any such proposed revision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for certain recommendations and determinations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In making any recommendation to the Congress regarding the addition of any area to the System or in determining whether, at the time of the inclusion of a System unit within the System, a coastal barrier is undeveloped, the Secretary shall consider whether within the area—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the density of development is less than 1 structure per 5 acres of land above mean high tide; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> there is existing infrastructure consisting of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a road, with a reinforced road bed, to each lot or building site in the area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a wastewater disposal system sufficient to serve each lot or building site in the area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> electric service for each lot or building site in the area; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a fresh water supply for each lot or building site in the area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Structure defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In paragraph (1), the term “structure” means a walled and roofed building, other than a gas or liquid storage tank, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is principally above ground and affixed to a permanent site, including a manufactured home on a permanent foundation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> covers an area of at least 200 square feet.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection supersedes the official maps referred to in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 4</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–396, § 8</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2007</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–707, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–591, § 3</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2931</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–167, § 3(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–514</ref>, §§ 2–3(b)(1), (c), (d), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2394</ref>, 2395; <ref>Pub. L. 115–358</ref>, §§ 2(d), 3, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–117, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3504.</num>
<heading> Limitations on Federal expenditures affecting the System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction or purchase of structure, facility, road, airport, etc.; projects to prevent erosion; exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 3505 of this title</ref>, no new expenditures or new financial assistance may be made available under authority of any Federal law for any purpose within the System, including, but not limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the construction or purchase of any structure, appurtenance, facility, or related infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the construction or purchase of any road, airport, boat landing facility, or other facility on, or bridge or causeway to, any System unit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the carrying out of any project to prevent the erosion of, or to otherwise stabilize, any inlet, shoreline, or inshore area, except that such assistance and expenditures may be made available on units designated pursuant to <ref>section 3503 of this title</ref> on maps numbered S01 through S08 and LA07 for purposes other than encouraging development and, in all units, in cases where an emergency threatens life, land, and property immediately adjacent to that unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New expenditures or new financial assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An expenditure or financial assistance made available under authority of Federal law shall, for purposes of this chapter, be a new expenditure or new financial assistance if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in any case with respect to which specific appropriations are required, no money for construction or purchase purposes was appropriated before the date on which the relevant System unit or portion of the System unit was included within the System under this chapter or the Coastal Barrier Improvement Act of 1990; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no legally binding commitment for the expenditure or financial assistance was made before such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure of limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2024-11-25">November 25, 2024</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall issue regulations requiring the owner or lessor of real property located in a community affected by this chapter, as determined by the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, to disclose to a prospective buyer or lessee such location of such real property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 5</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1656</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–591</ref>, §§ 2(b)(2), 5(c), <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2931</ref>, 2936; <ref>Pub. L. 118–117, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3505.</num>
<heading> Exceptions to limitations on expenditures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3504 of this title</ref>, the appropriate Federal officer, after consultation with the Secretary, may make Federal expenditures and may make financial assistance available within the System for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any use or facility necessary for the exploration, extraction, or transportation of energy resources which can be carried out only on, in, or adjacent to a coastal water area because the use or facility requires access to the coastal water body.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The maintenance or construction of improvements of existing Federal navigation channels (including the Intracoastal Waterway) and related structures (such as jetties), including the disposal of dredge materials related to such maintenance or construction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The maintenance, replacement, reconstruction, or repair, but not the expansion, of publicly owned or publicly operated roads, structures, or facilities that are essential links in a larger network or system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Military activities essential to national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The construction, operation, maintenance, and rehabilitation of Coast Guard facilities and access thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Any of the following actions or projects, if a particular expenditure or the making available of particular assistance for the action or project is consistent with the purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Projects for the study, management, protection, and enhancement of fish and wildlife resources and habitats, including acquisition of fish and wildlife habitats and related lands, stabilization projects for fish and wildlife habitats, and recreational projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Establishment, operation, and maintenance of air and water navigation aids and devices, and for access thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Projects under chapter 2003 of title 54 and the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1451</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Scientific research, including aeronautical, atmospheric, space, geologic, marine, fish and wildlife, and other research, development, and applications.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Emergency actions necessary to the saving of lives and the protection of property and the public health and safety, if such actions are performed pursuant to sections 5170a, 5170b, 5173, and 5192 of title 42 and are limited to actions that are necessary to alleviate the applicable emergency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Maintenance, replacement, reconstruction, or repair, but not the expansion (except with respect to United States route 1 in the Florida Keys), of publicly owned or publicly operated roads, structures, and facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Nonstructural projects for shoreline stabilization that are designed to mimic, enhance, or restore a natural stabilization system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> Aquaculture operations that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> produce shellfish (including oysters, clams, and mussels), cultivate micro- or macro-algae, or do not require the use of aquaculture feeds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> adhere to best management practices and conservation measures recommended by the Secretary through the consultation process referred to in this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Use of a sand source within a System unit by Federal coastal storm risk management projects or their predecessor projects that have used a System unit for sand to nourish adjacent beaches outside the System pursuant to <ref>section 701n of title 33</ref> at least once between <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date> and <date date="2023-12-31">December 31, 2023</date> in response to an emergency situation prior to <date date="2023-12-31">December 31, 2023</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing Federal navigation channels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)(2), a Federal navigation channel or a related structure is an existing channel or structure, respectively, if it was authorized before the date on which the relevant System unit or portion of the System unit was included within the System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expansion of highways in Michigan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The limitations on the use of Federal expenditures or financial assistance within the System under subsection (a)(3) shall not apply to a highway—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> located in a unit of the System in Michigan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in existence on <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Services and facilities outside System</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, limitations on the use of Federal expenditures or financial assistance within the System under <ref>section 3504 of this title</ref> shall not apply to expenditures or assistance provided for services or facilities and related infrastructure located outside the boundaries of unit T–11 of the System (as depicted on the maps referred to in <ref>section 3503(a) of this title</ref>) which relate to an activity within that unit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of flood insurance coverage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No new flood insurance coverage may be provided under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.) for any new construction or substantial improvements relating to services or facilities and related infrastructure located outside the boundaries of unit T–11 of the System that facilitate an activity within that unit that is not consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of HUD assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No financial assistance for acquisition, construction, or improvement purposes may be provided under any program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for any services or facilities and related infrastructure located outside the boundaries of unit T–11 of the System that facilitate an activity within that unit that is not consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Financial assistance” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “financial assistance” includes any contract, loan, grant, cooperative agreement, or other form of assistance, including the insurance or guarantee of a loan, mortgage, or pool of mortgages.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to Otherwise Protected Areas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The prohibitions on new Federal expenditures and financial assistance described in <ref>section 3504(a) of this title</ref> do not apply within Otherwise Protected Areas except with respect to limitations on new flood insurance coverage described in section 1321 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4028</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), new Federal flood insurance may be provided for a structure in an Otherwise Protected Area that is used in a manner consistent with the purpose for which such Otherwise Protected Area is protected.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to additions and insurable structures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to an addition to the System made under <ref>section 3503 of this title</ref> on or after <date date="2024-11-25">November 25, 2024</date>, subject to paragraph (2), the prohibitions on new Federal expenditures and financial assistance described in <ref>section 3504(a) of this title</ref> shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date on which such addition is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurable structures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The prohibitions on new Federal expenditures and financial assistance described in <ref>section 3504(a) of this title</ref> do not apply to an insurable structure.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurable structure defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this subsection, the term “insurable structure” means an insurable structure that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> located within an addition described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in existence before the expiration of the applicable 1-year period described in paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 6</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1656</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 109(h)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–591, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2934</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(34)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3267</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–117, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3506.</num>
<heading> Certification of compliance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2024-11-25">November 25, 2024</date>, the head of each Federal agency affected by this chapter shall revise or issue regulations and guidance as necessary to ensure compliance with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of each Federal agency affected by this chapter shall report and certify that each such agency is in compliance with the provisions of this chapter. Such reports and certifications shall be submitted annually to the Committees and the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 7</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–591, § 14</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–117, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3507.</num>
<heading> Priority of laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as indicating an intent on the part of the Congress to change the existing relationship of other Federal laws to the law of a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or to relieve any person of any obligation imposed by any law of any State, or political subdivision of a State. No provision of this chapter shall be construed to invalidate any provision of State or local law unless there is a direct conflict between such provision and the law of the State, or political subdivision of the State, so that the two cannot be reconciled or consistently stand together. This chapter shall in no way be interpreted to interfere with a State’s right to protect, rehabilitate, preserve, and restore lands within its established boundary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 8</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1658</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3508.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of the chapter and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 9</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1658</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3509.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–514, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2396</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3510.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2010; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $1,962,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2031.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–348, § 10</ref>, formerly § 12, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1659</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–591, § 13(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–461, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4804</ref>; renumbered § 10 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–514, § 5</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–226, § 5</ref>, <date date="2006-05-25">May 25, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–117, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>