<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 100—</num>
<heading>NUTRIA ERADICATION AND CONTROL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8101.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Wetlands, tidal marshes, and agricultural lands provide significant cultural, economic, and ecological benefits to the Nation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The South American nutria (Myocastor coypus) is directly contributing to substantial marsh loss on Federal, State, and private land.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Traditional harvest methods to control or eradicate nutria have failed. Consequently, marsh loss, loss of public and private wetlands, and loss of agricultural lands are accelerating.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The nutria eradication and control pilot program authorized by <ref>Public Law 105–322</ref> is to develop new and effective methods for eradication of nutria.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide financial assistance to any State that has demonstrated the need for a program to implement measures to eradicate or control nutria and restore marshland damaged by nutria.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–16, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–186, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 901</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8102.</num>
<heading> Nutria eradication program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this chapter as the “Secretary”),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002874">1</ref> may provide financial assistance to a State, in an amount that is in proportion to the total impacted area of such State affected by nutria, that has demonstrated to the Secretary sufficient need for a program to implement measures to eradicate or control nutria and restore marshland, public and private wetlands, and agricultural lands damaged by nutria.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the State of Maryland, the Secretary shall require that the program consist of management, research, and public education activities carried out in accordance with the document published by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service entitled “Eradication Strategies for Nutria in the Chesapeake and Delaware Bay Watersheds”, dated March 2002.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal share of the costs of a State program referred to in subsection (a) may not exceed 75 percent of the total costs of the program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In-kind contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The non-Federal share of the costs of a State program referred to in subsection (a) may be provided in the form of in-kind contributions of materials or services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 5 percent of financial assistance provided to a State by the Secretary under this section may be used for administrative expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For financial assistance under this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $12,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–16, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–186, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 901</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>