<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 92—</num>
<heading>FOREST LANDSCAPE RESTORATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7301.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to encourage the collaborative, science-based ecosystem restoration of priority forest landscapes through a process that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> encourages ecological, economic, and social sustainability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> leverages local resources with national and private resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitates the reduction of wildfire management costs, including through reestablishing natural fire regimes and reducing the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> demonstrates the degree to which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> various ecological restoration techniques—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> achieve ecological and watershed health objectives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> affect wildfire activity and management costs; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of forest restoration byproducts can offset treatment costs while benefitting local rural economies and improving forest health.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title IV, § 4001</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Fund” means the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Fund established by <ref>section 7303(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “program” means the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program established under <ref>section 7303(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “proposal” means a collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal described in <ref>section 7303(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “strategy” means a landscape restoration strategy described in <ref>section 7303(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title IV, § 4002</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7303.</num>
<heading> Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall establish a Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program to select and fund ecological restoration treatments for priority forest landscapes in accordance with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for nomination under subsection (c), a collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> be based on a landscape restoration strategy that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is complete or substantially complete;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> identifies and prioritizes ecological restoration treatments for a 10-year period within a landscape that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at least 50,000 acres;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> comprised primarily of forested National Forest System land, but may also include land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, or other Federal, State, tribal, or private land;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in need of active ecosystem restoration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> accessible by existing or proposed wood-processing infrastructure at an appropriate scale to use woody biomass and small-diameter wood removed in ecological restoration treatments;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> incorporates the best available science and scientific application tools in ecological restoration strategies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> fully maintains, or contributes toward the restoration of, the structure and composition of old growth stands according to the pre-fire suppression old growth conditions characteristic of the forest type, taking into account the contribution of the stand to landscape fire adaptation and watershed health and retaining the large trees contributing to old growth structure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> would carry out any forest restoration treatments that reduce hazardous fuels by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> focusing on small diameter trees, thinning, strategic fuel breaks, and fire use to modify fire behavior, as measured by the projected reduction of uncharacteristically severe wildfire effects for the forest type (such as adverse soil impacts, tree mortality or other impacts); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> maximizing the retention of large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote fire-resilient stands; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> does not include the establishment of permanent roads; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> would commit funding to decommission all temporary roads constructed to carry out the strategy;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> be developed and implemented through a collaborative process that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes multiple interested persons representing diverse interests; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is transparent and nonexclusive; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under subsections (c) through (f) of <ref>section 7125 of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002856">1</ref></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> describe plans to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire, including through the use of fire for ecological restoration and maintenance and reestablishing natural fire regimes, where appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improve fish and wildlife habitat, including for endangered, threatened, and sensitive species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> maintain or improve water quality and watershed function;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> prevent, remediate, or control invasions of exotic species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> maintain, decommission, and rehabilitate roads and trails;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> use woody biomass and small-diameter trees produced from projects implementing the strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> report annually on performance, including through performance measures from the plan entitled the “10 Year Comprehensive Strategy Implementation Plan” and dated December 2006; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> take into account any applicable community wildfire protection plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> analyze any anticipated cost savings, including those resulting from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduced wildfire management costs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a decrease in the unit costs of implementing ecological restoration treatments over time;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> estimate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the annual Federal funding necessary to implement the proposal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of new non-Federal investment for carrying out the proposal that would be leveraged;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> describe the collaborative process through which the proposal was developed, including a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> participation by or consultation with State, local, and Tribal governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any established record of successful collaborative planning and implementation of ecological restoration projects on National Forest System land and other land included in the proposal by the collaborators; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> benefit local economies by providing local employment or training opportunities through contracts, grants, or agreements for restoration planning, design, implementation, or monitoring with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> local private, nonprofit, or cooperative entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Youth Conservation Corps crews or related partnerships, with State, local, and non-profit youth groups;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> existing or proposed small or micro-businesses, clusters, or incubators; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other entities that will hire or train local people to complete such contracts, grants, or agreements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> be subject to any other requirements that the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, determines to be necessary for the efficient and effective administration of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nomination process</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A proposal shall be submitted to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate Regional Forester; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if actions under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior are proposed, the appropriate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> State Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Regional Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other official of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nomination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A Regional Forester may nominate for selection by the Secretary any proposals that meet the eligibility criteria established by subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrence</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any proposal nominated by the Regional Forester that proposes actions under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior shall include the concurrence of the appropriate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> State Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Regional Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other official of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Documentation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to each proposal that is nominated under paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the appropriate Regional Forester shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> include a plan to use Federal funds allocated to the region to fund those costs of planning and carrying out ecological restoration treatments on National Forest System land, consistent with the strategy, that would not be covered by amounts transferred to the Secretary from the Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide evidence that amounts proposed to be transferred to the Secretary from the Fund during the first 2 fiscal years following selection would be used to carry out ecological restoration treatments consistent with the strategy during the same fiscal year in which the funds are transferred to the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if actions under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior are proposed, the nomination shall include a plan to fund such actions, consistent with the strategy, by the appropriate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> State Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Regional Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other official of the Department of the Interior; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if actions on land not under the jurisdiction of the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior are proposed, the appropriate Regional Forester shall provide evidence that the landowner intends to participate in, and provide appropriate funding to carry out, the actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection process</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After consulting with the advisory panel established under subsection (e), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall, subject to paragraph (2), select the best proposals that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have been nominated under subsection (c)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meet the eligibility criteria established by subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In selecting proposals under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give special consideration to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the strength of the proposal and strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the strength of the ecological case of the proposal and the proposed ecological restoration strategies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the strength of the collaborative process and the likelihood of successful collaboration throughout implementation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether the proposal is likely to achieve reductions in long-term wildfire management costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> whether the proposal would reduce the relative costs of carrying out ecological restoration treatments as a result of the use of woody biomass and small-diameter trees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> whether an appropriate level of non-Federal investment would be leveraged in carrying out the proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may select not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 10 proposals to be funded during any fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 proposals in any 1 region of the National Forest System to be funded during any fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of proposals that the Secretary determines are likely to receive adequate funding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), after consulting with the advisory panel established under subsection (e), if the Secretary determines that a proposal that has been selected under paragraph (1) and is being carried out continues to meet the eligibility criteria established by subsection (b), the Secretary, on a case-by-case basis, may issue for the proposal a 1-time extension of the 10-year period requirement under paragraph (1)(B) of that subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The extension described in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be for the shortest period of time practicable to complete implementation of the proposal, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not exceed 10 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory panel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish and maintain an advisory panel comprised of not more than 15 members to evaluate, and provide recommendations on, each proposal that has been nominated under subsection (c)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that the membership of the advisory panel is fairly balanced in terms of the points of view represented and the functions to be performed by the advisory panel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The advisory panel shall include experts in ecological restoration, fire ecology, fire management, rural economic development, strategies for ecological adaptation to climate change, fish and wildlife ecology, and woody biomass and small-diameter tree utilization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the “Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Fund”, to be used to pay up to 50 percent of the cost of carrying out and monitoring ecological restoration treatments on National Forest System land for each proposal selected to be carried out under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The cost of carrying out ecological restoration treatments as provided in paragraph (1) may, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, include cancellation and termination costs required to be obligated for contracts to carry out ecological restoration treatments on National Forest System land for each proposal selected to be carried out under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall consist of such amounts as are appropriated to the Fund under paragraph (6).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures from Fund</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On request by the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the Fund to the Secretary such amounts as the Secretary determines are appropriate, in accordance with paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall not expend money from the Fund on any 1 proposal—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> during a period of more than 10 fiscal years; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in excess of $4,000,000 in any 1 fiscal year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The limitation described in subparagraph (B)(i) shall not apply to a proposal for which a 1-time extension is granted under subsection (d)(4).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounting and reporting system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish an accounting and reporting system for the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $80,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program implementation and monitoring</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Work plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the date on which a proposal is selected to be carried out, the Secretary shall create, in collaboration with the interested persons, an implementation work plan and budget to implement the proposal that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the manner in which the proposal would be implemented to achieve ecological and community economic benefit, including capacity building to accomplish restoration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a business plan that addresses—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the anticipated unit treatment cost reductions over 10 years;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the anticipated costs for infrastructure needed for the proposal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the projected sustainability of the supply of woody biomass and small-diameter trees removed in ecological restoration treatments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the projected local economic benefits of the proposal;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> documentation of the non-Federal investment in the priority landscape, including the sources and uses of the investments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a plan to decommission any temporary roads established to carry out the proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Amounts transferred to the Secretary from the Fund shall be used to carry out ecological restoration treatments that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consistent with the proposal and strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identified through the collaborative process described in subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of the Interior and interested persons, shall prepare an annual report on the accomplishments of each selected proposal that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of all acres (or other appropriate unit) treated and restored through projects implementing the strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an evaluation of progress, including performance measures and how prior year evaluations have contributed to improved project performance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of community benefits achieved, including any local economic benefits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the results of the multiparty monitoring, evaluation, and accountability process under paragraph (4); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> a summary of the costs of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> treatments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> relevant fire management activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiparty monitoring</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall, in collaboration with the Secretary of the Interior and interested persons, use a multiparty monitoring, evaluation, and accountability process to assess the positive or negative ecological, social, and economic effects of projects implementing a selected proposal for not less than 15 years after project implementation commences.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 5 years after the first fiscal year in which funding is made available to carry out ecological restoration projects under the program, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall submit a report on the program, including an assessment of whether, and to what extent, the program is fulfilling the purposes of this chapter, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title IV, § 4003</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8629</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4865</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7304.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title IV, § 4004</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>