<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 56—</num>
<heading>NORTH ATLANTIC SALMON FISHING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3601.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Act of 1976” means the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the conservation and management of the fisheries, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1976-04-13">April 13, 1976</date> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Commission” means any of the Commissions of the Organization that are established by the Convention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Commissioner” means a United States Commissioner appointed under <ref>section 3602 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Convention” means the Convention for the Conservation of Salmon in the North Atlantic Ocean, signed at Reykjavik, Iceland, on <date date="1982-03-02">March 2, 1982</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “Council” means the Council established by the Convention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “fishing” has the same meaning as such term has in section 3(10) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002755">1</ref> of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1802(10)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “Organization” means the North Atlantic Salmon Conservation Organization established under the Convention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “person” has the same meaning as such term has in section 3(19) <sup>1</sup> of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1802(19)</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “salmon” means all species of salmon which migrate in or into the waters of the Atlantic Ocean north of 36 degrees north latitude.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3602.</num>
<heading> United States representation on Council and Commissions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and qualifications of Commissioners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States shall be represented on the Council and Commissions by three United States Commissioners to be appointed by the President to serve at his pleasure. Of such Commissioners, one shall be an official of the United States Government, and two shall be individuals (not officials of the United States Government) who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning the conservation and management of salmon of United States origin.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternate Commissioners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior, may designate alternate United States Commissioners. In the absence of a Commissioner appointed under subsection (a) of this section, an alternate Commissioner may exercise at any meeting of the Organization, the Council, or any Commission all functions of such Commissioner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited Federal employee status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Individuals who serve as Commissioners and alternate Commissioners shall not receive any compensation for such service. Such individuals shall not be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, except for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with other parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out their functions under the Convention, the Commissioners may consult with the appropriate Regional Fishery Management Councils established by section 302 of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1852</ref>), and may consult with such other interested parties as they consider appropriate. Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to consultations described in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–44, title I, § 102(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-07-12">July 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(117)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3603.</num>
<heading> Receipt of Organization communications by Secretary of State</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrence with Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior on regulatory measures; action on other matters</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receive, on behalf of the United States, reports, requests, recommendations, proposals, and other communications of the Organization and its subsidiary organs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with the concurrence of the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior, approve, object to, or withdraw objections to regulatory measures proposed in accordance with the Convention; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> act upon, or refer to other appropriate authority, any communication referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection other than a proposed regulatory measure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to President on failure of concurrence on regulatory matters</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the concurrence required under subsection (a)(2) of this section has not been obtained by the Secretary of State—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> regarding the approval of, or the objection to, a proposed regulatory measure within forty-five days after the measure was received on behalf of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regarding the withdrawal of an objection of the United States to a proposed regulatory measure within forty-five days after such withdrawal is proposed by the Secretary of State;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary of State shall submit the matter in disagreement, together with a statement of the opposing positions, to the President for timely disposition.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1952</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3604.</num>
<heading> Regulations and reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgation of regulations; implementation; applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall promulgate such regulations pursuant to <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref> as may be necessary to carry out the purposes and objectives of the Convention and this chapter, and to implement regulatory measures that are binding on the United States under the Convention. Any such regulation may be made applicable, as necessary, to all persons and all vessels subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, wherever located.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation and submission of reports by certain Secretaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall prepare all statements, reports, and notifications, required by articles 14 and 15 of the Convention and submit such documents to the Secretary of State for transmission to the Organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3605.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with other agencies and institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal and State agencies; private institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of the Convention, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, may arrange for the cooperation of agencies of the United States and the States, and of private institutions and organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Federal facilities; reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriate agencies of the United States may cooperate in the conduct of scientific and other programs, and may furnish facilities and personnel, for the purposes of assisting the Organization in carrying out its duties under the Convention. Such agencies may accept reimbursement from the Organization for providing such services, facilities, and personnel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3606.</num>
<heading> Violations and penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Directed fishing for salmon; Convention, rules and regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person, or any vessel, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to conduct directed fishing for salmon in waters seaward of twelve miles from the baselines from which the breadths of territorial seas are measured, in waters of the Atlantic Ocean north of 36 degrees north latitude; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to violate any provision of the Convention or this chapter, or of any regulation promulgated under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil and criminal penalties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any person who commits any act that is unlawful under subsection (a) of this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be liable to the United States for a civil penalty under section 308 of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1858</ref>) to the same extent as if such act were an act prohibited under section 307 of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1857</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be guilty of an offense under section 309 of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1859</ref>) to the same extent as if such act were an act prohibited by section 307(1)(D), (E), (F), or (H) of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1857(1)(D)</ref>, (E), (F), or (H)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil forfeiture of vessel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any vessel used, and any fish (or the fair market value thereof) taken or retained in any manner, in connection with or as the result of the commission of an act which is unlawful under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to civil forfeiture under section 310 of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1860</ref>) to the same extent as if such vessel was used in, or such fish was taken or retained in connection with or as the result of, the commission of an act prohibited by section 307 of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1857</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–44, title I, § 102(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-07-12">July 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3607.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall enforce the provisions of this chapter and any regulation issued under this chapter. For purposes of such enforcement, such provisions and regulations shall be considered to be provisions of the Act of 1976 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.] to which section 311(a), (b), (c), and (d) of the Act of 1976 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1861(a)</ref>, (b), (c), and (d), respectively) apply.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3608.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated from time to time such sums as may be necessary for carrying out the purposes and provisions of the Convention and this chapter including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> necessary travel expenses of the Commissioners and alternate Commissioners in accordance with the Federal Travel Regulation and sections 5701, 5702, 5704 through 5708, and 5731 of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States contribution to the Organization as provided in Article 16 of the Convention, not to exceed $50,000 for fiscal year 1983, and not to exceed, for each succeeding fiscal year, the amount assessed by the Organization for the United States for such year.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>