<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 89—</num>
<heading>PACIFIC WHITING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7001.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory panel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “advisory panel” means the Advisory Panel on Pacific Hake/Whiting established by the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Agreement” means the Agreement between the Government of the United States and the Government of Canada on Pacific Hake/Whiting, signed at Seattle, Washington, on <date date="2003-11-21">November 21, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Catch</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “catch” means all fishery removals from the offshore whiting resource, including landings, discards, and bycatch in other fisheries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint management committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “joint management committee” means the joint management committee established by the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint technical committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “joint technical committee” means the joint technical committee established by the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offshore whiting resource</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “offshore whiting resource” means the transboundary stock of Merluccius productus that is located in the offshore waters of the United States and Canada except in Puget Sound and the Strait of Georgia.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scientific review group</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “scientific review group” means the scientific review group established by the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States Section” means the United States representatives on the joint management committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7002.</num>
<heading> United States representation on joint management committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representatives</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint 4 individuals to represent the United States as the United States Section on the joint management committee. In making the appointments, the Secretary shall select representatives from among individuals who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning the offshore whiting resource. Of these—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 1 shall be an official of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 1 shall be a member of the Pacific Fishery Management Council, appointed with consideration given to any recommendation provided by that Council;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed from a list submitted by the treaty Indian tribes with treaty fishing rights to the offshore whiting resource; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed from the commercial sector of the whiting fishing industry concerned with the offshore whiting resource.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each representative appointed under paragraph (1) shall be appointed for a term not to exceed 4 years, except that, of the initial appointments, 2 representatives shall be appointed for terms of 2 years. Any individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term of office of that individual’s predecessor shall be appointed for the remainder of that term. A representative may be appointed for a term of less than 4 years if such term is necessary to ensure that the term of office of not more than 2 representatives will expire in any single year. An individual appointed to serve as a representative is eligible for reappointment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Unless otherwise agreed by all of the 4 representatives, the chair shall rotate annually among the 4 members, with the order of rotation determined by lot at the first meeting.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternate representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may designate alternate representatives of the United States to serve on the joint management committee. An alternative representative may exercise, at any meeting of the committee, all the powers and duties of a representative in the absence of a duly designated representative for whatever reason.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7003.</num>
<heading> United States representation on the scientific review group</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint no more than 2 scientific experts to serve on the scientific review group. An individual shall not be eligible to serve on the scientific review group while serving on the joint technical committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual appointed under subsection (a) shall be appointed for a term of not to exceed 4 years, but shall be eligible for reappointment. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of a term of office of that individual’s predecessor shall be appointed to serve for the remainder of that term.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint appointments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to individuals appointed under subsection (a), the Secretary, jointly with the Government of Canada, may appoint to the scientific review group, from a list of names provided by the advisory panel—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> up to 2 independent members of the scientific review group; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 2 public advisors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7004.</num>
<heading> United States representation on joint technical committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scientific experts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint no more than 2 individuals to serve as scientific experts on the joint technical committee, at least 1 of whom shall be an official of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An individual appointed under paragraph (1) shall be appointed for a term of not to exceed 4 years, but shall be eligible for reappointment. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term of office of that individual’s predecessor shall be appointed for the remainder of that term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to individuals appointed under subsection (a), the Secretary, jointly with the Government of Canada, shall appoint 1 independent member to the joint technical committee selected from a list of names provided by the advisory panel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3646</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–348, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7005.</num>
<heading> United States representation on advisory panel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint at least 6 but not more than 12 individuals to serve as members of the advisory panel, selected from among individuals who are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> knowledgeable or experienced in the harvesting, processing, marketing, management, conservation, or research of the offshore whiting resource; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not employees of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An individual appointed under paragraph (1) shall be appointed for a term of not to exceed 4 years, but shall be eligible for reappointment. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term of office of that individual’s predecessor shall be appointed for the remainder of that term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3646</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7006.</num>
<heading> Responsibilities of the Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is responsible for carrying out the Agreement and this chapter, including the authority, to be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of State, to accept or reject, on behalf of the United States, recommendations made by the joint management committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations; cooperation with Canadian officials</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In exercising responsibilities under this chapter, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes and objectives of the Agreement and this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may cooperate with officials of the Canadian Government duly authorized to carry out the Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3646</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7007.</num>
<heading> Rulemaking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application with Magnuson-Stevens Act</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish the United States catch level for Pacific whiting according to the standards and procedures of the Agreement and this chapter rather than under the standards and procedures of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), except to the extent necessary to address the rebuilding needs of other species. Except for establishing the catch level, all other aspects of Pacific whiting management shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subject to the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consistent with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint management committee recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For any year in which both parties to the Agreement approve recommendations made by the joint management committee with respect to the catch level, the Secretary shall implement the approved recommendations. Any regulation promulgated by the Secretary to implement any such recommendation shall apply, as necessary, to all persons and all vessels subject to the jurisdiction of the United States wherever located.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Years with no approved catch recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the parties to the Agreement do not approve the joint management committee’s recommendation with respect to the catch level for any year, the Secretary shall establish the total allowable catch for Pacific whiting for the United States catch. In establishing the total allowable catch under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> take into account any recommendations from the Pacific Fishery Management Council, the joint management committee, the joint technical committee, the scientific review group, and the advisory panel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> base the total allowable catch on the best scientific information available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use the default harvest rate set out in paragraph 1 of Article III of the Agreement unless the Secretary determines that the scientific evidence demonstrates that a different rate is necessary to sustain the offshore whiting resource; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish the United State’s <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002847">1</ref> share of the total allowable catch based on paragraph 2 of Article III of the Agreement and make any adjustments necessary under section 5 of Article II of the Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 608</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3647</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7008.</num>
<heading> Administrative matters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Individuals appointed under section 7002, 7003, 7004, or 7005 of this title, other than officers or employees of the United States Government, shall not be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, except for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), an individual appointed under this chapter shall receive no compensation for the individual’s service as a representative, alternate representative, scientific expert, or advisory panel member under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scientific review group</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary may employ and fix the compensation of an individual appointed under <ref>section 7003(a) of this title</ref> to serve as a scientific expert on the scientific review group who is not employed by the United States Government, a State government, or an Indian tribal government in accordance with <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary shall pay the necessary travel expenses of individuals appointed under this chapter in accordance with the Federal Travel Regulations and sections 5701, 5702, 5704 through 5708, and 5731 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint appointees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to the 2 independent members of the scientific review group and the 2 public advisors to the scientific review group jointly appointed under <ref>section 7003(c) of this title</ref>, and the 1 independent member to the joint technical committee jointly appointed under <ref>section 7004(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary may pay up to 50 percent of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any compensation paid to such individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the necessary travel expenses of such individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 609</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3647</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–348, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7009.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administer and enforce this chapter and any regulations issued under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> request and utilize on a reimbursed or non-reimbursed basis the assistance, services, personnel, equipment, and facilities of other Federal departments and agencies in the administration and enforcement of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collect, utilize, and disclose such information as may be necessary to implement the Agreement and this chapter, subject to sections 552 and 552a of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person to violate any provision of this chapter or the regulations promulgated under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by the Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prevent any person from violating this chapter in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1857</ref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter. Any person that violates any provision of this chapter is subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.] in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, power, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of that Act were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall be enforced by the Secretary as if a violation of this chapter or of any regulation promulgated by the Secretary under this chapter were a violation of section 307 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1857</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 610</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3648</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7010.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out the obligations of the United States under the Agreement and this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 611</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>