<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 83A—</num>
<heading>CORAL REEF CONSERVATION, MANAGEMENT, AND ASSISTANCE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES CORAL REEF TASK FORCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6451.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a task force to lead, coordinate, and strengthen Federal Government actions to better preserve, conserve, and restore coral reef ecosystems, to be known as the “United States Coral Reef Task Force” (in this subchapter referred to as the “Task Force”).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10011</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6452.</num>
<heading> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The duties of the Task Force shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to coordinate, in cooperation with covered States, covered Native entities, Federal reef managers, covered reef managers, coral reef research centers designated under <ref>section 6411(b) of this title</ref> (as added by this division), and other nongovernmental and academic partners as appropriate, activities regarding the mapping, monitoring, research, conservation, mitigation, and restoration of coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to monitor and advise regarding implementation of the policy and Federal agency responsibilities set forth in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Executive Order 13089 (63 Fed. Reg. 32701; relating to coral reef protection); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to work in coordination with the other members of the Task Force—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to assess the United States role in international trade and protection of coral species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to encourage implementation of appropriate strategies and actions to promote conservation and sustainable use of coral reef resources worldwide; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to collaborate with international communities successful in managing coral reefs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> to provide technical assistance for the development and implementation, as appropriate, of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coral reef action plans under <ref>section 6404 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> to produce a report each year, for submission to the appropriate congressional committees and publication on the public website of the Task Force, highlighting the status of the coral reef resources of a covered State on a rotating basis, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of recent coral reef management and restoration activities undertaken in that State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> updated estimates of the direct and indirect economic activity supported by, and other benefits associated with, those coral reef resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10012</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3952</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6453.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The voting members of the Task Force shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and the Secretary of Interior, who shall be co-chairpersons of the Task Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such representatives from other Federal agencies as the President, in consultation with the Under Secretary, determines appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Governor, or a representative of the Governor, of each covered State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonvoting members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Task Force shall have the following nonvoting members:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member of the South Atlantic Fishery Management Council who is designated by the Governor of Florida under <ref>section 1852(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A member of the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council who is designated by the Governor of Florida under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council who is designated under such section and selected as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For the period beginning on <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and ending on December 31 of the calendar year during which such date occurs, the member shall be selected jointly by the Governors of Hawaii, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For each calendar year thereafter, the Governors of Hawaii, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall, on a rotating basis, take turns selecting the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the Caribbean Fishery Management Council who is designated under such section and selected as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For the period beginning on <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and ending on December 31 of the calendar year during which such date occurs, the member shall be selected jointly by the Governors of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For each calendar year thereafter, the Governors of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands shall, on an alternating basis, take turns selecting the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A member appointed by the President of the Federated States of Micronesia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A member appointed by the President of the Republic of the Marshall Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> A member appointed by the President of the Republic of Palau.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10013</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3952</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6454.</num>
<heading> Responsibilities of Federal agency members</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A member of the Task Force described in <ref>section 6453(a) of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify the actions of the agency that member represents that may affect coral reef ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use the programs and authorities of that agency to protect and enhance the conditions of such ecosystems, including through the promotion of basic and applied scientific research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collaborate with the Task Force to appropriately reflect budgetary needs for coral reef conservation and restoration activities in all agency budget planning and justification documents and processes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> engage in any other coordinated efforts approved by the Task Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Co-chairpersons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to their responsibilities under subsection (a), the co-chairpersons of the Task Force shall perform the administrative functions of the Task Force and facilitate the coordination of the members of the Task Force described in <ref>section 6453(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not less than 30 days before each meeting of the Task Force, the program offices of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration responsible for implementing this title shall provide a briefing to the relevant congressional committees on efforts and spending associated with such implementation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10014</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6455.</num>
<heading> Working groups</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The co-chairpersons of the Task Force may establish working groups as necessary to meet the goals and carry out the duties of the Task Force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests from members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Task Force may request that the co-chairpersons establish a working group under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation by nongovernmental organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The co-chairpersons may allow nongovernmental organizations as appropriate, including academic institutions, conservation groups, and commercial and recreational fishing associations, to participate in a working group established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002827">1</ref> shall not apply to working groups established under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10015</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6456.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation, coral, coral reef, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “conservation”, “coral”, “coral reef”, “coral reef ecosystem”, “covered reef manager”, “covered State”, “Federal reef manager”, “National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy”, “restoration”, “resilience”, and “State” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 6415 of this title</ref>, as added by this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10016</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR CORAL REEF AUTHORITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6471.</num>
<heading> Coral reef conservation and restoration assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may provide scientific expertise and technical assistance, and subject to the availability of appropriations, financial assistance for the conservation and restoration of coral reefs consistent with all applicable laws governing resource management in Federal, State, and Tribal waters, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coral reef action plans in effect under section 205 of the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 6404</ref>], as added by this division, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral Reef Initiative</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may establish a Coral Reef Initiative Program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to provide grant funding to support local management, conservation, and protection of coral reef ecosystems in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coastal areas of covered States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Freely Associated States;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to enhance resource availability of National Park Service and National Wildlife Refuge System management units to implement coral reef conservation and restoration activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to complement the other conservation and assistance activities conducted under this Act or the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 6401</ref> et seq.], as amended by section 10001; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to provide other technical, scientific, and financial assistance and conduct conservation and restoration activities that advance the purposes of this title and the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000, as amended by this division.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with the Department of Commerce</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coral reef conservation and restoration activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Interior may consult with the Secretary of Commerce regarding the conduct of any activities to conserve and restore coral reefs and coral reef ecosystems in waters managed under the jurisdiction of the Federal agencies specified in paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 203(c) of the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 6402(c)(2)</ref>, (3)], as added by this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of Coral Reef Management Fellowship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Interior shall consult with the Secretary of Commerce to award the Susan L. Williams Coral Reef Management Fellowship under subchapter III of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of the Interior may enter into cooperative agreements with covered reef managers to fund coral reef conservation and restoration activities in waters managed under the jurisdiction of such managers that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are consistent with the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> support and enhance the success of coral reef action plans in effect under section 205 of the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 6404</ref>], as added by this division.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation, coral, coral reef, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “conservation”, “coral reef”, “covered reef manager”, “covered State”, “National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy”, “restoration”, and “State” have the meanings given those terms in section 216 of the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 6415</ref>], as added by this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribe; Tribal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “Tribe” and “Tribal” refer to Indian Tribes (as defined in <ref>section 5130 of title 25</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10021</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SUSAN L. WILLIAMS NATIONAL CORAL REEF MANAGEMENT FELLOWSHIP</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6481.</num>
<heading> Susan L. Williams National Coral Reef Management Fellowship</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alaska Native Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Alaska Native Corporation” has the meaning given the term “Native Corporation” in <ref>section 1602 of title 43</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fellow</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “fellow” means a National Coral Reef Management Fellow.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fellowship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “fellowship” means the National Coral Reef Management Fellowship established in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered Native entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “covered Native entity” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 6415 of this title</ref>, as added by this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “covered State” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 6415 of this title</ref>, as added by this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Native entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Native entity” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 6415 of this title</ref>, as added by this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of fellowship program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established a National Coral Reef Management Fellowship Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The purposes of the fellowship are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to encourage future leaders of the United States to develop additional coral reef management capacity in States and local communities with coral reefs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide management agencies of covered States and covered Native entities with highly qualified candidates whose education and work experience meet the specific needs of each covered State or covered Native entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to provide fellows with professional experience in management of coastal and coral reef resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fellowship awards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall award a fellowship in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of fellowship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A fellowship awarded under this subsection shall be for a term of not more than 2 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall award a fellowship to individuals who have demonstrated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an intent to pursue a career in marine services and outstanding potential for such a career;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> leadership potential, actual leadership experience, or both;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> possession of a college or graduate degree in biological science, a college or graduate degree in resource management with experience that correlates with aptitude and interest for marine management, or both;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> proficient writing and speaking skills; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such other attributes as the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the non-Federal share of the costs of a fellowship under this section shall be 25 percent of such costs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of matching requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may waive the application of paragraph (1) to a fellowship if the Secretary finds that such waiver is necessary to support a project that the Secretary has identified as a high priority.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10031</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3955</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>