<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15A—</num>
<heading>GREAT LAKES FISHERIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 931.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> “Convention” means the Convention on Great Lakes Fisheries between the United States of America and Canada signed at Washington, <date date="1954-09-10">September 10, 1954</date>;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> “Commission” means the Great Lakes Fishery Commission provided for by article II of the convention;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> “United States Section” means the United States Commissioners on the Commission;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> “Great Lakes State” means any of the following States: Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, or Wisconsin;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> “Great Lakes” means any of the following bodies of water: Lake Ontario (including the Saint Lawrence River from Lake Ontario to the forty-fifth parallel of latitude), Lake Erie, Lake Huron (including Lake Saint Clair), Lake Michigan, or Lake Superior.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 2</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 932.</num>
<heading> Commissioners; appointment, number, and compensation; term of office; vacancy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The United States shall be represented on the Commission by 4 Commissioners who shall be appointed by the President and who may not receive compensation for service as Commissioners. Of the Commissioners—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 1 shall be an official of the United States Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 3 shall be individuals who reside in different Great Lakes States and who are knowledgeable regarding the fisheries of the Great Lakes, except that 1 of them must also be an official of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002559">1</ref> Great Lakes State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The President shall appoint an alternate Commissioner who shall perform the duties of a Commissioner—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> until a vacancy referred to in subsection (b)(3) is filled; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the event of the absence of a Commissioner from any meeting of the United States Section or the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Individuals serving as such Commissioners shall not be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, except for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term of office of Commissioners appointed under subsection (a)(1)(B) is 6 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Of the Commissioners first appointed under subsection (a)(1)(B) after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, 1 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, 1 shall be appointed for a term of 4 years, and 1 shall be appointed for a term of 6 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whenever a vacancy occurs among Commissioners appointed under subsection (a)(1)(B), the President shall appoint an individual to fill that vacancy for the remainder of the applicable term.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–659, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–562, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2000-12-23">Dec. 23, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 933.</num>
<heading> Advisory Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and number of members; factors in selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States Section shall appoint an advisory committee for each of the Great Lakes, upon which committee each State bordering on the lake may be represented by not more than four members. In making such appointments, the United States Section shall make its selection for each State from a list proposed by the Governor of that State; and shall give due consideration to the interests of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> State agencies having jurisdiction over fisheries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the commercial fishing industry of the lake;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the sports fishing of the lake; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the public at large.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership on other committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of the advisory committee for one lake may also be a member of the advisory committee for one or more other lakes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the advisory committee shall receive no compensation from the Government of the United States for their services as such members. Not more than ten members of all the committees, designated by the committees and approved by the United States Section, may be paid by the Government of the United States for transportation expenses and per diem incident to attendance at the annual meeting of the Commission or of the United States Section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the advisory committee for each lake shall be invited to attend all nonexecutive meetings of the United States Section relating to that lake and at such meetings shall be granted opportunity to examine and be heard on all proposed recommendations, programs, and activities relating to that lake.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 4</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1364</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 934.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 92–471, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-09">Oct. 9, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 787</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 935.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of real property; construction and operation of lamprey control works; entry into agreements for construction and operation of works</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to carry out the obligations of the United States under the Convention, the United States Section is authorized—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> to acquire any real property, or any interest therein, by purchase, exchange, gift, dedication, condemnation, or otherwise;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> to construct, operate, and maintain any project or works designed to facilitate compliance with the provisions of the Convention relating to the sea lamprey control program; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> to enter into contract or agreement with any State or other public agency or private agency or individual for the construction, operation, or maintenance of any such project or works.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 6</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 936.</num>
<heading> Secretary of the Interior; authority to transfer lamprey control projects and act on behalf of United States Section</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, upon the request of the United States Section—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> to transfer to the United States Section any lamprey control project or works under his jurisdiction now existing or now under construction; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> to act for or on behalf of the United States Section in the exercise of the powers granted by this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 7</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 937.</num>
<heading> United States Section as agency of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Section shall, for the purposes of these <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002560">1</ref> provisions of title 28, relating to claims against the United States and tort claims procedure, be deemed to be an agency of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 8</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 938.</num>
<heading> Notice of proposals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At least thirty days before approving a proposal to utilize a lamprey control measure or install a device in any stream, the United States Section shall cause notice of such proposal to be sent to the official agency having jurisdiction over fisheries in each of the States through which the stream flows.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 9</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 939.</num>
<heading> Transmission of recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall upon the receipt from the Commission of any recommendation of a conservation measure made in accordance with article IV of the Convention transmit a copy of the recommendation with his comments thereon to the Governor of each Great Lakes State for consideration and such action as may be found to be appropriate. The Secretary of State shall also inform such other public agencies as he may deem appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 10</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 939a.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agency of the United States Government is authorized to cooperate with the United States Section in the conduct of research programs and related activities and, on a reimbursable or other basis, to enter into agreements with the United States Section for the purpose of assisting it in carrying out the program for the control of lamprey populations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 11</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 939b.</num>
<heading> State laws and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as preventing any of the Great Lakes States from making or enforcing laws or regulations within their respective jurisdictions so far as such laws or regulations do not conflict with the Convention or this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 12</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 939c.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated from time to time such sums as may be necessary for carrying out the purposes and provisions of the Convention and this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 13</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>