<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 4—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION OF TIMBER, AND DEPREDATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 591, 592.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Feb. 28, 1933, ch. 131, § 1</ref>, <ref>47 Stat. 1349</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 593.</num>
<heading> Protection of timber in Florida</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to employ so much of the land and naval forces of the United States as may be necessary effectually to prevent the felling, cutting down, or other destruction of the timber of the United States in Florida, and to prevent the transportation or carrying away any such timber as may be already felled or cut down; and to take such other and further measures as may be deemed advisable for the preservation of the timber of the United States in Florida.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2460.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 594.</num>
<heading> Protection of timber owned by United States from fire, disease, or insect ravages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to protect and preserve, from fire, disease, or the ravages of beetles, or other insects, timber owned by the United States upon the public lands, national parks, national monuments, Indian reservations, or other lands under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior owned by the United States, either directly or in cooperation with other departments of the Federal Government, with States, or with owners of timber; and appropriations are authorized to be made for such purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 20, 1922, ch. 349</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 594–1 to 594–5.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 16(a)(3)</ref>, formerly § 13(a)(3), <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 374</ref>; renumbered § 16(a)(3), <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1215(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 594a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 16(a)(2)</ref>, formerly § 13(a)(2), <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 374</ref>; renumbered § 16(a)(2), <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1215(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 595, 596.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Feb. 28, 1933, ch. 131, § 1</ref>, <ref>47 Stat. 1349</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 597 to 600.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Dec. 16, 1930, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1028</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 601.</num>
<heading> Disposition of moneys collected for depredations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys collected for depredations upon the public lands shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States as other moneys received from the sale of public lands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1878, ch. 76, § 2</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 46</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 602.</num>
<heading> Seizure of timber cut</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any timber cut on the public lands shall be exported from the Territories of the United States, it shall be liable to seizure by United States authority wherever found.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1878, ch. 76, § 2</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 46</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 603.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 604.</num>
<heading> Cutting timber on certain mineral lands; permits to corporations; railroad corporations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All citizens of the United States and other persons, bona fide residents of the States of Colorado, Nevada, New Mexico, Arizona, Utah, Wyoming, North Dakota, South Dakota, Idaho, or Montana, and all other mineral districts of the United States, are authorized and permitted to fell and remove, for building, agricultural, mining, or other domestic purposes, any timber or other trees growing or being on the public lands, said lands being mineral, and not subject to entry under existing laws of the United States, except for mineral entry, in said States or districts of which such citizens or persons may be at the time bona fide residents, subject to such rules and regulations as the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe for the protection of the timber and of the undergrowth growing upon such lands, and for other purposes. It shall be lawful for the Secretary of the Interior to grant permits in accordance with the provisions of this section, to corporations incorporated under a Federal law of the United States or incorporated under the laws of a State or Territory of the United States, other than the State in which the privilege is requested. Such permits to confer the same rights and benefits upon such corporations as are conferred upon corporations incorporated in the State in which the privilege is to be exercised, but all such corporations shall first have complied with the laws of that State so as to entitle them to do business therein. The provisions of this section and sections 605 and 606 of this title shall not extend to railroad corporations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 3, 1878, ch. 150, § 1</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref>Jan. 11, 1921, ch. 22</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1088</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 605.</num>
<heading> Unlawful cutting on mineral lands; notice to Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the duty of such officer as the Secretary of the Interior may designate in whose district any mineral land may be situated to ascertain from time to time whether any timber is being cut or used upon any such lands, except for the purposes authorized by <ref>section 604 of this title</ref>, within such land district; and, if so, he shall immediately notify the Secretary of the Interior of that fact; and all necessary expenses incurred in making such proper examinations shall be paid for and allowed such officer in making up his next quarterly account.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 3, 1878, ch. 150, § 2</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 88</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7876, <ref>60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 606.</num>
<heading> Offense for unlawful cutting on mineral lands; punishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person or persons who shall violate the provisions of sections 604 and 605 of this title, or any rules and regulations in pursuance thereof made by the Secretary of the Interior, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction, shall be fined in any sum not exceeding $500, and to which may be added imprisonment for any term not exceeding six months.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 3, 1878, ch. 150, § 3</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 89</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 607.</num>
<heading> Cutting and removal of timber on certain public lands for certain purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the States of Alaska, Colorado, Montana, Idaho, North Dakota, and South Dakota, Wyoming, New Mexico, and Arizona, and the gold and silver regions of Nevada, California, Oregon, Washington, and Utah in any criminal prosecution or civil action by the United States for a trespass on such public timber lands or to recover timber or lumber cut thereon it shall be a defense if the defendant shall show that the said timber was so cut or removed from the timber lands for use in such State by a resident thereof for agricultural, mining, manufacturing, or domestic purposes under rules and regulations made and prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior and has not been transported out of the same, but nothing herein contained shall operate to enlarge the rights of any railway company to cut timber on the public domain. The Secretary of the Interior may make suitable rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this section, and he may designate the sections or tracts of land where timber may be cut, and it shall not be lawful to cut or remove any timber except as may be prescribed by such rules and regulations, but this section shall not operate to repeal sections 604 to 606 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 559</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 1093</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 8</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Feb. 13, 1893, ch. 103</ref>, <ref>27 Stat. 444</ref>; <ref>July 1, 1898, ch. 546, § 1</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 618</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 855</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 1436</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 862</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1919, ch. 111</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 1321</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1919, ch. 115</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 1322</ref>; <ref>Feb. 27, 1922, ch. 82</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref>Aug. 21, 1935, ch. 591</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 41</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 607a.</num>
<heading> Cutting and use of timber in Alaska by settlers, residents, miners, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may permit under regulations to be prescribed by him the use of timber found upon the public land in Alaska by actual settlers, residents, individual miners, and prospectors for minerals, for firewood, fencing, buildings, mining, prospecting, and for domestic purposes, as may actually be needed by such persons for such purposes and may permit such use by churches, hospitals, and charitable institutions in Alaska for firewood, fencing, buildings, and for domestic purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 14, 1898, ch. 299, § 11</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 414</ref>; <ref>June 15, 1938, ch. 437</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608.</num>
<heading> Permits to cut and remove timber; citizens of Malheur County, Oregon</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be lawful for the Secretary of the Interior to grant permits under the provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref> to citizens of Malheur County, Oregon, to cut timber in the State of Idaho for agricultural, mining, or other domestic purposes, and to remove the timber so cut to Malheur County, State of Oregon.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 8</ref> (part), as added <ref>Mar. 3, 1919, ch. 111</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 1321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 609.</num>
<heading> Permits to cut and remove timber; citizens of Modoc County, California</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be lawful for the Secretary of the Interior to grant permits under the provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref>, to citizens of Modoc County, California, to cut timber in the State of Nevada for agricultural, mining, or other domestic purposes, and to remove the timber so cut to Modoc County, State of California.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 8</ref> (part), as added <ref>Mar. 3, 1919, ch. 115</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 1322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 610.</num>
<heading> Permits to cut and remove timber; citizens of Washington County and Kane County, Utah</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be lawful for the Secretary of the Interior to grant permits under the provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref>, to citizens of Washington County and of Kane County, Utah, to cut timber on the public lands of the counties of Mohave and Coconino, Arizona, for agricultural, mining, or other domestic purposes, and remove the timber so cut to said Washington County and Kane County, Utah.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 8</ref> (part), as added <ref>Feb. 27, 1922, ch. 82</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 611.</num>
<heading> Permits to cut and remove timber; citizens of Idaho and Wyoming</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be lawful for the Secretary of the Interior to grant permits under the provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref>, to citizens of Idaho and Wyoming to cut timber in the State of Wyoming west of the Continental Divide on the Snake River and its tributaries to the boundary line of Idaho, for agricultural, mining, or other domestic purposes, and to remove the timber so cut to the State of Idaho.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 8</ref> (part), as added <ref>July 1, 1898, ch. 546, § 1</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 611a.</num>
<heading> Permits to cut and remove timber; citizens of Bear Lake County, Idaho</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to grant permits, subject to the provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref>, to citizens of Bear Lake County, Idaho, to cut and remove timber on the unappropriated public domain in Lincoln County, Wyoming, for domestic use in Bear Lake County, Idaho: <i>Provided</i>, That no live standing timber shall be taken without compensation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 8</ref> (part), as added <ref>Aug. 21, 1935, ch. 591</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 665</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612.</num>
<heading> Permits to cut and remove timber to certain corporations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be lawful for the Secretary of the Interior to grant permits in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref>, to corporations incorporated under a Federal law of the United States or incorporated under the laws of a State or Territory of the United States, other than the State in which the privilege is requested, said permits to confer the same rights and benefits upon such corporations as are conferred upon corporations incorporated in the State in which the privilege is to be exercised: <i>Provided</i>, That all such corporations shall first have complied with the laws of that State so as to entitle them to do business therein; but nothing herein shall operate to enlarge the rights of any railway company to cut timber on the public domain.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Jan. 11, 1921, ch. 22</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1088</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 613.</num>
<heading> Limitations of use of timber taken not to apply to certain territory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 607 of this title</ref>, limiting the use of timber taken from public lands to residents of the State in which such timber is found, for use within said State, shall not apply to the south slope of Pryor Mountains, in the State of Montana, lying south of the Crow Reservation, west of the Big Horn River, and east of Sage Creek; but within the above-described boundaries the provisions of said section shall apply equally to the residents of the States of Wyoming and Montana, and to the use of timber taken from the above-described tract in either of the above-named States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 862</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 1439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 614, 615.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–689, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-09-25">Sept. 25, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 588</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 615a.</num>
<heading> Sale of timber in Alaska; appraisal; local consumption; accounting; deposit in Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, under such rules and regulations as he may prescribe, may cause to be appraised the timber or any part thereof upon public lands in Alaska, and may from time to time sell so much thereof as he may deem proper for not less than the appraised value thereof, in such quantities to each purchaser as he shall prescribe, to be used in Alaska except as aforesaid, but not for export therefrom except as provided under <ref>section 615b of this title</ref>. And such sales shall at all times be limited to actual necessities for consumption in Alaska from year to year, and payments for such timber shall be made to such officer as the Secretary of the Interior may designate of the local land office of the land district in which said timber may be sold, under such rules and regulations as the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe, and the moneys arising therefrom shall be accounted for by such officer as the Secretary of the Interior may designate to the Secretary of the Interior in a separate account, and shall be covered into the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 14, 1898, ch. 299, § 11</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 414</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1921, ch. 114, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 462</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1144</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan. No. 3, § 403, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7876, <ref>60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 615b.</num>
<heading> Exportation of timber pulp wood and wood pulp from Alaska</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Birch timber and pulp wood or wood pulp manufactured from timber in Alaska may be exported therefrom.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 1, 1905, ch. 288, § 2</ref>, <ref>33 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>June 5, 1920, ch. 235, § 1</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 616.</num>
<heading> Exportation of timber cut on national forest or public land in Alaska</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Timber lawfully cut on any national forest, or on the public lands in Alaska, may be exported from the State or Territory where grown if, in the judgment of the Secretary of the department administering the national forests, or the public lands in Alaska, the supply of timber for local use will not be endangered thereby, and the respective Secretaries concerned are authorized to issue rules and regulations to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<date date="1926-04-12">Apr. 12, 1926</date>, § 1, ch. 117, <ref>44 Stat. 242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 617.</num>
<heading> Exportation of unprocessed timber from Federal lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation of quantity available for export</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each of the calendar years 1969 through 1973, inclusive, not more than 350 million board feet, in the aggregate, of unprocessed timber may be sold for export from the United States from Federal lands located west of the 100th meridian.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surplus quantities and species available for export; public hearing; administrative finding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After public hearing and a finding by the appropriate Secretary of the department administering Federal lands referred to in subsection (a) that specific quantities and species of unprocessed timber are surplus to the needs of domestic users and processors, such quantities and species may be designated by the said Secretary as available for export from the United States in addition to that quantity stated in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations; prevention of substitution of Federal for non-Federal timber</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretaries of the departments administering lands referred to in subsection (a) may issue rules and regulations to carry out the purposes of this section, including the prevention of substitution of timber restricted from export by this section for exported non-Federal timber.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations inapplicable to sales of prescribed minimum value</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In issuing rules and regulations pursuant to subsection (c), the appropriate Secretaries may include therein provisions authorizing the said Secretaries, in their discretion, to exclude from the limitations imposed by this section sales having an appraised value of less than $2,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 12, 1926, ch. 117, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 90–554</ref>, pt. IV, § 401, <date date="1968-10-08">Oct. 8, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 966</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title IX, § 921</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1817</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 618.</num>
<heading> Timber contract payment modification</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of purpose, authorization, scope, qualifications, financial requirements, etc., for buy-out</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, in order to retain jobs, to preserve free competition, to utilize the potential productive capacity of plants, to preserve small communities dependent on a single economic sector to assure an open and competitive market for future sales of Government timber, and to lessen the impact of unemployment, the Secretary of Agriculture for national forest lands and the Secretary of the Interior for public lands under their respective jurisdictions are authorized and directed to permit a requesting purchaser to return to the Government a volume of the purchaser’s timber contracts as determined under paragraph (2) upon payment of a buy-out charge from such purchaser in an amount as determined under paragraph (3). The purchaser shall be released from further obligation to cut, remove, and pay for timber under such contract upon payment, or arrangement for payment as provided under paragraph (3)(E), of such buy-out charge and completion of any obligation required pursuant to paragraph (4)(B). The Government does not hereby surrender any other claim against a purchaser which arose under a contract prior to effectuation of this release and not in connection with this release from obligation to cut, harvest and pay for timber.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To qualify for buy-out under this section, a timber sales contract must have been bid prior to <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, for an original contract period of 10 years or less, and be held as of <date date="1984-06-01">June 1, 1984</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That any such contract that was defaulted after <date date="1981-01-01">January 1, 1981</date> may qualify for buy-out under this section so long as (i) settlement for damages has not been reached between the purchaser and the United States; and (ii) the purchaser’s loss on all of its qualifying timber sales contracts, as determined in paragraph (3)(A), is in excess of 50 per centum of the net book worth of the purchaser. A contract is qualified for buy-out notwithstanding the fact that it was reformed after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, pursuant to Bureau of Land Management Instructional Memorandum 83–743 or is included in a Forest Service multisale plan pursuant to the President’s program of <date date="1983-07-28">July 28, 1983</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A purchaser holding more than twenty-seven million three hundred thousand board feet of net merchantable sawtimber as of <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, in qualifying contracts as provided in subparagraph (A) shall be entitled to buy out up to 55 per centum of such timber volume up to a maximum of two hundred million board feet.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A purchaser holding twenty-seven million three hundred thousand or less board feet of net merchantable sawtimber as of <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, in qualifying contracts as provided in subparagraph (A) shall be entitled to buy out up to fifteen million board feet of such timber volume or one contract, whichever is greater in volume.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> So long as the volume limitation of two hundred million board feet is not exceeded, the percentage limitation of subparagraph (B) or the volume limitation of subparagraph (C) may be exceeded by a volume amount not to exceed the volume of the smallest volume contract bought out by the purchaser if the purchaser could not otherwise attain his percentage or volume entitlement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Timber returned to the Government pursuant to this subsection shall be available for resale by the Government upon payment, or arrangement for payment, of the buy-out charge and completion of obligations, if any, under paragraph (4)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Sums collected by the appropriate Secretary in connection with the buy-out of contracts pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited in and paid from the Treasury in the same manner as moneys received from timber sales from such lands and shall be determined as follows: The purchaser’s loss on any qualifying timber sales contracts shall be determined by the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management by subtracting the current delivered log value (as determined by such agency) from the delivered log cost based on the current contract return (as determined by such agency) of any such contracts. If such loss is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in excess of 100 per centum of the net book worth of the purchaser, the buy-out cost shall be $10 per one thousand board feet of currently held volume bought out;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in excess of 50 per centum up to 100 per centum of the net book worth of the purchaser, the buy-out cost shall be 10 per centum of the contract overbid but at least $10 per one thousand board feet of currently held volume bought out; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> up to 50 per centum or less of the net book worth of the purchaser, the buy-out cost shall be 15 per centum for the purchaser’s first one hundred twenty-five million board feet, 20 per centum for additional board feet above one hundred twenty-five million up to one hundred fifty million, 25 per centum for additional board feet above one hundred fifty million up to one hundred seventy-five million, and 30 per centum for additional board feet above one hundred seventy-five million up to two hundred million, of the contract overbid but at least $10 per one thousand board feet of currently held volume bought out.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “net book worth” does not include the value of any outstanding uncut Federal timber sales contracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Net book worth shall be, subject to agency verification, as determined by an independent certified public accountant in accordance with generally accepted accounting standards for the timber industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A purchaser may elect to pay the buy-out cost imposed by subparagraph (A)(iii) in lieu of utilizing loss and net book worth determinations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Where a purchaser is not able to obtain sufficient credit elsewhere to finance the buy-out charge at reasonable rates and terms, purchaser may, upon payment of 5 per centum of the buy-out charge, pay the remainder of the buy-out charge in equal quarterly payments over a period not to exceed 5 years at an interest rate adjusted with each payment equal to the average market yield of outstanding Treasury obligations with remaining years to maturity of five years payment must be secured by bond, deposited securities or other forms of security acceptable to the appropriate Secretary in an amount sufficient to cover the entire buy-out payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “contract overbid” is the difference between the advertised contract rate and the rate the purchaser bid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Contracts returned pursuant to this subsection under which no harvest has begun shall be returned in full.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Contracts returned to the appropriate Secretary pursuant to this subsection under which harvest has begun, shall be returned conditionally and shall not be considered as part of the outstanding volume of timber under contract for the purposes of this Act. The return shall become final after the purchaser has completed stages of contractual obligations for the units on which the harvest has begun, including work on roads, to logical stopping points as determined by the Secretary after consultation with the purchaser. All remaining unharvested units must be returned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The appropriate Secretary may reject return of a contract on which harvest has begun if he determines, in his discretion, that the remaining unharvested portion is substantially unrepresentative of the original sale as a whole in terms of species, logging methods, or other appropriate criteria, and that accepting the return of such contract would seriously disadvantage the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Timber from returned or defaulted contracts shall be offered for resale in an orderly fashion as part of, and not in addition to, the normal congressionally authorized timber sales program, and in a manner which does not disrupt regional markets or artificially depress domestic timber prices. Timber from returned or defaulted contracts shall be given preference for resale in the Forest Service timber sales programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Timber sales in Forest Service region 6 shall not exceed four billion three hundred million board feet of net merchantable sawtimber in fiscal year 1984.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Beginning in fiscal year 1985 and continuing through fiscal year 1991 or the fiscal year in which timber contract extensions in region 6 granted under the President’s program of <date date="1983-07-28">July 28, 1983</date> (as constituted on <date date="1984-10-16">October 16, 1984</date>), are completed, whichever is later, the Secretary of Agriculture shall set, and periodically adjust as necessary, the maximum annual timber sale volume in region 6. Such maximum sale volume shall be set so as to achieve a volume of region 6 net merchantable sawtimber under contract at the end of each fiscal year which does not exceed twelve billion three hundred million board feet: <i>Provided, however</i>, That such maximum annual sale volume shall not exceed five billion two hundred million board feet of net merchantable sawtimber. The sale of timber within region 6 shall be made in such a manner as not to result in discriminatory treatment as between different forests in the region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall publish final rules for the implementation of this subsection in the Federal Register within ninety days after <date date="1984-10-16">October 16, 1984</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such final rules shall require purchasers to submit buy-out requests to the appropriate Secretary within ninety days after the publication of such rules.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For purposes only of determining a purchaser’s buy-out limitation under paragraph (2) and net worth in connection with buy-out cost under paragraph (3), concerns which are affiliates as defined under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall be treated as a single entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Definition of affiliates: Concerns are affiliates of each other when either directly or indirectly, one concern controls or has the power to control the other, or a third party or parties controls or has the power to control both. In determining whether or not affiliation exists, consideration shall be given to all appropriate factors, including, but not limited to, common ownership, common management, and contractual relationships.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Definition of purchaser: For the purposes of this Act, a purchaser is the holder of a contract to purchase timber from the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of time for performance of contracts; covered contracts; damages for default</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Timber contracts bid prior to <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, not bought out pursuant to subsection (a) and included in the President’s program of <date date="1983-07-28">July 28, 1983</date>, shall not be subject to any further extension of time for performance except as permitted under the President’s program of <date date="1983-07-28">July 28, 1983</date>, as implemented by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, providing for the extension of certain timber sale contracts and requiring the phased harvesting of such extended contracts, which program is hereby ratified except as modified by paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, timber contracts extended pursuant to the President’s program of <date date="1983-07-28">July 28, 1983</date>, as implemented by the Secretary of Agriculture shall not be subject to inclusion of additional provisions for calculating damages for default.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring of bidding patterns on timber sale contracts; discouragement of bids; reporting requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall monitor bidding patterns on timber sale contracts and take action to discourage bidding at such a rate as would indicate that the bidder, if awarded the contract, would be unable to perform the obligations as required, or that the bid is otherwise for the purpose of speculation. Each Secretary shall include in the annual report to Congress information concerning actions taken under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cash down-payment and periodic payments for contracts; effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1985-01-01">January 1, 1985</date>, in any contract for the sale of timber from the National Forests, the Secretary of Agriculture shall require a cash down-payment at the time the contract is executed and periodic payments to be made over the remaining period of the contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–478, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-10-16">Oct. 16, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 619.</num>
<heading> Emergency stumpage rate redeterminations in Alaska</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application; applicable period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Emergency stumpage rate redetermination shall be made upon the written application of the purchaser of National Forest timber in Alaska, bid after <date date="1974-01-01">January 1, 1974</date>, and rates established as a result thereof shall be effective for timber scaled during a period between <date date="1981-01-01">January 1, 1981</date>, and five years from <date date="1984-10-16">October 16, 1984</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive effect of modification of contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making the emergency rate redeterminations the Secretary may modify existing contract terms, including the amount of the bid premium, in order to provide rates which will permit the holders of contracts bid after <date date="1974-01-01">January 1, 1974</date>, to be competitive with other purchasers of National Forest timber.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excepted contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not apply to contracts held by the holders of 50-year timber sale contracts in Alaska.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–478, § 4</ref>, <date date="1984-10-16">Oct. 16, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Timber is essential to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Forests, forest resources, and the forest environment are exhaustible natural resources that require efficient and effective conservation efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the interest of conserving those resources, the United States has set aside millions of acres of otherwise harvestable timberlands in the western United States, representing well over 100,000,000,000 board feet of otherwise harvestable timber.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In recent years, administrative, statutory, or judicial action has been taken to set aside an increased amount of otherwise harvestable timberlands for conservation purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the next few months and years, additional amounts of otherwise harvestable timberlands may be set aside for conservation purposes, pursuant to the Endangered Species Act of 1973 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.], the National Forest Management Act of 1976, or other expected statutory, administrative, and judicial actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> There is evidence of a shortfall in the supply of unprocessed timber in the western United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> There is reason to believe that any shortfall which may already exist may worsen unless action is taken.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In conjunction with the broad conservation actions expected in the next few months and years, conservation action is necessary with respect to exports of unprocessed timber.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of sections 620 to 620j of this title are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to promote the conservation of forest resources in conjunction with State and Federal resources management plans, and other actions or decisions, affecting the use of forest resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to take action essential for the acquisition and distribution of forest resources or products in short supply in the western United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to take action necessary, to meet the goals of Article XI 2.(a) of the GATT 1994 (as defined in <ref>section 3501(1)(B) of title 19</ref>), to ensure sufficient supplies of certain forest resources or products which are essential to the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to continue and refine the existing Federal policy of restricting the export of unprocessed timber harvested from Federal lands in the western United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to effect measures aimed at meeting these objectives in conformity with the obligations of the United States under the WTO Agreement and the multilateral trade agreements (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (9) and (4), respectively, of <ref>section 3501 of title 19</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 488</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620a.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on exports of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on export of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person who acquires unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States may export such timber from the United States, or sell, trade, exchange, or otherwise convey such timber to any other person for the purpose of exporting such timber from the United States, unless such timber has been determined under subsection (b) to be surplus to the needs of timber manufacturing facilities in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surpluses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations by Secretary concerned</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The prohibition contained in subsection (a) shall not apply to specific quantities of grades and species of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands which the Secretary concerned determines to be surplus to domestic manufacturing needs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any determination under paragraph (1) shall be made in regulations issued in accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>. Any such determination shall be reviewed at least once in every 3-year period. The Secretary concerned shall publish notice of such review in the Federal Register, and shall give the public an opportunity to comment on such review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 489</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620b.</num>
<heading> Limitations on substitution of unprocessed Federal timber for unprocessed timber exported from private lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct substitution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (3) and subsection (c), no person may purchase directly from any department or agency of the United States unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such unprocessed timber is to be used in substitution for exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such person has, during the preceding 24-month period, exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Federal timber purchased pursuant to a contract entered into between the purchaser and the Secretary concerned before the date on which regulations to carry out this subsection are issued under <ref>section 620f of this title</ref> shall be governed by the regulations of the Secretary concerned in effect before such date that restrict the substitution of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands for exported timber originating from private lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the 1-year period beginning on <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, any person who operates under a Cooperative Sustained Yield Unit Agreement, and who has an historic export quota shall be limited to entering into contracts under such a quota to a volume equal to not more than 66 percent of the person’s historic export quota used during fiscal year 1989;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a person referred to in subparagraph (B) shall reduce the person’s remaining substitution volume by an equal amount each year thereafter such that no volume is substituted under such a quota in fiscal year 1995 or thereafter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the 24-month period referred to in paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply to any person who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> before <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, has, under an historic export quota approved by the Secretary concerned, purchased unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States in substitution for exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> certifies to the Secretary concerned, within 3 months after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, that the person will, within 6 months after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, cease exporting unprocessed timber originating from private lands; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> ceases exports in accordance with such certification.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of the purchase by a person of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands west of the 119th meridian in the State of Washington, paragraph (1) shall apply only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the private lands referred to in paragraph (1) are owned by the person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the person has the exclusive right to harvest timber from the private lands described in paragraph (1) during a period of more than 7 years, and may exercise that right at any time of the person’s choosing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indirect substitution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no person may, beginning 21 days after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, purchase from any other person unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States if such person would be prohibited from purchasing such timber directly from a department or agency of the United States. Acquisitions of western red cedar which are domestically processed into finished products to be sold into domestic or international markets are exempt from the prohibition contained in this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Agriculture shall, as soon as practicable but not later than 9 months after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, establish, by rule, a limited amount of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands described in subparagraph (B) which may be purchased by a person otherwise covered by the prohibition contained in paragraph (1). Such limit shall equal—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of such timber acquired by such person, based on the higher of the applicant’s actual timber purchasing receipts or the appropriate Federal agency’s records, during fiscal years 1988, 1989, and 1990, divided by 3, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 15 million board feet,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">whichever is less, except that such limit shall not exceed such person’s proportionate share, with respect to all persons covered under this paragraph, of 50 million board feet.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Federal lands referred to in subparagraph (A) are Federal lands administered by the United States Forest Service Region 6 that are located north of the Columbia River from its mouth and east to its first intersection with the 119th meridian, and from that point north of the 46th parallel and east.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any person may sell, trade, or otherwise exchange with any other person the rights obtained under subparagraph (A), except that such rights may not be sold, traded, or otherwise exchanged to persons already in possession of such rights obtained under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Federal timber purchased from Federal lands described in subparagraph (B) pursuant to a contract entered into between the purchaser and the Secretary of Agriculture before the date on which regulations to carry out this subsection are issued under <ref>section 620f of this title</ref> shall be governed by the regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture in effect before such date that restrict the substitution of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands for exported timber originating from private lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sourcing areas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The prohibitions contained in subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply with respect to the acquisition of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands within a sourcing area west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States approved by the Secretary concerned under this subsection by a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the previous 24 months, has not exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands within the sourcing area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during the period in which such approval is in effect, does not export unprocessed timber originating from private lands within the sourcing area.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Secretary concerned may waive the 24-month requirement set forth in subparagraph (A) for any person who, within 3 months after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, certifies that, within 6 months after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, such person will, for a period of not less than 3 years, cease exporting unprocessed timber originating from private lands within the sourcing area.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for application for sourcing areas for processing facilities located outside the northwestern private timber open market area</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretaries concerned shall, not later than 3 months after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, prescribe procedures to be used by a person applying for approval of a sourcing area under paragraph (1). Such procedures shall require, at a minimum, the applicant to provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information regarding the location of private lands (except private land located in the northwestern private timber open market area) from which such person has, within the previous year, harvested or otherwise acquired unprocessed timber which has been exported from the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information regarding the location of each timber manufacturing facility owned or operated by such person within the proposed sourcing area boundaries at which the applicant proposes to process timber originating from Federal lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The prohibition contained in subsection (a) shall not apply to a person before the date which is 1 month after the procedures referred to in this paragraph are prescribed. With respect to any person who submits an application in accordance with such procedures by the end of the time period set forth in the preceding sentence, the prohibition contained in subsection (a) shall not apply to such person before the date on which the Secretary concerned approves or disapproves such application.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant of approval for sourcing areas for processing facilities located outside of the northwestern private timber open market area</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For each applicant, the Secretary concerned shall, on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing, not later than 4 months after receipt of the application for a sourcing area, either approve or disapprove the application. The Secretary concerned may approve such application only if the Secretary determines that the area that is the subject of the application, in which the timber manufacturing facilities at which the applicant desires to process timber originating from Federal lands are located, is geographically and economically separate from any geographic area from which that person harvests for export any unprocessed timber originating from private lands.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For timber manufacturing facilities located in Idaho</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (D), in making a determination referred to in subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall consider the private timber export and the private and Federal timber sourcing patterns for the applicant’s timber manufacturing facilities, as well as the private and Federal timber sourcing patterns for the timber manufacturing facilities of other persons in the same local vicinity of the applicant, and the relative similarity of such private and Federal timber sourcing patterns.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For timber manufacturing facilities located in States other than Idaho</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (D), in making the determination referred to in subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall consider the private timber export and the Federal timber sourcing patterns for the applicant’s timber manufacturing facilities, as well as the Federal timber sourcing patterns for the timber manufacturing facilities of other persons in the same local vicinity of the applicant, and the relative similarity of such Federal timber sourcing patterns. Private timber sourcing patterns shall not be a factor in such determinations in States other than Idaho.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Area not included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In deciding whether to approve or disapprove an application, the Secretary shall not—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consider land located in the northwestern private timber open market area; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> condition approval of the application on the inclusion of any such land in the applicant’s sourcing area, such land being includable in the sourcing area only to the extent requested by the applicant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of application for sourcing areas for processing facilities located outside the northwestern private timber open market area</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the 9-month period after receiving disapproval of an application submitted pursuant to this subsection, the applicant may purchase unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands in the area which is the subject of the application in an amount not to exceed 75 percent of the annual average of such person’s purchases of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands in the same area during the 5 full fiscal years immediately prior to submission of the application. In the subsequent 6-month period, such person may purchase not more than 25 percent of such annual average, after which time the prohibitions contained in subsection (a) shall fully apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a person referred to in subparagraph (A) certifies to the Secretary concerned, within 90 days after receiving disapproval of such application, that such person shall, within 15 months after such disapproval, cease the export of unprocessed timber originating from private lands from the geographic area determined by the Secretary for which the application would have been approved, such person may continue to purchase unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands in the area which is the subject of the application, without being subject to the restrictions of subparagraph (A), except that such purchases during that 15-month period may not exceed 125 percent of the annual average of such person’s purchases of unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands in the same area during the 5 full fiscal years immediately prior to submission of the application which was denied.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any person to whom subparagraph (B) applies may not, during the 15-month period after the person’s application for sourcing area boundaries is denied, export unprocessed timber originating from private lands in the geographic area determined by the Secretary concerned for which the application would have been approved in amounts that exceed 125 percent of the annual average of such person’s exports of unprocessed timber from such private lands during the 5 full fiscal years immediately prior to submission of the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of determinations for sourcing areas for processing facilities located outside the northwestern private timber open market area</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Determinations made under paragraph (3) shall be reviewed, in accordance with the procedures prescribed in sections 620 to 620j of this title, not less often than every 5 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sourcing areas for processing facilities located in the northwestern private timber open market area</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the northwestern private timber open market area—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a sourcing area boundary shall be a circle around the processing facility of the sourcing area applicant or holder;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the radius of the circle—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall be the furthest distance that the sourcing area applicant or holder proposes to haul Federal timber for processing at the processing facility; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall be determined solely by the sourcing area applicant or holder;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a sourcing area shall become effective on written notice to the Regional Forester for Region 6 of the Forest Service of the location of the boundary of the sourcing area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the 24-month requirement in paragraph (1)(A) shall not apply;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> a sourcing area holder—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> may adjust the radius of the sourcing area not more frequently than once every 24 months; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall provide written notice to the Regional Forester for Region 6 of the adjusted boundary of its sourcing area before using the adjusted sourcing area; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a sourcing area holder that relinquishes a sourcing area may not reestablish a sourcing area for that processing facility before the date that is 24 months after the date on which the sourcing area was relinquished.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">With respect to a portion of a sourcing area established before <date date="1997-11-14">November 14, 1997</date>, that contains Federal timber under contract before <date date="1997-11-14">November 14, 1997</date>, and is outside the boundary of a new sourcing area established under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that portion shall continue to be a sourcing area only until unprocessed Federal timber from the portion is no longer in the possession of the sourcing area holder; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> unprocessed timber from private land in that portion shall be exportable immediately after unprocessed timber from Federal land in the portion is no longer in the possession of the sourcing area holder.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relinquishment and termination of sourcing areas</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A sourcing area may be relinquished at any time.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A relinquishment of a sourcing area shall be effective as of the date on which written notice is provided by the sourcing area holder to the Regional Forester with jurisdiction over the sourcing area where the processing facility of the holder is located.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exportability</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">On relinquishment or termination of a sourcing area, unprocessed timber from private land within the former boundary of the relinquished or terminated sourcing area is exportable immediately after unprocessed timber from Federal land from within that area is no longer in the possession of the former sourcing area holder.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No restriction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The exportability of unprocessed timber from private land located outside of a sourcing area shall not be restricted or in any way affected by relinquishment or termination of a sourcing area.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic transportation and processing of private timber</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section restricts or authorizes any restriction on the domestic transportation or processing of timber harvested from private land, except that the Secretary may prohibit processing facilities located in the State of Idaho that have sourcing areas from processing timber harvested from private land outside of the boundaries of those sourcing areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 490</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620c.</num>
<heading> Restriction on exports of unprocessed timber from State and other public lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Order to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (g), the Secretary of Commerce shall issue orders to prohibit the export from the United States of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, as provided in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule for determination to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> States with annual sales of 400,000,000 board feet or less</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to States with annual sales volumes of 400,000,000 board feet or less, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the export of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, effective <date date="1993-06-01">June 1, 1993</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> States with annual sales of greater than 400,000,000 board feet</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any State with an annual sales volume greater than 400,000,000 board feet, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the export of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, effective as of <date date="1997-11-14">November 14, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on substitution</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), each order of the Secretary of Commerce under paragraph (1) or (2) shall also prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person from purchasing, directly or indirectly, unprocessed timber originating from public lands in a State if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such unprocessed timber would be used in substitution for exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands in that State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such person has, during the preceding 24-month period, exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands in that State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The prohibitions referred to in subparagraph (A) shall not apply in a State on or after the date on which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Governor of that State provides the Secretary of Commerce with notification of a prior program under subparagraph (C) of subsection (d)(2),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce approves a program of that State under subparagraph (A) of subsection (d)(2), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> regulations of the Secretary of Commerce issued under subsection (c) to carry out this section take effect,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">whichever occurs first.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1995-06-01">June 1, 1995</date>, the Secretary of Commerce, in conjunction with the Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior, shall issue a report to the Congress on the effects of the reallocation, as a result of the enactment of sections 620 to 620j of this title, of public lands timber resources to the domestic timber processing sector, the ability of the domestic timber processing sector to meet domestic demand for forest products, the volume of transshipment of timber originating from public lands across State borders, the effectiveness of rules issued and administered by the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to sections 620 to 620j of this title and the effectiveness of State programs authorized under subsection (d), and trends in growth and productivity in the domestic timber processing sector.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration by the Secretary of Commerce</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary of Commerce shall, as soon as possible after <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determine the species, grades, and geographic origin of unprocessed timber to be prohibited from export in each State that is subject to an order issued under subsection (a);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> administer the prohibitions consistent with sections 620 to 620j of this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> ensure that the species, grades, and geographic origin of unprocessed timber prohibited from export within each State is representative of the species, grades, and geographic origin of timber comprising the total timber sales program of the State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The actions and regulations of the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a State that is administering and enforcing a program under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to enter into agreements with Federal and State agencies with appropriate jurisdiction to assist the Secretary in carrying out sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized State programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of new State programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (c), the Governor of any State may submit a program to the Secretary of Commerce for approval that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> implements, with respect to unprocessed timber originating from public lands in that State, the prohibition on exports set forth in the Secretary’s order under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensures that the species, grades, and geographic origin of unprocessed timber prohibited from export within the State is representative of the species, grades, and geographic origin of timber comprising the total timber sales program of the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of State programs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after the submission of a program under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Commerce shall approve the program unless the Secretary finds that the program will result in the export of unprocessed timber from public lands in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title and publishes that finding in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State program in lieu of Federal program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Secretary of Commerce approves a program submitted under paragraph (1), the Governor of the State for which the program was submitted, or such other official of that State as the Governor may designate, may administer and enforce the program, which shall apply in that State in lieu of the regulations issued under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior State programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>, the Governor of any State that had, before <date date="1993-05-04">May 4, 1993</date>, issued regulations under this subsection as in effect before <date date="1993-05-04">May 4, 1993</date>, may provide the Secretary of Commerce with written notification that the State has a program that was in effect on <date date="1993-05-03">May 3, 1993</date>, and that meets the requirements of paragraph (1). Upon such notification, that State may administer and enforce that program in that State until the end of the 9-month period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Commerce issues regulations under subsection (c), and that program shall, during the period in which it is so administered and enforced, apply in that State in lieu of the regulations issued under subsection (c). Such Governor may submit, with such notification, the program for approval by the Secretary under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> any contract for the purchase of unprocessed timber originating from public lands that was entered into before—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="1990-09-10">September 10, 1990</date>, with respect to States with annual sales volumes of 400,000,000 board feet or less; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, with respect to States with annual sales volumes greater than 400,000,000 board feet; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any contract under which exports of unprocessed timber were permitted pursuant to an order of the Secretary of Commerce in effect under this section before <date date="1992-10-23">October 23, 1992</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Western red cedar</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede section 4606(i) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002463">1</ref> of title 50.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized, after suitable notice and a public comment period of not less than 120 days, to suspend the provisions of this section if a panel of experts has reported to the Dispute Settlement Body of the World Trade Organization (as the term “World Trade Organization” is defined in <ref>section 3501(8) of title 19</ref>), or a ruling issued under the formal dispute settlement proceeding provided under any other trade agreement finds, that the provisions of this section are in violation of, or inconsistent with, United States obligations under that trade agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal or modifications of State restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Based upon a determination that it is in the national economic interest, the President may remove or modify any prohibition on exports from public lands in a State if that State petitions the President to remove or modify such prohibition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of prior Federal law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of Federal law which imposes requirements with respect to the generation of revenue from State timberlands and was enacted before <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, shall be construed to invalidate, supersede, or otherwise affect any action of a State or political subdivision of a State pursuant to sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surplus timber</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The prohibitions on exports contained in orders of the Secretary of Commerce issued under subsection (a) shall not apply to specific quantities of grades and species of unprocessed timber originating from public lands which the Secretary concerned determines by rule to be surplus to the needs of timber manufacturing facilities in the United States. Any such determination may, by rule, be withdrawn by the Secretary concerned if the Secretary determines that the affected timber is no longer surplus to the needs of timber manufacturing facilities in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of prohibitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, beginning on <date date="1998-01-01">January 1, 1998</date>, and annually thereafter, if the President finds, upon review of the purposes and implementation of sections 620 to 620j of this title, that the prohibitions on exports required by subsection (a) no longer promote the purposes of sections 620 to 620j of this title, then the President may suspend such prohibitions, except that such suspension shall not take effect until 90 days after the President notifies the Congress of such finding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing authority not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in sections 620 to 620j of this title shall be construed to limit the authority of the President or the United States Trade Representative to take action authorized by law to respond appropriately to any measures taken by a foreign government in connection with sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 491</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–45, § 2</ref>, <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title VI, § 602(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1002(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 133</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620d.</num>
<heading> Monitoring and enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with regulations issued under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each person who acquires, either directly or indirectly, unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States shall report the receipt and disposition of such timber to the Secretary concerned, in such form as such Secretary may by rule prescribe; except that nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to hold any person responsible for the reporting of the disposition of any such timber held by subsequent persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> each person who transfers to another person unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States shall, before completing such transfer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide to such other person a written notice, in such form as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, which shall identify the Federal origin of such timber;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> receive from such other person a written acknowledgment of such notice and a written agreement that such other person will comply with the requirements of sections 620 to 620j of this title, in such form as the Secretary concerned may prescribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary concerned copies of all notices, acknowledgments, and agreements referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> each person who acquires, either directly or indirectly, unprocessed timber originating from public lands in a State that is subject to an order issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref>section 620c(a) of this title</ref>, other than a State that is administering and enforcing a program under <ref>section 620c(d) of this title</ref>, shall report the receipt and disposition of the timber to the Secretary of Commerce, in such form as the Secretary may by rule prescribe, except that nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to hold any person responsible for reporting the disposition of any timber held by subsequent persons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> each person who transfers to another person unprocessed timber originating from public lands in a State that is subject to an order issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref>section 620c(a) of this title</ref>, other than a State that is administering and enforcing a program under <ref>section 620c(d) of this title</ref>, shall, before completing the transfer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide to such other person a written notice, in such form as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe, that shall identify the public lands from which the timber originated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> receive from such other person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a written acknowledgment of the notice, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a written agreement that the recipient of the timber will comply with the requirements of sections 620 to 620j of this title,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">in such form as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary of Commerce copies of all notices, acknowledgments, and agreements referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Using the information gathered under subsection (a), the Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior shall, not later than <date date="1995-06-01">June 1, 1995</date>, submit to the Congress a report on the disposition of unprocessed timber harvested from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States, and recommendations concerning the practice of indirect substitution of such timber for exported timber harvested from private lands. Specifically, such report shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> analyze the effects of indirect substitution on market efficiency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> analyze the effects of indirect substitution on domestic log supply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> offer any recommendations that the Secretaries consider necessary for specific statutory or regulatory changes regarding indirect substitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide summaries of the data collected;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> analyze the effects of the provisions of <ref>section 620b(b)(2)(C) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide such other information as the Secretaries consider appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties for violation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exports</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Secretary concerned finds, on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing, that a person, with willful disregard for the prohibition contained in sections 620 to 620j of this title against exporting Federal timber, exported or caused to be exported unprocessed timber originating from Federal lands in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title, such Secretary may assess against such person a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 for each violation, or 3 times the gross value of the unprocessed timber involved in the violation, whichever amount is greater.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to clause (ii), if the Secretary of Commerce finds, on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing, that a person, with willful disregard for the restrictions contained in an order of the Secretary under <ref>section 620c(a) of this title</ref> on exports of unprocessed timber from public lands, exported or caused to be exported unprocessed timber originating from public lands in violation of such order, the Secretary may assess against such person a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 for each violation, or 3 times the gross value of the unprocessed timber involved in the violation, whichever amount is greater.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Clause (i) shall not apply with respect to exports of unprocessed timber originating from public lands in a State that is administering and enforcing a program under <ref>section 620c(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other violations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary concerned finds, on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing, that a person has violated any provision of sections 620 to 620j of this title or any regulation issued under sections 620 to 620j of this title relating to lands which they administer (notwithstanding that such violation may not have caused the export of unprocessed Federal timber in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title), such Secretary may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assess against such person a civil penalty of not more than $75,000 for each violation if the Secretary determines that the person committed such violation in disregard of such provision or regulation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assess against such person a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each violation if the Secretary determines that the person should have known that the action constituted a violation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> assess against such person a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 if the Secretary determines that the person committed such violation willfully.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to clause (ii), if the Secretary of Commerce finds, on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing, that a person has violated, on or after <date date="1993-06-01">June 1, 1993</date>, any provision of sections 620 to 620j of this title or any regulation issued under sections 620 to 620j of this title relating to the export of unprocessed timber originating from public lands (whether or not the violation caused the export of unprocessed timber from public lands in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title), the Secretary may assess against such person a civil penalty to the same extent as the Secretary concerned may impose a penalty under clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Clause (i) shall not apply with respect to unprocessed timber originating from public lands in a State that is administering and enforcing a program under <ref>section 620c(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Mitigation of penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary concerned—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in determining the applicability of any penalty imposed under this paragraph, shall take into account all relevant mitigating factors, including mistake, inadvertence, and error; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> based on any mitigating factor, may, with respect to any penalty imposed under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> reduce the penalty;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> not impose the penalty; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> on condition of there being no further violation under this paragraph for a prescribed period, suspend imposition of the penalty.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contractural</inline> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002464">1</ref> <inline class="small-caps">remedies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a minor violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title (including a regulation), the Secretary concerned shall, to the maximum extent practicable, permit a contracting officer to redress the violation in accordance with the applicable timber sale contract rather than assess a penalty under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties not exclusive; judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A penalty assessed under this subsection shall not be exclusive of any other penalty provided by law and shall be subject to review in an appropriate United States district court.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative remedies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Debarment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the head of the appropriate Federal department or agency under sections 620 to 620j of this title may debar any person who violates sections 620 to 620j of this title, or any regulation or contract issued under sections 620 to 620j of this title, from entering into any contract for the purchase of unprocessed timber from Federal lands for a period of not more than 5 years. Such person shall also be precluded from taking delivery of Federal timber purchased by another party for the period of debarment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prerequisites for debarment</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">No person may be debarred from bidding for or entering into a contract for the purchase of unprocessed timber from Federal lands under subparagraph (A) unless the head of the appropriate Federal department or agency first finds, on the record and after an opportunity for a hearing, that debarment is warranted.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding of awards during debarment proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The head of an appropriate Federal department or agency may withhold an award under sections 620 to 620j of this title of a contract for the purchase of unprocessed timber from Federal lands during a debarment proceeding.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cancellation of contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The head of the appropriate Federal department or agency under sections 620 to 620j of this title may cancel any contract entered into with a person found to have violated sections 620 to 620j of this title or regulations issued under sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsections (c) and (d) do not apply to violations of <ref>section 620i of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 492</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–45, § 3</ref>, <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1620</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620e.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of sections 620 to 620j of this title:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “acquire” means to come into possession of, whether directly or indirectly, through a sale, trade, exchange, or other transaction, and the term “acquisition” means the act of acquiring.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Federal lands” means lands that are owned by the United States, but does not include any lands the title to which is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> held in trust by the United States for the benefit of any Indian tribe or individual,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> held by any Indian tribe or individual subject to a restriction by the United States against alienation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> held by any Native Corporation as defined in <ref>section 1602 of title 43</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minor violation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “minor violation” means a violation, other than an intentional violation, involving a single contract, purchase order, processing facility, or log yard involving a quantity of logs that is less than 25 logs and has a total value (at the time of the violation) of less than $10,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Northwestern private timber open market area</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “northwestern private timber open market area” means the State of Washington.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity and includes any subsidiary, subcontractor, or parent company, and business affiliates where 1 affiliate controls or has the power to control the other or when both are controlled directly or indirectly by a third person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “private lands” means lands held or owned by a person. Such term does not include Federal lands or public lands, or any lands the title to which is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> held in trust by the United States for the benefit of any Indian tribe or individual,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> held by any Indian tribe or individual subject to a restriction by the United States against alienation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> held by any Native Corporation as defined in <ref>section 1602 of title 43</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> The term “public lands” means lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States, that are held or owned by a State or political subdivision thereof, or any other public agency. Such term does not include any lands the title to which is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> held by the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> held in trust by the United States for the benefit of any Indian tribe or individual,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> held by any Indian tribe or individual subject to a restriction by the United States against alienation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> held by any Native Corporation as defined in <ref>section 1602 of title 43</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to Federal lands administered by that Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior with respect to Federal lands administered by that Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “unprocessed timber” means trees or portions of trees or other roundwood not processed to standards and specifications suitable for end product use.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “unprocessed timber” does not include timber processed into any one of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Lumber or construction timbers, except Western Red Cedar, meeting current American Lumber Standards Grades or Pacific Lumber Inspection Bureau Export R or N list grades, sawn on 4 sides, not intended for remanufacture.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Lumber, construction timbers, or cants for remanufacture, except Western Red Cedar, meeting current American Lumber Standards Grades or Pacific Lumber Inspection Bureau Export R or N list clear grades, sawn on 4 sides, not to exceed 12 inches in thickness.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Lumber, construction timbers, or cants for remanufacture, except Western Red Cedar, that do not meet the grades referred to in clause (ii) and are sawn on 4 sides, with wane less than ¼ of any face, not exceeding 8¾ inches in thickness.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Chips, pulp, or pulp products.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Veneer or plywood.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Poles, posts, or piling cut or treated with preservatives for use as such.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Shakes or shingles.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> Aspen or other pulpwood bolts, not exceeding 100 inches in length, exported for processing into pulp.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> Pulp logs, cull logs, and incidental volumes of grade 3 and 4 sawlogs processed at domestic pulp mills, domestic chip plants, or other domestic operations for the primary purpose of conversion of the logs into chips, or to the extent that a small quantity of such logs are processed, into other products at domestic processing facilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The acquisition of unprocessed timber from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian in the contiguous 48 States to be used in “substitution” for exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands means acquiring unprocessed timber from such Federal lands and engaging in exporting, or selling for export, unprocessed timber originating from private lands within the same geographic and economic area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “violation” means a violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title (including a regulation issued to implement sections 620 to 620j of this title) with regard to a course of action, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a violation by the original purchaser of unprocessed timber, an act or omission with respect to a single timber sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a violation of a subsequent purchaser of the timber, an act or omission with respect to an operation at a particular processing facility or log yard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 493</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620f.</num>
<heading> Regulations and review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agriculture and Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior shall, in consultation, each prescribe new coordinated and consistent regulations to implement sections 620 to 620j of this title on lands which they administer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce shall promulgate such rules and guidelines as may be necessary to carry out sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in sections 620 to 620j of this title, regulations and guidelines required under this subsection shall be issued not later than <date date="1998-06-01">June 1, 1998</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The regulations and guidelines issued under sections 620 to 620j of this title that were in effect prior to <date date="1995-09-08">September 8, 1995</date> shall remain in effect until new regulations and guidelines are issued under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Painting and branding</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary concerned shall issue regulations that impose reasonable painting, branding, or other forms of marking or tracking requirements on unprocessed timber if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the benefits of the requirements outweigh the cost of complying with the requirements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary determines that, without the requirements, it is likely that the unprocessed timber—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> would be exported in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if the unprocessed timber originated from Federal lands, would be substituted for unprocessed timber originating from private lands west of the 100th Meridian in the contiguous 48 States in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum size</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary concerned shall not impose painting, branding, or other forms of marking or tracking requirements on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the face of a log that is less than 7 inches in diameter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> unprocessed timber that is less than 8 feet in length or less than ⅓ sound wood.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waivers</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Secretary concerned may waive log painting and branding requirements—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> for a geographic area, if the Secretary determines that the risk of the unprocessed timber being exported from the area or used in substitution is low;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> with respect to unprocessed timber originating from private lands located within an approved sourcing area for a person who certifies that the timber will be processed at a specific domestic processing facility to the extent that the processing does occur; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> as part of a log yard agreement that is consistent with the purposes of the export and substitution restrictions imposed under sections 620 to 620j of this title.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and termination of waivers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A waiver granted under clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be reviewed once a year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall remain effective until terminated by the Secretary.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In making a determination under this paragraph, the Secretary concerned shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the risk of unprocessed timber of that species, grade, and size being exported or used in substitution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the location of the unprocessed timber and the effect of the location on its being exported or used in substitution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the history of the person involved with respect to compliance with log painting and branding requirements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other factor that is relevant to determining the likelihood of the unprocessed timber being exported or used in substitution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary concerned shall issue regulations that impose reasonable documentation and reporting requirements if the benefits of the requirements outweigh the cost of complying with the requirements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waivers</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Secretary concerned may waive documentation and reporting requirements for a person if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an audit of the records of the facility of the person reveals substantial compliance with all notice, reporting, painting, and branding requirements during the preceding year; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the person transferring the unprocessed timber and the person processing the unprocessed timber enter into an advance agreement with the Secretary concerned regarding the disposition of the unprocessed timber by domestic processing.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and termination of waivers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A waiver granted under clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be reviewed once a year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall remain effective until terminated by the Secretary.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior shall, in consultation, review the definition of unprocessed timber under <ref>section 620e(7) of this title</ref> for purposes of sections 620 to 620j of this title and, not later than 18 months after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, submit to the Congress any recommendations they have with respect to such definition. Specifically, the Secretaries shall report on the effects of maintaining 2 size standards under section 620e(B)(ii) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002465">1</ref> and (iii) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 495</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1622</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620g.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 496</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620h.</num>
<heading> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in sections 620 to 620j of this title, or regulations issued under sections 620 to 620j of this title, shall be construed to abrogate or affect any timber sale contract entered into before <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 497</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620i.</num>
<heading> Eastern hardwoods study</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, in conjunction with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, shall conduct a study of the export from the United States, during the 2-year period beginning on <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, of unprocessed hardwood timber harvested from Federal lands or public lands east of the 100th meridian. In order to carry out the provisions of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce shall require each person exporting such timber from the United States to declare, in addition to the information normally required in the Shipper’s Export Declarations, the State in which the timber was grown and harvested; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall ensure that all hardwood saw timber harvested from Federal lands east of the 100th meridian is marked in such a manner as to make it readily identifiable at all times before its manufacture, and shall take such steps as each Secretary considers appropriate to ensure that such markings are not altered or destroyed before manufacturing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1993-04-01">April 1, 1993</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Committees on Agriculture, Natural Resources, and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report describing the volume and value of unprocessed timber grown and harvested from Federal lands or public lands east of the 100th meridian that is exported from the United States during the 2-year period beginning on <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, the country to which such timber is exported, and the State in which such timber was grown and harvested.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 498</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(35)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620j.</num>
<heading> Authority of Export Administration Act of 1979</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in sections 620 to 620j of this title shall be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prejudice the outcome of pending or prospective petitions filed under, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> warrant the exercise of the authority contained in,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">section 7 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002466">1</ref> of the Export Administration Act of 1979 with respect to the export of unprocessed timber.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 499</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>