<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 20—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL FISHERIES CENTER AND AQUARIUM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1051.</num>
<heading> Authorization of Administrator of General Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Planning, construction, and maintenance of Center and Aquarium</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services (hereinafter referred to as the “Administrator”) is authorized to plan, construct, and maintain a National Fisheries Center and Aquarium in the District of Columbia or its vicinity for research in fisheries and for the display of fresh water and marine fishes and other aquatic resources for educational, recreational, cultural, and scientific purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use, purchase, lease, etc. of Federal lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator is further authorized to use Federal land and property for purposes of this chapter with the consent of the particular agency having administrative jurisdiction thereover, and, if said property is unavailable for purposes hereof, he may purchase, lease, or otherwise acquire such lands, waters, and interests therein, as he may deem necessary to carry out the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 752</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1052.</num>
<heading> Authorization of Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation of Center and Aquarium</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall operate the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specimens and exhibits; catalogs and other printed matter and films, animations and photographic and other material; employment of experts, consultants, and organizations; use of auditorium and other areas; use of facilities by foreigners</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is further authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> construct, purchase or lease, and operate and maintain vessels for specimen collecting purposes and, without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>, to contract for such collection of specimens and to purchase or exchange specimens and exhibit materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare for free distribution or exhibit or to offer for sale at cost illustrated catalogs of specimens, brochures, and other printed matter and films, animations and photographic and other material pertaining to the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium and its objectives and to aquariums generally, all or any of which may be reproduced by any printing or other process without regard to existing regulations, the proceeds of sales to be covered into the United States Treasury;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> employ, as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, but at rates not to exceed $50 per diem plus expenses, experts, consultants, or organizations thereof, as required to assist with the planning, design, construction, and operation of the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> permit on such terms and conditions as he shall consider to be in the public interest the use of auditorium and other areas for meetings and exhibits of societies and groups whose purposes are related to fish and wildlife generally; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> encourage the use of the educational and scientific facilities and equipment at the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium by individuals of any nation with which the United States maintains diplomatic relations and which extends similar use of its educational and scientific facilities and equipment to citizens of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 752</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1053.</num>
<heading> Delegation of responsibility for operation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall assign the responsibility for the operation of the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium and related activities to that branch of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service having as its major activity the rearing and holding of living fishes, including the operation of aquariums.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 753</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–271, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1974-04-22">Apr. 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 92</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1054.</num>
<heading> Advisory Board; establishment; meetings; functions; quorum; executive secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a nonpartisan Advisory Board to be known as the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium Advisory Board. The Advisory Board shall meet from time to time on the call of the Chairman. The functions of the Board shall be to render advice and to submit recommendations to the Secretary of the Interior upon his request, or upon its own initiative, concerning the management and operation of the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium. Five members shall constitute a quorum to transact business. The Secretary may designate an employee of the Department to serve as Executive Secretary to the Board.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 4</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1055.</num>
<heading> Members of Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and number of members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Advisory Board shall be composed of nine members. The Secretary shall designate the Chairman of the Advisory Board. The Assistant Secretary of the Interior for Fish and Wildlife shall be a member of such Board ex officio. The remaining eight members of such Board shall be appointed as follows—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> two Members of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> two Members of the House of Representatives, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> two individuals appointed by the Secretary, one of whom shall be engaged in or closely associated with, sport fishing, and one of whom shall be engaged in, or closely associated with, commercial fishing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> two individuals appointed by the Secretary from the public at large.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each class of two members of the Advisory Board referred to in subsection (a) shall be appointed for terms of four years, except that, of each such class of two members initially appointed, one shall be appointed for a term of two years. Any person appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term. Of each class of two members of such Board referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), not more than one shall be from the same political party, and not more than one shall be from the same State. Any member of such Board referred to in such paragraphs (1) and (2) who shall cease to be a Member of Congress during the term of his appointment under this section shall cease to be a member of such Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any vacancy in the Advisory Board shall be filled in the same manner as in the case of the original appointment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 5</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1056.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Advisory Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Advisory Board, other than members appointed under paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (a) of <ref>section 1055 of this title</ref>, shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of the duties vested in the Board. Members of the Board appointed under paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (a) of <ref>section 1055 of this title</ref> may each receive $50 per diem when engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Board, in addition to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of such duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 6</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1057.</num>
<heading> Preparation of annual report by Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium shall prepare for the Advisory Board an annual report for presentation to the Secretary of the Interior and to the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 7</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1058.</num>
<heading> Limitation on appropriations and expenditures; charges for visitation and use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated and expended hereunder for construction of the buildings for the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium shall not exceed $10,000,000: <i>Provided</i>, That the expenditure of such funds shall be made subject to the condition that the Secretary of the Interior shall establish charges relating to visitation to and uses of the National Fisheries Center and Aquarium at such rates as in the Secretary’s judgment will produce revenues to (a) liquidate the costs of construction within a period of not to exceed thirty years and (b) pay for the annual operation and maintenance costs thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–758, § 8</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>