<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 36—</num>
<heading>FOREST AND RANGELAND RENEWABLE RESOURCES PLANNING</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PLANNING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1600.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the management of the Nation’s renewable resources is highly complex and the uses, demand for, and supply of the various resources are subject to change over time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public interest is served by the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture, in cooperation with other agencies, assessing the Nation’s renewable resources, and developing and preparing a national renewable resource program, which is periodically reviewed and updated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to serve the national interest, the renewable resource program must be based on a comprehensive assessment of present and anticipated uses, demand for, and supply of renewable resources from the Nation’s public and private forests and rangelands, through analysis of environmental and economic impacts, coordination of multiple use and sustained yield opportunities as provided in the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 (<ref>74 Stat. 215</ref>; <ref>16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>), and public participation in the development of the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the new knowledge derived from coordinated public and private research programs will promote a sound technical and ecological base for effective management, use, and protection of the Nation’s renewable resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> inasmuch as the majority of the Nation’s forests and rangeland is under private, State, and local governmental management and the Nation’s major capacity to produce goods and services is based on these nonfederally managed renewable resources, the Federal Government should be a catalyst to encourage and assist these owners in the efficient long-term use and improvement of these lands and their renewable resources consistent with the principles of sustained yield and multiple use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Forest Service, by virtue of its statutory authority for management of the National Forest System, research and cooperative programs, and its role as an agency in the Department of Agriculture, has both a responsibility and an opportunity to be a leader in assuring that the Nation maintains a natural resource conservation posture that will meet the requirements of our people in perpetuity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> recycled timber product materials are as much a part of our renewable forest resources as are the trees from which they originally came, and in order to extend our timber and timber fiber resources and reduce pressures for timber production from Federal lands, the Forest Service should expand its research in the use of recycled and waste timber product materials, develop techniques for the substitution of these secondary materials for primary materials, and promote and encourage the use of recycled timber product materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1601.</num>
<heading> Renewable Resource Assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation by Secretary of Agriculture; time of preparation, updating and contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In recognition of the vital importance of America’s renewable resources of the forest, range, and other associated lands to the Nation’s social and economic well-being, and of the necessity for a long term perspective in planning and undertaking related national renewable resource programs administered by the Forest Service, the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this subchapter as the “Secretary”) shall prepare a Renewable Resource Assessment (hereinafter called the “Assessment”). The Assessment shall be prepared not later than <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>, and shall be updated during 1979 and each tenth year thereafter, and shall include but not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of present and anticipated uses, demand for, and supply of the renewable resources, with consideration of the international resource situation, and an emphasis of pertinent supply and demand and price relationship trends;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an inventory, based on information developed by the Forest Service and other Federal agencies, of present and potential renewable resources, and an evaluation of opportunities for improving their yield of tangible and intangible goods and services, together with estimates of investment costs and direct and indirect returns to the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of Forest Service programs and responsibilities in research, cooperative programs and management of the National Forest System, their interrelationships, and the relationship of these programs and responsibilities to public and private activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a discussion of important policy considerations, laws, regulations, and other factors expected to influence and affect significantly the use, ownership, and management of forest, range, and other associated lands; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002666">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an analysis of the potential effects of global climate change on the condition of renewable resources on the forests and rangelands of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> an analysis of the rural and urban forestry opportunities to mitigate the buildup of atmospheric carbon dioxide and reduce the risk of global climate change,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002667">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of Assessments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall report in the 1979 and subsequent Assessments on:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the additional fiber potential in the National Forest System including, but not restricted to, forest mortality, growth, salvage potential, potential increased forest products sales, economic constraints, alternate markets, contract considerations, and other multiple use considerations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the potential for increased utilization of forest and wood product wastes in the National Forest System and on other lands, and of urban wood wastes and wood product recycling, including recommendations to the Congress for actions which would lead to increased utilization of material now being wasted both in the forests and in manufactured products; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the milling and other wood fiber product fabrication facilities and their location in the United States, noting the public and private forested areas that supply such facilities, assessing the degree of utilization into product form of harvested trees by such facilities, and setting forth the technology appropriate to the facilities to improve utilization either individually or in aggregate units of harvested trees and to reduce wasted wood fibers. The Secretary shall set forth a program to encourage the adoption by these facilities of these technologies for improving wood fiber utilization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public involvement; consultation with governmental departments and agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing the reports required under subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary shall provide opportunity for public involvement and shall consult with other interested governmental departments and agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional policy of multiple use sustained yield management; examination and certification of lands; estimate of appropriations necessary for reforestation and other treatment; budget requirements; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It is the policy of the Congress that all forested lands in the National Forest System shall be maintained in appropriate forest cover with species of trees, degree of stocking, rate of growth, and conditions of stand designed to secure the maximum benefits of multiple use sustained yield management in accordance with land management plans. Accordingly, the Secretary is directed to identify and report to the Congress annually at the time of submission of the President’s budget together with the annual report provided for under <ref>section 1606(c) of this title</ref>, beginning with submission of the President’s budget for fiscal year 1978, the amount and location by forests and States and by productivity class, where practicable, of all lands in the National Forest System where objectives of land management plans indicate the need to reforest areas that have been cut-over or otherwise denuded or deforested, and all lands with stands of trees that are not growing at their best potential rate of growth. All national forest lands treated from year to year shall be examined after the first and third growing seasons and certified by the Secretary in the report provided for under this subsection as to stocking rate, growth rate in relation to potential and other pertinent measures. Any lands not certified as satisfactory shall be returned to the backlog and scheduled for prompt treatment. The level and types of treatment shall be those which secure the most effective mix of multiple use benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 1607 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall, annually during each of the 10 years beginning after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, transmit to the Congress in the manner provided in this subsection an estimate of the sums necessary to be appropriated, in addition to the funds available from other sources, to replant and otherwise treat an acreage equal to the acreage to be cut over that year, plus a sufficient portion of the backlog of lands found to be in need of treatment to eliminate the backlog within the 10-year period. After the 10-year period, the Secretary shall transmit annually to the Congress an estimate of the sums necessary to replant and otherwise treat all lands being cut over and maintain planned timber production on all other forested lands in the National Forest System so as to prevent the development of a backlog of needed work larger than the needed work at the beginning of the fiscal year. The Secretary’s estimate of sums necessary, in addition to the sums available under other authorities, for accomplishment of the reforestation and other treatment of National Forest System lands under this section shall be provided annually for inclusion in the President’s budget and shall also be transmitted to the Speaker of the House and the President of the Senate together with the annual report provided for under <ref>section 1606(c) of this title</ref> at the time of submission of the President’s budget to the Congress beginning with the budget for fiscal year 2021. The sums estimated as necessary for reforestation and other treatment shall include moneys needed to secure seed, grow seedlings, prepare sites, plant trees, thin, remove deleterious growth and underbrush, build fence to exclude livestock and adverse wildlife from regeneration areas and otherwise establish and improve growing forests to secure planned production of trees and other multiple use values.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Effective for the fiscal year beginning <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>, and each fiscal year thereafter, there is hereby authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of reforesting and treating lands in the National Forest System $200,000,000 annually to meet requirements of this subsection. All sums appropriated for the purposes of this subsection shall be available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reforestation requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this paragraph:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Natural regeneration.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “natural regeneration” means the establishment of a tree or tree age class from natural seeding, sprouting, or suckering in accordance with the management objectives of an applicable land management plan.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “natural regeneration” may include any site preparation activity to enhance the success of regeneration to the desired species composition and structure.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority land</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “priority land” means National Forest System land that, due to an unplanned event—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> does not meet the conditions for appropriate forest cover described in paragraph (1);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> requires reforestation to meet the objectives of an applicable land management plan; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> is unlikely to experience natural regeneration without assistance.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reforestation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “reforestation” means the act of renewing tree cover, taking into consideration species composition and resilience, by establishing young trees through—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> natural regeneration;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> natural regeneration with site preparation; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> planting or direct seeding.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Unplanned event.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “unplanned event” means any unplanned disturbance that—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> disrupts ecosystem or forest structure or composition; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> changes resources, substrate availability, or the physical environment.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “unplanned event” may include—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> a wildfire;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> an infestation of insects or disease;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> a weather event; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> animal damage.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each reforestation activity under this section shall be carried out in accordance with applicable Forest Service management practices and definitions, including definitions relating to silvicultural practices and forest management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reforestation priority.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to projects on the priority list described in clause (ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Priority list.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall, based on recommendations from regional foresters, create a priority list of reforestation projects that—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> primarily take place on priority land;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> promote effective reforestation following unplanned events; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> may include activities to ensure adequate and appropriate seed availability.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ranking</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall rank projects on the priority list under subclause (I) based on—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> documentation of an effective reforestation project plan;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the ability to measure the progress and success of the project; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> the ability of a project to provide benefits relating to forest function and health, soil health and productivity, wildlife habitat, improved air and water quality, carbon sequestration potential, resilience, job creation, and enhanced recreational opportunities.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on herbicides and pesticides</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit an annual report to the Congress on the amounts, types, and uses of herbicides and pesticides used in the National Forest System, including the beneficial or adverse effects of such uses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 3</ref>, formerly § 2, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 476</ref>; renumbered § 3 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2–4, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2950; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIV, § 2408(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. G, title III, § 70302(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1602.</num>
<heading> Renewable Resource Program; preparation by Secretary and transmittal to President; purpose and development of program; time of preparation, updating and contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to provide for periodic review of programs for management and administration of the National Forest System, for research, for cooperative State and private Forest Service programs, and for conduct of other Forest Service activities in relation to the findings of the Assessment, the Secretary, utilizing information available to the Forest Service and other agencies within the Department of Agriculture, including data prepared pursuant to <ref>section 1010a of title 7</ref>, shall prepare and transmit to the President a recommended Renewable Resource Program (hereinafter called the “Program”). The Program transmitted to the President may include alternatives, and shall provide in appropriate detail for protection, management, and development of the National Forest System, including forest development roads and trails; for cooperative Forest Service programs; and for research. The Program shall be developed in accordance with principles set forth in the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of <date date="1960-06-12">June 12, 1960</date> (<ref>74 Stat. 215</ref>; <ref>16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>), and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>83 Stat. 852</ref>) [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.]. The Program shall be prepared not later than <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>, to cover the four-year period beginning <date date="1976-10-01">October 1, 1976</date>, and at least each of the four fiscal decades next following such period, and shall be updated no later than during the first half of the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, and the first half of each fifth fiscal year thereafter to cover at least each of the four fiscal decades beginning next after such updating. The Program shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an inventory of specific needs and opportunities for both public and private program investments. The inventory shall differentiate between activities which are of a capital nature and those which are of an operational nature;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specific identification of Program outputs, results anticipated, and benefits associated with investments in such a manner that the anticipated costs can be directly compared with the total related benefits and direct and indirect returns to the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a discussion of priorities for accomplishment of inventoried Program opportunities, with specified costs, outputs, results, and benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a detailed study of personnel requirements as needed to implement and monitor existing and ongoing programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Program recommendations which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> evaluate objectives for the major Forest Service programs in order that multiple-use and sustained-yield relationships among and within the renewable resources can be determined;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> explain the opportunities for owners of forests and rangeland to participate in programs to improve and enhance the condition of the land and the renewable resource products therefrom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recognize the fundamental need to protect and, where appropriate, improve the quality of soil, water, and air resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> state national goals that recognize the interrelationships between and interdependence within the renewable resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> evaluate the impact of the export and import of raw logs upon domestic timber supplies and prices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> account for the effects of global climate change on forest and rangeland conditions, including potential effects on the geographic ranges of species, and on forest and rangeland products.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 4</ref>, formerly § 3, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 477</ref>, renumbered § 4 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2, 5, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2951; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIV, § 2408(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1603.</num>
<heading> National Forest System resource inventories; development, maintenance, and updating by Secretary as part of Assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a part of the Assessment, the Secretary shall develop and maintain on a continuing basis a comprehensive and appropriately detailed inventory of all National Forest System lands and renewable resources. This inventory shall be kept current so as to reflect changes in conditions and identify new and emerging resources and values.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 5</ref>, formerly § 4, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 477</ref>, renumbered § 5, <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1604.</num>
<heading> National Forest System land and resource management plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development, maintenance, and revision by Secretary as part of program; coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a part of the Program provided for by <ref>section 1602 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall develop, maintain, and, as appropriate, revise land and resource management plans for units of the National Forest System, coordinated with the land and resource management planning processes of State and local governments and other Federal agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the development and maintenance of land management plans for use on units of the National Forest System, the Secretary shall use a systematic interdisciplinary approach to achieve integrated consideration of physical, biological, economic, and other sciences.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incorporation of standards and guidelines by Secretary; time of completion; progress reports; existing management plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall begin to incorporate the standards and guidelines required by this section in plans for units of the National Forest System as soon as practicable after <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, and shall attempt to complete such incorporation for all such units by no later than <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>. The Secretary shall report to the Congress on the progress of such incorporation in the annual report required by <ref>section 1606(c) of this title</ref>. Until such time as a unit of the National Forest System is managed under plans developed in accordance with this subchapter, the management of such unit may continue under existing land and resource management plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public participation and consultation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide for public participation in the development, review, and revision of land management plans including, but not limited to, making the plans or revisions available to the public at convenient locations in the vicinity of the affected unit for a period of at least three months before final adoption, during which period the Secretary shall publicize and hold public meetings or comparable processes at locations that foster public participation in the review of such plans or revisions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No additional consultation required after approval of land management plans</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not be required to engage in consultation under this section or any other provision of law (including <ref>section 7 of Public Law 93–205</ref> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1536</ref>) and section 402.16 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the listing of a species as threatened or endangered, or a designation of critical habitat pursuant to <ref>Public Law 93–205</ref> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.), if a land management plan has been adopted by the Secretary as of the date of listing or designation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any provision of a land management plan adopted as described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 15 years have passed since the date on which the Secretary adopted the land management plan described in clause (i) of that subparagraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 5 years have passed since the date of enactment of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002668">1</ref> or the date of the listing of a species as threatened or endangered for a species known to occur on the unit or the designation of critical habitat within the unit as described in clause (i) of that subparagraph, whichever is later.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of paragraph</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph affects any applicable requirement of the Secretary to consult with the head of any other Federal department or agency—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> regarding any project carried out, or proposed to be carried out, to implement a land management plan pursuant to <ref>Public Law 93–205</ref> (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.), including any requirement to consult regarding the consideration of cumulative impacts of completed, ongoing, and planned projects; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the development of a modification to a land management plan; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an amendment or revision to a land management plan in accordance with paragraph (4) or (5) of subsection (f).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required assurances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing, maintaining, and revising plans for units of the National Forest System pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall assure that such plans—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for multiple use and sustained yield of the products and services obtained therefrom in accordance with the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>], and, in particular, include coordination of outdoor recreation, range, timber, watershed, wildlife and fish, and wilderness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determine forest management systems, harvesting levels, and procedures in the light of all of the uses set forth in subsection (c)(1), the definition of the terms “multiple use” and “sustained yield” as provided in the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960, and the availability of lands and their suitability for resource management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Plans developed in accordance with this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> form one integrated plan for each unit of the National Forest System, incorporating in one document or one set of documents, available to the public at convenient locations, all of the features required by this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be embodied in appropriate written material, including maps and other descriptive documents, reflecting proposed and possible actions, including the planned timber sale program and the proportion of probable methods of timber harvest within the unit necessary to fulfill the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be prepared by an interdisciplinary team. Each team shall prepare its plan based on inventories of the applicable resources of the forest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> be amended in any manner whatsoever after final adoption after public notice, and, if such amendment would result in a significant change in such plan, in accordance with the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section and public involvement comparable to that required by subsection (d) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> be revised (A) from time to time when the Secretary finds conditions in a unit have significantly changed, but at least every fifteen years, and (B) in accordance with the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section and public involvement comparable to that required by subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgation of regulations for development and revision of plans; environmental considerations; resource management guidelines; guidelines for land management plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As soon as practicable, but not later than two years after <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, the Secretary shall in accordance with the procedures set forth in <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, promulgate regulations, under the principles of the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>] that set out the process for the development and revision of the land management plans, and the guidelines and standards prescribed by this subsection. The regulations shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specifying procedures to insure that land management plans are prepared in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.], including, but not limited to, direction on when and for what plans an environmental impact statement required under section 102(2)(C) of that Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</ref>] shall be prepared;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> specifying guidelines which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require the identification of the suitability of lands for resource management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for obtaining inventory data on the various renewable resources, and soil and water, including pertinent maps, graphic material, and explanatory aids; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide for methods to identify special conditions or situations involving hazards to the various resources and their relationship to alternative activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> specifying guidelines for land management plans developed to achieve the goals of the Program which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> insure consideration of the economic and environmental aspects of various systems of renewable resource management, including the related systems of silviculture and protection of forest resources, to provide for outdoor recreation (including wilderness), range, timber, watershed, wildlife, and fish;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for diversity of plant and animal communities based on the suitability and capability of the specific land area in order to meet overall multiple-use objectives, and within the multiple-use objectives of a land management plan adopted pursuant to this section, provide, where appropriate, to the degree practicable, for steps to be taken to preserve the diversity of tree species similar to that existing in the region controlled by the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> insure research on and (based on continuous monitoring and assessment in the field) evaluation of the effects of each management system to the end that it will not produce substantial and permanent impairment of the productivity of the land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> permit increases in harvest levels based on intensified management practices, such as reforestation, thinning, and tree improvement if (i) such practices justify increasing the harvests in accordance with the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960, and (ii) such harvest levels are decreased at the end of each planning period if such practices cannot be successfully implemented or funds are not received to permit such practices to continue substantially as planned;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> insure that timber will be harvested from National Forest System lands only where—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> soil, slope, or other watershed conditions will not be irreversibly damaged;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> there is assurance that such lands can be adequately restocked within five years after harvest;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> protection is provided for streams, streambanks, shorelines, lakes, wetlands, and other bodies of water from detrimental changes in water temperatures, blockages of water courses, and deposits of sediment, where harvests are likely to seriously and adversely affect water conditions or fish habitat; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the harvesting system to be used is not selected primarily because it will give the greatest dollar return or the greatest unit output of timber; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> insure that clearcutting, seed tree cutting, shelterwood cutting, and other cuts designed to regenerate an evenaged stand of timber will be used as a cutting method on National Forest System lands only where—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for clearcutting, it is determined to be the optimum method, and for other such cuts it is determined to be appropriate, to meet the objectives and requirements of the relevant land management plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the interdisciplinary review as determined by the Secretary has been completed and the potential environmental, biological, esthetic, engineering, and economic impacts on each advertised sale area have been assessed, as well as the consistency of the sale with the multiple use of the general area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> cut blocks, patches, or strips are shaped and blended to the extent practicable with the natural terrain;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> there are established according to geographic areas, forest types, or other suitable classifications the maximum size limits for areas to be cut in one harvest operation, including provision to exceed the established limits after appropriate public notice and review by the responsible Forest Service officer one level above the Forest Service officer who normally would approve the harvest proposal: <i>Provided</i>, That such limits shall not apply to the size of areas harvested as a result of natural catastrophic conditions such as fire, insect and disease attack, or windstorm; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> such cuts are carried out in a manner consistent with the protection of soil, watershed, fish, wildlife, recreation, and esthetic resources, and the regeneration of the timber resource.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scientific committee to aid in promulgation of regulations; termination; revision committees; clerical and technical assistance; compensation of committee members</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In carrying out the purposes of subsection (g) of this section, the Secretary shall appoint a committee of scientists who are not officers or employees of the Forest Service. The committee shall provide scientific and technical advice and counsel on proposed guidelines and procedures to assure that an effective interdisciplinary approach is proposed and adopted. The committee shall terminate upon promulgation of the regulations, but the Secretary may, from time to time, appoint similar committees when considering revisions of the regulations. The views of the committees shall be included in the public information supplied when the regulations are proposed for adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Clerical and technical assistance, as may be necessary to discharge the duties of the committee, shall be provided from the personnel of the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> While attending meetings of the committee, the members shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate of $100 per diem, including traveltime, and while away from their homes or regular places of business they may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>, for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency of resource plans, permits, contracts, and other instruments with land management plans; revision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Resource plans and permits, contracts, and other instruments for the use and occupancy of National Forest System lands shall be consistent with the land management plans. Those resource plans and permits, contracts, and other such instruments currently in existence shall be revised as soon as practicable to be made consistent with such plans. When land management plans are revised, resource plans and permits, contracts, and other instruments, when necessary, shall be revised as soon as practicable. Any revision in present or future permits, contracts, and other instruments made pursuant to this section shall be subject to valid existing rights.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of land management plans and revisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Land management plans and revisions shall become effective thirty days after completion of public participation and publication of notification by the Secretary as required under subsection (d) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of land management plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing land management plans pursuant to this subchapter, the Secretary shall identify lands within the management area which are not suited for timber production, considering physical, economic, and other pertinent factors to the extent feasible, as determined by the Secretary, and shall assure that, except for salvage sales or sales necessitated to protect other multiple-use values, no timber harvesting shall occur on such lands for a period of 10 years. Lands once identified as unsuitable for timber production shall continue to be treated for reforestation purposes, particularly with regard to the protection of other multiple-use values. The Secretary shall review his decision to classify these lands as not suited for timber production at least every 10 years and shall return these lands to timber production whenever he determines that conditions have changed so that they have become suitable for timber production.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program evaluation; process for estimating long-term costs and benefits; summary of data included in annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> formulate and implement, as soon as practicable, a process for estimating long-terms <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002669">2</ref> costs and benefits to support the program evaluation requirements of this subchapter. This process shall include requirements to provide information on a representative sample basis of estimated expenditures associated with the reforestation, timber stand improvement, and sale of timber from the National Forest System, and shall provide a comparison of these expenditures to the return to the Government resulting from the sale of timber; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> include a summary of data and findings resulting from these estimates as a part of the annual report required pursuant to <ref>section 1606(c) of this title</ref>, including an identification on a representative sample basis of those advertised timber sales made below the estimated expenditures for such timber as determined by the above cost process; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002670">3</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of standards to ensure culmination of mean annual increment of growth; silvicultural practices; salvage harvesting; exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> standards to insure that, prior to harvest, stands of trees throughout the National Forest System shall generally have reached the culmination of mean annual increment of growth (calculated on the basis of cubic measurement or other methods of calculation at the discretion of the Secretary): <i>Provided</i>, That these standards shall not preclude the use of sound silvicultural practices, such as thinning or other stand improvement measures: <i>Provided further</i>, That these standards shall not preclude the Secretary from salvage or sanitation harvesting of timber stands which are substantially damaged by fire, windthrow or other catastrophe, or which are in imminent danger from insect or disease attack; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> exceptions to these standards for the harvest of particular species of trees in management units after consideration has been given to the multiple uses of the forest including, but not limited to, recreation, wildlife habitat, and range and after completion of public participation processes utilizing the procedures of subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 6</ref>, formerly, § 5, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 477</ref>, renumbered § 6 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2, 6, 12(a), <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2952, 2958; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1065</ref>, 1066.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1605.</num>
<heading> Protection, use and management of renewable resources on non-Federal lands; utilization of Assessment, surveys and Program by Secretary to assist States, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may utilize the Assessment, resource surveys, and Program prepared pursuant to this subchapter to assist States and other organizations in proposing the planning for the protection, use, and management of renewable resources on non-Federal land.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 7</ref>, formerly § 6, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 478</ref>, renumbered § 7, <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1606.</num>
<heading> Budget requests by President for Forest Service activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal to Speaker of House and President of Senate of Assessment, Program and Statement of Policy used in framing requests; time for transmittal; implementation by President of programs established under Statement of Policy unless Statement subsequently disapproved by Congress; time for disapproval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the date Congress first convenes in 1976 and thereafter following each updating of the Assessment and the Program, the President shall transmit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate, when Congress convenes, the Assessment as set forth in <ref>section 1601 of this title</ref> and the Program as set forth in <ref>section 1602 of this title</ref>, together with a detailed Statement of Policy intended to be used in framing budget requests by that Administration for Forest Service activities for the five- or ten-year program period beginning during the term of such Congress for such further action deemed appropriate by the Congress. Following the transmission of such Assessment, Program, and Statement of Policy, the President shall, subject to other actions of the Congress, carry out programs already established by law in accordance with such Statement of Policy or any subsequent amendment or modification thereof approved by the Congress, unless, before the end of the first period of ninety calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date on which the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House are recipients of the transmission of such Assessment, Program, and Statement of Policy, either House adopts a resolution reported by the appropriate committee of jurisdiction disapproving the Statement of Policy. For the purpose of this subsection, the continuity of a session shall be deemed to be broken only by an adjournment sine die, and the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a day certain shall be excluded in the computation of the ninety-day period. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, Congress may revise or modify the Statement of Policy transmitted by the President, and the revised or modified Statement of Policy shall be used in framing budget requests.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of requests to show extent of compliance of projected programs and policies with policies approved by Congress; requests not conforming to approved policies; expenditure of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commencing with the fiscal budget for the year ending <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, requests presented by the President to the Congress governing Forest Service activities shall express in qualitative and quantitative terms the extent to which the programs and policies projected under the budget meet the policies approved by the Congress in accordance with subsection (a) of this section. In any case in which such budget so presented recommends a course which fails to meet the policies so established, the President shall specifically set forth the reason or reasons for requesting the Congress to approve the lesser programs or policies presented. Amounts appropriated to carry out the policies approved in accordance with subsection (a) of this section shall be expended in accordance with the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual evaluation report to Congress of Program components; time of submission; status of major research programs; application of findings; status, etc., of cooperative forestry assistance programs and activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of providing information that will aid Congress in its oversight responsibilities and improve the accountability of agency expenditures and activities, the Secretary shall prepare an annual report which evaluates the component elements of the Program required to be prepared by <ref>section 1602 of this title</ref> which shall be furnished to the Congress at the time of submission of the annual fiscal budget commencing with the third fiscal year after <date date="1974-08-17">August 17, 1974</date>. With regard to the research component of the program, the report shall include, but not be limited to, a description of the status of major research programs, significant findings, and how these findings will be applied in National Forest System management and in cooperative State and private Forest Service programs. With regard to the cooperative forestry assistance part of the Program, the report shall include, but not be limited to, a description of the status, accomplishments, needs, and work backlogs for the programs and activities conducted under the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required contents of annual evaluation report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">These annual evaluation reports shall set forth progress in implementing the Program required to be prepared by <ref>section 1602 of this title</ref>, together with accomplishments of the Program as they relate to the objectives of the Assessment. Objectives should be set forth in qualitative and quantitative terms and accomplishments should be reported accordingly. The report shall contain appropriate measurements of pertinent costs and benefits. The evaluation shall assess the balance between economic factors and environmental quality factors. Program benefits shall include, but not be limited to, environmental quality factors such as esthetics, public access, wildlife habitat, recreational and wilderness use, and economic factors such as the excess of cost savings over the value of foregone benefits and the rate of return on renewable resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional required contents of annual evaluation report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports shall indicate plans for implementing corrective action and recommendations for new legislation where warranted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of annual evaluation report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports shall be structured for Congress in concise summary form with necessary detailed data in appendices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 8</ref>, formerly § 7, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 478</ref>, renumbered § 8 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2, 7, 12(b), <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2956, 2958; <ref>Pub. L. 95–313, § 15</ref>, formerly § 12, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 374</ref>, renumbered § 15, <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1215(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3525</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1606a.</num>
<heading> Reforestation Trust Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; source of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund, to be known as the Reforestation Trust Fund (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Trust Fund”), consisting of such amounts as are transferred to the Trust Fund under subsection (b)(1) and any interest earned on investment of amounts in the Trust Fund under subsection (c)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers to Trust Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Trust Fund an amount equal to the sum of the tariffs received in the Treasury after <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>, under headings 4401 through 4412 and subheadings 4418.50.00, 4418.90.20, 4420.10.00, 4420.90.80, 4421.90.10 through 4421.90.20, and 4421.90.70 of chapter 44, subheadings 6808.00.00 and 6809.11.00 of chapter 68 and subheading 9614.10.00 of chapter 96 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Frequency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amounts required to be transferred to the Trust Fund under paragraph (1) shall be transferred at least quarterly from the general fund of the Treasury to the Trust Fund on the basis of estimates made by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of estimates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Proper adjustment shall be made in the amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were in excess of or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress; printing as House and Senate document; investments; sale and redemption of obligations; credits for Trust Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury to hold the Trust Fund, and (after consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture) to report to the Congress each year on the financial condition and the results of the operations of the Trust Fund during the preceding fiscal year and on its expected condition and operations during the next fiscal year. Such report shall be printed as both a House and Senate document of the session of the Congress to which the report is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> It shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury to invest such portion of the Trust Fund as is not, in his judgment, required to meet current withdrawals. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States. For such purpose, such obligations may be acquired (i) on original issue at the issue price, or (ii) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price. The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of special obligations exclusively to the Trust Fund. Such special obligations shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average rate of interest, computed as to the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of such issue, borne by all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the Public Debt; except that where such average rate is not a multiple of one-eighth of 1 percent, the rate of interest of such special obligations shall be the multiple of one-eighth of 1 percent next lower than such average rate. Such special obligations shall be issued only if the Secretary of the Treasury determines that the purchase of other interest-bearing obligations of the United States, or of obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States on original issue or at the market price, is not in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any obligation acquired by the Trust Fund (except special obligations issued exclusively to the Trust Fund) may be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price, and such special obligations may be redeemed at par plus accrued interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Trust Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligations from Trust Fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is on and after <date date="1985-12-19">December 19, 1985</date>, authorized to obligate such sums as are available in the Trust Fund (including any amounts not obligated in previous fiscal years) for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reforestation and timber stand improvement as specified in subsection (e) of <ref>section 1601 of this title</ref> and other forest stand improvement activities to enhance forest health and reduce hazardous fuel loads of forest stands in the National Forest System; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> properly allocable administrative costs of the Federal Government for the activities specified above.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–451, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title IV, § 422</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–190, § 101(d) [title II, § 201]</ref>, <date date="1985-12-19">Dec. 19, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1224</ref>, 1245; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1214(r)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1160</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–83, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. G, title III, § 70302(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1607.</num>
<heading> National Forest System renewable resources; development and administration by Secretary in accordance with multiple use and sustained yield concepts for products and services; target year for operational posture of resources; budget requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall take such action as will assure that the development and administration of the renewable resources of the National Forest System are in full accord with the concepts for multiple use and sustained yield of products and services as set forth in the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>]. To further these concepts, the Congress hereby sets the year 2030 as the target year when the renewable resources of the National Forest System shall be in an operating posture whereby all backlogs of needed treatment for their restoration shall be reduced to a current basis and the major portion of planned intensive multiple-use sustained-yield management procedures shall be installed and operating on an environmentally-sound basis. The annual budget shall contain requests for funds for an orderly program to eliminate such backlogs: <i>Provided</i>, That when the Secretary finds that (1) the backlog of areas that will benefit by such treatment has been eliminated, (2) the cost of treating the remainder of such area exceeds the economic and environmental benefits to be secured from their treatment, or (3) the total supplies of the renewable resources of the United States are adequate to meet the future needs of the American people, the budget request for these elements of restoration may be adjusted accordingly.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 9</ref>, formerly § 8, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 479</ref>, renumbered § 9, <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. G, title III, § 70302(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1608.</num>
<heading> National Forest Transportation System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional declaration of policy; time for development; method of financing; financing of forest development roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress declares that the installation of a proper system of transportation to service the National Forest System, as is provided for in sections 532 to 538 of this title, shall be carried forward in time to meet anticipated needs on an economical and environmentally sound basis, and the method chosen for financing the construction and maintenance of the transportation system should be such as to enhance local, regional, and national benefits: <i>Provided</i>, That limitations on the level of obligations for construction of forest roads by timber purchasers shall be established in annual appropriation Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of temporary roadways in connection with timber contracts, and other permits or leases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless the necessity for a permanent road is set forth in the forest development road system plan, any road constructed on land of the National Forest System in connection with a timber contract or other permit or lease shall be designed with the goal of reestablishing vegetative cover on the roadway and areas where the vegetative cover has been disturbed by the construction of the road, within ten years after the termination of the contract, permit, or lease either through artificial or natural means. Such action shall be taken unless it is later determined that the road is needed for use as a part of the National Forest Transportation System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards of roadway construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Roads constructed on National Forest System lands shall be designed to standards appropriate for the intended uses, considering safety, cost of transportation, and impacts on land and resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 10</ref>, formerly § 9, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 479</ref>, renumbered § 10 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2, 8, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2956; <ref>Pub. L. 97–100, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1981-12-23">Dec. 23, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1609.</num>
<heading> National Forest System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional declaration of constituent elements and purposes; lands etc., included within; return of lands to public domain</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress declares that the National Forest System consists of units of federally owned forest, range, and related lands throughout the United States and its territories, united into a nationally significant system dedicated to the long-term benefit for present and future generations, and that it is the purpose of this section to include all such areas into one integral system. The “National Forest System” shall include all national forest lands reserved or withdrawn from the public domain of the United States, all national forest lands acquired through purchase, exchange, donation, or other means, the national grasslands and land utilization projects administered under title III of the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1010</ref> et seq.], and other lands, waters, or interests therein which are administered by the Forest Service or are designated for administration through the Forest Service as a part of the system. Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 473 of this title</ref>, no land now or hereafter reserved or withdrawn from the public domain as national forests pursuant to section 471 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002671">1</ref> of this title, or any act supplementary to and amendatory thereof, shall be returned to the public domain except by an act of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location of Forest Service offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The on-the-ground field offices, field supervisory offices, and regional offices of the Forest Service shall be so situated as to provide the optimum level of convenient, useful services to the public, giving priority to the maintenance and location of facilities in rural areas and towns near the national forest and Forest Service program locations in accordance with the standards in <ref>section 2204b–1(b) of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 11</ref>, formerly § 10, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 480</ref>, renumbered § 11 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2, 9, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2957.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1610.</num>
<heading> Implementation of provisions by Secretary; utilization of information and data of other organizations; avoidance of duplication of planning, etc.; “renewable resources” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall utilize information and data available from other Federal, State, and private organizations and shall avoid duplication and overlap of resource assessment and program planning efforts of other Federal agencies. The term “renewable resources” shall be construed to involve those matters within the scope of responsibilities and authorities of the Forest Service on <date date="1974-08-17">August 17, 1974</date> and on the date of enactment of any legislation amendatory or supplementary thereto.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 12</ref>, formerly § 11, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 480</ref>, renumbered § 12 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2, 10, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2957; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1611.</num>
<heading> Timber</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on removal; variations in allowable sale quantity; public participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall limit the sale of timber from each national forest to a quantity equal to or less than a quantity which can be removed from such forest annually in perpetuity on a sustained-yield basis: <i>Provided</i>, That, in order to meet overall multiple-use objectives, the Secretary may establish an allowable sale quantity for any decade which departs from the projected long-term average sale quantity that would otherwise be established: <i>Provided further</i>, That any such planned departure must be consistent with the multiple-use management objectives of the land management plan. Plans for variations in the allowable sale quantity must be made with public participation as required by <ref>section 1604(d) of this title</ref>. In addition, within any decade, the Secretary may sell a quantity in excess of the annual allowable sale quantity established pursuant to this section in the case of any national forest so long as the average sale quantities of timber from such national forest over the decade covered by the plan do not exceed such quantity limitation. In those cases where a forest has less than two hundred thousand acres of commercial forest land, the Secretary may use two or more forests for purposes of determining the sustained yield.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Salvage harvesting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in subsection (a) of this section shall prohibit the Secretary from salvage or sanitation harvesting of timber stands which are substantially damaged by fire, windthrow, or other catastrophe, or which are in imminent danger from insect or disease attack. The Secretary may either substitute such timber for timber that would otherwise be sold under the plan or, if not feasible, sell such timber over and above the plan volume.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 13</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 11</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2957</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1612.</num>
<heading> Public participation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adequate notice and opportunity to comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In exercising his authorities under this subchapter and other laws applicable to the Forest Service, the Secretary, by regulation, shall establish procedures, including public hearings where appropriate, to give the Federal, State, and local governments and the public adequate notice and an opportunity to comment upon the formulation of standards, criteria, and guidelines applicable to Forest Service programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory boards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing for public participation in the planning for and management of the National Forest System, the Secretary, pursuant to chapter 10 of title 5 and other applicable law, shall establish and consult such advisory boards as he deems necessary to secure full information and advice on the execution of his responsibilities. The membership of such boards shall be representative of a cross section of groups interested in the planning for and management of the National Forest System and the various types of use and enjoyment of the lands thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 11</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2958</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(114)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1613.</num>
<heading> Promulgation of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as he determines necessary and desirable to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 15</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 11</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2958</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1614.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this subchapter or the application thereof to any person or circumstances is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this subchapter and of the application of such provision to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–378, § 16</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–588, § 11</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1641.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Forests and rangeland, and the resources of forests and rangeland, are of strategic economic and ecological importance to the United States, and the Federal Government has an important and substantial role in ensuring the continued health, productivity, and sustainability of the forests and rangeland of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Over 75 percent of the productive commercial forest land in the United States is privately owned, with some 60 percent owned by small nonindustrial private owners. These 10,000,000 nonindustrial private owners are critical to providing both commodity and noncommodity values to the citizens of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The National Forest System manages only 17 percent of the commercial timberland of the United States, with over half of the standing softwoods inventory located on that land. Dramatic changes in Federal agency policy during the early 1990’s have significantly curtailed the management of this vast timber resource, causing abrupt shifts in the supply of timber from public to private ownership. As a result of these shifts in supply, some 60 percent of total wood production in the United States is now coming from private forest land in the southern United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> At the same time that pressures are building for the removal of even more land from commercial production, the Federal Government is significantly reducing its commitment to productivity-related research regarding forests and rangeland, which is critically needed by the private sector for the sustained management of remaining available timber and forage resources for the benefit of all species.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Uncertainty over the availability of the United States timber supply, increasing regulatory burdens, and the lack of Federal Government support for research is causing domestic wood and paper producers to move outside the United States to find reliable sources of wood supplies, which in turn results in a worsening of the United States trade balance, the loss of employment and infrastructure investments, and an increased risk of infestations of exotic pests and diseases from imported wood products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Wood and paper producers in the United States are being challenged not only by shifts in Federal Government policy, but also by international competition from tropical countries where growth rates of trees far exceed those in the United States. Wood production per acre will need to quadruple from 1996 levels for the United States forestry sector to remain internationally competitive on an ever decreasing forest land base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Better and more frequent forest inventorying and analysis is necessary to identify productivity-related forestry research needs and to provide forest managers with the current data necessary to make timely and effective management decisions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to other law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter shall be deemed to complement the policies and direction set forth in the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 1600</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter to authorize the Secretary to expand research activities to encompass international forestry and natural resource issues on a global scale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–307, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 611(a)(1)</ref>, formerly § 607(a)(1), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2072</ref>, renumbered § 611(a)(1), <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title II, § 253(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 558</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1642.</num>
<heading> Investigations, experiments, tests, and other activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization; scope and purposes of activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to conduct, support, and cooperate in investigations, experiments, tests, and other activities the Secretary deems necessary to obtain, analyze, develop, demonstrate, and disseminate scientific information about protecting, managing, and utilizing forest and rangeland renewable resources in rural, suburban, and urban areas. The activities conducted, supported, or cooperated in by the Secretary under this subchapter shall include, but not be limited to, the five major areas of renewable resource research identified in paragraphs (1) through (5) of this subsection.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Renewable resource management research shall include, as appropriate, research activities related to managing, reproducing, planting, and growing vegetation on forests and rangelands for timber, forage, water, fish and wildlife, esthetics, recreation, wilderness, energy production, activities related to energy conservation, and other purposes, including activities for encouraging improved reforestation of forest lands from which timber has been harvested; determining the role of forest and rangeland management in the productive use of forests and rangelands, in diversified agriculture, and in mining, transportation, and other industries; and developing alternatives for the management of forests and rangelands that will make possible the most effective use of their multiple products and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Renewable resource environmental research shall include, as appropriate, research activities related to understanding and managing surface and subsurface water flow, preventing and controlling erosion, and restoring damaged or disturbed soils on forest and range­land watersheds; maintaining and improving wildlife and fish habitats; managing vegetation to reduce air and water pollution, provide amenities, and for other purposes; and understanding, predicting, and modifying weather, climatic, and other environmental conditions that affect the protection and management of forests and rangelands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Renewable resource protection research shall include, as appropriate, research activities related to protecting vegetation and other forest and rangeland resources, including threatened and endangered flora and fauna, as well as wood and wood products in storage or use, from fires, insects, diseases, noxious plants, animals, air pollutants, and other agents through biological, chemical, and mechanical control methods and systems; and protecting people, natural resources, and property from fires in rural areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Renewable resource utilization research shall include, as appropriate, research activities related to harvesting, transporting, processing, marketing, distributing, and utilizing wood and other materials derived from forest and rangeland renewable resources; recycling and fully utilizing wood fiber; producing and conserving energy; and testing forest products, including necessary fieldwork associated therewith.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Renewable resource assessment research shall include, as appropriate, research activities related to developing and applying scientific knowledge and technology in support of the survey and analysis of forest and rangeland renewable resources described in subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of periodic Renewable Resource Assessment through survey and analysis of conditions; implementation; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To ensure the availability of adequate data and scientific information for development of the periodic Renewable Resource Assessment provided for in <ref>section 1601 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall make and keep current a comprehensive survey and analysis of the present and prospective conditions of and requirements for renewable resources of the forests and rangelands of the United States and of the supplies of such renewable resources, including a determination of the present and potential productivity of the land, and of such other facts as may be necessary and useful in the determination of ways and means needed to balance the demand for and supply of these renewable resources, benefits, and uses in meeting the needs of the people of the United States. The Secretary shall conduct the survey and analysis under such plans as the Secretary may determine to be fair and equitable, and cooperate with appropriate officials of each State and, either through them or directly, with private or other entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In implementing this subsection, the Secretary is authorized to develop and implement improved methods of survey and analysis of forest inventory information, for which purposes there are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually $10,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program of research and study relative to health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems; advisory committee; reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary, acting through the United States Forest Service, shall establish not later than 180 days after <date date="1988-10-24">October 24, 1988</date>, a 10-year program (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “Program”) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> increase the frequency of forest inventories in matters that relate to atmospheric pollution and conduct such surveys as are necessary to monitor long-term trends in the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determine the scope of the decline in the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> accelerate and expand existing research efforts (including basic forest ecosystem research) to evaluate the effects of atmospheric pollutants on forest ecosystems and their role in the decline in domestic forest health and productivity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> study the relationship between atmospheric pollution and other climatological, chemical, physical, and biological factors that may affect the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> develop recommendations for solving or mitigating problems related to the effects of atmospheric pollution on the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> foster cooperation among Federal, State, and private researchers and encourage the exchange of scientific information on the effects of atmospheric pollutants on forest ecosystems among the United States, Canada, European nations, and other nations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> support the long-term funding of research programs and related efforts to determine the causes of declines in the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems and the effects of atmospheric pollutants on the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> enlarge the Eastern Hardwood Cooperative by devoting additional resources to field analysis of the response of hardwood species to atmospheric pollution, and other factors that may affect the health and productivity of these ecosystems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish a committee to advise the Secretary in developing and carrying out the Program, which shall be composed of scientists with training and experience in various disciplines, including atmospheric, ecological, and biological sciences. Such scientists shall be selected from among individuals who are actively performing research for Federal or State agencies or for private industries, institutions, or organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall coordinate the Program with existing research efforts of Federal and State agencies and private industries, institutions, or organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall submit to the President and to Congress the following reports:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Not less than 30 days before establishing the Program, the Secretary shall submit an initial program report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> discussing existing information about declining health and productivity of forest ecosystems on public and private lands in North America and Europe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> outlining the findings and status of all current research and monitoring efforts in North America and Europe on the causes and effects of atmospheric pollution on the health and productivity of forest ecosystems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> describing the Program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> estimating the cost of implementing the Program for each fiscal year of its duration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than <date date="1990-01-15">January 15, 1990</date>, and January 15 of each year thereafter, during which the Program is in operation following the year in which the initial program report is submitted, the Secretary shall submit an annual report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> updating information about declining health and productivity of forest ecosystems on public and private lands in North America and Europe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> updating the findings and status of all current research and monitoring efforts in North America and Europe on the causes and effects of atmospheric pollution on the health and productivity of forest ecosystems, including efforts conducted under the Program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> recommending additional research and monitoring efforts to be undertaken under the Program to determine the effects of atmospheric pollution on the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> recommending methods for solving or mitigating problems stemming from the effects of atmospheric pollution on the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 10 years after the date on which the initial program report is submitted, the Secretary shall submit a final report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reviewing existing information about declining health and productivity of forest ecosystems on public and private lands in North America and Europe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reviewing the nature and findings of all research and monitoring efforts conducted under the Program and any other relevant research and monitoring efforts related to the effects of atmospheric pollution on forest ecosystem; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> making final recommendations for solving or mitigating problems stemming from the effects of atmospheric pollution on the health and productivity of domestic forest ecosystems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High priority forestry and rangeland research and education</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may conduct, support, and cooperate in forestry and rangeland research and education that is of the highest priority to the United States and to users of public and private forest land and rangeland in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The research and education priorities include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The biology of forest organisms and rangeland organisms.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Functional characteristics and cost-effective management of forest and rangeland ecosystems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Interactions between humans and forests and rangeland.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Wood and forage as a raw material.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> International trade, competition, and cooperation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Northeastern States research cooperative</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">At the request of the Governor of the State of Maine, New Hampshire, New York, or Vermont, the Secretary may cooperate with the northeastern States of New Hampshire, New York, Maine, and Vermont, land-grant colleges and universities of those States, natural resources and forestry schools of those States, other Federal agencies, and other interested persons in those States to coordinate and improve ecological and economic research relating to agricultural research, extension, and education, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> research on ecosystem health, forest management, product development, economics, and related fields;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> research to assist those States and landowners in those States to achieve sustainable forest management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> technology transfer to the wood products industry of technologies that promote efficient processing, pollution prevention, and energy conservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> dissemination of existing and new information to landowners, public and private resource managers, State forest citizen advisory committees, and the general public through professional associations, publications, and other information clearinghouse activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> analysis of strategies for the protection of areas of outstanding ecological significance or high biological diversity, and strategies for the provision of important recreational opportunities and traditional uses, including strategies for areas identified through State land conservation planning processes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest inventory and analysis</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In compliance with other applicable provisions of law, the Secretary shall establish a program to inventory and analyze, in a timely manner, public and private forests and their resources in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual State inventory</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than the end of each full fiscal year beginning after <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, the Secretary shall prepare for each State, in cooperation with the State forester for the State, an inventory of forests and their resources in the State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sample plots</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of preparing the inventory for a State, the Secretary shall measure annually 20 percent of all sample plots that are included in the inventory program for that State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compilation of inventory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On completion of the inventory for a year, the Secretary shall make available to the public a compilation of all data collected for that year from measurements of sample plots as well as any analysis made of the samples.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 5-year reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not more often than every 5 full fiscal years after <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, the Secretary shall prepare, publish, and make available to the public a report, prepared in cooperation with State foresters, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contains a description of each State inventory of forests and their resources, incorporating all sample plot measurements conducted during the 5 years covered by the report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> displays and analyzes on a nationwide basis the results of the annual reports required by paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contains an analysis of forest health conditions and trends over the previous 2 decades, with an emphasis on such conditions and trends during the period subsequent to the immediately preceding report under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National standards and definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To ensure uniform and consistent data collection for all forest land that is publicly or privately owned and for each State, the Secretary shall develop, in consultation with State foresters and Federal land management agencies not under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, and publish national standards and definitions to be applied in inventorying and analyzing forests and their resources under this subsection. The standards shall include a core set of variables to be measured on all sample plots under paragraph (2) and a standard set of tables to be included in the reports under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection for private property rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall obtain authorization from property owners prior to collecting data from sample plots located on private property pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a strategic plan to implement and carry out this subsection, including the annual updates required by paragraph (2) and the reports required by paragraph (3), that shall describe in detail—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the financial resources required to implement and carry out this subsection, including the identification of any resources required in excess of the amounts provided for forest inventorying and analysis in recent appropriations Acts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the personnel necessary to implement and carry out this subsection, including any personnel in addition to personnel currently performing inventorying and analysis functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the organization and procedures necessary to implement and carry out this subsection, including proposed coordination with Federal land management agencies and State foresters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the schedules for annual sample plot measurements in each State inventory required by paragraph (2) within the first 5-year interval after <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the core set of variables to be measured in each sample plot under paragraph (2) and the standard set of tables to be used in each State and national report under paragraph (3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the process for employing, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, remote sensing, global positioning systems, and other advanced technologies to carry out this subsection, and the subsequent use of the technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–307, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 254</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–521, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2601</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1241(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title II, § 253(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 559</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title VII, § 753(a)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–32.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1643.</num>
<heading> Implementation of provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and maintenance of research facilities; acquisition, expenditures, etc., for property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this subchapter, the Secretary is authorized to establish and maintain a system of experiment stations, research laboratories, experimental areas, and other forest and rangeland research facilities. The Secretary is authorized, with donated or appropriated funds, to acquire by lease, donation, purchase, exchange, or otherwise, land or interests in land within the United States needed to implement this subchapter, to make necessary expenditures to examine, appraise, and survey such property, and to do all things incident to perfecting title thereto in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance, holding, and administration of gifts, donations, and bequests; use and investment of gifts, proceeds, etc.; funding requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this subchapter, the Secretary is authorized to accept, hold, and administer gifts, donations, and bequests of money, real property, or personal property from any source not otherwise prohibited by law and to use such gifts, donations, and bequests to (1) establish or operate any forest and rangeland research facility within the United States, or (2) perform any forest and rangeland renewable resource research activity authorized by this subchapter. Such gifts, donations, and bequests, or the proceeds thereof, and money appropriated for these purposes shall be deposited in the Treasury in a special fund. At the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury may invest or reinvest any money in the fund that in the opinion of the Secretary is not needed for current operations. Such investments shall be in public debt securities with maturities suitable for the needs of the fund and bearing interest at prevailing market rates. There are hereby authorized to be expended from such fund such amounts as may be specified in annual appropriation Acts, which shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with international, Federal, State, and other governmental agencies, public and private agencies, etc.; funding requirements for contributions from cooperators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this subchapter, the Secretary may cooperate with international, Federal, State, and other governmental agencies, with public or private agencies, institutions, universities, and organizations, and with businesses and individuals in the United States and in other countries. The Secretary may receive money and other contributions from cooperators under such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe. Any money contributions received under this subsection shall be credited to the applicable appropriation or fund to be used for the same purposes and shall remain available until expended as the Secretary may direct for use in conducting research activities authorized by this subchapter and in making refunds to contributors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–307, § 4(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 354</ref>, 355; <ref>Pub. L. 101–513, title VI, § 611(a)(2)</ref>, formerly § 607(a)(2), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2072</ref>, renumbered § 611(a)(2), <ref>Pub. L. 102–574, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1644.</num>
<heading> Forestry and rangeland competitive research grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive grant authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any grants made under other laws, the Secretary is authorized to make competitive grants that will further research activities authorized by this subchapter to Federal, State, and other governmental agencies, public or private agencies, institutions, universities, and organizations, and businesses and individuals in the United States. In making these grants, the Secretary shall emphasize basic and applied research activities that are important to achieving the purposes of this subchapter, and shall obtain, through review by qualified scientists and other methods, participation in research activities by scientists throughout the United States who have expertise in matters related to forest and rangeland renewable resources. Grants under this section shall be made at the discretion of the Secretary under whatever conditions the Secretary may prescribe, after publicly soliciting research proposals, allowing sufficient time for submission of the proposals, and considering qualitative, quantitative, financial, administrative, and other factors that the Secretary deems important in judging, comparing, and accepting the proposals. The Secretary may reject any or all proposals received under this section if the Secretary determines that it is in the public interest to do so.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emphasis on certain high priority forestry research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may use up to 5 percent of the amounts made available for research under <ref>section 1642 of this title</ref> to make competitive grants regarding forestry research in the high priority research areas identified under <ref>section 1642(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emphasis on certain high priority rangeland research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may use up to 5 percent of the amounts made available for research under <ref>section 1642 of this title</ref> to make competitive grants regarding rangeland research in the high priority research areas identified under <ref>section 1642(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making grants under subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary shall give priority to research proposals under which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the proposed research will be collaborative research organized through a center of scientific excellence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the applicant agrees to provide matching funds (in the form of direct funding or in-kind support) in an amount equal to not less than 50 percent of the grant amount; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the proposed research will be conducted as part of an existing private and public partnership or cooperative research effort and involves several interested research partners.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–307, § 5</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title II, § 253(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1645.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds to cooperators and grantees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make funds available to cooperators and grantees under this subchapter without regard to the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31, which prohibits advances of public money.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of cooperative aid and grants with other aid and grant authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To avoid duplication, the Secretary shall coordinate cooperative aid and grants under this subchapter with cooperative aid and grants the Secretary makes under any other authority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination of knowledge and technology developed from research activities; cooperation with specified entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall use the authorities and means available to the Secretary to disseminate the knowledge and technology developed from research activities conducted under or supported by this subchapter. In meeting this responsibility, the Secretary shall cooperate, as the Secretary deems appropriate, with the entities identified in subsection (d)(3) of this section and with others.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional implementative authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In implementing this subchapter, the Secretary, as the Secretary deems appropriate and practical, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use, and encourage cooperators and grantees to use, the best available scientific skills from a variety of disciplines within and outside the fields of agriculture and forestry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> seek, and encourage cooperators and grantees to seek, a proper mixture of short-term and long-term research and a proper mixture of basic and applied research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> avoid unnecessary duplication and coordinate activities under this section among agencies of the Department of Agriculture and with other affected Federal departments and agencies, State agricultural experiment stations, State extension services, State foresters or equivalent State officials, forestry schools, and private research organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage the development, employment, retention, and exchange of qualified scientists and other specialists through postgraduate, postdoctoral, and other training, national and international exchange of scientists, and other incentives and programs to improve the quality of forest and rangeland renewable resources research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of statutory provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter shall be construed as supplementing all other laws relating to the Department of Agriculture and shall not be construed as limiting or repealing any existing law or authority of the Secretary except as specifically cited in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter, the terms “United States” and “State” shall include each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–307, § 6</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1646.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated annually such sums as may be needed to implement this subchapter. Funds appropriated under this subchapter shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–307, § 7</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1647.</num>
<heading> Other Federal programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repeal of statutory authorities relating to investigation, experiments, and tests in reforestation and forest products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1928-05-22">May 22, 1928</date>, known as the McSweeney-McNary Act (<ref>45 Stat. 699–702</ref>, as amended; <ref>16 U.S.C. 581</ref>, 581a, 581b–581i), is hereby repealed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Force and effect of cooperative and other agreements under repealed statutory authorities relating to investigation, etc., in reforestation and forest products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Contracts and cooperative and other agreements under the McSweeney-McNary Act shall remain in effect until revoked or amended by their own terms or under other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of rules and regulations for implementation of provisions and coordination with agricultural research, extension, and teaching provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to issue such rules and regulations as the Secretary deems necessary to implement the provisions of this subchapter and to coordinate this subchapter with title XIV of the Food and Agriculture Act of 1977 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds appropriated under repealed statutory authorities relating to investigation, etc., in reforestation and forest products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated under the authority of the McSweeney-McNary Act shall be available for expenditure for the programs authorized under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–307, § 8</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1648.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8201</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4839</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1649.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8202</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4839</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1649a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8004</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1650.</num>
<heading> Hardwood technology transfer and applied research</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter the “Secretary”) is hereby and hereafter authorized to conduct technology transfer and development, training, dissemination of information and applied research in the management, processing and utilization of the hardwood forest resource. This authority is in addition to any other authorities which may be available to the Secretary including, but not limited to, the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978, as amended (<ref>16 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.), and the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Act of 1978, as amended (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1600–161</ref>4).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002672">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements; gifts and donations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this authority, the Secretary may enter into grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements with public and private agencies, organizations, corporations, institutions and individuals. The Secretary may accept gifts and donations pursuant to <ref>section 2269 of title 7</ref> including gifts and donations from a donor that conducts business with any agency of the Department of Agriculture or is regulated by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of assets of Wood Education and Resource Center; establishment of Institute of Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby and hereafter authorized to operate and utilize the assets of the Wood Education and Resource Center (previously named the Robert C. Byrd Hardwood Technology Center in West Virginia) as part of a newly formed “Institute of Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research” (hereinafter the “Institute”). The Institute, in addition to the Wood Education and Resource Center, will consist of a Director, technology transfer specialists from State and Private Forestry, the Forestry Sciences Laboratory in Princeton, West Virginia, and any other organizational unit of the Department of Agriculture as the Secretary deems appropriate. The overall management of the Institute will be the responsibility of the Forest Service, State and Private Forestry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Generation of revenue; deposit into Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby and hereafter authorized to generate revenue using the authorities provided herein. Any revenue received as part of the operation of the Institute shall be deposited into a special fund in the Treasury of the United States, known as the “Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research Fund”, which shall be available to the Secretary until expended, without further appropriation, in furtherance of the purposes of this section, including upkeep, management, and operation of the Institute and the payment of salaries and expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby and hereafter authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 332]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–197.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>EXTENSION PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1671.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the extension program of the Department of Agriculture and the extension activities of each State provide useful and productive educational programs for private forest and range landowners and processors and consumptive and nonconsumptive users of forest and rangeland renewable resources, and these educational programs complement research and assistance programs conducted by the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to meet national goals, it is essential that all forest and rangeland renewable resources (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as “renewable resources”), including fish and wildlife, forage, outdoor recreation opportunities, timber, and water, be fully considered in designing educational programs for landowners, processors, and users;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> more efficient utilization and marketing of renewable resources extend available supplies of such resources, provide products to consumers at prices less than they would otherwise be, and promote reasonable returns on the investments of landowners, processors, and users;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> trees and forests in urban areas improve the esthetic quality, reduce noise, filter impurities from the air and add oxygen to it, save energy by moderating temperature extremes, control wind and water erosion, and provide habitat for wildlife; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> trees and shrubs used as shelterbelts protect farm lands from wind and water erosion, promote moisture accumulation in the soil, and provide habitat for wildlife.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1672.</num>
<heading> General program authorization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of programs; preconditions and cooperation with State program directors, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”), under conditions the Secretary may prescribe and in cooperation with the State directors of cooperative extension service programs and eligible colleges and universities, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide educational programs that enable individuals to recognize, analyze, and resolve problems dealing with renewable resources, including forest- and range-based outdoor recreation opportunities, trees and forests in urban areas, and trees and shrubs in shelterbelts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use educational programs to disseminate the results of research on renewable resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct educational programs that transfer the best available technology to those involved in the management and protection of forests and rangelands and the processing and use of their associated renewable resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop and implement educational programs that give special attention to the educational needs of small, private nonindustrial forest landowners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop and implement educational programs in range and fish and wildlife management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> assist in providing continuing education programs for professionally trained individuals in fish and wildlife, forest, range, and watershed management and related fields;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> help forest and range landowners in securing technical and financial assistance to bring appropriate expertise to bear on their problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> help identify areas of needed research regarding renewable resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> in cooperation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, promote public understanding of the energy conservation, economic, social, environmental, and psychological values of trees and open space in urban and community area environments and expand knowledge of the ecological relationships and benefits of trees and related resources in urban and community environments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> conduct a comprehensive natural resource and environmental education program for landowners and managers, public officials, and the public, with particular emphasis on youth.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Eligible colleges and universities” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this subchapter, the term “eligible colleges and universities” means colleges and universities eligible to be supported and maintained, in whole or in part, with funds made available under the provisions of the Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date> (<ref>12 Stat. 503–505</ref>, as amended; <ref>7 U.S.C. 301–305</ref>, 307, 308), and the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref>26 Stat. 417–419</ref>, as amended; <ref>7 U.S.C. 321–326</ref>, 328), including Tuskegee Institute, and colleges and universities eligible for assistance under the Act of <date date="1962-10-10">October 10, 1962</date> (<ref>76 Stat. 806–807</ref>, as amended; <ref>16 U.S.C. 582a</ref>, 582a–1—582a–7).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of appropriate educational methods required; scope of methods</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this section, all appropriate educational methods may be used, including, but not limited to, meetings, short courses, workshops, tours, demonstrations, publications, news releases, and radio and television programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1219(b)(1), 1251(b), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3538</ref>, 3552; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1018(d)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1673.</num>
<heading> State programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development by State program director, etc., of comprehensive and coordinated program by mutual agreement; consultations; review procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The State director of cooperative extension programs (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “State director”) and the administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities in each State shall jointly develop, by mutual agreement, a single comprehensive and coordinated renewable resources extension program in which the role of each eligible college and university is well-defined. In meeting this responsibility, the State director and the administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities shall consult and seek agreement with the administrative technical representatives and the forestry representatives provided for by the Secretary in implementation of the Act of <date date="1962-10-10">October 10, 1962</date> (<ref>76 Stat. 806–807</ref>, as amended; <ref>16 U.S.C. 582a</ref>, 582a–1—582a–7), in the State. Each State’s renewable resources extension program shall be submitted to the Secretary annually. The National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board established under <ref>section 3123 of title 7</ref> shall review and make recommendations to the Secretary pertaining to programs conducted under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Encouragement by State director, etc., of cooperation between county and State extension staffs and appropriate Federal and State agencies and organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The State director and the administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities in each State shall encourage close cooperation between extension staffs at the county and State levels, and State and Federal research organizations dealing with renewable resources, State and Federal agencies that manage forests and rangelands and their associated renewable resources, State and Federal agencies that have responsibilities associated with the processing or use of renewable resources, and other agencies or organizations the State director and administrative heads of extension deem appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and coordination of program by State director; exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State renewable resources extension program shall be administered and coordinated by the State director, except that, in States having colleges eligible to receive funds under the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref>26 Stat. 417–419</ref>, as amended; <ref>7 U.S.C. 321–326</ref>, 328), including Tuskegee Institute, the State renewable resources extension program shall be administered by the State director and the administrative head or heads of extension for the college or colleges eligible to receive such funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and use of advisory committees by State director, etc.; composition of advisory committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In meeting the provisions of this section, each State director and administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities shall appoint and use one or more advisory committees comprised of forest and range landowners, professionally trained individuals in fish and wildlife, forest, range, and watershed management, and related fields, as appropriate, and other suitable persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “State” means any one of the fifty States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the District of Columbia, and the Virgin Islands of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 802(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1674.</num>
<heading> Renewable Resources Extension Program plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation and submission to Congress; purposes; contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare a five-year plan for implementing this subchapter, which is to be called the “Renewable Resources Extension Program” and shall submit such plan to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate no later than the last day of the first half of the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, and the last day of the first half of each fifth fiscal year thereafter. The Renewable Resources Extension Program shall provide national emphasis and direction as well as guidance to State directors and administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities in the development of their respective State renewable resources extension programs, which are to be appropriate in terms of the conditions, needs, and opportunities in each State. The Renewable Resources Extension Program shall contain, but not be limited to, brief outlines of general extension programs for fish and wildlife management (for both game and nongame species), range management, timber management (including brief outlines of general extension programs for timber utilization, timber harvesting, timber marketing, wood utilization, and wood products marketing), and watershed management (giving special attention to water quality protection), as well as brief outlines of general extension programs for recognition and enhancement of forest- and range-based outdoor recreation opportunities, for urban and community forestry activities, and for planting and management of trees and shrubs in shelterbelts, and give special attention to water quality protection and natural resource and environmental education for landowners and managers, public officials, and the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations governing preparation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In preparing the Renewable Resources Extension Program, the Secretary shall take into account the respective capabilities of private forests and rangelands for yielding renewable resources and the relative needs for such resources identified in the periodic Renewable Resource Assessment provided for in <ref>section 1601 of this title</ref> and the periodic appraisal of land and water resources provided for in <ref>section 2004 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of activities and evaluation of progress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist Congress and the public in evaluating the Renewable Resources Extension Program, the program shall include a review of activities undertaken in response to the preceding five-year plan and an evaluation of the progress made toward accomplishing the goals and objectives set forth in such preceding plan. Such review and evaluation shall be displayed in the program, for the Nation as a whole, and for each State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 5</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–231, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-01-05">Jan. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII</ref>, §§ 1219(b)(2), 1251(c), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3539</ref>, 3553.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1674a.</num>
<heading> Expanded programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and the State cooperative extension services, and in consultation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, school boards, and universities, shall expand forestry and natural resources education programs conducted under this subchapter for private forest owners and managers, public officials, youth, and the general public, and shall include guidelines for the transfer of technology.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In expanding the programs conducted under this subchapter, the Secretary shall ensure that activities are undertaken to promote policies and practices that enhance the health, vitality, productivity, economic value, and environmental attributes of the forest lands of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The activities referred to in paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> demonstrating and teaching landowners and forest managers the concepts of multiple-use and sustainable natural resource management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conducting comprehensive environmental education programs that assist citizens to participate in environmentally positive activities such as tree planting, recycling, erosion prevention, and waste management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> educational programs and materials that will improve the capacity of schools, local governments and resource agencies to deliver forestry and natural resources information to young people, environmentally concerned citizens, and action groups.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 5A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1251(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3552</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(34)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(c)(34), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2032.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1674b.</num>
<heading> Sustainable Forestry Outreach Initiative</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the “Sustainable Forestry Outreach Initiative”, to educate landowners concerning the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The value and benefits of practicing sustainable forestry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The importance of professional forestry advice in achieving sustainable forestry objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The variety of public and private sector resources available to assist the landowners in planning for and practicing sustainable forestry.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 5B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VIII, § 8101(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1675.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations; criteria for eligibility of States for funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subchapter $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2023. Generally, States shall be eligible for funds appropriated under this subchapter according to the respective capabilities of their private forests and rangelands for yielding renewable resources and relative needs for such resources identified in the periodic Renewable Resource Assessment provided for in <ref>section 1601 of this title</ref> and the periodic appraisal of land and water resources provided for in <ref>section 2004 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 6</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–231, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-01-05">Jan. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–185, title III, § 301(h)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–171, title VIII, § 8101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7413(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7413(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2017; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VII, § 7405(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 898</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7509(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1676.</num>
<heading> Issuance of rules and regulations for implementation of provisions and coordination with agricultural, research, extension, and teaching provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to issue such rules and regulations as the Secretary deems necessary to implement the provisions of this subchapter and to coordinate this subchapter with title XIV of the Food and Agriculture Act of 1977 [<ref>7 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–306, § 7</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>WOOD RESIDUE UTILIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1681.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to develop, demonstrate, and make available information on feasible methods that have potential for commercial application to increase and improve utilization, in residential, commercial, and industrial or powerplant applications, of wood residues resulting from timber harvesting and forest protection and management activities occurring on public and private forest lands, and from the manufacture of forest products, including woodpulp.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–554, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1682.</num>
<heading> Pilot projects and demonstrations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment, implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may establish pilot projects and demonstrations to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. The pilot projects and demonstrations established under this section (1) may be operated by the Secretary; or (2) may be carried out through contracts or agreements with owners of private forest lands or other persons, or in conjunction with projects, contracts, or agreements entered into under any other authority which the Secretary may possess: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing contained in this subchapter shall abrogate or modify provisions of existing contracts or agreements, including contracts or agreements for the sale of national forest timber, except to the extent such changes are mutually agreed to by the parties to such contracts or agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope; residue removal credits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pilot projects and demonstrations carried out under this section may include, but are not limited to (1) establishment and operation of utilization demonstration areas; (2) establishment and operation of fuel wood concentration and distribution centers; and (3) construction of access roads needed to facilitate wood residue utilization: <i>Provided</i>, That residue removal credits may be utilized by the Secretary only as provided in <ref>section 1683 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–554, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1683.</num>
<heading> Pilot projects; requirements; residue removal credits as compensation; implementation guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may carry out pilot wood residue utilization projects under which purchasers of National Forest System timber under contracts awarded prior to <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>, may, except as otherwise provided in this section, be required to remove wood residues not purchased by them to points of prospective use in return for compensation in the form of “residue removal credits.” Such projects may be carried out where the Secretary identifies situations in which pilot wood residue utilization projects on the National Forest system can provide important information on various methods and approaches to increasing the utilization, in residential, commercial, and industrial or powerplant applications, of wood residues and where such information cannot reasonably be obtained unless the pilot projects are done in conjunction with normal National Forest timber sale activities. The residue removal credits shall be applied against the amount payable for the timber purchased and shall represent the anticipated cost of removal of wood residues. The following guidelines shall apply to projects carried out under this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except in cases where wood residue removal is determined to be necessary for fire prevention, site preparation for regeneration, wildlife habitat improvement, or other land management purposes, the Secretary may not provide for removal of wood residues in instances where the anticipated cost of removal would exceed the anticipated value.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The residue removal credits authorized by this section shall not exceed the amount payable by the purchaser for timber after the application of all other designated charges and credits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may sell the wood residues removed to points of prospective use for not less than their appraised value.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Pilot projects, demonstrations, and other programs established pursuant to this subchapter shall be carried out in a manner which does not result in an adverse effect on the furnishing of timber, free of charge, under any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Wood residues shall be collected from a site so as to avoid soil depletion or erosion giving full consideration to the protection of wildlife habitat.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For the purposes of <ref>section 500 of this title</ref>, (A) any residue removal credit applied under this section shall be considered as “money received” or “moneys received”, respectively, and (B) the “money received” or “moneys received”, respectively, from the sales of wood residues removed to points of prospective use shall be the proceeds of the sales less the sum of any residue removal credit applied with respect to such residues plus any costs incurred by the Forest Service in processing and storing such residues.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–554, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1684.</num>
<heading> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make annual reports to the Congress on the programs authorized by this subchapter. These reports shall be submitted with the reports required under <ref>section 1606(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–554, § 5</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1685.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary deems necessary to implement the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–554, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1686.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Anticipated cost of removal” means the projected cost of removal of wood residues from timber sales areas to points of prospective use, as determined by the Secretary at the time of advertisement of the timber sales contract in accordance with appropriate appraisal and sale procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Anticipated value” means the projected value of wood residues as fuel or other merchantable wood products, as determined by the Secretary at the time of advertisement of the timber sales contract in accordance with appropriate appraisal and sale procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Points of prospective use” means the locations where the wood residues are sold or otherwise put to use, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with appropriate appraisal and sale procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Person” means an individual, partnership, joint-stock company, corporation, association, trust, estate, or any other legal entity, or any agency of Federal or State government or of a political subdivision of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “Wood residues” includes, but is not limited to, logging slash, down timber material, woody plants, and standing live or dead trees which do not meet utilization standards because of size, species, merchantable volume, or economic selection criteria and which, in the case of live trees, are surplus to growing stock needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–554, § 7</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1687.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $25,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985, and 1986 to carry out the pilot projects and demonstrations authorized by <ref>section 1682 of this title</ref>, the residue removal credits authorized by <ref>section 1683 of this title</ref>, and the other provisions of this subchapter: <i>Provided</i>, That not to exceed $2,500,000 of such amount may be appropriated for administrative expenses to carry out this subchapter for the period beginning <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, and ending <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>. Such sums shall be in addition to those provided under other provisions of law and shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–554, § 8</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>