<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 94—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL OCEANS AND COASTAL SECURITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coastal county</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “coastal county” has the meaning given the term by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in the document entitled “NOAA’s List of Coastal Counties for the Bureau of the Census” (or similar successor document).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coastal State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “coastal State” has the meaning given the term “coastal state” in <ref>section 1453 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Foundation” means the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation established by <ref>section 3701(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Fund” means the National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund established under <ref>section 7503(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” means any federally recognized Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise specifically provided, the term “Administrator” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tidal shoreline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “tidal shoreline” has the meaning given that term pursuant to section 923.110(c)(2)(i) of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or a similar successor regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3031</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7502.</num>
<heading> Purposes and agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to better understand and utilize the oceans, coasts, and Great Lakes of the United States, and ensure present and future generations will benefit from the full range of ecological, economic, social, and recreational opportunities, security, and services these resources are capable of providing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator and the Foundation may enter into such agreements as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3031</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7503.</num>
<heading> National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator and the Foundation are authorized to establish the National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund as a tax exempt fund to further the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be deposited into the Fund amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibitions on donations from foreign governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No amounts donated by a foreign government, as defined in <ref>section 7342 of title 5</ref>, may be deposited into the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any amounts received by the Foundation pursuant to this chapter shall be subject to the provisions of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.), except the provisions of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 4(e)(1)(B) of that Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3703(e)(1)(B)</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> section 10(a) of that Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amounts deposited into the Fund for each fiscal year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> funds may be used by the Foundation to award grants to coastal States under <ref>section 7505(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> funds may be used by the Foundation to award grants under <ref>section 7505(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> no more than 2 percent may be used by the Administrator and the Foundation for administrative expenses to carry out this chapter, which amount shall be divided between the Administrator and the Foundation pursuant to an agreement reached and documented by both the Administrator and the Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery of payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Administrator is authorized to recover any Federal payments under this section if the Foundation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> makes a withdrawal or expenditure from the Fund that is not consistent with the requirements of <ref>section 7504 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fails to comply with a procedure, measure, method, or standard established under <ref>section 7505(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3031</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7504.</num>
<heading> Eligible uses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Fund may be allocated by the Foundation to support programs and activities intended to better understand and utilize ocean and coastal resources, coastal infrastructure, and ecosystem services provided by natural systems such as coral reefs, including baseline scientific research, ocean observing, and other programs and activities carried out in coordination with Federal and State departments or agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on use of funds for litigation or other purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No funds made available under this chapter may be used to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fund litigation against the Federal Government; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fund the creation of national marine monuments and marine protected areas, marine spatial planning, or the National Ocean Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3032</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title C, § 10001(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7505.</num>
<heading> Grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after funds are deposited into the Fund and made available to the Foundation for administrative purposes, the Foundation shall establish the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Application and review procedures for the awarding of grants under this section, including requirements ensuring that any amounts awarded under such subsections may only be used for an eligible use described under <ref>section 7504 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Selection procedures and criteria for the awarding of grants under this section that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> require consultation with the Administrator and the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> prioritize the projects or activities where non-Federal partners have committed to share the cost of the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Eligibility criteria for awarding grants—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under subsection (b) to coastal States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> under subsection (c) to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> entities including States, local governments, and Indian tribes; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the research and restoration work of associations, nongovernmental organizations, public-private partnerships, and academic institutions.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Performance accountability and monitoring measures for programs and activities funded by a grant awarded under subsection (b) or (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Procedures and methods to ensure accurate accounting and appropriate administration of grants awarded under this section, including standards of recordkeeping.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Procedures to carry out audits of the Fund as necessary, but not less frequently than once every year if grants have been awarded in that year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Procedures to carry out audits of the recipients of grants under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Procedures to make publicly available on the Internet a list of all projects funded by the Fund, that includes at a minimum the grant recipient, grant amount, project description, and project status.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Foundation shall submit to the Administrator for approval each procedure, measure, method, and standard established under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants to coastal States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Administrator and the Foundation may award grants according to the procedures established in subsection (a) to coastal States and United States territories to support activities consistent with section 7503 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002862">1</ref> of this title. In determining distribution of grants, the Foundation may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> consider for each State—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> percent of total United States shoreline miles;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> coastal population density; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other factors;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish criteria for States, including the requirement for a State to establish a plan to distribute the funds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establish a maximum and minimum percentage of funding to be awarded to each State or United States territory.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition on receipt of a grant under this subsection, a State that receives a grant under this subsection shall ensure that Indian tribes in the State are eligible to participate in any competitive grants established in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National grants for oceans, coasts, and Great Lakes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator and the Foundation may award grants according to the procedures established in subsection (a) to support activities consistent with <ref>section 7504 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory panel</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Foundation may establish an advisory panel to conduct reviews of applications for grants under paragraph (1) and the Foundation may consider the recommendations of the advisory panel with respect to such applications.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The advisory panel described under subparagraph (A) shall include persons representing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ocean and coastal dependent industries;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> geographic regions as defined by the Foundation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> academic institutions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3032</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7506.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002863">1</ref> beginning with fiscal year 2017, not later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Foundation shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the operation of the Fund during that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each annual report submitted under subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a full and complete statement of the receipts, including the source of all receipts, expenditures, and investments of the Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement of the amounts deposited in the Fund and the balance remaining in the Fund at the end of the fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the expenditures made from the Fund for the fiscal year, including the purpose of the expenditures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IX, § 907</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3034</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7507.</num>
<heading> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary for fiscal years 2017, 2018, and 2019 for this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IX, § 908</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3034</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>