<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>FISH AND WILDLIFE SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 741.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 88–488, title IV, § 402(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 492</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742a.</num>
<heading> Declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress declares that the fish, shellfish, and wildlife resources of the Nation make a material contribution to our national economy and food supply, as well as a material contribution to the health, recreation, and well-being of our citizens; that such resources are a living, renewable form of national wealth that is capable of being maintained and greatly increased with proper management, but equally capable of destruction if neglected or unwisely exploited; that such resources afford outdoor recreation throughout the Nation and provide employment, directly or indirectly, to a substantial number of citizens; that the fishing industries strengthen the defense of the United States through the provision of a trained seafaring citizenry and action-ready fleets of seaworthy vessels; that the training and sport afforded by fish and wildlife resources strengthen the national defense by contributing to the general health and physical fitness of millions of citizens; and that properly developed, such fish and wildlife resources are capable of steadily increasing these valuable contributions to the life of the Nation.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Congress further declares that the fishing industry, in its several branches, can prosper and thus fulfill its proper function in national life only if certain fundamental needs are satisfied by means that are consistent with the public interest and in accord with constitutional functions of governments. Among these needs are:</p>
<p class="indent1">(1) Freedom of enterprise—freedom to develop new areas, methods, products, and markets in accordance with sound economic principles, as well as freedom from unnecessary administrative or legal restrictions that unreasonably conflict with or ignore economic needs;</p>
<p class="indent1">(2) Protection of opportunity—maintenance of an economic atmosphere in which domestic production and processing can prosper; protection from subsidized competing products; protection of opportunity to fish on the high seas in accordance with international law;</p>
<p class="indent1">(3) Assistance—assistance consistent with that provided by the Government for industry generally, such as is involved in promoting good industrial relations, fair trade standards, harmonious labor relations, better health standards and sanitation; and including, but not limited to—</p>
<p class="indent2">(a) services to provide current information on production and trade, market promotion and development, and an extension service,</p>
<p class="indent2">(b) research services for economic and technologic development and resource conservation, and</p>
<p class="indent2">(c) resource management to assure the maximum sustainable production for the fisheries.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Congress further declares that the provisions of this Act are necessary in order to accomplish the objective of proper resource development, and that this Act shall be administered with due regard to the inherent right of every citizen and resident of the United States to engage in fishing for his own pleasure, enjoyment, and betterment, and with the intent of maintaining and increasing the public opportunities for recreational use of our fish and wildlife resources, and stimulating the development of a strong, prosperous, and thriving fishery and fish processing industry.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 2</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1119</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742b.</num>
<heading> United States Fish and Wildlife Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistant Secretary for Fish and Wildlife</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of the Interior the position of Assistant Secretary for Fish and Wildlife. Such Assistant Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be compensated at the same rate as other Assistant Secretaries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; Director of United States Fish and Wildlife Service; appointment; qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of the Interior the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. The functions of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall be administered under the supervision of the Director, who shall be subject to the supervision of the Assistant Secretary for Fish and Wildlife. The Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. No individual may be appointed as the Director unless he is, by reason of scientific education and experience, knowledgeable in the principles of fisheries and wildlife management.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Succession to United States Fish and Wildlife Service and Bureau of Sport Fisheries and Wildlife</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Fish and Wildlife Service established by subsection (b) shall succeed to and replace the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (as constituted on <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>) and the Bureau of Sport Fisheries and Wildlife (as constituted on such date). All laws and regulations in effect on <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, which relate to matters administered by the Department of the Interior through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (as constituted on such date) and the Bureau of Sport Fisheries and Wildlife (as constituted on such date) shall remain in effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions and responsibilities of Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All functions and responsibilities placed in the Department of the Interior or any official thereof by this Act shall be included among the functions and responsibilities of the Secretary of the Interior, as the head of the Department, and shall be carried out under his direction pursuant to such procedures or delegations of authority as he may deem advisable and in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–367, title I, § 103(14)</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 788</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–793, § 607(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–271, § 1</ref>, <date date="1974-04-22">Apr. 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 92</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742b–1.</num>
<heading> Assistant Director for Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the United States Fish and Wildlife Service of the Department of the Interior the position of Assistant Director for Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Superior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Director for Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs shall report directly to the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Director for Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Programs shall be responsible for the administration, management, and oversight of the Federal Assistance Program for State Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration under the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 669</ref> et seq.) and the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 777</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–408, title I, § 132</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742c.</num>
<heading> Loans for financing or refinancing of cost of purchasing, constructing, equipping, maintaining, repairing, or operating commercial fishing vessels or gear</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, under such rules and regulations and under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, to make loans for financing or refinancing of the cost of purchasing, constructing, equipping, maintaining, repairing, or operating new or used commercial fishing vessels or gear.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any loans made under the provisions of this section shall be subject to the following restrictions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Bear an interest rate of not less than (a) a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the average market yield on outstanding Treasury obligations of comparable maturity, plus (b) such additional charge, if any, toward covering other costs of the program as the Secretary may determine to be consistent with its purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Mature in not more than ten years, except that where a loan is for all or part of the costs of constructing a new fishing vessel, such period may be fourteen years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No financial assistance shall be extended pursuant to this section unless reasonable financial assistance applied for is not otherwise available on reasonable terms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Loans shall be approved only upon the furnishing of such security or other reasonable assurance of repayment as the Secretary may require considering the objectives of this section which are to upgrade commercial fishing vessels and gear and to provide reasonable financial assistance not otherwise available to commercial fishermen. The proposed collateral for a loan must be of such a nature that, when considered with the integrity and ability of the management, and the applicant’s past and prospective earnings, repayment of the loan will be reasonably assured.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The applicant shall possess the ability, experience, resources, and other qualifications necessary to enable him to operate and maintain new or used commercial fishing vessels or gear.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Before the Secretary approves a loan for the purchase or construction of a new or used vessel which will not replace an existing commercial fishing vessel, he shall determine that the applicant’s contemplated operation of such vessel in a fishery will not cause economic hardship or injury to the efficient vessel operators already operating in that fishery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> An applicant for a fishery loan must be a citizen or national of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Within the meaning of this section, a corporation, partnership, or association shall not be deemed to be a citizen of the United States unless the Secretary determines that it satisfactorily meets all of the requirements set forth in <ref>section 50501 of title 46</ref> for determining the United States citizenship of a corporation, partnership, or association operating a vessel in the coastwise trade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The nationality of an applicant shall be established to the satisfaction of the Secretary. Within the meaning of this section, no corporation, partnership, or association organized under the laws of American Samoa shall be deemed a national of the United States unless 75 per centum of the interest therein is owned by nationals of the United States, citizens of the United States, or both, and in the case of a corporation, unless its president or other chief executive officer and the chairman of its board are nationals or citizens of the United States and unless no more of its directors than a minority of the number necessary to constitute a quorum are nonnationals and noncitizens.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Seventy-five per centum of the interest in a corporation shall not be deemed to be owned by nationals of the United States, citizens of the United States, or both, (i) if the title to 75 per centum of its stock is not vested in such nationals and citizens free from any trust or fiduciary obligation in favor of any person not a national or citizen of the United States; or (ii) if 75 per centum of the voting power in such corporation is not vested in nationals of the United States, citizens of the United States, or both; or (iii) if through any contract or understanding it is so arranged that more than 25 per centum of the voting power may be exercised, directly or indirectly, in behalf of any person who is not a national or citizen of the United States; or (iv) if by any other means whatsoever control of any interest in the corporation in excess of 25 per centum is conferred upon or permitted to be exercised by any person who is not a national or citizen of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fisheries loan fund; interest payments on appropriations available as capital to the fund less average undispersed cash balance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is created a fisheries loan fund, which shall be used by the Secretary as a revolving fund to make loans for financing and refinancing under this section. Any funds received by the Secretary on or before <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, in payment of principal or interest on any loans so made shall be deposited in the fund and be available for making additional loans under this section. Any funds received in the fisheries loan fund after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. There is authorized to be appropriated to the fisheries loan fund the sum of $20,000,000 to provide initial capital.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of loan contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, subject to the specific limitations in this section, may consent to the modification, with respect to the rate of interest, time of payment of any installment of principal, or security, of any loan contract to which he is a party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chartering vessels; loans to Alaskan earthquake victims; termination date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized under such terms and conditions and pursuant to regulations prescribed by him to use the funds appropriated under this section to make loans to commercial fishermen for the purpose of chartering fishing vessels pending the construction or repair of vessels lost, destroyed, or damaged by the earthquake of <date date="1964-03-27">March 27, 1964</date>, and subsequent tidal waves related thereto: <i>Provided</i>, That any loans made under this subsection shall only be repaid from the net profits of the operations of such chartered vessels, which profits shall be reduced by such reasonable amount as determined by the Secretary for the salary of the fishermen chartering such vessels. The funds authorized herein shall not be available for such loans after <date date="1966-06-30">June 30, 1966</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 4</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–888</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–309, § 9</ref>, <date date="1964-05-20">May 20, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–85</ref>, §§ 1–4, <date date="1965-07-24">July 24, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 262</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–279, § 9</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–387</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1970-08-24">Aug. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 2(8)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–478, § 16(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–347, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1652</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–44, title I, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-07-12">July 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title IV, § 430(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2310</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–659, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742c–1.</num>
<heading> Investment in obligations of the United States; proceeds to be used for fisheries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys in the Fisheries Loan Fund established under Section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002500">1</ref> 742c of this title shall be invested by the Secretary of Commerce in obligations of the United States, except so much as shall be currently needed for loans or administrative expenses authorized under the Fisheries Loan Fund. All accrued proceeds from such investment shall be, subject to amounts provided in advance by appropriations, credited by the Secretary of the Treasury to the debt of the Secretary of Commerce incurred under <ref>section 53723 of title 46</ref> in connection with fisheries financing under chapter 537 of title 46 for so long as such debt exists. All accrued proceeds from such investment, after such debt has been liquidated, shall be, subject to amounts provided in advance by appropriations, credited to the fisheries portion of the Federal Ship Financing Fund established under section 1102 of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, as amended, and used for the fisheries purposes provided in chapter 537 of title 46.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742d.</num>
<heading> Investigations; preparation and dissemination of information; reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002501">1</ref> The Secretary shall conduct continuing investigations, prepare and disseminate information, and make periodical reports to the public, to the President, and to Congress, with respect to the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The production and flow to market of fish and fishery products domestically produced, and also those produced by foreign producers which affect the domestic fisheries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The availability and abundance and the biological requirements of the fish and wildlife resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The competitive economic position of the various fish and fishery products with respect to each other, and with respect to competitive domestic and foreign-produced commodities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The collection and dissemination of statistics on commercial and sport fishing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The collection and dissemination of statistics on the nature and availability of wildlife, progress in acquisition of additional refuges and measures being taken to foster a coordinated program to encourage and develop wildlife values;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The improvement of production and marketing practices in regard to commercial species and the conduct of educational and extension services relative to commercial and sport fishing, and wildlife matters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Any other matters which in the judgment of the Secretary are of public interest in connection with any phases of fish and wildlife operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 5</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742d–1.</num>
<heading> Studies of effects in use of chemicals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency is authorized and directed to undertake comprehensive continuing studies on the effects of insecticides, herbicides, fungicides and pesticides, upon the fish and wildlife resources of the United States, for the purpose of determining the amounts, percentages, and formulations of such chemicals that are lethal to or injurious to fish and wildlife and the amounts, percentages, mixtures, or formulations that can be used safely, and thereby prevent losses of fish and wildlife from such spraying, dusting, or other treatment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–582, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-08-01">Aug. 1, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 479</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 2(a)(2)(i), eff. <date date="1970-12-02">Dec. 2, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15623, <ref>84 Stat. 2086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742e.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions to Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be transferred to the Secretary all functions of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, and the head of any other department or agency, as determined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to relate primarily to the development, advancement, management, conservation, and protection of commercial fisheries; but nothing in this section shall be construed to modify the authority of the Department of State or the Secretary of State to negotiate or enter into any international agreements, or conventions with respect to the development, management, or protection of any fisheries and wildlife resources or with respect to international commissions operating under conventions to which the United States is a party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel, property, records, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be transferred to the Department of the Interior so much of the personnel, property, facilities, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds (available or to be made available) as the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines to be necessary in connection with the exercise of any functions transferred to the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation of other departments and agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may request and secure the advice or assistance of any department or agency of the Government in carrying out the provisions of this Act, and any such department or agency which furnishes advice or assistance to the Secretary may expend its own funds for such purposes, with or without reimbursement from the Secretary as may be agreed upon between the Secretary and the department or agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 6</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1122</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 7959, <ref>84 Stat. 2085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742f.</num>
<heading> Powers of Secretaries of the Interior and Commerce</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policies, procedures, and recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, with such advice and assistance as he may require from the Assistant Secretary for Fish and Wildlife, shall consider and determine the policies and procedures that are necessary and desirable in carrying out efficiently and in the public interest the laws relating to fish and wildlife. The Secretary, with the assistance of the departmental staff herein authorized, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and recommend measures which are appropriate to assure the maximum sustainable production of fish and fishery products and to prevent unnecessary and excessive fluctuations in such production;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> study the economic condition of the industry, and whenever he determines that any segment of the domestic fisheries has been seriously disturbed either by wide fluctuation in the abundance of the resource supporting it, or by unstable market or fishing conditions or due to any other factors he shall make such recommendations to the President and the Congress as he deems appropriate to aid in stabilizing the domestic fisheries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop and recommend special promotional and informational activities with a view to stimulating the consumption of fishery products whenever he determines that there is a prospective or actual surplus of such products; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> take such steps as may be required for the development, advancement, management, conservation, and protection of fish and wildlife resources including, but not limited to, research, development of existing facilities, and acquisition by purchase or exchange of land and water, or interests therein.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gifts, devises, or bequests for performance of activities and services of United States Fish and Wildlife Service; restrictive or affirmative covenants or conditions of servitude; separate account in Treasury; disbursement orders; gifts or bequests to United States for Federal tax purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In furtherance of the purposes of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to accept any gifts, devises, or bequests of real and personal property, or proceeds therefrom, or interests therein, for the benefit of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, in performing its activities and services. Such acceptance may be subject to the terms of any restrictive or affirmative covenant, or condition of servitude, if such terms are deemed by the Secretary to be in accordance with law and compatible with the purpose for which acceptance is sought.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of gifts, devises, and bequests.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any gifts and bequests of money and proceeds from the sales of other property received as gifts or bequests pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited in a separate account in the Treasury and shall be disbursed upon order of the Secretary for the benefit of programs administered by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Gifts, devises, and bequests to particular refuges.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disbursal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any gift, devise, or bequest made for the benefit of a particular national wildlife refuge or complex of geographically related refuges shall be disbursed only for the benefit of that refuge or complex of refuges and without further appropriations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matching</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the availability of appropriations and the requirements of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 668dd</ref> et seq.) and other applicable law, the Secretary may provide funds to match gifts, devises, and bequests made for the benefit of a particular national wildlife refuge or complex of geographically related refuges. With respect to each gift, devise, or bequest, the amount of Federal funds may not exceed the amount (or, in the case of property or in-kind services, the fair market value) of the gift, devise, or bequest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purpose of Federal income, estate, and gift taxes, property, or proceeds therefrom, or interests therein, accepted under this subsection shall be considered as a gift or bequest to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Volunteer services; incidental expenses; Federal employee status; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce may each recruit, train, and accept, without regard to the provisions of title 5, the services of individuals without compensation as volunteers for, or in aid of programs conducted by either Secretary through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce are each authorized to provide for incidental expenses such as transportation, uniforms, lodging, awards (including nominal cash awards) and recognition, and subsistence of such volunteers without regard to their places of residence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, a volunteer shall not be deemed a Federal employee and shall not be subject to the provisions of law relating to Federal employment, including those relative to hours of work, rates of compensation, leave, unemployment compensation, and Federal employee benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For the purpose of the tort claim provisions of title 28, a volunteer under this subsection shall be considered a Federal employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For the purposes of subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5, relating to compensation to Federal employees for work injuries, volunteers under this subsection shall be deemed employees of the United States within the meaning of the term “employees” as defined in <ref>section 8101 of title 5</ref>, and the provisions of that subchapter shall apply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senior volunteer corps</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior may establish a Senior Volunteer Corps, consisting of volunteers over the age of 50. To assist in the recruitment and retention of the volunteers, the Secretary may provide for additional incidental expenses to members of the Corps beyond the incidental expenses otherwise provided to volunteers under this subsection. The members of the Corps shall be subject to the other provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community partnership enhancement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of partner organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “partner organization” means an organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> draws its membership from private individuals, organizations, corporations, academic institutions, or State or local governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is established to promote the understanding of, education relating to, and the conservation of the fish, wildlife, plants, and cultural and historical resources of a particular refuge or complex of geographically related refuges; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is described in <ref>section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, the Secretary of the Interior may negotiate and enter into a cooperative agreement with a partner organization, academic institution, State or local government agency, or other person to implement one or more projects or programs for a refuge or complex of geographically related refuges in accordance with the purposes of this subsection and in compliance with the policies of other relevant authorities, regulations, and policy guidance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects and programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to the requirements of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 668dd</ref> et seq.) and other applicable law, and such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the Secretary may approve projects and programs for a refuge or complex of geographically related refuges that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> promote the stewardship of resources of the refuge through habitat maintenance, restoration, and improvement, biological monitoring, or research;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> support the operation and maintenance of the refuge through constructing, operating, maintaining, or improving the facilities and services of the refuge;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> increase awareness and understanding of the refuge and the National Wildlife Refuge System through the development, publication, or distribution of educational materials and products;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> advance education concerning the purposes of the refuge and the mission of the System through the use of the refuge as an outdoor classroom and development of other educational programs; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> contribute financial resources to the refuge, under terms that require that the net revenues be used exclusively for the benefit of the refuge, through donation of net revenues from the sale of educational materials and products and through encouragement of gifts, devises, and bequests.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal funding and ownership</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subject to the availability of appropriations and the requirements of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 668dd</ref> et seq.) and other applicable law, the Secretary may provide funds to match non-Federal funds donated under a cooperative agreement under this paragraph. With respect to each project or program, the amount of funds provided by the Secretary may not exceed the amount of the non-Federal funds donated through the project or program.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Federal funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any Federal funds used to fund a project or program under a cooperative agreement may be used only for expenses directly related to the project or program and may not be used for operation or administration of any non-Federal entity.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ownership of facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Any new facility, improvement to an existing facility, or other permanent improvement to a refuge constructed under this subsection shall be the property of the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treasury account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Amounts received by the Secretary of the Interior as a result of projects and programs under subparagraph (B) shall be deposited in a separate account in the Treasury. Amounts in the account that are attributable to activities at a particular refuge or complex of geographically related refuges shall be available to the Secretary of the Interior, without further appropriation, to pay the costs of incidental expenses related to volunteer activities, and to carry out cooperative agreements for the refuge or complex of refuges.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refuge education program enhancement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="1998-10-05">October 5, 1998</date>, the Secretary of the Interior shall develop guidance for refuge education programs to further the mission of the National Wildlife Refuge System and the purposes of individual refuges through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing outdoor classroom opportunities for students on national wildlife refuges that combine educational curricula with the personal experiences of students relating to fish, wildlife, and plants and their habitat and to the cultural and historical resources of the refuges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promoting understanding and conservation of fish, wildlife, and plants and cultural and historical resources of the refuges; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> improving scientific literacy in conjunction with both formal and nonformal education programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refuge programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Based on the guidance developed under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior may develop or enhance refuge education programs as appropriate, based on the resources of individual refuges and the opportunities available for such programs in State, local, and private schools. In developing and implementing each program, the Secretary should cooperate with State and local education authorities, and may cooperate with partner organizations in accordance with subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2011-01-04">January 4, 2011</date>, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit a report to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluating the accomplishments of the volunteer program, the community partnerships program, and the refuge education programs authorized under this section, and of the National Volunteer Coordination Program and volunteer coordination strategy under <ref>section 742f–1 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> making recommendations to improve the effectiveness of such programs, including regarding implementing subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1) of subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior to carry out subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f), $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 7</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–616, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–347, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1652</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–44, title I, § 103(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-07-12">July 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–498, title IV, § 430(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2310</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–242</ref>, §§ 3, 4(b), (c), 5–7, <date date="1998-10-05">Oct. 5, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1574–1578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–327</ref>, §§ 2, 4, <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–357</ref>, §§ 2, 4(a), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3979</ref>, 3980; <ref>Pub. L. 115–168, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. O, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742f–1.</num>
<heading> National Volunteer Coordination Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, and in conformance with the strategy developed under paragraph (2) and consistent with the authorities regarding gifts, volunteer services, community partnerships, and refuge education enhancement under <ref>section 742f of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Interior, through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, shall carry out a National Volunteer Coordination Program within the National Wildlife Refuge System to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> augment and support the capabilities and efforts of Federal employees to implement resource management, conservation, and public education programs and activities across the National Wildlife Refuge System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide meaningful opportunities for volunteers to support the resource management, conservation, and public education programs and activities of national wildlife refuges or complexes of geographically related national wildlife refuges in each United States Fish and Wildlife Service region; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fulfill the purpose and mission of the National Wildlife Refuge System under the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 668dd</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Volunteer coordination strategy</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No later than one year after <date date="2011-01-04">January 4, 2011</date>, the Director shall publish in the Federal Register a national strategy for the coordination and utilization of volunteers within the National Wildlife Refuge System.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The strategy shall be developed in consultation with State fish and wildlife agencies, Indian tribes, refuge friends groups or similar volunteer organizations, and other relevant stakeholders.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Volunteer coordinators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall provide, subject to the availability of appropriations, no less than one regional volunteer coordinator for each United States Fish and Wildlife Service region to implement the strategy published under this paragraph. Such coordinators may be responsible for assisting partner organizations in developing and implementing volunteer projects and activities under cooperative agreements under <ref>section 742f(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $2,000,000 for each fiscal year through fiscal year 2014.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–242, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-05">Oct. 5, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–327, § 3</ref>, <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–357</ref>, §§ 3, 4(b), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3979</ref>, 3981.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742g.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with State Department</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation at international meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall cooperate to the fullest practicable extent with the Secretary of State in providing representation at all meetings and conferences relating to fish and wildlife in which representatives of the United States and foreign countries participate.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall designate the Secretary of the Interior or the Assistant Secretary for Fish and Wildlife, or a person designated by the Secretary of the Interior to represent the Department of the Interior, as a member of the United States delegation attending such meetings and conferences and also as a member of the negotiating team of any such delegation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with officials responsible for technical and economic aid</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State and all other officials having responsibilities in the fields of technical and economic aid to foreign nations shall consult with the Secretary in all cases in which the interests of fish and wildlife are involved, with a view to assuring that such interests are adequately represented at all times.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International negotiations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall be represented in all international negotiations conducted by the United States pursuant to <ref>section 1351 of title 19</ref>, in any case in which fish products are directly affected by such negotiations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with governmental, private nonprofit, and other organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult periodically with the various governmental, private nonprofit, and other organizations and agencies which have to do with any phase of fish and wildlife with respect to any problems that may arise in connection with such fish and wildlife.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 8</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742h.</num>
<heading> Reports on fishery products</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2237</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary is authorized to make a report to the President and the Congress, and, when requested by the United States International Trade Commission in connection with <ref>section 1364 of title 19</ref>, or when an investigation is made under the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1332</ref>), the Secretary is authorized to make a report to such Commission, concerning the following matters with respect to any fishery product which is imported into the United States, or such reports may be made upon a request from any segment of the domestic industry producing a like or directly competitive product—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether there has been a downward trend in the production, employment in the production, or prices, or a decline in the sales, of the like or directly competitive product by the domestic industry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether there has been an increase in the imports of the fishery products into the United States, either actual or relative to the production of the like or directly competitive product produced by the domestic industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 9</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 171(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2009</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742i.</num>
<heading> Effect on rights of States and international commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall be construed (1) to interfere in any manner with the rights of any State under the Submerged Lands Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.] or otherwise provided by law, or to supersede any regulatory authority over fisheries exercised by the States either individually or under interstate compacts; or (2) to interfere in any manner with the authority exercised by any International Commission established under any treaty or convention to which the United States is a party.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 10</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742j.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 11</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742j–1.</num>
<heading> Airborne hunting</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition; penalty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> while airborne in an aircraft shoots or attempts to shoot for the purpose of capturing or killing any bird, fish, or other animal; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> uses an aircraft to harass any bird, fish, or other animal; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> knowingly participates in using an aircraft for any purpose referred to in paragraph (1) or (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception; report of State to Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to any person if such person is employed by, or is an authorized agent of or is operating under a license or permit of, any State or the United States to administer or protect or aid in the administration or protection of land, water, wildlife, livestock, domesticated animals, human life, or crops, and each such person so operating under a license or permit shall report to the applicable issuing authority each calendar quarter the number and type of animals so taken.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In any case in which a State, or any agency thereof, issues a permit referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, it shall file with the Secretary of the Interior an annual report containing such information as the Secretary shall prescribe, including but not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name and address of each person to whom a permit was issued;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the animals authorized to be taken thereunder, the number of animals authorized to be taken, and a description of the area from which the animals are authorized to be taken;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number and type of animals taken by such person to whom a permit was issued; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the reason for issuing the permit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Aircraft” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “aircraft” means any contrivance used for flight in the air.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement; regulations; arrest; search; issuance and execution of warrants and process; cooperative agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall enforce the provisions of this section and shall promulgate such regulations as he deems necessary and appropriate to carry out such enforcement. Any employee of the Department of the Interior authorized by the Secretary of the Interior to enforce the provisions of this section may, without warrant, arrest any person committing in his presence or view a violation of this section or of any regulation issued hereunder and take such person immediately for examination or trial before an officer or court of competent jurisdiction; may execute any warrant or other process issued by an officer or court of competent jurisdiction for the enforcement of the provisions of this section; and may, with or without a warrant, as authorized by law, search any place. The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with State fish and wildlife agencies or other appropriate State authorities to facilitate enforcement of this section, and by such agreements to delegate such enforcement authority to State law enforcement personnel as he deems appropriate for effective enforcement of this section. Any judge of any court established under the laws of the United States, and any United States magistrate judge may, within his respective jurisdiction, upon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause, issue warrants in all such cases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forfeiture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All birds, fish, or other animals shot or captured contrary to the provisions of this section, or of any regulation issued hereunder, and all guns, aircraft, and other equipment used to aid in the shooting, attempting to shoot, capturing, or harassing of any bird, fish, or other animal in violation of this section or of any regulation issued hereunder shall be subject to forfeiture to the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain customs laws applied</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All provisions of law relating to the seizure, forfeiture, and condemnation of a vessel for violation of the customs laws, the disposition of such vessel or the proceeds from the sale thereof, and the remission or mitigation of such forfeitures, shall apply to the seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this section, insofar as such provisions of law are applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions of this section; except that all powers, rights, and duties conferred or imposed by the customs laws upon any officer or employee of the Treasury Department shall, for the purposes of this section, be exercised or performed by the Secretary of the Interior or by such persons as he may designate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 13</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 92–159, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-11-18">Nov. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 480</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 92–502</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742j–2.</num>
<heading> Uniform allowance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002502">1</ref> 5901(a) of title 5, the uniform allowance for each uniformed employee of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service may be up to $400 annually.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–291, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742k.</num>
<heading> Management and disposition of vessels and other property acquired and arising out of fishery loans or related type of activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of facilitating administration of, and protecting the interest of the Government in, the fishery loan fund established by <ref>section 742c of this title</ref> and any related type of activities relating to fisheries for which the Department of the Interior is now or may hereafter be responsible, the Secretary of the Interior, notwithstanding any other provisions of law, may hereafter administer, complete, recondition, reconstruct, renovate, repair, maintain, operate, charter, assign, or sell upon such terms and conditions as he may deem most advantageous to the United States, any vessel, plant, or other property acquired by him on behalf of the United States and arising out of any fishery loan or any related type of activity by the Secretary of the Interior. The Secretary may use any of the applicable funds in each particular instance for the aforesaid purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–219</ref>, <date date="1961-09-13">Sept. 13, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742l.</num>
<heading> Enforcement authority for the protection of fish and wildlife resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement training program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In order to provide for and encourage training, research, and development for the purpose of improving fish and wildlife law enforcement and developing new methods for the prevention, detection, and reduction of violation of fish and wildlife laws, and the apprehension of violators of such laws, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce may each—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish and conduct national training programs to provide, at the request of any State, training for State fish and wildlife law enforcement personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop new or improved approaches, techniques, systems, equipment, and service to improve and strengthen fish and wildlife law enforcement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist in conducting, at the request of any appropriate State official, local or regional training programs for the training of State fish and wildlife law enforcement personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such training programs shall be conducted to the maximum extent practicable through established programs.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated beginning with fiscal year 1980 such funds as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of subsection (b), and the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce may each require reimbursement from the States for expenditures made pursuant to subsections (b)(1)(A) and (C).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement cooperative agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce may each utilize by agreement, with or without reimbursement, the personnel, services and facilities of any other Federal or State agency to the extent he deems it necessary and appropriate for effective enforcement of any Federal or State laws on lands, waters, or interests therein under his jurisdiction which are administered or managed for fish and wildlife purposes and for enforcement of any laws administered by him relating to fish and wildlife. Persons so designated by either Secretary, who are not employees of another Federal agency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall not be deemed a Federal employee and shall not be subject to the provisions of law relating to Federal employment, including those relating to hours of work, competitive examination, rates of compensation, and Federal employee benefits, but may be considered eligible for compensation for work injuries under subchapter III of chapter 81 of title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be considered to be investigative or law enforcement officers of the United States for the purposes of the tort claim provisions of title 28;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may, to the extent specified by either Secretary, search, seize, arrest, and exercise any other law enforcement functions or authorities under Federal laws relating to fish and wildlife, where such authorities are made applicable by this or any other law to employees, officers, or other persons designated or employed by either Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall be considered to be officers or employees of the Department of the Interior or the Department of Commerce, as the case may be, within the meaning of sections 111 and 1114 of title 18.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposal of abandoned or forfeited property</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), notwithstanding any other provision of law, all fish, wildlife, plants, or any other items abandoned or forfeited to the United States under any laws administered by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce relating to fish, wildlife, or plants, shall be disposed of by either Secretary in such a manner as he deems appropriate (including, but not limited to, loan, gift, sale, or destruction).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on sale of certain items</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce may not sell any species of fish, wildlife, or plant, or derivative thereof, for which the sale is prohibited by another Federal law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of revenues</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce may each expend any revenues received from the disposal of items under paragraph (1), and all sums referred to in the first sentence of <ref>section 1540(d) of this title</ref> and the first sentence of <ref>section 3375(d) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to make payments in accordance with those sections; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to pay costs associated with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shipping items referred to in paragraph (1) to and from the place of storage, sale, or temporary or final disposal, including temporary or permanent loan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> storage of the items, including inventory of, and security for, the items;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> appraisal of the items;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> sale or other disposal of the items in accordance with applicable law, including auctioneer commissions and related expenses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> payment of any valid liens or other encumbrances on the items and payment for other measures required to clear title to the items; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> in the case of the Secretary of the Interior only, processing and shipping of eagles and other migratory birds, and parts of migratory birds, for Native American religious purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclaimer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to invalidate any law enforcement agreement or delegation made by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce with respect to fish and wildlife matters prior to <date date="1978-11-08">November 8, 1978</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (j) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement operations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to any undercover or other enforcement operation which is necessary for the detection and prosecution of violations of any laws administered by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or the National Marine Fisheries Service relating to fish, wildlife, or plants, the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce may, notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> direct the advance of funds which may be deposited in commercial banks or other financial institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use appropriations for payment for information, rewards, or evidence concerning violations, without reference to any rewards to which such persons may otherwise be entitled by law, and any moneys subsequently recovered shall be reimbursed to the current appropriation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use appropriations to establish or acquire proprietary corporations or business entities as part of an undercover operation, operate such corporations or business entities on a commercial basis, lease space and make other necessary expenditures, and use the proceeds from such undercover operations to offset necessary and reasonable expenses incurred in such operations: <i>Provided</i>, That at the conclusion of each such operation the proceeds shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–616, § 3</ref> (less (e)–(j)), <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–396, § 7</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2006</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–328, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3058</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742l–1.</num>
<heading> Authority to use available law enforcement funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 2023 and hereafter of the amount available for law enforcement, up to $750,000, to remain available until expended, may at the discretion of the Secretary be used for payment for information, rewards, or evidence concerning violations of laws administered by the Service, and miscellaneous and emergency expenses of enforcement activity, authorized or approved by the Secretary and to be accounted for solely on the Secretary’s certificate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. E, title I</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 988</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. G, title I</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742m.</num>
<heading> Relinquishment of exclusive legislative jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, may relinquish to a State, or to a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, the exclusive legislative jurisdiction of the United States over all or part of any United States Fish and Wildlife Service lands or interests therein, including but not limited to National Wildlife Refuge System and National Fish Hatchery System lands, in that State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession. Relinquishment of exclusive legislative jurisdiction under this subsection may be accomplished (1) by filing with the Governor (or, if none, the chief executive officer) of the State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession concerned, a notice of relinquishment to take effect upon acceptance thereof, or (2) as the laws of the State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession may otherwise provide.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–653, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 743.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–280, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-10">May 10, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 123</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 743a.</num>
<heading> Detail of personnel and loan of equipment to Director of Bureau of Sport Fisheries and Wildlife</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Agency” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “agency” means the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, the Department of the Air Force, the Atomic Energy Commission, and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel and equipment available</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The chief executive officer of each agency may from time to time—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> detail from the agency for duty under the Director of the Bureau of Sport Fisheries and Wildlife, Department of the Interior, such commissioned and enlisted personnel and civilian employees as may be spared for such duty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> consonant with the operational needs of the agency, loan equipment of the agency to the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall make a report to Congress at the end of any fiscal year that the provisions of this section are utilized, which describes the use of the provisions of this section, and the additional cost, if any, to the Federal Government resulting therefrom. Such report shall be referred in the Senate to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and in the House of Representatives to the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1885, ch. 360, § 1(2)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–280, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-10">May 10, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 123</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(t)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 744.</num>
<heading> Investigations; fish propagation; investigations of damages by predacious fishes; executive assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as appropriate, shall prosecute investigations and inquiries on the subject, with the view of ascertaining whether any and what diminution in the number of the food fishes of the coast and the lakes of the United States has taken place; and, if so, to what causes the same is due; and also whether any and what protective, prohibitory, or precautionary measures should be adopted in the premises; and shall report upon the same to Congress. He is authorized and directed to conduct investigations and experiments for the purpose of ameliorating the damage wrought to the fisheries by dogfish and other predacious fishes and aquatic animals. Said investigations and experiments shall be such as to develop the best and cheapest means of taking such fishes and aquatic animals, of utilizing them for economic purposes, especially for food, and to encourage the establishment of fisheries and markets for them.</p>
<p class="indent0">The heads of the several executive departments shall cause to be rendered all necessary and practicable aid to the Secretary in the prosecution of his investigations and inquiries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. §§ 4396, 4397; <ref>Mar. 3, 1887, ch. 362</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 523</ref>; <ref>June 21, 1916, ch. 160</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref>39 Stat. 232</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), (f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 3, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref>62 Stat. 1262</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 745.</num>
<heading> Powers of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as appropriate, may take or cause to be taken at all times, in the waters of the seacoast of the United States, where the tide ebbs and flows, and also in the waters of the lakes, such fish or specimens thereof as may in his judgment, from time to time, be needful or proper for the conduct of his duties, any law, custom, or usage of any State to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 4398; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 746.</num>
<heading> Vessels of Fish and Wildlife Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy is authorized to place the vessels of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service on the same footing with the Navy Department as those of the National Ocean Survey.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 31, 1880, ch. 113</ref>, <ref>21 Stat. 151</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 746a.</num>
<heading> Operation and maintenance fees for the M/V Tiglax and other vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date>, pursuant to <ref>section 9701 of title 31</ref> and notwithstanding <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary shall charge reasonable fees for the full costs of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service in operating and maintaining the M/V Tiglax and other vessels, to be credited to this account and to be available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–236.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 747.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 748.</num>
<heading> Expenditure of appropriations for propagation of food fishes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations for propagation of food fishes shall not be expended for hatching or planting fish or eggs in any State in which, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Interior, there are not adequate laws for the protection of the fishes, nor in any State in which the United States Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service and his duly authorized agents are not accorded full and free right to conduct fish-cultural operations, and all fishing and other operations necessary therefor, in such manner and at such times as is considered necessary and proper by the said director or his agents.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 1, 1918, ch. 113, § 1</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 693</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 749.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 750.</num>
<heading> Station on Mississippi River for rescue of fishes and propagation of mussels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be established on the Mississippi River, at a point to be selected by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as appropriate, a station for the rescue of fishes and the propagation of mussels in connection with fish-rescue operations throughout the Mississippi Valley.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 28, 1922, ch. 153, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 501</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 751.</num>
<heading> Personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In connection with the establishment of such fish-rescue station there is authorized the following personnel, namely: One district supervisor, to have general charge of fish-rescue and fish-cultural operations in the Mississippi Valley; a superintendent, two field foremen, four fish-culturists at large, one engineer at large, one clerk, two coxswains at large, and two apprentice fish-culturists.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 28, 1922, ch. 153, § 2</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 752.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 753.</num>
<heading> Cooperative work</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1942-07-02">July 2, 1942</date>, cooperative work conducted by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall be subject to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1919-07-24">July 24, 1919</date> [<ref>7 U.S.C. 2220</ref>, 2279i].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1942, ch. 473, § 1</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 558</ref>; <ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 753a.</num>
<heading> Cooperative research and training programs for fish and wildlife resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of developing adequate, coordinated, cooperative research and training programs for fish and wildlife resources, the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as appropriate, is authorized to continue to enter into cooperative agreements with colleges and universities, with game and fish departments of the several States, and with nonprofit organizations relating to cooperative research units: <i>Provided</i>, That Federal participation in the conduct of such cooperative unit programs shall be limited to the assignment of Department of the Interior or Department of Commerce scientific personnel by the Secretary to serve at the respective units, to the provision of assistance (including reasonable financial compensation) for the work of researchers on fish and wildlife ecology and resource management projects funded under this subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002503">1</ref> to supply for the use of the particular units’ operations such equipment as may be available to the Secretary for such purposes, and the payment of incidental expenses of Federal personnel and employees of cooperating agencies assigned to the units.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–686, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 733</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–616, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 753b.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 753a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–686, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 733</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 754.</num>
<heading> Commutation of rations for officers and crews of vessels of Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1942-07-02">July 2, 1942</date>, commutation of rations (not to exceed $1 per man per day) may be paid to officers and crews of vessels of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior, and money accruing from commutation of rations on board vessels may be paid on proper vouchers to the persons having charge of the mess of such vessels; and <ref>section 5911 of title 5</ref>, shall not be construed to require deductions from the salaries of officers and crews of vessels of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service for quarters and rations furnished on vessels of said Service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1942, ch. 473, § 1</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 558</ref>; <ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 754a.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for United States Fish and Wildlife Service; purchases from</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may purchase, to the extent of not to exceed $5,000, from the appropriations for the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, clothing and small stores for the crews of vessels, to be sold to the employees of said service and the appropriations reimbursed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 1, 1918, ch. 113, § 1</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 694</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), (f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref>Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 754b.</num>
<heading> Funds from private entities credited to Resource Management account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in fiscal year 1999 and thereafter, sums provided by private entities for activities pursuant to reimbursable agreements shall be credited to the “Resource Management” account and shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–139.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 754c.</num>
<heading> Work under reimbursable agreements; recording obligations and crediting amounts received</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before, on, and after <date date="1999-11-29">November 29, 1999</date>, in carrying out work under reimbursable agreements with any State, local, or tribal government, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service may, without regard to <ref>section 1341 of title 31</ref> and notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, record obligations against accounts receivable from such entities, and shall credit amounts received from such entities to this appropriation, such credit to occur within 90 days of the date of the original request by the Service for payment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–140.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 754d.</num>
<heading> Fee schedule for forensic laboratory services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 2001 and thereafter and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall establish and implement a fee schedule to permit a return to the Service for forensic laboratory services provided to non-Department of the Interior entities. Fees shall be collected as determined appropriate by the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service and shall be credited to this appropriation and be available for expenditure without further appropriation until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–291, title I, § 136</ref>, <date date="2000-10-11">Oct. 11, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 754e.</num>
<heading> Funds for contaminant sample analyses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 2012 and hereafter, of the amount provided for environmental contaminants, up to $1,000,000 may remain available until expended for contaminant sample analyses.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. E, title I</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 988</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>