<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 10C—</num>
<heading>FISH RESEARCH AND EXPERIMENTATION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 778.</num>
<heading> Establishment of experiment stations; purpose of research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish 1 or more centers for the purpose of carrying on a program of research and experimentation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to determine species of fishes most suitable for culture on a commercial basis in shallow reservoirs and flooded rice lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to determine methods for production of fingerling fishes for stocking in commercial reservoirs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to develop methods for the control of parasites and diseases of brood fishes and of fingerlings prior to stocking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to develop economical methods for raising the more desirable species of fishes to a marketable size;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to determine, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, the effects of fish-rice rotations, including crops other than rice commonly grown on rice farms, upon both the fish and other crops; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to develop suitable methods for harvesting the fish crop and preparing it for marketing, including a study of sport fishing as a means of such harvest.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–342, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-03-15">Mar. 15, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 889(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 778a.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of lands; construction of buildings; employment of personnel; cooperation with other agencies; publication of results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized (1) to acquire by purchase, condemnation, or otherwise such suitable lands, to construct such buildings, to acquire such equipment and apparatus, and to employ such officers and employees as he deems necessary; (2) to cooperate with State and other institutions and agencies upon such terms and conditions as he determines to be appropriate; and (3) to make public the results of such research and experiments conducted pursuant to <ref>section 778 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–342, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-03-15">Mar. 15, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 889(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 778b.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to cooperate in carrying out the provisions of this chapter by furnishing such information and assistance as may be requested by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–342, § 3</ref>, <date date="1958-03-15">Mar. 15, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 889(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 778c.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–342, § 4</ref>, <date date="1958-03-15">Mar. 15, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 35</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 778d to 778h.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</chapter>