<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 23—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL WILDERNESS PRESERVATION SYSTEM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1131.</num>
<heading> National Wilderness Preservation System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; Congressional declaration of policy; wilderness areas; administration for public use and enjoyment, protection, preservation, and gathering and dissemination of information; provisions for designation as wilderness areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to assure that an increasing population, accompanied by expanding settlement and growing mechanization, does not occupy and modify all areas within the United States and its possessions, leaving no lands designated for preservation and protection in their natural condition, it is hereby declared to be the policy of the Congress to secure for the American people of present and future generations the benefits of an enduring resource of wilderness. For this purpose there is hereby established a National Wilderness Preservation System to be composed of federally owned areas designated by Congress as “wilderness areas”, and these shall be administered for the use and enjoyment of the American people in such manner as will leave them unimpaired for future use and enjoyment as wilderness, and so as to provide for the protection of these areas, the preservation of their wilderness character, and for the gathering and dissemination of information regarding their use and enjoyment as wilderness; and no Federal lands shall be designated as “wilderness areas” except as provided for in this chapter or by a subsequent Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management of area included in System; appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The inclusion of an area in the National Wilderness Preservation System notwithstanding, the area shall continue to be managed by the Department and agency having jurisdiction thereover immediately before its inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System unless otherwise provided by Act of Congress. No appropriation shall be available for the payment of expenses or salaries for the administration of the National Wilderness Preservation System as a separate unit nor shall any appropriations be available for additional personnel stated as being required solely for the purpose of managing or administering areas solely because they are included within the National Wilderness Preservation System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Wilderness” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A wilderness, in contrast with those areas where man and his own works dominate the landscape, is hereby recognized as an area where the earth and its community of life are untrammeled by man, where man himself is a visitor who does not remain. An area of wilderness is further defined to mean in this chapter an area of undeveloped Federal land retaining its primeval character and influence, without permanent improvements or human habitation, which is protected and managed so as to preserve its natural conditions and which (1) generally appears to have been affected primarily by the forces of nature, with the imprint of man’s work substantially unnoticeable; (2) has outstanding opportunities for solitude or a primitive and unconfined type of recreation; (3) has at least five thousand acres of land or is of sufficient size as to make practicable its preservation and use in an unimpaired condition; and (4) may also contain ecological, geological, or other features of scientific, educational, scenic, or historical value.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–577, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 890</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1132.</num>
<heading> Extent of System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of wilderness areas; filing of maps and descriptions with Congressional committees; correction of errors; public records; availability of records in regional offices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All areas within the national forests classified at least 30 days before <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> by the Secretary of Agriculture or the Chief of the Forest Service as “wilderness”, “wild”, or “canoe” are hereby designated as wilderness areas. The Secretary of Agriculture shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Within one year after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, file a map and legal description of each wilderness area with the Interior and Insular Affairs Committees of the United States Senate and the House of Representatives, and such descriptions shall have the same force and effect as if included in this chapter: <i>Provided, however</i>, That correction of clerical and typographical errors in such legal descriptions and maps may be made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Maintain, available to the public, records pertaining to said wilderness areas, including maps and legal descriptions, copies of regulations governing them, copies of public notices of, and reports submitted to Congress regarding pending additions, eliminations, or modifications. Maps, legal descriptions, and regulations pertaining to wilderness areas within their respective jurisdictions also shall be available to the public in the offices of regional foresters, national forest supervisors, and forest rangers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by Secretary of Agriculture of classifications as primitive areas; Presidential recommendations to Congress; approval of Congress; size of primitive areas; Gore Range-Eagles Nest Primitive Area, Colorado</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall, within ten years after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, review, as to its suitability or nonsuitability for preservation as wilderness, each area in the national forests classified on <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> by the Secretary of Agriculture or the Chief of the Forest Service as “primitive” and report his findings to the President. The President shall advise the United States Senate and House of Representatives of his recommendations with respect to the designation as “wilderness” or other reclassification of each area on which review has been completed, together with maps and a definition of boundaries. Such advice shall be given with respect to not less than one-third of all the areas now classified as “primitive” within three years after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, not less than two-thirds within seven years after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, and the remaining areas within ten years after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>. Each recommendation of the President for designation as “wilderness” shall become effective only if so provided by an Act of Congress. Areas classified as “primitive” on <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> shall continue to be administered under the rules and regulations affecting such areas on <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> until Congress has determined otherwise. Any such area may be increased in size by the President at the time he submits his recommendations to the Congress by not more than five thousand acres with no more than one thousand two hundred and eighty acres of such increase in any one compact unit; if it is proposed to increase the size of any such area by more than five thousand acres or by more than one thousand two hundred and eighty acres in any one compact unit the increase in size shall not become effective until acted upon by Congress. Nothing herein contained shall limit the President in proposing, as part of his recommendations to Congress, the alteration of existing boundaries of primitive areas or recommending the addition of any contiguous area of national forest lands predominantly of wilderness value. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the Secretary of Agriculture may complete his review and delete such area as may be necessary, but not to exceed seven thousand acres, from the southern tip of the Gore Range-Eagles Nest Primitive Area, Colorado, if the Secretary determines that such action is in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by Secretary of the Interior of roadless areas of national park system and national wildlife refuges and game ranges and suitability of areas for preservation as wilderness; authority of Secretary of the Interior to maintain roadless areas in national park system unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within ten years after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> the Secretary of the Interior shall review every roadless area of five thousand contiguous acres or more in the national parks, monuments and other units of the national park system and every such area of, and every roadless island within the national wildlife refuges and game ranges, under his jurisdiction on <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> and shall report to the President his recommendation as to the suitability or nonsuitability of each such area or island for preservation as wilderness. The President shall advise the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives of his recommendation with respect to the designation as wilderness of each such area or island on which review has been completed, together with a map thereof and a definition of its boundaries. Such advice shall be given with respect to not less than one-third of the areas and islands to be reviewed under this subsection within three years after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, not less than two-thirds within seven years of <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> and the remainder within ten years of <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>. A recommendation of the President for designation as wilderness shall become effective only if so provided by an Act of Congress. Nothing contained herein shall, by implication or otherwise, be construed to lessen the present statutory authority of the Secretary of the Interior with respect to the maintenance of roadless areas within units of the national park system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions precedent to administrative recommendations of suitability of areas for preservation as wilderness; publication in Federal Register; public hearings; views of State, county, and Federal officials; submission of views to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall, prior to submitting any recommendations to the President with respect to the suitability of any area for preservation as wilderness—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> give such public notice of the proposed action as they deem appropriate, including publication in the Federal Register and in a newspaper having general circulation in the area or areas in the vicinity of the affected land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> hold a public hearing or hearings at a location or locations convenient to the area affected. The hearings shall be announced through such means as the respective Secretaries involved deem appropriate, including notices in the Federal Register and in newspapers of general circulation in the area: <i>Provided</i>, That if the lands involved are located in more than one State, at least one hearing shall be held in each State in which a portion of the land lies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at least thirty days before the date of a hearing advise the Governor of each State and the governing board of each county, or in Alaska the borough, in which the lands are located, and Federal departments and agencies concerned, and invite such officials and Federal agencies to submit their views on the proposed action at the hearing or by no later than thirty days following the date of the hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any views submitted to the appropriate Secretary under the provisions of (1) of this subsection with respect to any area shall be included with any recommendations to the President and to Congress with respect to such area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification or adjustment of boundaries; public notice and hearings; administrative and executive recommendations to Congress; approval of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any modification or adjustment of boundaries of any wilderness area shall be recommended by the appropriate Secretary after public notice of such proposal and public hearing or hearings as provided in subsection (d) of this section. The proposed modification or adjustment shall then be recommended with map and description thereof to the President. The President shall advise the United States Senate and the House of Representatives of his recommendations with respect to such modification or adjustment and such recommendations shall become effective only in the same manner as provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–577, § 3</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 891</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1133.</num>
<heading> Use of wilderness areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of national forests, national park system, and national wildlife refuge system; other provisions applicable to national forests, Superior National Forest, and national park system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are hereby declared to be within and supplemental to the purposes for which national forests and units of the national park and national wildlife refuge systems are established and administered and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to be in interference with the purpose for which national forests are established as set forth in the Act of <date date="1897-06-04">June 4, 1897</date> (<ref>30 Stat. 11</ref>), and the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of <date date="1960-06-12">June 12, 1960</date> (<ref>74 Stat. 215</ref>) [<ref>16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall modify the restrictions and provisions of the Shipstead-Nolan Act (Public Law 539, Seventy-first Congress, <date date="1930-07-10">July 10, 1930</date>; <ref>46 Stat. 1020</ref>), the Thye-Blatnik Act (Public Law 733, Eightieth Congress, <date date="1948-06-22">June 22, 1948</date>; <ref>62 Stat. 568</ref>), and the Humphrey-Thye-Blatnik-Andresen Act (Public Law 607, Eighty-Fourth Congress, <date date="1956-06-22">June 22, 1956</date>; <ref>70 Stat. 326</ref>), as applying to the Superior National Forest or the regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall modify the statutory authority under which units of the national park system are created. Further, the designation of any area of any park, monument, or other unit of the national park system as a wilderness area pursuant to this chapter shall in no manner lower the standards evolved for the use and preservation of such park, monument, or other unit of the national park system in accordance with section 100101(b)(1), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of title 54, the statutory authority under which the area was created, or any other Act of Congress which might pertain to or affect such area, including, but not limited to, <ref>section 796(2) of this title</ref>; and chapters 3201 and 3203 of title 54.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency responsibility for preservation and administration to preserve wilderness character; public purposes of wilderness areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, each agency administering any area designated as wilderness shall be responsible for preserving the wilderness character of the area and shall so administer such area for such other purposes for which it may have been established as also to preserve its wilderness character. Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, wilderness areas shall be devoted to the public purposes of recreational, scenic, scientific, educational, conservation, and historical use.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition provisions: commercial enterprise, permanent or temporary roads, mechanical transports, and structures or installations; exceptions: area administration and personal health and safety emergencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as specifically provided for in this chapter, and subject to existing private rights, there shall be no commercial enterprise and no permanent road within any wilderness area designated by this chapter and, except as necessary to meet minimum requirements for the administration of the area for the purpose of this chapter (including measures required in emergencies involving the health and safety of persons within the area), there shall be no temporary road, no use of motor vehicles, motorized equipment or motorboats, no landing of aircraft, no other form of mechanical transport, and no structure or installation within any such area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following special provisions are hereby made:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aircraft or motorboats; fire, insects, and diseases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within wilderness areas designated by this chapter the use of aircraft or motorboats, where these uses have already become established, may be permitted to continue subject to such restrictions as the Secretary of Agriculture deems desirable. In addition, such measures may be taken as may be necessary in the control of fire, insects, and diseases, subject to such conditions as the Secretary deems desirable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mineral activities, surveys for mineral value</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall prevent within national forest wilderness areas any activity, including prospecting, for the purpose of gathering information about mineral or other resources, if such activity is carried on in a manner compatible with the preservation of the wilderness environment. Furthermore, in accordance with such program as the Secretary of the Interior shall develop and conduct in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, such areas shall be surveyed on a planned, recurring basis consistent with the concept of wilderness preservation by the United States Geological Survey and the United States Bureau of Mines to determine the mineral values, if any, that may be present; and the results of such surveys shall be made available to the public and submitted to the President and Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mining and mineral leasing laws; leases, permits, and licenses; withdrawal of minerals from appropriation and disposition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, until midnight <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>, the United States mining laws and all laws pertaining to mineral leasing shall, to the same extent as applicable prior to <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, extend to those national forest lands designated by this chapter as “wilderness areas”; subject, however, to such reasonable regulations governing ingress and egress as may be prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture consistent with the use of the land for mineral location and development and exploration, drilling, and production, and use of land for transmission lines, waterlines, telephone lines, or facilities necessary in exploring, drilling, producing, mining, and processing operations, including where essential the use of mechanized ground or air equipment and restoration as near as practicable of the surface of the land disturbed in performing prospecting, location, and, in oil and gas leasing, discovery work, exploration, drilling, and production, as soon as they have served their purpose. Mining locations lying within the boundaries of said wilderness areas shall be held and used solely for mining or processing operations and uses reasonably incident thereto; and hereafter, subject to valid existing rights, all patents issued under the mining laws of the United States affecting national forest lands designated by this chapter as wilderness areas shall convey title to the mineral deposits within the claim, together with the right to cut and use so much of the mature timber therefrom as may be needed in the extraction, removal, and beneficiation of the mineral deposits, if needed timber is not otherwise reasonably available, and if the timber is cut under sound principles of forest management as defined by the national forest rules and regulations, but each such patent shall reserve to the United States all title in or to the surface of the lands and products thereof, and no use of the surface of the claim or the resources therefrom not reasonably required for carrying on mining or prospecting shall be allowed except as otherwise expressly provided in this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That, unless hereafter specifically authorized, no patent within wilderness areas designated by this chapter shall issue after <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>, except for the valid claims existing on or before <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>. Mining claims located after <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, within the boundaries of wilderness areas designated by this chapter shall create no rights in excess of those rights which may be patented under the provisions of this subsection. Mineral leases, permits, and licenses covering lands within national forest wilderness areas designated by this chapter shall contain such reasonable stipulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture for the protection of the wilderness character of the land consistent with the use of the land for the purposes for which they are leased, permitted, or licensed. Subject to valid rights then existing, effective <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>, the minerals in lands designated by this chapter as wilderness areas are withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under the mining laws and from disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral leasing and all amendments thereto.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water resources, reservoirs, and other facilities; grazing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within wilderness areas in the national forests designated by this chapter, (1) the President may, within a specific area and in accordance with such regulations as he may deem desirable, authorize prospecting for water resources, the establishment and maintenance of reservoirs, water-conservation works, power projects, transmission lines, and other facilities needed in the public interest, including the road construction and maintenance essential to development and use thereof, upon his determination that such use or uses in the specific area will better serve the interests of the United States and the people thereof than will its denial; and (2) the grazing of livestock, where established prior to <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, shall be permitted to continue subject to such reasonable regulations as are deemed necessary by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commercial services may be performed within the wilderness areas designated by this chapter to the extent necessary for activities which are proper for realizing the recreational or other wilderness purposes of the areas.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State water laws exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall constitute an express or implied claim or denial on the part of the Federal Government as to exemption from State water laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State jurisdiction of wildlife and fish in national forests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as affecting the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the several States with respect to wildlife and fish in the national forests.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–577, § 4</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 893</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–495, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 172</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(21)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1134.</num>
<heading> State and private lands within wilderness areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access; exchange of lands; mineral interests restriction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case where State-owned or privately owned land is completely surrounded by national forest lands within areas designated by this chapter as wilderness, such State or private owner shall be given such rights as may be necessary to assure adequate access to such State-owned or privately owned land by such State or private owner and their successors in interest, or the State-owned land or privately owned land shall be exchanged for federally owned land in the same State of approximately equal value under authorities available to the Secretary of Agriculture: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the United States shall not transfer to a State or private owner any mineral interests unless the State or private owner relinquishes or causes to be relinquished to the United States the mineral interest in the surrounded land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Customary means for ingress and egress to wilderness areas subject to mining claims or other occupancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case where valid mining claims or other valid occupancies are wholly within a designated national forest wilderness area, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, by reasonable regulations consistent with the preservation of the area as wilderness, permit ingress and egress to such surrounded areas by means which have been or are being customarily enjoyed with respect to other such areas similarly situated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the appropriation of funds by Congress, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to acquire privately owned land within the perimeter of any area designated by this chapter as wilderness if (1) the owner concurs in such acquisition or (2) the acquisition is specifically authorized by Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–577, § 5</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1135.</num>
<heading> Gifts, bequests, and contributions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance by Secretary of Agriculture of land for preservation as wilderness; regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may accept gifts or bequests of land within wilderness areas designated by this chapter for preservation as wilderness. The Secretary of Agriculture may also accept gifts or bequests of land adjacent to wilderness areas designated by this chapter for preservation as wilderness if he has given sixty days advance notice thereof to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. Land accepted by the Secretary of Agriculture under this section shall be come part of the wilderness area involved. Regulations with regard to any such land may be in accordance with such agreements, consistent with the policy of this chapter, as are made at the time of such gift, or such conditions, consistent with such policy, as may be included in, and accepted with, such bequest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to accept private contributions and gifts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to accept private contributions and gifts to be used to further the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–577, § 6</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1136.</num>
<heading> Annual reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the opening of each session of Congress, the Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior shall jointly report to the President for transmission to Congress on the status of the wilderness system, including a list and descriptions of the areas in the system, regulations in effect, and other pertinent information, together with any recommendations they may care to make.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–577, § 7</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>