<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 62—</num>
<heading>AFRICAN ELEPHANT CONSERVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4201.</num>
<heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to perpetuate healthy populations of African elephants.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2002</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2315</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4202.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Elephant populations in Africa have declined at an alarming rate since the mid-1970’s.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The large illegal trade in African elephant ivory is the major cause of this decline and threatens the continued existence of the African elephant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The African elephant is listed as threatened under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.) and its continued existence will be further jeopardized if this decline is not reversed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Because African elephant ivory is indistinguishable from Asian elephant ivory, there is a need to ensure that the trade in African elephant ivory does not further endanger the Asian elephant, which is listed as endangered under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1533</ref>) and under Appendix I of CITES.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In response to the significant illegal trade in African elephant ivory, the parties to CITES established the CITES Ivory Control System to curtail the illegal trade and to encourage African countries to manage, conserve, and protect their African elephant populations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The CITES Ivory Control System entered into force recently and should be allowed to continue in force for a reasonable period of time to assess its effectiveness in curtailing the illegal trade in African elephant ivory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Although some African countries have effective African elephant conservation programs, many do not have sufficient resources to properly manage, conserve, and protect their elephant populations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The United States, as a party to CITES and a large market for worked ivory, shares responsibility for supporting and implementing measures to stop the illegal trade in African elephant ivory and to provide for the conservation of the African elephant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> There is no evidence that sport hunting is part of the poaching that contributes to the illegal trade in African elephant ivory, and there is evidence that the proper utilization of well-managed elephant populations provides an important source of funding for African elephant conservation programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2003</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2315</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4203.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assist in the conservation and protection of the African elephant by supporting the conservation programs of African countries and the CITES Secretariat; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide financial resources for those programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2004</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>AFRICAN ELEPHANT CONSERVATION ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4211.</num>
<heading> Provision of assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may provide financial assistance under this subchapter from the Fund for approved projects for research, conservation, management, or protection of African elephants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project proposal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any African government agency responsible for African elephant conservation and protection, the CITES Secretariat, and any organization or individual with experience in African elephant conservation may submit to the Secretary a project proposal under this section. Each such proposal shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name of the person responsible for conducting the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a succinct statement of the need for and purposes of the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the qualifications of the individuals who will be conducting the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an estimate of the funds and time required to complete the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> evidence of support of the project by governmental entities of countries within which the project will be conducted, if such support may be important for the success of the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any other information the Secretary considers to be necessary or appropriate for evaluating the eligibility of the project for funding under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project review and approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall review each project proposal to determine if it meets the criteria set forth in subsection (d) and otherwise merits assistance under this chapter. Not later than six months after receiving a project proposal, and subject to the availability of funds, the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the proposal and provide written notification to the person who submitted the proposal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may approve a project under this section if the project will enhance programs for African elephant research, conservation, management, or protection by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> developing in a usable form sound scientific information on African elephant habitat condition and carrying capacity, total elephant numbers and population trends, or annual reproduction and mortality; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> assisting efforts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to ensure that any taking of African elephants in the country is effectively controlled and monitored;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to implement conservation programs to provide for healthy, sustainable African elephant populations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to enhance compliance with the CITES Ivory Control System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project sustainability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent practical, in determining whether to approve project proposals under this section, the Secretary shall give consideration to projects that will enhance sustainable conservation programs to ensure effective long-term conservation of African elephants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each entity that receives assistance under this section shall provide such periodic reports to the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service as the Director considers relevant and appropriate. Each report shall include all information requested by the Director for evaluating the progress and success of the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiyear grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may award to a person who is otherwise eligible for a grant under this section a multiyear grant of up to 5 years to carry out a project that the person demonstrates is an effective, long-term conservation strategy for African elephants and the habitat of African elephants.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection precludes the Secretary from awarding a grant on an annual basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2101</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2316</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–111</ref>, §§ 5, 6(a)(1), <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2096</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–132, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-06">Dec. 6, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LIII, § 5303(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2445</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4212.</num>
<heading> Acceptance and use of donations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may accept and use donations of funds to provide assistance under this subchapter. Amounts received by the Secretary in the form of such donations shall be transferred by the Secretary to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit into the Fund.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2102</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2317</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–111, § 6(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4213.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4214.</num>
<heading> Advisory group</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist in carrying out this chapter, the Secretary may convene an advisory group consisting of individuals representing public and private organizations actively involved in the conservation of African elephants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Advisory Group <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002790">1</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that each meeting of the advisory group is open to the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide, at each meeting, an opportunity for interested persons to present oral or written statements concerning items on the agenda.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide to the public timely notice of each meeting of the advisory group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minutes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Minutes of each meeting of the advisory group shall be kept by the Secretary and shall be made available to the public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption from chapter 10 of title 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the advisory group.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2104</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–111, § 4</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2095</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–141, § 5(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-02-12">Feb. 12, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 14</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(120)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MORATORIA AND PROHIBITED ACTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4221.</num>
<heading> Review of African elephant conservation programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within one month after <date date="1988-10-07">October 7, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall issue a call for information on the African elephant conservation program of each ivory producing country by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> publishing a notice in the Federal Register requesting submission of such information to the Secretary by all interested parties; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submitting a written request for such information through the Secretary of State to each ivory producing country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and determination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall review the African elephant conservation program of each ivory producing country and, not later than one year after <date date="1988-10-07">October 7, 1988</date>, shall issue and publish in the Federal Register a determination of whether or not the country meets the following criteria:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The country is a party to CITES and adheres to the CITES Ivory Control System.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The country’s elephant conservation program is based on the best available information, and the country is making expeditious progress in compiling information on the elephant habitat condition and carrying capacity, total population and population trends, and the annual reproduction and mortality of the elephant populations within the country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The taking of elephants in the country is effectively controlled and monitored.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The country’s ivory quota is determined on the basis of information referred to in subparagraph (B) and reflects the amount of ivory which is confiscated or consumed domestically by the country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The country has not authorized or allowed the export of amounts of raw ivory which exceed its ivory quota under the CITES Ivory Control System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delay in issuing determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary finds within one year after <date date="1988-10-07">October 7, 1988</date>, that there is insufficient information upon which to make the determination under paragraph (1), the Secretary may delay issuing the determination until no later than <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>. The Secretary shall issue and publish in the Federal Register at the time of the finding a statement explaining the reasons for any such delay.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2201</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4222.</num>
<heading> Moratoria</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ivory producing countries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a moratorium on the importation of raw and worked ivory from an ivory producing country immediately upon making a determination that the country does not meet all the criteria set forth in <ref>section 4221(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Later establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With regard to any ivory producing country for which the Secretary has insufficient information to make a determination pursuant to <ref>section 4221(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall establish a moratorium on the importation of raw and worked ivory from such country not later than <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, unless, based on new information, the Secretary concludes before that date that the country meets all of the criteria set forth in <ref>section 4221(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intermediary countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a moratorium on the importation of raw and worked ivory from an intermediary country immediately upon making a determination that the country—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not a party to CITES;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> does not adhere to the CITES Ivory Control System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> imports raw ivory from a country that is not an ivory producing country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> imports raw or worked ivory from a country that is not a party to CITES;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> imports raw or worked ivory that originates in an ivory producing country in violation of the laws of that ivory producing country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> substantially increases its imports of raw or worked ivory from a country that is subject to a moratorium under this chapter during the first three months of that moratorium; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> imports raw or worked ivory from a country that is subject to a moratorium under this chapter after the first three months of that moratorium, unless the ivory is imported by vessel during the first six months of that moratorium and is accompanied by shipping documents which show that it was exported before the establishment of the moratorium.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of moratorium</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall suspend a moratorium established under this section if, after notice and public comment, the Secretary determines that the reasons for establishing the moratorium no longer exist.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person may at any time submit a petition in writing requesting that the Secretary establish or suspend a moratorium under this section. Such a petition shall include such substantial information as may be necessary to demonstrate the need for the action requested by the petition.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration and ruling</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall publish a notice of receipt of a petition under this subsection in the Federal Register and shall provide an opportunity for the public to comment on the petition. The Secretary shall rule on such petition not later than 90 days after the close of the public comment period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sport-hunted trophies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Individuals may import sport-hunted elephant trophies that they have legally taken in an ivory producing country that has submitted an ivory quota. The Secretary shall not establish any moratorium under this section, pursuant to a petition or otherwise, which prohibits the importation into the United States of sport-hunted trophies from elephants that are legally taken by the importer or the importer’s principal in an ivory producing country that has submitted an ivory quota.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confiscated ivory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Trade in raw or worked ivory that is confiscated by an ivory producing country or an intermediary country and is disposed of pursuant to the CITES Ivory Control System shall not be the sole cause for the establishment of a moratorium under this subchapter if all proceeds from the disposal of the confiscated ivory are used solely to enhance wildlife conservation programs or conservation purposes of CITES. With respect to any country that was not a party to CITES at the time of such confiscation, this subsection shall not apply until such country develops appropriate measures to assure that persons with a history of illegal dealings in ivory shall not benefit from the disposal of confiscated ivory.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2202</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4223.</num>
<heading> Prohibited acts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 4222(e) of this title</ref>, it is unlawful for any person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to import raw ivory from any country other than an ivory producing country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to export raw ivory from the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to import raw or worked ivory that was exported from an ivory producing country in violation of that country’s laws or of the CITES Ivory Control System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to import worked ivory, other than personal effects, from any country unless that country has certified that such ivory was derived from legal sources; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to import raw or worked ivory from a country for which a moratorium is in effect under <ref>section 4222 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2203</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4224.</num>
<heading> Penalties and enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly violates <ref>section 4223 of this title</ref> shall, upon conviction, be fined under title 18 or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever violates <ref>section 4223 of this title</ref> may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary of not more than $5,000 for each such violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures for assessment of civil penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Proceedings for the assessment of a civil penalty under this section shall be conducted in accordance with the procedures provided for in <ref>section 1540(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to appropriations, penalties collected under this section may be used by the Secretary of the Treasury to pay rewards under <ref>section 4225 of this title</ref> and, to the extent not used to pay such rewards, shall be deposited by the Secretary of the Treasury into the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall enforce this subchapter in the same manner such Secretaries carry out enforcement activities under <ref>section 1540(e) of this title</ref>. <ref>Section 1540(c) of this title</ref> shall apply to actions arising under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2204</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4225.</num>
<heading> Rewards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the recommendation of the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury may pay a reward to any person who furnishes information which leads to a civil penalty or a criminal conviction under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of a reward under this section shall be equal to not more than one-half of any criminal or civil penalty or fine with respect to which the reward is paid, or $25,000, whichever is less.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer or employee of the United States or of any State or local government who furnishes information or renders service in the performance of his or her official duties shall not be eligible for a reward under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2205</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4241.</num>
<heading> Relationship to Endangered Species Act of 1973</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary under this chapter is in addition to and shall not affect the authority of the Secretary under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.) or diminish the Secretary’s authority under the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3371</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2302</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4242.</num>
<heading> Certification under Pelly amendment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary finds in administering this chapter that a country does not adhere to the CITES Ivory Control System, that country is deemed, for purposes of <ref>section 1978(a)(2) of title 22</ref>, to be diminishing the effectiveness of an international program for endangered or threatened species.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2303</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4243.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–111, § 6(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2096</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4244.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “African elephant” means any animal of the species loxodonta africana;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “CITES” means the Convention on the International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “CITES Ivory Control System” means the ivory quota and marking system established by CITES to curtail illegal trade in African elephant ivory;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Fund” means the account established by division A, section 101(e), title I of <ref>Public Law 105–277</ref> under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">multinational species conservation fund</inline>” [<ref>16 U.S.C. 4246</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the terms “import” and “importation” have the meanings such terms have in the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “intermediary country” means a country that exports raw or worked ivory that does not originate in that country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “ivory producing country” means any African country within which is located any part of the range of a population of African elephants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “ivory quota” means a quota submitted by an ivory producing country to the CITES Secretariat in accordance with the CITES Ivory Control System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the term “personal effects” means articles which are not intended for sale and are part of a shipment of the household effects of a person who is moving his or her residence to or from the United States, or are included in personal accompanying baggage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the term “raw ivory” means any African elephant tusk, and any piece thereof, the surface of which, polished or unpolished, is unaltered or minimally carved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the term “United States” means the fifty States, the District of Columbia, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the term “worked ivory” means any African elephant tusk, and any piece thereof, which is not raw ivory.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2305</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2322</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–111, § 6(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4245.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund and to the Secretary a total of not to exceed $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029 to carry out this chapter, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of amounts available each fiscal year to carry out this chapter, the Secretary may expend not more than 3 percent or $100,000, whichever is greater, to pay the administrative expenses necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–478, title II, § 2306</ref>, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–440, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–217, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-08-05">Aug. 5, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–111</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–141, § 5(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-02-12">Feb. 12, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 14</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–132, § 2(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2007-12-06">Dec. 6, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title VII, § 7001(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LIII, § 5303(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2445</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4246.</num>
<heading> Multinational Species Conservation Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 1999 and thereafter, donations to provide assistance under <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>, part I of the African Elephant Conservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 4211</ref> et seq.), and <ref>section 4264 of this title</ref> shall be deposited to this Fund and shall be available without further appropriation: <i>Provided further</i>, That in fiscal year 1999 and thereafter, all penalties received by the United States under section 2204 of the African Elephant Conservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 4224</ref>) which are not used to pay rewards under section 2205 of the African Elephant Conservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 4225</ref>) shall be deposited to this Fund to provide assistance under section 2101 of the African Elephant Conservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 4211</ref>) and shall be available without further appropriation: <i>Provided further</i>, That in fiscal year 1999 and thereafter, not more than three percent of amounts appropriated to this Fund may be used by the Secretary of the Interior to administer the Fund.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–237; <ref>Pub. L. 107–111, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2096</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–112, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2098</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–141, § 5(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-02-12">Feb. 12, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 14</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>