<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5A—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION AND CONSERVATION OF WILDLIFE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GAME, FUR-BEARING ANIMALS, AND FISH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 661.</num>
<heading> Short title; authorization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This Act may be cited as the “Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of recognizing the vital contribution of our wildlife resources to the Nation, the increasing public interest and significance thereof due to expansion of our national economy and other factors, and to provide that wildlife conservation shall receive equal consideration and be coordinated with other features of water-resource development programs through the effectual and harmonious planning, development, maintenance, and coordination of wildlife conservation and rehabilitation for the purposes of this Act in the United States, its Territories and possessions, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized (1) to provide assistance to, and cooperate with, Federal, State, and public or private agencies and organizations in the development, protection, rearing, and stocking of all species of wildlife, resources thereof, and their habitat, in controlling losses of the same from disease or other causes, in minimizing damages from overabundant species, in providing public shooting and fishing areas, including easements across public lands for access thereto, and in carrying out other measures necessary to effectuate the purposes of this Act; (2) to make surveys and investigations of the wildlife of the public domain, including lands and waters or interests therein acquired or controlled by any agency of the United States; and (3) to accept donations of land and contributions of funds in furtherance of the purposes of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 1</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 401</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), (f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–624, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title VII, § 7001(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 779</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 662.</num>
<heading> Impounding, diverting, or controlling of waters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations between agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as hereafter stated in subsection (h) of this section, whenever the waters of any stream or other body of water are proposed or authorized to be impounded, diverted, the channel deepened, or the stream or other body of water otherwise controlled or modified for any purpose whatever, including navigation and drainage, by any department or agency of the United States, or by any public or private agency under Federal permit or license, such department or agency first shall consult with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, Department of the Interior, and with the head of the agency exercising administration over the wildlife resources of the particular State wherein the impoundment, diversion, or other control facility is to be constructed, with a view to the conservation of wildlife resources by preventing loss of and damage to such resources as well as providing for the development and improvement thereof in connection with such water-resource development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports and recommendations; consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In furtherance of such purposes, the reports and recommendations of the Secretary of the Interior on the wildlife aspects of such projects, and any report of the head of the State agency exercising administration over the wildlife resources of the State, based on surveys and investigations conducted by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and such State agency for the purpose of determining the possible damage to wildlife resources and for the purpose of determining means and measures that should be adopted to prevent the loss of or damage to such wildlife resources, as well as to provide concurrently for the development and improvement of such resources, shall be made an integral part of any report prepared or submitted by any agency of the Federal Government responsible for engineering surveys and construction of such projects when such reports are presented to the Congress or to any agency or person having the authority or the power, by administrative action or otherwise, (1) to authorize the construction of water-resource development projects or (2) to approve a report on the modification or supplementation of plans for previously authorized projects, to which this Act applies. Recommendations of the Secretary of the Interior shall be as specific as is practicable with respect to features recommended for wildlife conservation and development, lands to be utilized or acquired for such purposes, the results expected, and shall describe the damage to wildlife attributable to the project and the measures proposed for mitigating or compensating for these damages. The reporting officers in project reports of the Federal agencies shall give full consideration to the report and recommendations of the Secretary of the Interior and to any report of the State agency on the wildlife aspects of such projects, and the project plan shall include such justifiable means and measures for wildlife purposes as the reporting agency finds should be adopted to obtain maximum overall project benefits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of projects; acquisition of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Federal agencies authorized to construct or operate water-control projects are authorized to modify or add to the structures and operations of such projects, the construction of which has not been substantially completed on the date of enactment of the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act, and to acquire lands in accordance with <ref>section 663 of this title</ref>, in order to accommodate the means and measures for such conservation of wildlife resources as an integral part of such projects: <i>Provided</i>, That for projects authorized by a specific Act of Congress before the date of enactment of the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (1) such modification or land acquisition shall be compatible with the purposes for which the project was authorized; (2) the cost of such modifications or land acquisition, as means and measures to prevent loss of and damage to wildlife resources to the extent justifiable, shall be an integral part of the cost of such projects; and (3) the cost of such modifications or land acquisition for the development or improvement of wildlife resources may be included to the extent justifiable, and an appropriate share of the cost of any project may be allocated for this purpose with a finding as to the part of such allocated cost, if any, to be reimbursed by non-Federal interests.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The cost of planning for and the construction or installation and maintenance of such means and measures adopted to carry out the conservation purposes of this section shall constitute an integral part of the cost of such projects: <i>Provided</i>, That such cost attributable to the development and improvement of wildlife shall not extend beyond that necessary for (1) land acquisition, (2) facilities as specifically recommended in water resource project reports, (3) modification of the project, and (4) modification of project operations, but shall not include the operation of wildlife facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of construction by a Federal agency, that agency is authorized to transfer to the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, out of appropriations or other funds made available for investigations, engineering, or construction, such funds as may be necessary to conduct all or part of the investigations required to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estimation of wildlife benefits or losses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to other requirements, there shall be included in any report submitted to Congress supporting a recommendation for authorization of any new project for the control or use of water as described herein (including any new division of such project or new supplemental works on such project) an estimation of the wildlife benefits or losses to be derived therefrom including benefits to be derived from measures recommended specifically for the development and improvement of wildlife resources, the cost of providing wildlife benefits (including the cost of additional facilities to be installed or lands to be acquired specifically for that particular phase of wildlife conservation relating to the development and improvement of wildlife), the part of the cost of joint-use facilities allocated to wildlife, and the part of such costs, if any, to be reimbursed by non-Federal interests.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall be applicable with respect to any project for the control or use of water as prescribed herein, or any unit of such project authorized before or after the date of enactment of the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act for planning or construction, but shall not be applicable to any project or unit thereof authorized before the date of enactment of the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act if the construction of the particular project or unit thereof has been substantially completed. A project or unit thereof shall be considered to be substantially completed when sixty percent or more of the estimated construction cost has been obligated for expenditure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exempt projects and activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this Act shall not be applicable to those projects for the impoundment of water where the maximum surface area of such impoundments is less than ten acres, nor to activities for or in connection with programs primarily for land management and use carried out by Federal agencies with respect to Federal lands under their jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 2</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 401</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), (f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–624, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–72, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-09">July 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 663.</num>
<heading> Impoundment or diversion of waters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation, maintenance, and management of wildlife resources; development and improvement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the exceptions prescribed in <ref>section 662(h) of this title</ref>, whenever the waters of any stream or other body of water are impounded, diverted, the channel deepened, or the stream or other body of water otherwise controlled or modified for any purpose whatever, including navigation and drainage, by any department or agency of the United States, adequate provision, consistent with the primary purposes of such impoundment, diversion, or other control, shall be made for the use thereof, together with any areas of land, water, or interests therein, acquired or administered by a Federal agency in connection therewith, for the conservation, maintenance, and management of wildlife resources thereof, and its habitat thereon, including the development and improvement of such wildlife resources pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 662 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use and availability of waters, land, or interests therein</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The use of such waters, land, or interests therein for wildlife conservation purposes shall be in accordance with general plans approved jointly (1) by the head of the particular department or agency exercising primary administration in each instance, (2) by the Secretary of the Interior, and (3) by the head of the agency exercising the administration of the wildlife resources of the particular State wherein the waters and areas lie. Such waters and other interests shall be made available, without cost for administration, by such State agency, if the management of the properties relate to the conservation of wildlife other than migratory birds, or by the Secretary of the Interior, for administration in such manner as he may deem advisable, where the particular properties have value in carrying out the national migratory bird management program: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture to cooperate with the States or in making lands available to the States with respect to the management of wildlife and wildlife habitat on lands administered by him.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of land, waters, and interests therein; report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When consistent with the purposes of this Act and the reports and findings of the Secretary of the Interior prepared in accordance with <ref>section 662 of this title</ref>, land, waters, and interests therein may be acquired by Federal construction agencies for the wildlife conservation and development purposes of this Act in connection with a project as reasonably needed to preserve and assure for the public benefit the wildlife potentials of the particular project area: <i>Provided</i>, That before properties are acquired for this purpose, the probable extent of such acquisition shall be set forth, along with other data necessary for project authorization, in a report submitted to the Congress, or in the case of a project previously authorized, no such properties shall be acquired unless specifically authorized by Congress, if specific authority for such acquisition is recommended by the construction agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of acquired properties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Properties acquired for the purposes of this section shall continue to be used for such purposes, and shall not become the subject of exchange or other transactions if such exchange or other transaction would defeat the initial purpose of their acquisition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of Federal lands acquired or withdrawn for Federal water-resource purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Federal lands acquired or withdrawn for Federal water-resource purposes and made available to the States or to the Secretary of the Interior for wildlife management purposes, shall be made available for such purposes in accordance with this Act, notwithstanding other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National forest lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any lands acquired pursuant to this section by any Federal agency within the exterior boundaries of a national forest shall, upon acquisition, be added to and become national forest lands, and shall be administered as a part of the forest within which they are situated, subject to all laws applicable to lands acquired under the provisions of the Act of <date date="1911-03-01">March 1, 1911</date> (<ref>36 Stat. 961</ref>), unless such lands are acquired to carry out the National Migratory Bird Management Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 3</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 401</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1081</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–624, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 664.</num>
<heading> Administration; rules and regulations; availability of lands to State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such areas as are made available to the Secretary of the Interior for the purposes of this Act, pursuant to sections 661 and 663 of this title or pursuant to any other authorization, shall be administered by him directly or in accordance with cooperative agreements entered into pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 661 of this title</ref> and in accordance with such rules and regulations for the conservation, maintenance, and management of wildlife, resources thereof, and its habitat thereon, as may be adopted by the Secretary in accordance with general plans approved jointly by the Secretary of the Interior and the head of the department or agency exercising primary administration of such areas: <i>Provided</i>, That such rules and regulations shall not be inconsistent with the laws for the protection of fish and game of the States in which such area is situated: <i>Provided, further</i>, That lands having value to the National Migratory Bird Management Program may, pursuant to general plans, be made available without cost directly to the State agency having control over wildlife resources, if it is jointly determined by the Secretary of the Interior and such State agency that this would be in the public interest: <i>And provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Interior shall have the right to assume the management and administration of such lands in behalf of the National Migratory Bird Management Program if the Secretary finds that the State agency has withdrawn from or otherwise relinquished such management and administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 4</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 402</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), (f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1081</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–624, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 665.</num>
<heading> Investigations as to effect of sewage, industrial wastes; reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, through the Fish and Wildlife Service and the United States Bureau of Mines, is authorized to make such investigations as he deems necessary to determine the effects of domestic sewage, mine, petroleum, and industrial wastes, erosion silt, and other polluting substances on wildlife, and to make reports to the Congress concerning such investigations and of recommendations for alleviating dangerous and undesirable effects of such pollution. These investigations shall include (1) the determination of standards of water quality for the maintenance of wildlife; (2) the study of methods of abating and preventing pollution, including methods for the recovery of useful or marketable products and byproducts of wastes; and (3) the collation and distribution of data on the progress and results of such investigations for the use of Federal, State, municipal, and private agencies, individuals, organizations, or enterprises.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 5</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 402</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref>54 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1081</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 665a.</num>
<heading> Maintenance of adequate water levels in upper Mississippi River</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the management of existing facilities (including locks, dams, and pools) in the Mississippi River between Rock Island, Illinois, and Minneapolis, Minnesota, administered by the United States Corps of Engineers of the Department of the Army, that Department is directed to give full consideration and recognition to the needs of fish and other wildlife resources and their habitat dependent on such waters, without increasing additional liability to the Government, and, to the maximum extent possible without causing damage to levee and drainage districts, adjacent railroads and highways, farm lands, and dam structures, shall generally operate and maintain pool levels as though navigation was carried on throughout the year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 5A</ref>, as added <ref>June 19, 1948, ch. 528</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated from time to time, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act and regulations made pursuant thereto, including the construction of such facilities, buildings, and other improvements necessary for economical administration of areas made available to the Secretary of the Interior under this Act, and the employment in the city of Washington and elsewhere of such persons and means as the Secretary of the Interior may deem necessary for such purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 6</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666a.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who shall violate any rule or regulation promulgated in accordance with this Act shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than $500 or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666b.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The terms “wildlife” and “wildlife resources” as used herein include birds, fishes, mammals, and all other classes of wild animals and all types of aquatic and land vegetation upon which wildlife is dependent.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666c.</num>
<heading> Applicability to Tennessee Valley Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this Act shall not apply to the Tennessee Valley Authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666c–1.</num>
<heading> Protection of water, oceans, coasts, and wildlife from invasive species</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Control</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “control”, with respect to an invasive species, means the eradication, suppression, or reduction of the population of the invasive species within the area in which the invasive species is present.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ecosystem</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “ecosystem” means the complex of a community of organisms and the environment of the organisms.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible State” means any of— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002467">1</ref></chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Guam;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> American Samoa;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the United States Virgin Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Invasive species</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “invasive species” means an alien species, the introduction of which causes, or is likely to cause, economic or environmental harm or harm to human health.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Associated definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “alien species”, with respect to a particular ecosystem, means any species (including the seeds, eggs, spores, or other biological material of the species that are capable of propagating the species) that is not native to the affected ecosystem.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manage; management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The terms “manage” and “management”, with respect to an invasive species, mean the active implementation of any activity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to reduce or stop the spread of the invasive species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to inhibit further infestations of the invasive species, the spread of the invasive species, or harm caused by the invasive species, including investigations regarding methods for early detection and rapid response, prevention, control, or management of the invasive species.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevent</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “prevent”, with respect to an invasive species, means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to hinder the introduction of the invasive species onto land or water; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to impede the spread of the invasive species within land or water by inspecting, intercepting, or confiscating invasive species threats prior to the establishment of the invasive species onto land or water of an eligible State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary concerned</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Army, with respect to Federal land administered by the Corps of Engineers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to Federal land administered by the Secretary of the Interior through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Reclamation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the National Park Service;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to Federal land administered by the Secretary of Agriculture through the Forest Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the head or a representative of any other Federal agency the duties of whom require planning relating to, and the treatment of, invasive species for the purpose of protecting water and wildlife on land and coasts and in oceans and water.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Species</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “species” means a group of organisms, all of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have a high degree of genetic similarity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are morphologically distinct;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> generally—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> interbreed at maturity only among themselves; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> produce fertile offspring; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> show persistent differences from members of allied groups of organisms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Control and management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Secretary concerned shall plan and carry out activities on land directly managed by the Secretary concerned to protect water and wildlife by controlling and managing invasive species—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to inhibit or reduce the populations of invasive species; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to effectuate restoration or reclamation efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Secretary concerned shall develop a strategic plan for the implementation of the invasive species program to achieve, to the maximum extent practicable, a substantive annual net reduction of invasive species populations or infested acreage on land or water managed by the Secretary concerned.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each strategic plan under paragraph (1) shall be developed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in coordination with affected—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> relevant Federal agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> eligible States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> political subdivisions of eligible States;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in consultation with stakeholders, including nongovernmental organizations and industry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in consultation with federally recognized Indian tribes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in accordance with the priorities established by 1 or more Governors of the eligible States in which an ecosystem affected by an invasive species is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors for consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In developing a strategic plan under this subsection, the Secretary concerned shall take into consideration the economic and ecological costs of action or inaction, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-effective methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In selecting a method to be used to control or manage an invasive species as part of a specific control or management project conducted as part of a strategic plan developed under subsection (c), the Secretary concerned shall prioritize the use of methods that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> effectively control and manage invasive species, as determined by the Secretary concerned, based on sound scientific data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minimize environmental impacts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> control and manage invasive species in the most cost-effective manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comparative economic assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To achieve compliance with subsection (d), the Secretary concerned shall require a comparative economic assessment of invasive species control and management methods to be conducted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretaries concerned shall use all tools and flexibilities available (as of <date date="2019-03-12">March 12, 2019</date>) to expedite the projects and activities described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of projects and activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A project or activity referred to in paragraph (1) is a project or activity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to protect water or wildlife from an invasive species that, as determined by the Secretary concerned is, or will be, carried out on land or water that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> directly managed by the Secretary concerned; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> located in an area that is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> at high risk for the introduction, establishment, or spread of invasive species; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> determined by the Secretary concerned to require immediate action to address the risk identified in subclause (I); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> carried out in accordance with applicable agency procedures, including any applicable—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> land or resource management plan; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> land use plan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to each Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include protection of land or water from an invasive species, the Secretary concerned shall use not less than 75 percent for on-the-ground control and management of invasive species, which may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the purchase of necessary products, equipment, or services to conduct that control and management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the use of integrated pest management options, including options that use pesticides authorized for sale, distribution, or use under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 136</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the use of biological control agents that are proven to be effective to reduce invasive species populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the use of revegetation or cultural restoration methods designed to improve the diversity and richness of ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the use of monitoring and detection activities for invasive species, including equipment, detection dogs, and mechanical devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the use of appropriate methods to remove invasive species from a vehicle or vessel capable of conveyance; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the use of other effective mechanical or manual control methods.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations, outreach, and public awareness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to each Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include protection of land or water from an invasive species, the Secretary concerned may use not more than 15 percent for investigations, development activities, and outreach and public awareness efforts to address invasive species control and management needs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to each Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include protection of land or water from an invasive species, not more than 10 percent may be used for administrative costs incurred to carry out those programs, including costs relating to oversight and management of the programs, recordkeeping, and implementation of the strategic plan developed under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the end of the second fiscal year beginning after <date date="2019-03-12">March 12, 2019</date>, each Secretary concerned shall submit to Congress a report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describing the use by the Secretary concerned during the 2 preceding fiscal years of funds for programs that address or include invasive species management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specifying the percentage of funds expended for each of the purposes specified in subsections (g), (h), and (i).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to other authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other invasive species control, prevention, and management authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section precludes the Secretary concerned from pursuing or supporting, pursuant to any other provision of law, any activity regarding the control, prevention, or management of an invasive species, including investigations to improve the control, prevention, or management of the invasive species.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public water supply systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section authorizes the Secretary concerned to suspend any water delivery or diversion, or otherwise to prevent the operation of a public water supply system, as a measure to control, manage, or prevent the introduction or spread of an invasive species.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of partnerships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the <sup>1</sup> subsections (m) and (n), the Secretary concerned may enter into any contract or cooperative agreement with another Federal agency, an eligible State, a federally recognized Indian tribe, a political subdivision of an eligible State, or a private individual or entity to assist with the control and management of an invasive species.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memorandum of understanding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As a condition of a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (<i>l</i>), the Secretary concerned and the applicable Federal agency, eligible State, political subdivision of an eligible State, or private individual or entity shall enter into a memorandum of understanding that describes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the nature of the partnership between the parties to the memorandum of understanding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the control and management activities to be conducted under the contract or cooperative agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A memorandum of understanding under this subsection shall contain, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A prioritized listing of each invasive species to be controlled or managed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An assessment of the total acres of land or area of water infested by the invasive species.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An estimate of the expected total acres of land or area of water infested by the invasive species after control and management of the invasive species is attempted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A description of each specific, integrated pest management option to be used, including a comparative economic assessment to determine the least-costly method.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any map, boundary, or Global Positioning System coordinates needed to clearly identify the area in which each control or management activity is proposed to be conducted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A written assurance that each partner will comply with <ref>section 2814 of title 7</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a partner to a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (<i>l</i>) is an eligible State, political subdivision of an eligible State, or private individual or entity, the memorandum of understanding under this subsection shall include a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the means by which each applicable control or management effort will be coordinated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the expected outcomes of managing and controlling the invasive species.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public outreach and awareness efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (<i>l</i>) involves any outreach or public awareness effort, the memorandum of understanding under this subsection shall include a list of goals and objectives for each outreach or public awareness effort that have been determined to be efficient to inform national, regional, State, Tribal, or local audiences regarding invasive species control and management.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of any invasive species-related investigation carried out under a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (<i>l</i>) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to develop solutions and specific recommendations for control and management of invasive species; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specifically to provide faster implementation of control and management methods.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with affected local governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each project and activity carried out pursuant to this section shall be coordinated with affected local governments in a manner that is consistent with <ref>section 1712(c)(9) of title 43</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $2,500,000 to the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $2,500,000 to the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 10</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title VII, § 7001(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 779</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–188, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 916</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–198, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666d.</num>
<heading> Skagit National Wildlife Refuge; exchange of lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in his discretion, at any time within ten years from <date date="1949-10-06">October 6, 1949</date>, to accept from the State of Washington on behalf of the United States title to any lands in the State of Washington which he deems chiefly valuable for wildlife refuge purposes, and which are equivalent in value to the lands of the United States within the Skagit National Wildlife Refuge, and in exchange therefor to convey by deed on behalf of the United States to the State of Washington the said lands of the United States in the Skagit National Wildlife Refuge.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 6, 1949, ch. 619, § 1</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666e.</num>
<heading> Administration of acquired lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any lands acquired by the Secretary of the Interior under the terms of this section and <ref>section 666d of this title</ref>, if located within or adjacent to an existing wildlife refuge or reservation, immediately shall become a part of such refuge or reservation and shall be administered under the laws and regulations applicable thereto, and, if not so located, may be administered as a migratory-waterfowl management area, refuge, reservation, or breeding ground in accordance with the provisions of the Act of <date date="1946-08-14">August 14, 1946</date> (<ref>60 Stat. 1080</ref>), and Acts supplementary thereto.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 6, 1949, ch. 619, § 2</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666f.</num>
<heading> Wildlife conservation and agricultural, industrial, recreational, and related uses for certain Federal lands; transfer of lands to Secretary of the Interior; administration, development, and disposition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to promote the orderly development and use of the lands and interests therein acquired by the United States in connection with the Crab Orchard Creek project and the Illinois Ordnance Plant in Williamson, Jackson, and Union Counties, Illinois, consistent with the needs of agriculture, industry, recreation, and wildlife conservation, all of the interests of the United States in and to such lands are hereby transferred to the Secretary of the Interior for administration, development, and disposition, in accordance with the provisions of this section and <ref>section 666g of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 5, 1947, ch. 489, § 1</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666g.</num>
<heading> Classification of lands; industrial leases; moneys subject to <ref>section 715s of this title</ref>; administration; jurisdiction of Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All of the lands transferred to the Secretary of the Interior, pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 666f of this title</ref> and this section, first shall be classified by him with a view to determining, in cooperation with Federal, State, and public or private agencies and organizations, the most beneficial use that may be made thereof to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 666f of this title</ref> and this section, including the development of wildlife conservation, agricultural, recreational, industrial, and related purposes. Such lands as have been or may hereafter be determined to be chiefly valuable for industrial purposes shall be leased for such purposes at such time and under such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Interior shall prescribe. All moneys received or collected in connection with such leases shall be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 715s of this title</ref>. Except to the extent otherwise provided in <ref>section 666f of this title</ref> and this section, all lands herein transferred shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior through the Fish and Wildlife Service in accordance with the provisions of the act of <date date="1946-08-14">August 14, 1946</date> (Public Law 732, Seventy-ninth Congress), and Acts supplementary thereto and amendatory thereof for the conservation of wildlife, and for the development of the agricultural, recreational, industrial, and related purposes specified in <ref>section 666f of this title</ref> and this section: <i>Provided</i>, That no jurisdiction shall be exercised by the Secretary of the Interior over that portion of such lands and the improvements thereon which are now utilized by the Department of the Army directly or indirectly until such time as it is determined by the Secretary of the Army that utilization of such portions of such lands and the improvements thereon directly or indirectly by the Department of the Army is no longer required: <i>Provided further</i>, That, subsequent to the determination referred to in the preceding proviso, the lands and improvements mentioned therein shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, and any lease or other disposition thereof shall be made subject to such terms, conditions, restrictions, and reservations imposed by the Secretary of the Army as will, in the opinion of the Secretary of the Army, be adequate to assure the continued availability for war production purposes of such lands and improvements.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 5, 1947, ch. 489, § 2</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–616, § 8</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3114</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667.</num>
<heading> Game management supply depots; appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations made for the administration, protection, maintenance, control, improvements, and development of wildlife sanctuaries, reservations, and refuges under the control of the Secretary of the Interior shall be available for the purchase, transportation, and handling of supplies and materials for distribution at cost from game management supply depots maintained by the Department of the Interior to projects specially provided for, and transfers between the appropriations for said purposes are authorized in order that the cost of supplies and materials, and transportation and handling thereof, drawn from central warehouses so maintained may be charged to the particular project benefited; and such supplies and materials as remain in said depots at the end of any fiscal year shall be continuously available for issuance during subsequent fiscal years and to be charged for by such transfers of funds between said appropriations for the fiscal year then current without decreasing in any way the appropriations made for that fiscal year: <i>Provided</i>, That supplies and materials shall not be purchased solely for the purpose of increasing the value of storehouse stock beyond reasonable requirements for any current fiscal year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 24, 1936, ch. 764</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1913</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), (f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667a.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667b.</num>
<heading> Transfer of certain real property for wildlife conservation purposes; reservation of rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request, real property which is under the jurisdiction or control of a Federal agency and no longer required by such agency, (1) can be utilized for wildlife conservation purposes by the agency of the State exercising administration over the wildlife resources of the State wherein the real property lies or by the Secretary of the Interior; and (2) is valuable for use for any such purpose, and which, in the determination of the Administrator of General Services, is available for such use may, notwithstanding any other provisions of law, be transferred without reimbursement or transfer of funds (with or without improvements as determined by said Administrator) by the Federal agency having jurisdiction or control of the property to (a) such State agency if the management thereof for the conservation of wildlife relates to other than migratory birds, or (b) to the Secretary of the Interior if the real property has particular value in carrying out the national migratory bird management program. Any such transfer to other than the United States shall be subject to the reservation by the United States of all oil, gas, and mineral rights, and to the condition that the property shall continue to be used for wildlife conservation or other of the above-stated purposes and in the event it is no longer used for such purposes or in the event it is needed for national defense purposes title thereto shall revert to the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 19, 1948, ch. 310, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 240</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, title I, § 105, <ref>63 Stat. 381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–432</ref>, <date date="1972-09-26">Sept. 26, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 723</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667c.</num>
<heading> Publication of designating order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any real property is transferred pursuant to sections 667b to 667d of this title, the Administrator of General Services shall make and have published in the Federal Register an appropriate order, which may be revised from time to time in like manner, designating for which of the purposes specified in <ref>section 667b of this title</ref> the property so transferred shall be used.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 19, 1948, ch. 310, § 2</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, title I, § 105, <ref>63 Stat. 381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667d.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A statement of the acreage and value of such property as may have been transferred pursuant to sections 667b to 667d of this title during the preceding fiscal year shall be annually prepared by the Administrator of General Services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 19, 1948, ch. 310, § 3</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, title I, § 105, <ref>63 Stat. 381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2091(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 730</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–79, § 9(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-11-16">Nov. 16, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1079</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667f.</num>
<heading> Availability of grain to prevent waterfowl depredations; payment of packaging, transporting, handling, and other charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of preventing crop damage by migratory waterfowl, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall make available to the Secretary of the Interior such wheat, corn, or other grains, acquired through price support operations and certified by the Commodity Credit Corporation to be available for purposes of sections 667f to 667f–3 of this title or in such condition through spoilage or deterioration as not to be desirable for human consumption, as the Secretary of the Interior shall requisition pursuant to <ref>section 667f–1 of this title</ref>. With respect to any grain thus made available, the Commodity Credit Corporation may pay packaging, transporting, handling, and other charges up to the time of delivery to one or more designated locations in each State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1956, ch. 512, § 1</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667f–1.</num>
<heading> Requisition of grain to prevent crop depredation by migratory waterfowl</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon a finding by the Secretary of the Interior that any area in the United States is threatened with damage to farmers’ crops by migratory waterfowl, whether or not during the open season for such migratory waterfowl, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to requisition from the Commodity Credit Corporation and to make available to Federal, State, or local governmental bodies or officials, or to private organizations or persons, such grain acquired by the Commodity Credit Corporation through price-support operations in such quantities and subject to such regulations as the Secretary determines will most effectively lure migratory waterfowl away from crop depredations and at the same time not expose such migratory waterfowl to shooting over areas to which the waterfowl have been lured by such feeding programs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1956, ch. 512, § 2</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667f–2.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement of packaging and transporting expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to all grain made available pursuant to <ref>section 667f–1 of this title</ref>, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall be reimbursed by the Secretary of the Interior for its expenses in packaging and transporting such grain for purposes of sections 667f to 667f–3 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1956, ch. 512, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667f–3.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for mitigating losses caused by waterfowl depredation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to reimburse the Commodity Credit Corporation for its investment in the grain transferred pursuant to sections 667f to 667f–3 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1956, ch. 512, § 4</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667g.</num>
<heading> Requisition of surplus grain; prevention of starvation of resident game birds and other resident wildlife; utilization by State agencies; reimbursement for packaging and transporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of meeting emergency situations caused by adverse weather conditions or other factors destructive of important wildlife resources, the States are authorized, upon the request of the State fish and game authority or other State agency having similar authority and a finding by the Secretary of the Interior that any area of the United States is threatened with serious damage or loss to resident game birds and other resident wildlife from starvation, to requisition from the Commodity Credit Corporation grain acquired by the Corporation through price support operations. Such grain may thereafter be furnished to the particular State for direct and sole utilization by the appropriate State agencies for purposes of sections 667g to 667g–2 of this title in such quantities as mutually agreed upon by the State and the Commodity Credit Corporation and subject to such regulations as may be considered desirable by the Corporation. The Corporation shall be reimbursed by the particular State in each instance for the expense of the Corporation in packaging and transporting such grain for purposes of sections 667g to 667g–2 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–152, § 1</ref>, <date date="1961-08-17">Aug. 17, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667g–1.</num>
<heading> Requisition and use of grain for prevention of starvation of migratory birds; reimbursement for packaging and transporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon a finding by the Secretary of the Interior that migratory birds are threatened with starvation in any area of the United States, the Secretary is authorized to requisition from the Commodity Credit Corporation grain acquired by that Corporation through price support operations in such quantities as may be mutually agreed upon. The Corporation shall be reimbursed by the Secretary for its expense in packaging and transporting of such grain for purposes of sections 667g to 667g–2 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–152, § 2</ref>, <date date="1961-08-17">Aug. 17, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667g–2.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for reimbursement of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to reimburse the Commodity Credit Corporation for its investment in grain transferred pursuant to sections 667g to 667g–2 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–152, § 3</ref>, <date date="1961-08-17">Aug. 17, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667h.</num>
<heading> Chronic Wasting Disease Task Force</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cervid</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cervid” means any species within the family Cervidae.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chronic wasting disease</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “chronic wasting disease” means the animal disease afflicting deer, elk, and moose populations that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a transmissible disease of the nervous system resulting in distinctive lesions in the brain; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> belongs to the group of diseases known as transmissible spongiform encephalopathies, which group includes scrapie, bovine spongiform encephalopathy, and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretaries” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, and the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, acting jointly.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretaries shall establish within the United States Fish and Wildlife Service a task force, to be known as the “Chronic Wasting Disease Task Force” (referred to in this subsection as the “Task Force”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Task Force shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collaborate with foreign governments to share research, coordinate efforts, and discuss best management practices to reduce, minimize, prevent, or eliminate chronic wasting disease in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> develop recommendations, including recommendations based on findings of the study conducted under subsection (c), and a set of best practices regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the interstate coordination of practices to prevent the new introduction of chronic wasting disease;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the prioritization and coordination of the future study of chronic wasting disease, based on evolving research needs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> ways to leverage the collective resources of Federal, State, and local agencies, Indian Tribes, and foreign governments, and resources from private, nongovernmental entities, to address chronic wasting disease in the United States and along the borders of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other area where containment or management efforts relating to chronic wasting disease may differ across jurisdictions; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> develop, from the recommendations developed under subparagraph (B), an action plan that gives States, the Federal Government, Indian Tribes, and the farmed cervid industry specific recommendations to ensure consistent and coordinated management and focused, prioritized research to stop the spread of and mitigate the impacts of chronic wasting disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Task Force shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 1 representative of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service with experience in chronic wasting disease, to be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this subsection as the “Secretary”);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 1 representative of the United States Geological Survey;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> 2 representatives of the Department of Agriculture with experience in chronic wasting disease, to be appointed by the Secretary of Agriculture—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 1 of whom shall have expertise in cervid health research; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 1 of whom shall have expertise in wildlife management;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of each State in which chronic wasting disease among elk, mule deer, white-tailed deer, or moose has been reported to the appropriate State agency, not more than 2 representatives, to be nominated by the Governor of the State—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> not more than 1 of whom shall be a representative of the State agency with jurisdiction over wildlife management or wildlife disease in the State; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the case of a State with a farmed cervid program or economy, not more than 1 of whom shall be a representative of the State agency with jurisdiction over farmed cervid regulation in the State;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> in the case of each State in which chronic wasting disease among elk, mule deer, white-tailed deer, or moose has not been documented, but that has carried out measures to prevent the introduction of chronic wasting disease among those species, not more than 2 representatives, to be nominated by the Governor of the State;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> not more than 2 representatives from an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization chosen in a process determined, in consultation with Indian Tribes, by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> not more than 5 nongovernmental members with relevant expertise appointed, after the date on which the members are first appointed under clauses (i) through (vi), by a majority vote of the State representatives appointed under clause (iv).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph requires a State to participate in the Task Force.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Co-Chairs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Federal representative described in paragraph (3)(A)(i);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 1 of the Federal representatives described in paragraph (3)(A)(iii); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 State representative appointed under paragraph (3)(A)(iv), to be selected by a majority vote of those State representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date of initial appointment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The members of the Task Force shall be appointed not later than 90 days after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>. The efforts of the Task Force shall not be contingent on the completion of the study required by subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On appointment of the members of the Task Force, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall notify the Chairs and Ranking Members of the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and Natural Resources and Agriculture of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any vacancy in the members appointed to the Task Force—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not affect the power or duty of the Task Force; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be filled not later than 30 days after the date of the vacancy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Task Force shall convene—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less frequently than twice each year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at such time and place, and by such means, as the Co-Chairs of the Task Force determine to be appropriate, which may include the use of remote conference technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interstate action plan</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the members of the Task Force are appointed, the Task Force shall submit to the Secretaries, and the heads of the State agencies with jurisdiction over wildlife disease and farmed cervid regulation of each State with a representative on the Task Force, the interstate action plan developed by the Task Force under paragraph (2)(C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretaries, any other applicable Federal agency, and each applicable State may enter into a cooperative agreement to fund necessary actions under the interstate action plan submitted under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Target date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretaries shall make the best effort of the Secretaries to enter into any cooperative agreement under clause (i) not later than 180 days after the date of submission of the interstate action plan under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching funds</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), for each fiscal year, the Secretaries may provide funds to carry out an interstate action plan through a cooperative agreement under subparagraph (B) in the amount of funds provided by the applicable States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The amount provided by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service under clause (i) for a fiscal year shall be not greater than $5,000,000.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than September 30 of the first full fiscal year after the date on which the first members of the Task Force are appointed, and each September 30 thereafter, the Task Force shall submit to the Secretaries, and the heads of the State agencies with jurisdiction over wildlife disease and farmed cervid regulation of each State with a representatives on the Task Force, a report describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> progress on the implementation of actions identified in the interstate action plan submitted under paragraph (8)(A), including the efficacy of funding under the cooperative agreement entered into under paragraph (8)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> updated resource requirements that are needed to reduce and eliminate chronic wasting disease in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any relevant updates to the recommended best management practices included in the interstate action plan submitted under paragraph (8)(B) to reduce or eliminate chronic wasting disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> new research findings and emerging research needs relating to chronic wasting disease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other relevant information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chronic wasting disease transmission in cervidae resource study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of Academy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “Academy” means the National Academy of Sciences.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretaries shall enter into an arrangement with the Academy under which the Academy shall conduct, and submit to the Secretaries a report describing the findings of, a special resource study to identify the predominant pathways and mechanisms of the transmission of chronic wasting disease in wild, captive, and farmed populations of cervids in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The arrangement under subparagraph (A) shall provide that the actual expenses incurred by the Academy in conducting the study under subparagraph (A) shall be paid by the Secretaries, subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of the study</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The study under paragraph (2) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to wild, captive, and farmed populations of cervids in the United States, identify—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to the extent possible, the pathways and mechanisms for the transmission of chronic wasting disease within live cervid populations and cervid products, which may include pathways and mechanisms for transmission from Canada;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the infection rates for each pathway and mechanism identified under subclause (I); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the relative frequency of transmission of each pathway and mechanism identified under subclause (I);</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> anthropogenic and environmental factors contributing to new chronic wasting disease emergence events;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the development of geographical areas with increased chronic wasting disease prevalence; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the overall geographical patterns of chronic wasting disease distribution;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> significant gaps in current scientific knowledge regarding the transmission pathways and mechanisms identified under clause (i)(I) and potential prevention, detection, and control methods identified under clause (v);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> for prioritization the scientific research projects that will address the knowledge gaps identified under clause (iii), based on the likelihood that a project will contribute significantly to the prevention or control of chronic wasting disease; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> potential prevention, detection, or control measures, practices, or technologies to be used to mitigate the transmission and spread of chronic wasting disease in wild, captive, and farmed populations of cervids in the United States;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assess the effectiveness of the potential prevention, detection, or control measures, practices, or technologies identified under subparagraph (A)(v); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> review and compare science-based best practices, standards, and guidance regarding the prevention, detection, and management of chronic wasting disease in wild, captive, and farmed populations of cervids in the United States that have been developed by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the National Chronic Wasting Disease Herd Certification Program of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the National Wildlife Research Center of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the United States Geological Survey;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> State wildlife and agricultural agencies, in the case of practices, standards, and guidance that provide practical, science-based recommendations to State and Federal agencies for minimizing or eliminating the risk of transmission of chronic wasting disease in the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> industry or academia, in the case of any published guidance on practices that provide practical, science-based recommendations to cervid producers for minimizing or eliminating the risk of transmission of chronic wasting disease within or between herds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The study under paragraph (2) shall be completed not later than 180 days after the date on which funds are first made available for the study.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data sharing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretaries shall share with the Academy, as necessary to conduct the study under paragraph (2), subject to the avoidance of a violation of a privacy or confidentiality requirement and the protection of confidential or privileged commercial, financial, or proprietary information, data and access to databases and research information on chronic wasting disease under the jurisdiction of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United States Geological Survey.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the date of completion of the study, the Secretaries shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the findings of the study; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any conclusions and recommendations that the Secretaries determine to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the period of fiscal years 2021 through 2030, $5,000,000 to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, to carry out administrative activities under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2021, $1,200,000 to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey, to carry out activities to fund research under subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2021, $1,200,000 to the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, to carry out activities to fund research under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–188, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–198, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667i.</num>
<heading> Chronic wasting disease research and management program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the date on which funds are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall offer to enter into cooperative agreements or other legal instruments, as authorized under <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002468">1</ref> 8312 of title 7, with eligible entities to conduct research on the transmission of, resistance to, and diagnosis of chronic wasting disease.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In entering into cooperative agreements or other legal instruments pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that shall conduct research relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> methods and products to effectively detect infectious chronic wasting disease prions in live cervids, cervid excreta, the environment, and inorganic surfaces, and to decontaminate such infectious prions; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> testing methods that significantly improve sensitivity and accelerate timelines for test results on non-live cervids;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the long-term suppression or eradication of chronic wasting disease; or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002469">2</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> determination markers for genetic resistance to chronic wasting disease and strategies for using genetic resistance to combat the spread of the disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> sustainable cervid harvest management practices to reduce chronic wasting disease occurrence and to prevent or limit spatial spread of chronic wasting disease; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> factors contributing to local emergence of chronic wasting disease, increased prevalence of chronic wasting disease, and distribution of chronic wasting disease, including mechanisms of disease transmission and effective barriers to transmission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Size of awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the maximum extent practicable, individual cooperative agreements or other legal instruments entered into under paragraph (1) shall be not less than two percent and not more than 10 percent of the funds appropriated to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative costs by eligible entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amount of a cooperative agreement or other legal instrument entered into with an eligible entity under paragraph (1), the eligible entity may use not more than 10 percent of such amounts for administrative costs incurred by the eligible entity in carrying out the research described in such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support for State efforts to manage and control chronic wasting disease</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall offer to enter into cooperative agreements or other legal instruments, as authorized under <ref>section 8312 of title 7</ref>, with State or Tribal wildlife agencies and departments of agriculture to provide direct financial assistance to support the efforts of such State or Tribal wildlife agencies and departments of agriculture to develop and implement management strategies to address chronic wasting disease within their respective jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State or Tribal wildlife agency or department of agriculture seeking direct financial assistance under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time and manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In allocating funds made available to carry out this subsection for a fiscal year among State and Tribal wildlife agencies or departments of agriculture that submit an application for direct financial assistance under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to States and Indian tribes that have—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> within their respective jurisdictions, the highest incidence of chronic wasting disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shown the greatest financial commitment to managing, monitoring, surveying, and researching chronic wasting disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> comprehensive policies and programs focused on chronic wasting disease management that have integrated the programs and policies of all involved agencies related to chronic wasting disease management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the greatest risk of an initial occurrence of chronic wasting disease originating from surrounding areas; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> the greatest need for response to new outbreaks of chronic wasting disease occurring in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> areas in which chronic wasting disease is already found; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> areas with first infections, with the intent of containing chronic wasting disease in any new area of infection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rapid response</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a State or Indian tribe detects chronic wasting disease in a cervid population within its jurisdiction that was not previously infected, the Secretary may, notwithstanding paragraphs (2) and (3), immediately issue funds made available under subsection (e), in an amount to be determined by the Secretary, to support State and Tribal efforts to immediately control the spread of chronic wasting disease within that population.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public education on chronic wasting disease</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with State and Tribal departments of agriculture and wildlife agencies, organizations representing the farmed cervid industry, and organizations representing deer hunters, shall develop and maintain materials based on the latest scientific knowledge to be used to educate the public on chronic wasting disease and techniques to help prevent the spread of the disease.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chronic wasting disease</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “chronic wasting disease” means the animal disease afflicting deer, elk, and moose populations that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a transmissible disease of the nervous system resulting in distinctive lesions in the brain; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> belongs to the group of diseases known as transmissible spongiform encephalopathies, which includes scrapie, bovine spongiform encephalopathy, and Cruetzfeldt-Jakob disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State or Tribal department of agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a State or Tribal wildlife agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a Tribal research facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an institution of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a research center conducting or qualified to conduct scientific research on chronic wasting disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of herd certification program standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting public feedback on potential updates and improvements to the chronic wasting disease herd certification program standards with special consideration given to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> minimizing or eliminating the interaction of captive and wild deer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reviewing and updating indemnity practices, including the use of live testing, to ensure the timely and targeted removal of chronic wasting disease positive deer from the landscape; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increasing participation in the herd certification program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $70,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through fiscal year 2028, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation among programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall allocate the funds made available under paragraph (1) evenly between the research program under subsection (a) and the management program under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Set-aside for wildlife agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that, of the funds made available and allocated to carry out subsection (b), not less than 75 percent of such funds are made available to State or Tribal wildlife agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the funds made available under subsection (e) for a fiscal year to carry out this section, the Secretary may use not more than 10 percent of such funds for administrative costs incurred by the Secretary in carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed as interfering with, or otherwise affecting, the authority of the Federal Government or States to manage wildlife and livestock on land within their respective jurisdictions, including managing, surveying, and monitoring the incidence of chronic wasting disease.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. HH, title V, § 603</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION OF BALD AND GOLDEN EAGLES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 668.</num>
<heading> Bald and golden eagles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited acts; criminal penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States or any place subject to the jurisdiction thereof, without being permitted to do so as provided in this subchapter, shall knowingly, or with wanton disregard for the consequences of his act take, possess, sell, purchase, barter, offer to sell, purchase or barter, transport, export or import, at any time or in any manner any bald eagle commonly known as the American eagle or any golden eagle, alive or dead, or any part, nest, or egg thereof of the foregoing eagles, or whoever violates any permit or regulation issued pursuant to this subchapter, shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than one year or both: <i>Provided</i>, That in the case of a second or subsequent conviction for a violation of this section committed after <date date="1972-10-23">October 23, 1972</date>, such person shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned not more than two years, or both: <i>Provided further</i>, That the commission of each taking or other act prohibited by this section with respect to a bald or golden eagle shall constitute a separate violation of this section: <i>Provided further</i>, That one-half of any such fine, but not to exceed $2,500, shall be paid to the person or persons giving information which leads to conviction: <i>Provided further</i>, That nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit possession or transportation of any bald eagle, alive or dead, or any part, nest, or egg thereof, lawfully taken prior to <date date="1940-06-08">June 8, 1940</date>, and that nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit possession or transportation of any golden eagle, alive or dead, or any part, nest, or egg thereof, lawfully taken prior to the addition to this subchapter of the provisions relating to preservation of the golden eagle.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States or any place subject to the jurisdiction thereof, without being permitted to do so as provided in this subchapter, shall take, possess, sell, purchase, barter, offer to sell, purchase or barter, transport, export or import, at any time or in any manner, any bald eagle, commonly known as the American eagle, or any golden eagle, alive or dead, or any part, nest, or egg thereof of the foregoing eagles, or whoever violates any permit or regulation issued pursuant to this subchapter, may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary of not more than $5,000 for each such violation. Each violation shall be a separate offense. No penalty shall be assessed unless such person is given notice and opportunity for a hearing with respect to such violation. In determining the amount of the penalty, the gravity of the violation, and the demonstrated good faith of the person charged shall be considered by the Secretary. For good cause shown, the Secretary may remit or mitigate any such penalty. Upon any failure to pay the penalty assessed under this section, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to institute a civil action in a district court of the United States for any district in which such person is found or resides or transacts business to collect the penalty and such court shall have jurisdiction to hear and decide any such action. In hearing any such action, the court must sustain the Secretary’s action if supported by substantial evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cancellation of grazing agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of any Federal agency who has issued a lease, license, permit, or other agreement authorizing the grazing of domestic livestock on Federal lands to any person who is convicted of a violation of this subchapter or of any permit or regulation issued hereunder may immediately cancel each such lease, license, permit, or other agreement. The United States shall not be liable for the payment of any compensation, reimbursement, or damages in connection with the cancellation of any lease, license, permit, or other agreement pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 8, 1940, ch. 278, § 1</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 14</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–884</ref>, <date date="1962-10-24">Oct. 24, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–535, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 668a.</num>
<heading> Taking and using of the bald and golden eagle for scientific, exhibition, and religious purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever, after investigation, the Secretary of the Interior shall determine that it is compatible with the preservation of the bald eagle or the golden eagle to permit the taking, possession, and transportation of specimens thereof for the scientific or exhibition purposes of public museums, scientific societies, and zoological parks, or for the religious purposes of Indian tribes, or that it is necessary to permit the taking of such eagles for the protection of wildlife or of agricultural or other interests in any particular locality, he may authorize the taking of such eagles pursuant to regulations which he is hereby authorized to prescribe: <i>Provided</i>, That on request of the Governor of any State, the Secretary of the Interior shall authorize the taking of golden eagles for the purpose of seasonally protecting domesticated flocks and herds in such State, in accordance with regulations established under the provisions of this section, in such part or parts of such State and for such periods as the Secretary determines to be necessary to protect such interests: <i>Provided further</i>, That bald eagles may not be taken for any purpose unless, prior to such taking, a permit to do so is procured from the Secretary of the Interior: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Interior, pursuant to such regulations as he may prescribe, may permit the taking, possession, and transportation of golden eagles for the purposes of falconry, except that only golden eagles which would be taken because of depredations on livestock or wildlife may be taken for purposes of falconry: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Interior, pursuant to such regulations as he may prescribe, may permit the taking of golden eagle nests which interfere with resource development or recovery operations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 8, 1940, ch. 278, § 2</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–884</ref>, <date date="1962-10-24">Oct. 24, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–535, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–616, § 9</ref>, <date date="1979-11-08">Nov. 8, 1979</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3114</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 668b.</num>
<heading> Enforcement provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arrest; search; issuance and execution of warrants and process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any employee of the Department of the Interior authorized by the Secretary of the Interior to enforce the provisions of this subchapter may, without warrant, arrest any person committing in his presence or view a violation of this subchapter or of any permit or regulations issued hereunder and take such person immediately for examination or trial before an officer or court of competent jurisdiction; may execute any warrant or other process issued by an officer or court of competent jurisdiction for the enforcement of the provisions of this subchapter; and may, with or without a warrant, as authorized by law, search any place. The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with State fish and wildlife agencies or other appropriate State authorities to facilitate enforcement of this subchapter, and by said agreements to delegate such enforcement authority to State law enforcement personnel as he deems appropriate for effective enforcement of this subchapter. Any judge of any court established under the laws of the United States, and any United States magistrate judge may, within his respective jurisdiction, upon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause, issue warrants in all such cases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forfeiture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All bald or golden eagles, or parts, nests, or eggs thereof, taken, possessed, sold, purchased, bartered, offered for sale, purchase, or barter, transported, exported, or imported contrary to the provisions of this subchapter, or of any permit or regulation issued hereunder, and all guns, traps, nets, and other equipment, vessels, vehicles, aircraft, and other means of transportation used to aid in the taking, possessing, selling, purchasing, bartering, offering for sale, purchase, or barter, transporting, exporting, or importing of any bird, or part, nest, or egg thereof, in violation of this subchapter or of any permit or regulation issued hereunder shall be subject to forfeiture to the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Customs laws applied</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All provisions of law relating to the seizure, forfeiture, and condemnation of a vessel for violation of the customs laws, the disposition of such vessel or the proceeds from the sale thereof, and the remission or mitigation of such forfeitures, shall apply to the seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this subchapter, insofar as such provisions of law are applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter: <i>Provided</i>, That all powers, rights, and duties conferred or imposed by the customs laws upon any officer or employee of the Treasury Department shall, for the purposes of this subchapter, be exercised or performed by the Secretary of the Interior or by such persons as he may designate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 8, 1940, ch. 278, § 3</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–535, § 3</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 668c.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this subchapter “whoever” includes also associations, partnerships, and corporations; “take” includes also pursue, shoot, shoot at, poison, wound, kill, capture, trap, collect, molest or disturb; “transport” includes also ship, convey, carry, or transport by any means whatever, and deliver or receive or cause to be delivered or received for such shipment, conveyance, carriage, or transportation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 8, 1940, ch. 278, § 4</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–535, § 4</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1065</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 668d.</num>
<heading> Availability of appropriations for Migratory Bird Treaty Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Moneys now or hereafter available to the Secretary of the Interior for the administration and enforcement of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act of <date date="1918-07-03">July 3, 1918</date> [<ref>16 U.S.C. 703</ref> et seq.], shall be equally available for the administration and enforcement of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 8, 1940, ch. 278, § 5</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 251</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ENDANGERED SPECIES OF FISH AND WILDLIFE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 668aa to 668cc–6.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–205, § 14</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 903</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 668dd.</num>
<heading> National Wildlife Refuge System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation; administration; continuance of resources-management-programs for refuge lands in Alaska; disposal of acquired lands; proceeds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purpose of consolidating the authorities relating to the various categories of areas that are administered by the Secretary for the conservation of fish and wildlife, including species that are threatened with extinction, all lands, waters, and interests therein administered by the Secretary as wildlife refuges, areas for the protection and conservation of fish and wildlife that are threatened with extinction, wildlife ranges, game ranges, wildlife management areas, or waterfowl production areas are hereby designated as the “National Wildlife Refuge System” (referred to herein as the “System”), which shall be subject to the provisions of this section, and shall be administered by the Secretary through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. With respect to refuge lands in the State of Alaska, those programs relating to the management of resources for which any other agency of the Federal Government exercises administrative responsibility through cooperative agreement shall remain in effect, subject to the direct supervision of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, as long as such agency agrees to exercise such responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The mission of the System is to administer a national network of lands and waters for the conservation, management, and where appropriate, restoration of the fish, wildlife, and plant resources and their habitats within the United States for the benefit of present and future generations of Americans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the System, it is the policy of the United States that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each refuge shall be managed to fulfill the mission of the System, as well as the specific purposes for which that refuge was established;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compatible wildlife-dependent recreation is a legitimate and appropriate general public use of the System, directly related to the mission of the System and the purposes of many refuges, and which generally fosters refuge management and through which the American public can develop an appreciation for fish and wildlife;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compatible wildlife-dependent recreational uses are the priority general public uses of the System and shall receive priority consideration in refuge planning and management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> when the Secretary determines that a proposed wildlife-dependent recreational use is a compatible use within a refuge, that activity should be facilitated, subject to such restrictions or regulations as may be necessary, reasonable, and appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In administering the System, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide for the conservation of fish, wildlife, and plants, and their habitats within the System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that the biological integrity, diversity, and environmental health of the System are maintained for the benefit of present and future generations of Americans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> plan and direct the continued growth of the System in a manner that is best designed to accomplish the mission of the System, to contribute to the conservation of the ecosystems of the United States, to complement efforts of States and other Federal agencies to conserve fish and wildlife and their habitats, and to increase support for the System and participation from conservation partners and the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ensure that the mission of the System described in paragraph (2) and the purposes of each refuge are carried out, except that if a conflict exists between the purposes of a refuge and the mission of the System, the conflict shall be resolved in a manner that first protects the purposes of the refuge, and, to the extent practicable, that also achieves the mission of the System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> ensure effective coordination, interaction, and cooperation with owners of land adjoining refuges and the fish and wildlife agency of the States in which the units of the System are located;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> assist in the maintenance of adequate water quantity and water quality to fulfill the mission of the System and the purposes of each refuge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> acquire, under State law, water rights that are needed for refuge purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> recognize compatible wildlife-dependent recreational uses as the priority general public uses of the System through which the American public can develop an appreciation for fish and wildlife;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> ensure that opportunities are provided within the System for compatible wildlife-dependent recreational uses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> ensure that priority general public uses of the System receive enhanced consideration over other general public uses in planning and management within the System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> provide increased opportunities for families to experience compatible wildlife-dependent recreation, particularly opportunities for parents and their children to safely engage in traditional outdoor activities, such as fishing and hunting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> continue, consistent with existing laws and interagency agreements, authorized or permitted uses of units of the System by other Federal agencies, including those necessary to facilitate military preparedness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> ensure timely and effective cooperation and collaboration with Federal agencies and State fish and wildlife agencies during the course of acquiring and managing refuges; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> monitor the status and trends of fish, wildlife, and plants in each refuge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> No acquired lands which are or become a part of the System may be transferred or otherwise disposed of under any provision of law (except by exchange pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of this section) unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines with the approval of the Migratory Bird Conservation Commission that such lands are no longer needed for the purposes for which the System was established; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> such lands are transferred or otherwise disposed of for an amount not less than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the acquisition costs of such lands, in the case of lands of the System which were purchased by the United States with funds from the migratory bird conservation fund, or fair market value, whichever is greater; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the fair market value of such lands (as determined by the Secretary as of the date of the transfer or disposal), in the case of lands of the System which were donated to the System.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall pay into the migratory bird conservation fund the aggregate amount of the proceeds of any transfer or disposal referred to in the preceding sentence.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Each area which is included within the System on <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, or thereafter, and which was or is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designated as an area within such System by law, Executive order, or secretarial order; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> so included by public land withdrawal, donation, purchase, exchange, or pursuant to a cooperative agreement with any State or local government, any Federal department or agency, or any other governmental entity,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall continue to be a part of the System until otherwise specified by Act of Congress, except that nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as precluding—</continuation>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the transfer or disposal of acquired lands within any such area pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the exchange of lands within any such area pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of this section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the disposal of any lands within any such area pursuant to the terms of any cooperative agreement referred to in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration; public accommodations contracts; acceptance and use of funds; exchange of properties; cash equalization payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In administering the System, the Secretary is authorized to take the following actions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Enter into contracts with any person or public or private agency through negotiation for the provision of public accommodations when, and in such locations, and to the extent that the Secretary determines will not be inconsistent with the primary purpose for which the affected area was established.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Accept donations of funds and to use such funds to acquire or manage lands or interests therein.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Acquire lands or interests therein by exchange (A) for acquired lands or public lands, or for interests in acquired or public lands, under his jurisdiction which he finds to be suitable for disposition, or (B) for the right to remove, in accordance with such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, products from the acquired or public lands within the System. The values of the properties so exchanged either shall be approximately equal, or if they are not approximately equal the values shall be equalized by the payment of cash to the grantor or to the Secretary as the circumstances require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Subject to standards established by and the overall management oversight of the Director, and consistent with standards established by this Act, to enter into cooperative agreements with State fish and wildlife agencies for the management of programs on a refuge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Issue regulations to carry out this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited and permitted activities; application of mining and mineral leasing laws, hunting or fishing regulations, and State laws or regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person shall disturb, injure, cut, burn, remove, destroy, or possess any real or personal property of the United States, including natural growth, in any area of the System; or take or possess any fish, bird, mammal, or other wild vertebrate or invertebrate animals or part or nest or egg thereof within any such area; or enter, use, or otherwise occupy any such area for any purpose; unless such activities are performed by persons authorized to manage such area, or unless such activities are permitted either under subsection (d) of this section or by express provision of the law, proclamation, Executive order, or public land order establishing the area, or amendment thereof: <i>Provided</i>, That the United States mining and mineral leasing laws shall continue to apply to any lands within the System to the same extent they apply prior to <date date="1966-10-15">October 15, 1966</date>, unless subsequently withdrawn under other authority of law. With the exception of endangered species and threatened species listed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 1533 of this title</ref> in States wherein a cooperative agreement does not exist pursuant to <ref>section 1535(c) of this title</ref>, nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to control or regulate hunting or fishing of resident fish and wildlife on lands not within the system. The regulations permitting hunting and fishing of resident fish and wildlife within the System shall be, to the extent practicable, consistent with State fish and wildlife laws and regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of areas; administration of migratory bird sanctuaries as game taking areas; rights of way, easements, and reservations; payment of fair market value</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary is authorized, under such regulations as he may prescribe, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> permit the use of any area within the System for any purpose, including but not limited to hunting, fishing, public recreation and accommodations, and access whenever he determines that such uses are compatible with the major purposes for which such areas were established: <i>Provided</i>, That not to exceed 40 per centum at any one time of any area that has been, or hereafter may be acquired, reserved, or set apart as an inviolate sanctuary for migratory birds, under any law, proclamation, Executive order, or public land order may be administered by the Secretary as an area within which the taking of migratory game birds may be permitted under such regulations as he may prescribe unless the Secretary finds that the taking of any species of migratory game birds in more than 40 percent of such area would be beneficial to the species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permit the use of, or grant easements in, over, across, upon, through, or under any areas within the System for purposes such as but not necessarily limited to, powerlines, telephone lines, canals, ditches, pipelines, and roads, including the construction, operation, and maintenance thereof, whenever he determines that such uses are compatible with the purposes for which these areas are established.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may not grant to any Federal, State, or local agency or to any private individual or organization any right-of-way, easement, or reservation in, over, across, through, or under any area within the system in connection with any use permitted by him under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection unless the grantee pays to the Secretary, at the option of the Secretary, either (A) in lump sum the fair market value (determined by the Secretary as of the date of conveyance to the grantee) of the right-of-way, easement, or reservation; or (B) annually in advance the fair market rental value (determined by the Secretary) of the right-of-way, easement, or reservation. If any Federal, State, or local agency is exempted from such payment by any other provision of Federal law, such agency shall otherwise compensate the Secretary by any other means agreeable to the Secretary, including, but not limited to, making other land available or the loan of equipment or personnel; except that (A) any such compensation shall relate to, and be consistent with, the objectives of the National Wildlife Refuge System, and (B) the Secretary may waive such requirement for compensation if he finds such requirement impracticable or unnecessary. All sums received by the Secretary pursuant to this paragraph shall, after payment of any necessary expenses incurred by him in administering this paragraph, be deposited into the Migratory Bird Conservation Fund and shall be available to carry out the provisions for land acquisition of the Migratory Bird Conservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 715</ref> et seq.) and the Migratory Bird Hunting Stamp Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 718</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as provided in clause (iv), the Secretary shall not initiate or permit a new use of a refuge or expand, renew, or extend an existing use of a refuge, unless the Secretary has determined that the use is a compatible use and that the use is not inconsistent with public safety. The Secretary may make the determinations referred to in this paragraph for a refuge concurrently with development of a conservation plan under subsection (e).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> On lands added to the System after <date date="1996-03-25">March 25, 1996</date>, the Secretary shall identify, prior to acquisition, withdrawal, transfer, reclassification, or donation of any such lands, existing compatible wildlife-dependent recreational uses that the Secretary determines shall be permitted to continue on an interim basis pending completion of the comprehensive conservation plan for the refuge.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Wildlife-dependent recreational uses may be authorized on a refuge when they are compatible and not inconsistent with public safety. Except for consideration of consistency with State laws and regulations as provided for in subsection (m), no other determinations or findings are required to be made by the refuge official under this Act or the Refuge Recreation Act for wildlife-dependent recreation to occur.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Compatibility determinations in existence on <date date="1997-10-09">October 9, 1997</date>, shall remain in effect until and unless modified.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 24 months after <date date="1997-10-09">October 9, 1997</date>, the Secretary shall issue final regulations establishing the process for determining under subparagraph (A) whether a use of a refuge is a compatible use. These regulations shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> designate the refuge official responsible for making initial compatibility determinations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> require an estimate of the timeframe, location, manner, and purpose of each use;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> identify the effects of each use on refuge resources and purposes of each refuge;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> require that compatibility determinations be made in writing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> provide for the expedited consideration of uses that will likely have no detrimental effect on the fulfillment of the purposes of a refuge or the mission of the System;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> provide for the elimination or modification of any use as expeditiously as practicable after a determination is made that the use is not a compatible use;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> require, after an opportunity for public comment, reevaluation of each existing use, other than those uses specified in clause (viii), if conditions under which the use is permitted change significantly or if there is significant new information regarding the effects of the use, but not less frequently than once every 10 years, to ensure that the use remains a compatible use, except that, in the case of any use authorized for a period longer than 10 years (such as an electric utility right-of-way), the reevaluation required by this clause shall examine compliance with the terms and conditions of the authorization, not examine the authorization itself;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> require, after an opportunity for public comment, reevaluation of each compatible wildlife-dependent recreational use when conditions under which the use is permitted change significantly or if there is significant new information regarding the effects of the use, but not less frequently than in conjunction with each preparation or revision of a conservation plan under subsection (e) or at least every 15 years, whichever is earlier; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> provide an opportunity for public review and comment on each evaluation of a use, unless an opportunity for public review and comment on the evaluation of the use has already been provided during the development or revision of a conservation plan for the refuge under subsection (e) or has otherwise been provided during routine, periodic determinations of compatibility for wildlife-dependent recreational uses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of this Act relating to determinations of the compatibility of a use shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> overflights above a refuge; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> activities authorized, funded, or conducted by a Federal agency (other than the United States Fish and Wildlife Service) which has primary jurisdiction over a refuge or a portion of a refuge, if the management of those activities is in accordance with a memorandum of understanding between the Secretary or the Director and the head of the Federal agency with primary jurisdiction over the refuge governing the use of the refuge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refuge conservation planning program for non-Alaskan refuge lands</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except with respect to refuge lands in Alaska (which shall be governed by the refuge planning provisions of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.)), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> propose a comprehensive conservation plan for each refuge or related complex of refuges (referred to in this subsection as a “planning unit”) in the System;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> publish a notice of opportunity for public comment in the Federal Register on each proposed conservation plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> issue a final conservation plan for each planning unit consistent with the provisions of this Act and, to the extent practicable, consistent with fish and wildlife conservation plans of the State in which the refuge is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> not less frequently than 15 years after the date of issuance of a conservation plan under clause (iii) and every 15 years thereafter, revise the conservation plan as may be necessary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prepare a comprehensive conservation plan under this subsection for each refuge within 15 years after <date date="1997-10-09">October 9, 1997</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall manage each refuge or planning unit under plans in effect on <date date="1997-10-09">October 9, 1997</date>, to the extent such plans are consistent with this Act, until such plans are revised or superseded by new comprehensive conservation plans issued under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Uses or activities consistent with this Act may occur on any refuge or planning unit before existing plans are revised or new comprehensive conservation plans are issued under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Upon completion of a comprehensive conservation plan under this subsection for a refuge or planning unit, the Secretary shall manage the refuge or planning unit in a manner consistent with the plan and shall revise the plan at any time if the Secretary determines that conditions that affect the refuge or planning unit have changed significantly.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In developing each comprehensive conservation plan under this subsection for a planning unit, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall identify and describe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the purposes of each refuge comprising the planning unit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the distribution, migration patterns, and abundance of fish, wildlife, and plant populations and related habitats within the planning unit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the archaeological and cultural values of the planning unit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such areas within the planning unit that are suitable for use as administrative sites or visitor facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> significant problems that may adversely affect the populations and habitats of fish, wildlife, and plants within the planning unit and the actions necessary to correct or mitigate such problems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> opportunities for compatible wildlife-dependent recreational uses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In preparing each comprehensive conservation plan under this subsection, and any revision to such a plan, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with this Act—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with adjoining Federal, State, local, and private landowners and affected State conservation agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinate the development of the conservation plan or revision with relevant State conservation plans for fish and wildlife and their habitats.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In accordance with subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall develop and implement a process to ensure an opportunity for active public involvement in the preparation and revision of comprehensive conservation plans under this subsection. At a minimum, the Secretary shall require that publication of any final plan shall include a summary of the comments made by States, owners of adjacent or potentially affected land, local governments, and any other affected persons, and a statement of the disposition of concerns expressed in those comments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Prior to the adoption of each comprehensive conservation plan under this subsection, the Secretary shall issue public notice of the draft proposed plan, make copies of the plan available at the affected field and regional offices of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and provide opportunity for public comment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowing violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person who knowingly violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of this Act or any regulations issued thereunder shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person who otherwise violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of this Act (including a regulation issued under this Act) shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement provision; arrests, searches, and seizures; custody of property; forfeitures; disposition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person authorized by the Secretary to enforce the provisions of this Act or any regulations issued thereunder, may, without a warrant, arrest any person violating this Act or regulations in his presence or view, and may execute any warrant or other process issued by an officer or court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this Act or regulations, and may with a search warrant search for and seize any property, fish, bird, mammal, or other wild vertebrate or invertebrate animals or part or nest or egg thereof, taken or possessed in violation of this Act or the regulations issued thereunder. Any property, fish, bird, mammal, or other wild vertebrate or invertebrate animals or part or egg thereof seized with or without a search warrant shall be held by such person or by a United States marshal, and upon conviction, shall be forfeited to the United States and disposed of by the Secretary, in accordance with law. The Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service is authorized to utilize by agreement, with or without reimbursement, the personnel and services of any other Federal or State agency for purposes of enhancing the enforcement of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations; continuation, modification, or rescission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations applicable to areas of the System that are in effect on <date date="1966-10-15">October 15, 1966</date>, shall continue in effect until modified or rescinded.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National conservation recreational area provisions; amendment, repeal, or modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to amend, repeal, or otherwise modify the provision of the Act of <date date="1962-09-28">September 28, 1962</date> (<ref>76 Stat. 653</ref>; <ref>16 U.S.C. 460k</ref>—460k–4) which authorizes the Secretary to administer the areas within the System for public recreation. The provisions of this section relating to recreation shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of said Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption from State water laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall constitute an express or implied claim or denial on the part of the Federal Government as to exemption from State water laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency power</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary may temporarily suspend, allow, or initiate any activity in a refuge in the System if the Secretary determines it is necessary to protect the health and safety of the public or any fish or wildlife population.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hunting and fishing on lands and waters not within System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to control or regulate hunting or fishing of fish and resident wildlife on lands or waters that are not within the System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as affecting the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of the several States to manage, control, or regulate fish and resident wildlife under State law or regulations in any area within the System. Regulations permitting hunting or fishing of fish and resident wildlife within the System shall be, to the extent practicable, consistent with State fish and wildlife laws, regulations, and management plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water rights</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this Act shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> create a reserved water right, express or implied, in the United States for any purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> affect any water right in existence on <date date="1997-10-09">October 9, 1997</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> affect any Federal or State law in existence on <date date="1997-10-09">October 9, 1997</date>, regarding water quality or water quantity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this Act shall diminish or affect the ability to join the United States in the adjudication of rights to the use of water pursuant to <ref>section 666 of title 43</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Coordination with State fish and wildlife agency personnel or with personnel of other affected State agencies pursuant to this Act shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–669, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–404, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-07-18">July 18, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–205, § 13(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–509, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1603</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–215, § 5</ref>, <date date="1976-02-17">Feb. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–223</ref>, <date date="1976-02-27">Feb. 27, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–616</ref>, §§ 3(f), 6, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3111</ref>, 3114; <ref>Pub. L. 100–226, § 4</ref>, <date date="1987-12-31">Dec. 31, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–653, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–57</ref>, §§ 3(b)–8, <date date="1997-10-09">Oct. 9, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1254–1259</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–312, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2958</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(99)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 668ee.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this Act:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “compatible use” means a wildlife-dependent recreational use or any other use of a refuge that, in the sound professional judgment of the Director, will not materially interfere with or detract from the fulfillment of the mission of the System or the purposes of the refuge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The terms “wildlife-dependent recreation” and “wildlife-dependent recreational use” mean a use of a refuge involving hunting, fishing, wildlife observation and photography, or environmental education and interpretation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “sound professional judgment” means a finding, determination, or decision that is consistent with principles of sound fish and wildlife management and administration, available science and resources, and adherence to the requirements of this Act and other applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The terms “conserving”, “conservation”, “manage”, “managing”, and “management”, mean to sustain and, where appropriate, restore and enhance, healthy populations of fish, wildlife, and plants utilizing, in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws, methods and procedures associated with modern scientific resource programs. Such methods and procedures include, consistent with the provisions of this Act, protection, research, census, law enforcement, habitat management, propagation, live trapping and transplantation, and regulated taking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Coordination Area” means a wildlife management area that is made available to a State—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by cooperative agreement between the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and a State agency having control over wildlife resources pursuant to <ref>section 664 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by long-term leases or agreements pursuant to title III of the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act (<ref>50 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref>7 U.S.C. 1010</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Director” means the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or a designee of that Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The terms “fish”, “wildlife”, and “fish and wildlife” mean any wild member of the animal kingdom whether alive or dead, and regardless of whether the member was bred, hatched, or born in captivity, including a part, product, egg, or offspring of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “plant” means any member of the plant kingdom in a wild, unconfined state, including any plant community, seed, root, or other part of a plant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The terms “purposes of the refuge” and “purposes of each refuge” mean the purposes specified in or derived from the law, proclamation, executive order, agreement, public land order, donation document, or administrative memorandum establishing, authorizing, or expanding a refuge, refuge unit, or refuge subunit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The term “refuge” means a designated area of land, water, or an interest in land or water within the System, but does not include Coordination Areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The terms “State” and “United States” mean the several States of the United States, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The term “System” means the National Wildlife Refuge System designated under <ref>section 668dd(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> The terms “take”, “taking”, and “taken” mean to pursue, hunt, shoot, capture, collect, or kill, or to attempt to pursue, hunt, shoot, capture, collect, or kill.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–669, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–57, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-10-09">Oct. 9, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 668ff to 668jj.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 668kk to 668ss.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>