<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 84—</num>
<heading>HEALTHY FOREST RESTORATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6501.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to reduce wildfire risk to communities, municipal water supplies, and other at-risk Federal land through a collaborative process of planning, prioritizing, and implementing hazardous fuel reduction projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to authorize grant programs to improve the commercial value of forest biomass (that otherwise contributes to the risk of catastrophic fire or insect or disease infestation) for producing electric energy, useful heat, transportation fuel, and petroleum-based product substitutes, and for other commercial purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to enhance efforts to protect watersheds and address threats to forest and rangeland health, including catastrophic wildfire, across the landscape;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to promote systematic gathering of information to address the impact of insect and disease infestations and other damaging agents on forest and rangeland health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to improve the capacity to detect insect and disease infestations at an early stage, particularly with respect to hardwood forests; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> to protect, restore, and enhance forest ecosystem components—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to promote the recovery of threatened and endangered species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to improve biological diversity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to enhance productivity and carbon sequestration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1888</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6502.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal land” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> land of the National Forest System (as defined in <ref>section 1609(a) of this title</ref>) administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> public lands (as defined in <ref>section 1702 of title 43</ref>), the surface of which is administered by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1888</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>HAZARDOUS FUEL REDUCTION ON FEDERAL LAND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6511.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> At-risk community</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “at-risk community” means an area—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> that is comprised of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an interface community as defined in the notice entitled “Wildland Urban Interface Communities Within the Vicinity of Federal Lands That Are at High Risk From Wildfire” issued by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior in accordance with title IV of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 (<ref>114 Stat. 1009</ref>) (66 Fed. Reg. 753, <date date="2001-01-04">January 4, 2001</date>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a group of homes and other structures with basic infrastructure and services (such as utilities and collectively maintained transportation routes) within or adjacent to Federal land;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in which conditions are conducive to a large-scale wildland fire disturbance event; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for which a significant threat to human life or property exists as a result of a wildland fire disturbance event.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized hazardous fuel reduction project</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “authorized hazardous fuel reduction project” means the measures and methods described in the definition of “appropriate tools” contained in the glossary of the Implementation Plan, on Federal land described in <ref>section 6512(a) of this title</ref> and conducted under sections 6513 and 6514 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “authorized hazardous fuel reduction project” includes, using the measures and methods described in subparagraph (A), the installation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a natural or manmade change in fuel characteristics that affects fire behavior such that a fire can be more readily controlled (commonly known as a “fuel break”); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a natural or constructed barrier used to stop or check a fire or to provide a control line from which to work to stop or check a fire (commonly known as a “firebreak”).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community wildfire protection plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “community wildfire protection plan” means a plan for an at-risk community that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is developed within the context of the collaborative agreements and the guidance established by the Wildland Fire Leadership Council and agreed to by the applicable local government, local fire department, and State agency responsible for forest management, in consultation with interested parties and the Federal land management agencies managing land in the vicinity of the at-risk community;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identifies and prioritizes areas for hazardous fuel reduction treatments and recommends the types and methods of treatment on Federal and non-Federal land that will protect 1 or more at-risk communities and essential infrastructure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommends measures to reduce structural ignitability throughout the at-risk community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition class 2</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “condition class 2”, with respect to an area of Federal land, means the condition class description developed by the Forest Service Rocky Mountain Research Station in the general technical report entitled “Development of Coarse-Scale Spatial Data for Wildland Fire and Fuel Management” (RMRS–87), dated April 2000 (including any subsequent revision to the report), under which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fire regimes on the land have been moderately altered from historical ranges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there exists a moderate risk of losing key ecosystem components from fire;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> fire frequencies have increased or decreased from historical frequencies by 1 or more return intervals, resulting in moderate changes to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the size, frequency, intensity, or severity of fires; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> landscape patterns; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> vegetation attributes have been moderately altered from the historical range of the attributes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition class 3</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “condition class 3”, with respect to an area of Federal land, means the condition class description developed by the Rocky Mountain Research Station in the general technical report referred to in paragraph (4) (including any subsequent revision to the report), under which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fire regimes on land have been significantly altered from historical ranges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there exists a high risk of losing key ecosystem components from fire;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> fire frequencies have departed from historical frequencies by multiple return intervals, resulting in dramatic changes to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the size, frequency, intensity, or severity of fires; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> landscape patterns; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> vegetation attributes have been significantly altered from the historical range of the attributes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “day” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a calendar day; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if a deadline imposed by this subchapter would expire on a nonbusiness day, the end of the next business day.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decision document</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “decision document” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a decision notice (as that term is used in the Forest Service Handbook);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a decision record (as that term is used in the Bureau of Land Management Handbook); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a record of decision (as that term is used in applicable regulations of the Council on Environmental Quality).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fire regime I</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fire regime I” means an area—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in which historically there have been low-severity fires with a frequency of 0 through 35 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is located primarily in low elevation forests of pine, oak, or pinyon juniper.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fire regime II</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fire regime II” means an area—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in which historically there are stand replacement severity fires with a frequency of 0 through 35 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is located primarily in low- to mid-elevation rangeland, grassland, or shrubland.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fire regime III</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fire regime III” means an area—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in which historically there are mixed severity fires with a frequency of 35 through 100 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is located primarily in forests of mixed conifer, dry Douglas fir, or wet Ponderosa pine.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation Plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Implementation Plan” means the Implementation Plan for the Comprehensive Strategy for a Collaborative Approach for Reducing Wildland Fire Risks to Communities and the Environment, dated May 2002, developed pursuant to the conference report to accompany the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 (House Report No. 106–64) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002828">1</ref> (and subsequent revisions).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Municipal water supply system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “municipal water supply system” means the reservoirs, canals, ditches, flumes, laterals, pipes, pipelines, and other surface facilities and systems constructed or installed for the collection, impoundment, storage, transportation, or distribution of drinking water.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resource management plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “resource management plan” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a land and resource management plan prepared for 1 or more units of land of the National Forest System described in <ref>section 6502(1)(A) of this title</ref> under <ref>section 1604 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a land use plan prepared for 1 or more units of the public land described in <ref>section 6502(1)(B) of this title</ref> under <ref>section 1712 of title 43</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land of the National Forest System described in <ref>section 6502(1)(A) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands described in <ref>section 6502(1)(B) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Threatened and endangered species habitat</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “threatened and endangered species habitat” means Federal land identified in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a determination that a species is an endangered species or a threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a designation of critical habitat of the species under that Act; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a recovery plan prepared for the species under that Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wildland-urban interface</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “wildland-urban interface” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an area within or adjacent to an at-risk community that is identified in recommendations to the Secretary in a community wildfire protection plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of any area for which a community wildfire protection plan is not in effect—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an area extending ½-mile from the boundary of an at-risk community;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> an area within 1½ miles of the boundary of an at-risk community, including any land that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> has a sustained steep slope that creates the potential for wildfire behavior endangering the at-risk community;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has a geographic feature that aids in creating an effective fire break, such as a road or ridge top; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> is in condition class 3, as documented by the Secretary in the project-specific environmental analysis; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an area that is adjacent to an evacuation route for an at-risk community that the Secretary determines, in cooperation with the at-risk community, requires hazardous fuel reduction to provide safer evacuation from the at-risk community.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1889</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6512.</num>
<heading> Authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As soon as practicable after <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>, the Secretary shall implement authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects, consistent with the Implementation Plan, on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Federal land in wildland-urban interface areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> condition class 3 Federal land, in such proximity to a municipal water supply system or a stream feeding such a system within a municipal watershed that a significant risk exists that a fire disturbance event would have adverse effects on the water quality of the municipal water supply or the maintenance of the system, including a risk to water quality posed by erosion following such a fire disturbance event;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> condition class 2 Federal land located within fire regime I, fire regime II, or fire regime III, in such proximity to a municipal water supply system or a stream feeding such a system within a municipal watershed that a significant risk exists that a fire disturbance event would have adverse effects on the water quality of the municipal water supply or the maintenance of the system, including a risk to water quality posed by erosion following such a fire disturbance event;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Federal land on which windthrow or blowdown, ice storm damage, the existence of an epidemic of disease or insects, or the presence of such an epidemic on immediately adjacent land and the imminent risk it will spread, poses a significant threat to an ecosystem component, or forest or rangeland resource, on the Federal land or adjacent non-Federal land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Federal land not covered by paragraphs (1) through (4) that contains threatened and endangered species habitat, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> natural fire regimes on that land are identified as being important for, or wildfire is identified as a threat to, an endangered species, a threatened species, or habitat of an endangered species or threatened species in a species recovery plan prepared under <ref>section 1533 of this title</ref>, or a notice published in the Federal Register determining a species to be an endangered species or a threatened species or designating critical habitat;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the authorized hazardous fuel reduction project will provide enhanced protection from catastrophic wildfire for the endangered species, threatened species, or habitat of the endangered species or threatened species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary complies with any applicable guidelines specified in any management or recovery plan described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to agency plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An authorized hazardous fuel reduction project shall be conducted consistent with the resource management plan and other relevant administrative policies or decisions applicable to the Federal land covered by the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than a total of 20,000,000 acres of Federal land may be treated under authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of certain Federal land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may not conduct an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project that would occur on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Federal land on which the removal of vegetation is prohibited or restricted by Act of Congress or Presidential proclamation (including the applicable implementation plan); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a Wilderness Study Area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Old growth stands</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection and subsection (f):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “applicable period” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the 2-year period beginning on <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a resource management plan that the Secretary is in the process of revising as of <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>, the 3-year period beginning on <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered project</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “covered project” means an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project carried out on land described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (5) of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management direction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “management direction” means definitions, designations, standards, guidelines, goals, or objectives established for an old growth stand under a resource management plan developed in accordance with applicable law, including <ref>section 1604(g)(3)(B) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Old growth stand</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “old growth stand” has the meaning given the term under management direction used pursuant to paragraphs (3) and (4), based on the structure and composition characteristic of the forest type, and in accordance with applicable law, including <ref>section 1604(g)(3)(B) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out a covered project, the Secretary shall fully maintain, or contribute toward the restoration of, the structure and composition of old growth stands according to the pre-fire suppression old growth conditions characteristic of the forest type, taking into account the contribution of the stand to landscape fire adaptation and watershed health, and retaining the large trees contributing to old growth structure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Newer management direction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the management direction for an old growth stand was established on or after <date date="1993-12-15">December 15, 1993</date>, the Secretary shall meet the requirements of paragraph (2) in carrying out a covered project by implementing the management direction.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendments or revisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any amendment or revision to management direction for which final administrative approval is granted after <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>, shall be consistent with paragraph (2) for the purpose of carrying out covered projects.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Older management direction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the management direction for an old growth stand was established before <date date="1993-12-15">December 15, 1993</date>, the Secretary shall meet the requirements of paragraph (2) in carrying out a covered project during the applicable period by implementing the management direction.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), during the applicable period for management direction referred to in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> review the management direction for affected covered projects, taking into account any relevant scientific information made available since the adoption of the management direction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> amend the management direction for affected covered projects to be consistent with paragraph (2), if necessary to reflect relevant scientific information the Secretary did not consider in formulating the management direction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review not completed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the Secretary does not complete the review of the management direction in accordance with subparagraph (B) before the end of the applicable period, the Secretary shall not carry out any portion of affected covered projects in stands that are identified as old growth stands (based on substantial supporting evidence) by any person during scoping, within the period—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> beginning at the close of the applicable period for the management direction governing the affected covered projects; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> ending on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the date the Secretary completes the action required by subparagraph (B) for the management direction applicable to the affected covered projects; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the date on which the acreage limitation specified in subsection (c) (as that limitation may be adjusted by a subsequent Act of Congress) is reached.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation to covered projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection requires the Secretary to revise or otherwise amend a resource management plan to make the project requirements of paragraph (2) apply to an activity other than a covered project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Large tree retention</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except in old growth stands where the management direction is consistent with subsection (e)(2), the Secretary shall carry out a covered project in a manner that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> focuses largely on small diameter trees, thinning, strategic fuel breaks, and prescribed fire to modify fire behavior, as measured by the projected reduction of uncharacteristically severe wildfire effects for the forest type (such as adverse soil impacts, tree mortality or other impacts); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maximizes the retention of large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote fire-resilient stands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wildfire risk</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection prevents achievement of the purposes described in <ref>section 6501(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and assessing forest and rangeland health</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For each Forest Service administrative region and each Bureau of Land Management State Office, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> monitor the results of a representative sample of the projects authorized under this subchapter for each management unit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 5 years after <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>, and each 5 years thereafter, issue a report that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the progress towards project goals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recommendations for modifications to the projects and management treatments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency of projects with recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An authorized hazardous fuel reduction project approved following the issuance of a monitoring report shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be consistent with any applicable recommendations in the report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Similar vegetation types</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The results of a monitoring report shall be made available for use (if appropriate) in an authorized hazardous fuels reduction project conducted in a similar vegetation type on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and assessments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Monitoring and assessment shall include a description of the changes in condition class, using the Fire Regime Condition Class Guidebook or successor guidance, specifically comparing end results to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pretreatment conditions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> historical fire regimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any applicable watershed or landscape goals or objectives in the resource management plan or other relevant direction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiparty monitoring</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In an area where significant interest is expressed in multiparty monitoring, the Secretary shall establish a multiparty monitoring, evaluation, and accountability process in order to assess the positive or negative ecological and social effects of authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects and projects conducted pursuant to <ref>section 6554 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diverse stakeholders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall include diverse stakeholders (including interested citizens and Indian tribes) in the process required under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Funds to carry out this paragraph may be derived from operations funds for projects described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of monitoring data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may collect monitoring data by entering into cooperative agreements or contracts with, or providing grants to, small or micro-businesses, cooperatives, nonprofit organizations, Youth Conservation Corps work crews, or related State, local, and other non-Federal conservation corps.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tracking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each administrative unit, the Secretary shall track acres burned, by the degree of severity, by large wildfires (as defined by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and maintenance of treated areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, develop a process for monitoring the need for maintenance of treated areas, over time, in order to preserve the forest health benefits achieved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6513.</num>
<heading> Prioritization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with the Implementation Plan, the Secretary shall develop an annual program of work for Federal land that gives priority to authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects that provide for the protection of at-risk communities or watersheds or that implement community wildfire protection plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaboration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall consider recommendations under subsection (a) that are made by at-risk communities that have developed community wildfire protection plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the planning process and recommendations concerning community wildfire protection plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal agency involvement in developing a community wildfire protection plan, or a recommendation made in a community wildfire protection plan, shall not be considered a Federal agency action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In implementing authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects on Federal land, the Secretary shall, in accordance with <ref>section 6514 of this title</ref>, comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding allocation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal land</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall use not less than 50 percent of the funds allocated for authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in the wildland-urban interface.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability and allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The funding allocation in subparagraph (A) shall apply at the national level. The Secretary may allocate the proportion of funds differently than is required under subparagraph (A) within individual management units as appropriate, in particular to conduct authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects on land described in <ref>section 6512(a)(4) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wildland-urban interface</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project for which a decision notice is issued during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>, the Secretary shall use existing definitions of the term “wildland-urban interface” rather than the definition of that term provided under <ref>section 6511 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal land</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In providing financial assistance under any provision of law for hazardous fuel reduction projects on non-Federal land, the Secretary shall consider recommendations made by at-risk communities that have developed community wildfire protection plans.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In allocating funding under this paragraph, the Secretary should, to the maximum extent practicable, give priority to communities that have adopted a community wildfire protection plan or have taken proactive measures to encourage willing property owners to reduce fire risk on private property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross-boundary hazardous fuel reduction projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hazardous fuel reduction project</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “hazardous fuel reduction project” means a hazardous fuel reduction project described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “non-Federal land” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> State land;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> county land;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Tribal land;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> private land; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> other non-Federal land.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may make grants to State foresters to support hazardous fuel reduction projects that incorporate treatments in landscapes across ownership boundaries on Federal and non-Federal land, particularly in areas identified as priorities in applicable State-wide forest resource assessments or strategies under <ref>section 2101a(a) of this title</ref>, as mutually agreed to by the State forester and the Regional Forester.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Land treatments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To conduct and fund treatments for hazardous fuel reduction projects carried out by State foresters using grants under paragraph (2), the Secretary may use the authorities of the Secretary relating to cooperation and technical and financial assistance, including the good neighbor authority under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 2113a of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 331 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1011</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 106–291</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out a hazardous fuel reduction project using a grant under paragraph (2) on non-Federal land, the State forester, in consultation with the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall consult with any applicable owners of the non-Federal land; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not implement the hazardous fuel reduction project on non-Federal land without the consent of the owner of the non-Federal land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8401</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(130)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4319</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6514.</num>
<heading> Environmental analysis</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, the Secretary shall conduct authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in accordance with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental assessment or environmental impact statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement pursuant to section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332(2)</ref>) for each authorized hazardous fuel reduction project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of alternatives</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (d), in the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement prepared under subsection (b), the Secretary shall study, develop, and describe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the proposed agency action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the alternative of no action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> an additional action alternative, if the additional alternative—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is proposed during scoping or the collaborative process under subsection (f); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets the purpose and need of the project, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Council on Environmental Quality.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple additional alternatives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If more than 1 additional alternative is proposed under paragraph (1)(C), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> select which additional alternative to consider, which is a choice that is in the sole discretion of the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide a written record describing the reasons for the selection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative analysis process for projects in wildland-urban interface</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed agency action and 1 action alternative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project that is proposed to be conducted in the wildland-urban interface, the Secretary is not required to study, develop, or describe more than the proposed agency action and 1 action alternative in the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement prepared pursuant to section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332(2)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed agency action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), but subject to paragraph (3), if an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project proposed to be conducted in the wildland-urban interface is located no further than 1½ miles from the boundary of an at-risk community, the Secretary is not required to study, develop, or describe any alternative to the proposed agency action in the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement prepared pursuant to section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332(2)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed agency action and community wildfire protection plan alternative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project described in paragraph (2), if the at-risk community has adopted a community wildfire protection plan and the proposed agency action does not implement the recommendations in the plan regarding the general location and basic method of treatments, the Secretary shall evaluate the recommendations in the plan as an alternative to the proposed agency action in the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement prepared pursuant to section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332(2)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice and meeting</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide notice of each authorized hazardous fuel reduction project in accordance with applicable regulations and administrative guidelines.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public meeting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">During the preparation stage of each authorized hazardous fuel reduction project, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct a public meeting at an appropriate location proximate to the administrative unit of the Federal land on which the authorized hazardous fuel reduction project will be conducted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide advance notice of the location, date, and time of the meeting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public collaboration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to encourage meaningful public participation during preparation of authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects, the Secretary shall facilitate collaboration among State and local governments and Indian tribes, and participation of interested persons, during the preparation of each authorized fuel reduction project in a manner consistent with the Implementation Plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental analysis and public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332(2)</ref>) and the applicable regulations and administrative guidelines, the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for public comment during the preparation of any environmental assessment or environmental impact statement for an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decision document</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall sign a decision document for authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects and provide notice of the final agency actions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6515.</num>
<heading> Special administrative review process</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim final regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall promulgate interim final regulations to establish a predecisional administrative review process for the period described in paragraph (2) that will serve as the sole means by which a person can seek administrative review regarding an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project on Forest Service land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The predecisional administrative review process required under paragraph (1) shall occur during the period—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> beginning after the completion of the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ending not later than the date of the issuance of the final decision approving the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to participate in the administrative review process for an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project under paragraph (1), a person shall submit to the Secretary, during scoping or the public comment period for the draft environmental analysis for the project, specific written comments that relate to the proposed action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The interim final regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall take effect on the date of promulgation of the regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate final regulations to establish the process described in subsection (a)(1) after the interim final regulations have been published and reasonable time has been provided for public comment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A person may bring a civil action challenging an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project in a Federal district court only if the person has challenged the authorized hazardous fuel reduction project by exhausting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the administrative review process established by the Secretary of Agriculture under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the administrative hearings and appeals procedures established by the Department of the Interior.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issues</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An issue may be considered in the judicial review of an action under <ref>section 6516 of this title</ref> only if the issue was raised in an administrative review process described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An exception to the requirement of exhausting the administrative review process before seeking judicial review shall be available if a Federal court finds that the futility or inadequacy exception applies to a specific plaintiff or claim.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If an agency fails or is unable to make information timely available during the administrative review process, a court should evaluate whether the administrative review process was inadequate for claims or issues to which the information is material.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1899</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6516.</num>
<heading> Judicial review in United States district courts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Venue</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 1391 of title 28</ref> or other applicable law, an authorized hazardous fuels reduction project conducted under this subchapter shall be subject to judicial review only in the United States district court for a district in which the Federal land to be treated under the authorized hazardous fuels reduction project is located.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expeditious completion of judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the judicial review of an action challenging an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project under subsection (a), Congress encourages a court of competent jurisdiction to expedite, to the maximum extent practicable, the proceedings in the action with the goal of rendering a final determination on jurisdiction, and (if jurisdiction exists) a final determination on the merits, as soon as practicable after the date on which a complaint or appeal is filed to initiate the action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Injunctions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), the length of any preliminary injunctive relief and stays pending appeal covering an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project carried out under this subchapter shall not exceed 60 days.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Renewal</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A court of competent jurisdiction may issue 1 or more renewals of any preliminary injunction, or stay pending appeal, granted under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In each renewal of an injunction in an action, the parties to the action shall present the court with updated information on the status of the authorized hazardous fuel reduction project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Balancing of short- and long-term effects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As part of its weighing the equities while considering any request for an injunction that applies to an agency action under an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project, the court reviewing the project shall balance the impact to the ecosystem likely affected by the project of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the short- and long-term effects of undertaking the agency action; against</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the short- and long-term effects of not undertaking the agency action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6517.</num>
<heading> Effect of subchapter</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter affects, or otherwise biases, the use by the Secretary of other statutory or administrative authority (including categorical exclusions adopted to implement the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.)) to conduct a hazardous fuel reduction project on Federal land (including Federal land identified in <ref>section 6512(d) of this title</ref>) that is not conducted using the process authorized by <ref>section 6514 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Forest System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For projects and activities of the National Forest System other than authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects, nothing in this subchapter affects, or otherwise biases, the notice, comment, and appeal procedures for projects and activities of the National Forest System contained in part 215 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, or the consideration or disposition of any legal action brought with respect to the procedures.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6518.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated $660,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023 to carry out—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> activities authorized by this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other hazardous fuel reduction activities of the Secretary, including making grants to States, local governments, Indian tribes, and other eligible recipients for activities authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8402</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>BIOMASS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6531.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8403(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4841</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>WATERSHED FORESTRY ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6541.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6542.</num>
<heading> Water Source Protection Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> End water user</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “end water user” means a non-Federal entity, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a political subdivision of a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a utility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a municipal water system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an irrigation district;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a nonprofit organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest management activity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “forest management activity” means a project carried out by the Secretary on National Forest System land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “forest plan” means a land management plan prepared by the Forest Service for a unit of the National Forest System pursuant to <ref>section 1604 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal partner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “non-Federal partner” means an end water user with whom the Secretary has entered into a partnership agreement under subsection (c)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the Water Source Protection Program established under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water source management plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “water source management plan” means the water source management plan developed under subsection (d)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and maintain a program, to be known as the “Water Source Protection Program”, to carry out watershed protection and restoration projects on National Forest System land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water source investment partnerships</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may enter into water source investment partnership agreements with end water users to protect and restore the condition of National Forest watersheds that provide water to the end water users.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A partnership agreement described in paragraph (1) may take the form of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a memorandum of understanding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a cost-share or collection agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a long-term funding matching commitment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> another appropriate instrument, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water source management plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary, in cooperation with the non-Federal partners and applicable State, local, and Tribal governments, may develop a water source management plan that describes the proposed implementation of watershed protection and restoration projects under the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A water source management plan shall be conducted in a manner consistent with the forest plan applicable to the National Forest System land on which the watershed protection and restoration project is carried out.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental analysis</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may conduct a single environmental impact statement or similar analysis required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for each watershed protection and restoration project included in the water source management plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as part of the development of, or after the finalization of, the water source management plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest management activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To the extent that forest management activities are necessary to protect, maintain, or enhance water quality, and in accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary shall carry out forest management activities as part of watershed protection and restoration projects carried out on National Forest System land, with the primary purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protecting a municipal water supply system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> restoring forest health from insect infestations and disease; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any combination of the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall carry out forest management activities under paragraph (1) in accordance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the applicable water source management plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the applicable forest plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other applicable laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Endangered Species Act of 1973</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may use the Manual on Adaptive Management of the Department of the Interior, including any associated guidance, to comply with the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds and services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may accept and use funding, services, and other forms of investment and assistance from non-Federal partners to implement the water source management plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching funds required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall require the contribution of funds or in-kind support from non-Federal partners to be in an amount that is at least equal to the amount of Federal funds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may accept and use investments described in paragraph (1) directly or indirectly through the National Forest Foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water source protection fund</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may establish a Water Source Protection Fund to match funds or in-kind support contributed by non-Federal partners under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of appropriated funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may make multiyear commitments, if necessary, to implement 1 or more partnership agreements under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title III, § 303</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8404(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6543.</num>
<heading> Watershed Condition Framework</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”), may establish and maintain a Watershed Condition Framework for National Forest System land—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to evaluate and classify the condition of watersheds, taking into consideration—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> water quality and quantity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> aquatic habitat and biota;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> riparian and wetland vegetation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the presence of roads and trails;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> soil type and condition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> groundwater-dependent ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> relevant terrestrial indicators, such as fire regime, risk of catastrophic fire, forest and rangeland vegetation, invasive species, and insects and disease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> other significant factors, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to identify for protection and restoration up to 5 priority watersheds in each National Forest, and up to 2 priority watersheds in each national grassland, taking into consideration the impact of the condition of the watershed condition on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> wildfire behavior;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> flood risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fish and wildlife;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> drinking water supplies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> irrigation water supplies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> forest-dependent communities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> other significant impacts, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to develop a watershed protection and restoration action plan for each priority watershed that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> takes into account existing restoration activities being implemented in the watershed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the major stressors responsible for the impaired condition of the watershed;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a set of essential projects that, once completed, will address the identified stressors and improve watershed conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a proposed implementation schedule;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> potential partners and funding sources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a monitoring and evaluation program;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to prioritize protection and restoration activities for each watershed restoration action plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to implement each watershed protection and restoration action plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to monitor the effectiveness of protection and restoration actions and indicators of watershed health.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate with interested non-Federal landowners and State, Tribal, and local governments within the relevant watershed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide for an active and ongoing public engagement process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency designation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of subsection (a), the Secretary may identify a watershed as a priority for rehabilitation in the Watershed Condition Framework without using the process described in that subsection if a Forest Supervisor determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a wildfire has significantly diminished the condition of the watershed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the emergency stabilization activities of the Burned Area Emergency Response Team are insufficient to return the watershed to proper function.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title III, § 304</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8405(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>INSECT INFESTATIONS AND RELATED DISEASES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6551.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> high levels of tree mortality resulting from insect infestation (including the interaction between insects and diseases) may result in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> increased fire risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> loss of old trees and old growth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> loss of threatened and endangered species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> loss of species diversity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> degraded watershed conditions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> increased potential for damage from other agents of disturbance, including exotic, invasive species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> decreased timber values;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> forest-damaging insects destroy hundreds of thousands of acres of trees each year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the West, more than 21,000,000 acres are at high risk of forest-damaging insect infestation, and in the South, more than 57,000,000 acres are at risk across all land ownerships; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> severe drought conditions in many areas of the South and West will increase the risk of forest-damaging insect infestations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the hemlock woolly adelgid is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> destroying streamside forests throughout the mid-Atlantic and Appalachian regions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> threatening water quality and sensitive aquatic species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> posing a potential threat to valuable commercial timber land in northern New England;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the emerald ash borer is a nonnative, invasive pest that has quickly become a major threat to hardwood forests because an emerald ash borer infestation is almost always fatal to affected trees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the emerald ash borer pest threatens to destroy more than 692,000,000 ash trees in forests in Michigan and Ohio alone, and between 5 and 10 percent of urban street trees in the Upper Midwest;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> epidemic populations of Southern pine beetles are ravaging forests in Alabama, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, and Virginia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in 2001, Florida and Kentucky experienced 146 percent and 111 percent increases, respectively, in Southern pine beetle populations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> those epidemic outbreaks of Southern pine beetles have forced private landowners to harvest dead and dying trees, in rural areas and increasingly urbanized settings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> according to the Forest Service, recent outbreaks of the red oak borer in Arkansas and Missouri have been unprecedented, with more than 1,000,000 acres infested at population levels never seen before;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> much of the damage from the red oak borer has taken place in national forests, and the Federal response has been inadequate to protect forest ecosystems and other ecological and economic resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> previous silvicultural assessments, while useful and informative, have been limited in scale and scope of application; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there have not been sufficient resources available to adequately test a full array of individual and combined applied silvicultural assessments;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> only through the full funding, development, and assessment of potential applied silvicultural assessments over specific time frames across an array of environmental and climatic conditions can the most innovative and cost effective management applications be determined that will help reduce the susceptibility of forest ecosystems to attack by forest pests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> often, there are significant interactions between insects and diseases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> many diseases (such as white pine blister rust, beech bark disease, and many other diseases) can weaken trees and forest stands and predispose trees and forest stands to insect attack; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> certain diseases are spread using insects as vectors (including Dutch elm disease and pine pitch canker); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> funding and implementation of an initiative to combat forest pest infestations and associated diseases should not come at the expense of supporting other programs and initiatives of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to require the Secretary to develop an accelerated basic and applied assessment program to combat infestations by forest-damaging insects and associated diseases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to enlist the assistance of colleges and universities (including forestry schools, land grant colleges and universities, and 1890 Institutions), State agencies, and private landowners to carry out the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to carry out applied silvicultural assessments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1907</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6552.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applied silvicultural assessment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “applied silvicultural assessment” means any vegetative or other treatment carried out for information gathering and research purposes.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “applied silvicultural assessment” includes timber harvesting, thinning, prescribed burning, pruning, and any combination of those activities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1890 Institution</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “1890 Institution” means a college or university that is eligible to receive funds under the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref>7 U.S.C. 321</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “1890 Institution” includes Tuskegee University.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest-damaging insect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “forest-damaging insect” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Southern pine beetle;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a mountain pine beetle;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a spruce bark beetle;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a gypsy moth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a hemlock woolly adelgid;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an emerald ash borer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a red oak borer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a white oak borer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such other insects as may be identified by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Forest Service, with respect to National Forest System land; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, acting through appropriate offices of the United States Geological Survey, with respect to federally owned land administered by the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6553.</num>
<heading> Accelerated information gathering regarding forest-damaging insects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information gathering</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Forest Service and United States Geological Survey, as appropriate, shall establish an accelerated program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to plan, conduct, and promote comprehensive and systematic information gathering on forest-damaging insects and associated diseases, including an evaluation of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> infestation prevention and suppression methods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> effects of infestations and associated disease interactions on forest ecosystems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> restoration of forest ecosystem efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> utilization options regarding infested trees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> models to predict the occurrence, distribution, and impact of outbreaks of forest-damaging insects and associated diseases;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist land managers in the development of treatments and strategies to improve forest health and reduce the susceptibility of forest ecosystems to severe infestations of forest-damaging insects and associated diseases on Federal land and State and private land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to disseminate the results of the information gathering, treatments, and strategies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation and assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> establish and carry out the program in cooperation with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> scientists from colleges and universities (including forestry schools, land grant colleges and universities, and 1890 Institutions);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Federal, State, and local agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> private and industrial landowners; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designate such colleges and universities to assist in carrying out the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6554.</num>
<heading> Applied silvicultural assessments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For information gathering and research purposes, the Secretary may conduct applied silvicultural assessments on Federal land that the Secretary determines is at risk of infestation by, or is infested with, forest-damaging insects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of certain areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subsection (a) does not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any Federal land on which, by Act of Congress or Presidential proclamation, the removal of vegetation is restricted or prohibited;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a congressionally-designated wilderness study area; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an area in which activities under subsection (a) would be inconsistent with the applicable land and resource management plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain treatment prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in subsection (a) authorizes the application of insecticides in municipal watersheds or associated riparian areas.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peer review</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Before being carried out, each applied silvicultural assessment under this subchapter shall be peer reviewed by scientific experts selected by the Secretary, which shall include non-Federal experts.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing peer review processes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may use existing peer review processes to the extent the processes comply with subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice and comment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide notice of each applied silvicultural assessment proposed to be carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide an opportunity for public comment before carrying out an applied silviculture assessment under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Categorical exclusion</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Applied silvicultural assessment and research treatments carried out under this section on not more than 1,000 acres for an assessment or treatment may be categorically excluded from documentation in an environmental impact statement and environmental assessment under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Applied silvicultural assessments and research treatments categorically excluded under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not be carried out in an area that is adjacent to another area that is categorically excluded under paragraph (1) that is being treated with similar methods; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be subject to the extraordinary circumstances procedures established by the Secretary pursuant to section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum categorical exclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The total number of acres categorically excluded under paragraph (1) shall not exceed 250,000 acres.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No additional findings required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with paragraph (1), the Secretary shall not be required to make any findings as to whether an applied silvicultural assessment project, either individually or cumulatively, has a significant effect on the environment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1910</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6555.</num>
<heading> Relation to other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority provided to each Secretary under this subchapter is supplemental to, and not in lieu of, any authority provided to the Secretaries under any other law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1911</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6556.</num>
<heading> Termination of effectiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority provided by this subchapter terminates effective <date date="2023-10-01">October 1, 2023</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8406(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>HEALTHY FORESTS RESERVE PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6571.</num>
<heading> Establishment of healthy forests reserve program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish the healthy forests reserve program for the purpose of restoring and enhancing forest ecosystems—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to promote the recovery of threatened and endangered species;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to improve biodiversity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to conserve forest land that provides habitat for species described in <ref>section 6572(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to enhance carbon sequestration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall carry out the healthy forests reserve program in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8407(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6572.</num>
<heading> Eligibility and enrollment of lands in program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce, shall describe and define forest ecosystems that are eligible for enrollment in the healthy forests reserve program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for enrollment in the healthy forests reserve program, land shall be private forest land, or private land being restored to forest land, the enrollment of which will maintain, restore, enhance, or otherwise measurably—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increase the likelihood of recovery of a species that is listed as endangered or threatened under <ref>section 1533 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> improve the well-being of a species that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not listed as endangered or threatened under such section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a candidate for such listing, a State-listed species, or a special concern species; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is deemed a species of greatest conservation need by a State wildlife action plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In enrolling land that satisfies the criteria under subsection (b), the Secretary of Agriculture shall give additional consideration to land the enrollment of which will—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve biological diversity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conserve forest land that provides habitat for species described in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increase carbon sequestration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enrollment by willing owners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall enroll land in the healthy forests reserve program only with the consent of the owner of the land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methods of enrollment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Land may be enrolled in the healthy forests reserve program in accordance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a 10-year cost-share agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a 30-year easement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a permanent easement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in a State that imposes a maximum duration for easements, an easement for the maximum duration allowed under State law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage owned by Indian tribes</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of acreage owned by Indian tribes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “acreage owned by Indian tribes” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> land that is held in trust by the United States for Indian tribes or individual Indians;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> land, the title to which is held by Indian tribes or individual Indians subject to Federal restrictions against alienation or encumbrance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> land that is subject to rights of use, occupancy, and benefit of certain Indian tribes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> land that is held in fee title by an Indian tribe; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> land that is owned by a native corporation formed under <ref>section 5124 of title 25</ref> or <ref>section 1607 of title 43</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a combination of 1 or more types of land described in clauses (i) through (v).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enrollment of acreage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of acreage owned by an Indian tribe, the Secretary may enroll acreage into the healthy forests reserve program through the use of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a 30-year contract (the value of which shall be equivalent to the value of a 30-year easement);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a 10-year cost-share agreement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a permanent easement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any combination of the options described in clauses (i) through (iii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enrollment priority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Species</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall give priority to the enrollment of land that provides the greatest conservation benefit to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> primarily, species listed as endangered or threatened under <ref>section 1533 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> secondarily, species that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are not listed as endangered or threatened under <ref>section 1533 of this title</ref>; but</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> are candidates for such listing, State-listed species, or special concern species; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> are deemed a species of greatest conservation need under a State wildlife action plan.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-effectiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Agriculture shall also consider the cost-effectiveness of each agreement or easement, and associated restoration plans, so as to maximize the environmental benefits per dollar expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Easement modification or termination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may modify or terminate an easement or other interest in land administered by the Secretary under this title if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the owner of the land agrees to the modification or termination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary determines that the modification or termination—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> will address a compelling public need for which there is no practicable alternative; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is in the public interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration; conditions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As consideration for termination of an easement or other interest in land under this subsection, the Secretary shall enter into a compensatory arrangement, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of a modification of an easement or other interest in land under this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as a condition of the modification, the owner of the land shall enter into a compensatory arrangement, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, to incur the costs of modification; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the modification will not adversely affect the forest ecosystem functions and values for which the easement or other interest in land was acquired;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any adverse impacts will be mitigated by enrollment and restoration of other land that provides greater forest ecosystem functions and values at no additional cost to the Federal Government; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the modification will result in equal or greater environmental and economic values to the United States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8205(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8205(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2056; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8203(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8407(a)(2)</ref>–(6), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4845</ref>, 4846; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. HH, title III, § 401</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6573.</num>
<heading> Restoration plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Land enrolled in the healthy forests reserve program shall be subject to a restoration plan, to be developed jointly by the landowner and the Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Practices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The restoration plan shall require such restoration practices and measures as are necessary to restore and enhance habitat for species described in <ref>section 6572(b) of this title</ref>, including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Land management practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Vegetative treatments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Structural practices and measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Practices to increase carbon sequestration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Practices to improve biological diversity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Other practices and measures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8407(a)(7)</ref>, (9), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6574.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permanent easements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of land enrolled in the healthy forests reserve program using a permanent easement (or an easement described in section 6572(f)(1)(C)(ii) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002829">1</ref> of this title), the Secretary of Agriculture shall pay the owner of the land an amount equal to not less than 75 percent, nor more than 100 percent, of (as determined by the Secretary)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the fair market value of the enrolled land during the period the land is subject to the easement, less the fair market value of the land encumbered by the easement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the actual costs of the approved conservation practices or the average cost of approved practices carried out on the land during the period in which the land is subject to the easement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Thirty-year easement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of land enrolled in the healthy forests reserve program using a 30-year easement, the Secretary of Agriculture shall pay the owner of the land an amount equal to not more than (as determined by the Secretary)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 75 percent of the fair market value of the land, less the fair market value of the land encumbered by the easement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 75 percent of the actual costs of the approved conservation practices or 75 percent of the average cost of approved practices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ten-year agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of land enrolled in the healthy forests reserve program using a 10-year cost-share agreement, the Secretary of Agriculture shall pay the owner of the land an amount equal to not more than (as determined by the Secretary)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fifty percent of the actual costs of the approved conservation practices; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fifty percent of the average cost of approved practices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance of contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may accept and use contributions of non-Federal funds to make payments under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1913</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8205(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8205(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2057.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6575.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall provide landowners with technical assistance to assist the owners in complying with the terms of plans (as included in agreements or easements) under the healthy forests reserve program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical service providers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may request the services of, and enter into cooperative agreements with, individuals or entities certified as technical service providers under <ref>section 3842 of this title</ref>, to assist the Secretary in providing technical assistance necessary to develop and implement the healthy forests reserve program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1913</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6576.</num>
<heading> Protections and measures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protections</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of a landowner that enrolls land in the program and whose conservation activities result in a net conservation benefit for listed, candidate, or other species, the Secretary of Agriculture shall make available to the landowner safe harbor or similar assurances and protection under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 1536(b)(4) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 1539(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Measures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If protection under subsection (a) requires the taking of measures that are in addition to the measures covered by the applicable restoration plan agreed to under <ref>section 6573 of this title</ref>, the cost of the additional measures, as well as the cost of any permit, shall be considered part of the restoration plan for purposes of financial assistance under <ref>section 6574 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6577.</num>
<heading> Involvement by other agencies and organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary of Agriculture may consult with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> nonindustrial private forest landowners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> State fish and wildlife agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> State forestry agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> State environmental quality agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other State conservation agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> nonprofit conservation organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6578.</num>
<heading> Funding</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal years 2009 through 2013 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002830">1</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary of Agriculture shall make available $9,750,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2012 <sup>1</sup> to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out this section $12,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional source of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to funds appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in subsection (b) for a fiscal year, the Secretary may use such amount of the funds appropriated for that fiscal year to carry out the Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 590a</ref> et seq.) as the Secretary determines necessary to cover the cost of technical assistance, management, and enforcement responsibilities for land enrolled in the healthy forests reserve program pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 6574 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The funds made available under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title V, § 508</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8205(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8205(c), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2057; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8203(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8407(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6591.</num>
<heading> Forest stands inventory and monitoring program to improve detection of and response to environmental threats</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall carry out a comprehensive program to inventory, monitor, characterize, assess, and identify forest stands (with emphasis on hardwood forest stands) and potential forest stands—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in units of the National Forest System (other than those units created from the public domain); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on private forest land, with the consent of the owner of the land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issues to be addressed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall address issues including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> early detection, identification, and assessment of environmental threats (including insect, disease, invasive species, fire, and weather-related risks and other episodic events);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> loss or degradation of forests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> degradation of the quality forest stands caused by inadequate forest regeneration practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> quantification of carbon uptake rates; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> management practices that focus on preventing further forest degradation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Early warning system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive early warning system for potential catastrophic environmental threats to forests to increase the likelihood that forest managers will be able to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> isolate and treat a threat before the threat gets out of control; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prevent epidemics, such as the American chestnut blight in the first half of the twentieth century, that could be environmentally and economically devastating to forests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2008.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6591a.</num>
<heading> Designation of treatment areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of declining forest health</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “declining forest health” means a forest that is experiencing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> substantially increased tree mortality due to insect or disease infestation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> dieback due to infestation or defoliation by insects or disease.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of treatment areas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, the Secretary shall, if requested by the Governor of the State, designate as part of an insect and disease treatment program 1 or more landscape-scale areas, such as subwatersheds (sixth-level hydrologic units, according to the System of Hydrologic Unit Codes of the United States Geological Survey), in at least 1 national forest in each State that is experiencing an insect or disease epidemic.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After the end of the 60-day period described in paragraph (1), the Secretary may designate additional landscape-scale areas under this section as needed to address insect or disease threats.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be designated a landscape-scale area under subsection (b), the area shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> experiencing declining forest health, based on annual forest health surveys conducted by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at risk of experiencing substantially increased tree mortality over the next 15 years due to insect or disease infestation, based on the most recent National Insect and Disease Risk Map published by the Forest Service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in an area in which the risk of hazard trees poses an imminent risk to public infrastructure, health, or safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of areas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may carry out priority projects on Federal land in the areas designated under subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to reduce the risk or extent of, or increase the resilience to, insect or disease infestation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to reduce hazardous fuels.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any project under paragraph (1) for which a public notice to initiate scoping is issued on or before <date date="2023-09-30">September 30, 2023</date>, may be carried out in accordance with subsections (b), (c), and (d) of <ref>section 6512 of this title</ref>, and sections 6514, 6515, and 6516 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Projects carried out under this subsection shall be considered authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects for purposes of the authorities described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In accordance with the schedule described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall issue 2 reports on actions taken to carry out this subsection, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the progress towards project goals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recommendations for modifications to the projects and management treatments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not earlier than <date date="2018-09-30">September 30, 2018</date>, issue the initial report under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not earlier than <date date="2024-09-30">September 30, 2024</date>, issue the second report under that subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tree retention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out projects under subsection (d) in a manner that maximizes the retention of old-growth and large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote stands that are resilient to insects and disease.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title VI, § 602</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8204</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 915</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII</ref>, §§ 8407(b), 8408, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4846</ref>, 4847.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6591b.</num>
<heading> Administrative review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), a project described in subsection (b) that is conducted in accordance with <ref>section 6591a(d) of this title</ref> may be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> considered an action categorically excluded from the requirements of <ref>Public Law 91–190</ref> (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> exempt from the special administrative review process under <ref>section 6515 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaborative restoration project</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A project referred to in subsection (a) is a project to carry out forest restoration treatments that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maximizes the retention of old-growth and large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote stands that are resilient to insects and disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> considers the best available scientific information to maintain or restore the ecological integrity, including maintaining or restoring structure, function, composition, and connectivity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> is developed and implemented through a collaborative process that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> includes multiple interested persons representing diverse interests; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is transparent and nonexclusive; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under subsections (c) through (f) of <ref>section 7125 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A project under this subsection may carry out part of a proposal that complies with the eligibility requirements of the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program under <ref>section 7303(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project size</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A project under this section may not exceed 3000 acres.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A project under this section shall be limited to areas—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the wildland-urban interface; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Condition Classes 2 or 3 in Fire Regime Groups I, II, or III, outside the wildland-urban interface.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Roads</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permanent roads</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A project under this section shall not include the establishment of permanent roads.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary may carry out necessary maintenance and repairs on existing permanent roads for the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall decommission any temporary road constructed under a project under this section not later than 3 years after the date on which the project is completed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any Federal land on which, by Act of Congress or Presidential proclamation, the removal of vegetation is restricted or prohibited;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a congressionally designated wilderness study area; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an area in which activities under subsection (a) would be inconsistent with the applicable land and resource management plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest management plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All projects and activities carried out under this section shall be consistent with the land and resource management plan established under <ref>section 1604 of this title</ref> for the unit of the National Forest System containing the projects and activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice and scoping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct public notice and scoping for any project or action proposed in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accountability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall prepare an annual report on the use of categorical exclusions under this section that includes a description of all acres (or other appropriate unit) treated through projects carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit the reports required under paragraph (1) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title VI, § 603</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8204</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 916</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6591c.</num>
<heading> Stewardship end result contracting projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Chief” means the Chief of the Forest Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief and the Director, via agreement or contract as appropriate, may enter into stewardship contracting projects with private persons or other public or private entities to perform services to achieve land management goals for the national forests and the public lands that meet local and rural community needs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Land management goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The land management goals of a project under subsection (b) may include any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Road and trail maintenance or obliteration to restore or maintain water quality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Soil productivity, habitat for wildlife and fisheries, or other resource values.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Setting of prescribed fires to improve the composition, structure, condition, and health of stands or to improve wildlife habitat.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Removing vegetation or other activities to promote healthy forest stands, reduce fire hazards, or achieve other land management objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Watershed restoration and maintenance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Restoration and maintenance of wildlife and fish.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Control of noxious and exotic weeds and reestablishing native plant species.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements or contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A source for performance of an agreement or contract under subsection (b) shall be selected on a best-value basis, including consideration of source under other public and private agreements or contracts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract for sale of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A contract entered into under this section may, at the discretion of the Secretary of Agriculture, be considered a contract for the sale of property under such terms as the Secretary may prescribe without regard to any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Chief and the Director may enter into a contract under subsection (b) in accordance with <ref>section 3903 of title 41</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The period of the contract under subsection (b) may exceed 5 years but may not exceed 10 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offsets</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chief and the Director may apply the value of timber or other forest products removed as an offset against the cost of services received under the agreement or contract described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methods of appraisal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The value of timber or other forest products used as an offset under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be determined using appropriate methods of appraisal commensurate with the quantity of products to be removed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> may—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> be determined using a unit of measure appropriate to the contracts; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> may include valuing products on a per-acre basis.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsections (d) and (g) of <ref>section 472a of this title</ref>, the Chief may enter into an agreement or contract under subsection (b). Notwithstanding the Materials Act of 1947 (<ref>30 U.S.C. 602(a)</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002831">1</ref> the Director may enter into an agreement or contract under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracting officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior may determine the appropriate contracting officer to enter into and administer an agreement or contract under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fire liability provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, the Chief shall issue for use in all contracts and agreements under this section fire liability provisions that are in substantially the same form as the fire liability provisions contained in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> integrated resource timber contracts, as described in the Forest Service contract numbered 2400–13, part H, section H.4; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> timber sale contracts conducted pursuant to <ref>section 472a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Receipts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief and the Director may collect monies from an agreement or contract under subsection (b) if the collection is a secondary objective of negotiating the contract that will best achieve the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Monies from an agreement or contract under subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be retained by the Chief and the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be available for expenditure without further appropriation at the project site from which the monies are collected or at another project site.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to other laws</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the value of services received by the Chief or the Director under a stewardship contract project conducted under this section, and any payments made or resources provided by the contractor, Chief, or Director shall not be considered monies received from the National Forest System or the public lands.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knutson-Vanderberg <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002832">2</ref> Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Act of <date date="1930-06-09">June 9, 1930</date> (commonly known as the “Knutson-Vanderberg <sup>2</sup> Act”) (<ref>16 U.S.C. 576</ref> et seq.) shall not apply to any agreement or contract under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs of removal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding the fact that a contractor did not harvest the timber, the Chief may collect deposits from a contractor covering the costs of removal of timber or other forest products under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 490 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 498 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance and payment guarantees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief and the Director may require performance and payment bonds under sections 28.103–2 and 28.103–3 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation, in an amount that the contracting officer considers sufficient to protect the investment in receipts by the Federal Government generated by the contractor from the estimated value of the forest products to be removed under a contract under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess offset value</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the offset value of the forest products exceeds the value of the resource improvement treatments, the Chief and the Director may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use the excess to satisfy any outstanding liabilities for cancelled agreements or contracts; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if there are no outstanding liabilities described in subparagraph (A), apply the excess to other authorized stewardship projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cancellation ceilings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3903(b)(1) of title 41</ref>, the Chief and the Director may obligate funds in stages that are economically or programmatically viable to cover any potential cancellation or termination costs for an agreement or contract under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advance notice to Congress of cancellation ceiling in excess of $25,000,000</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 30 days before entering into a multiyear agreement or contract under subsection (b) that includes a cancellation ceiling in excess of $25,000,000, but does not include proposed funding for the costs of cancelling the agreement or contract up to that cancellation ceiling, the Chief or the Director, as applicable, shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a written notice that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the cancellation ceiling amounts proposed for each program year in the agreement or contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reasons why the cancellation ceiling amounts described under subparagraph (A) were selected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the extent to which the costs of contract cancellation are not included in the budget for the agreement or contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an assessment of the financial risk of not including budgeting for the costs of agreement or contract cancellation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal of notice to OMB</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 14 days after the date on which written notice is provided under paragraph (2), the Chief or the Director, as appropriate, shall transmit a copy of the notice to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and evaluation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief and the Director shall establish a multiparty monitoring and evaluation process that accesses the stewardship contracting projects conducted under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Other than the Chief and Director, participants in the process described in paragraph (1) may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any cooperating governmental agencies, including tribal governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other interested groups or individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, and annually thereafter, the Chief and the Director shall submit to the congressional committees described in subsection (h)(2) a report on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the status of development, execution, and administration of agreements or contracts under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the specific accomplishments that have resulted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the role of local communities in the development of agreements or contract plans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title VI, § 604</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title VIII, § 8205(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 918</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. G, title IV, § 422</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II</ref>, §§ 204–206, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1064</ref>, 1065.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6591d.</num>
<heading> Wildfire resilience projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Hazardous fuels reduction projects, as defined in <ref>section 6511(2) of this title</ref> may be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carried out in accordance with subsections (b), (c), and (d) of <ref>section 6512 of this title</ref> and sections 6514 and 6515 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> considered an action categorically excluded from the requirements of <ref>Public Law 91–190</ref> (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> exempt from the special administrative review process under <ref>section 6515 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaborative restoration project</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A project referred to in subsection (a) is a project to carry out forest restoration treatments that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maximizes the retention of old-growth and large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote stands that are resilient to insects and disease, and reduce the risk or extent of, or increase the resilience to, wildfires;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> considers the best available scientific information to maintain or restore the ecological integrity, including maintaining or restoring structure, function, composition, and connectivity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> is developed and implemented through a collaborative process that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> includes multiple interested persons representing diverse interests; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is transparent and nonexclusive; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under subsections (c) through (f) of <ref>section 7125 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A project under this subsection may carry out part of a proposal that complies with the eligibility requirements of the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program under <ref>section 7303(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project size</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A project under this section may not exceed 3000 acres.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A project under this section shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Prioritized within the wildland-urban interface;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If located outside the wildland-urban interface, limited to areas within Condition Classes 2 or 3 in Fire Regime Groups I, II, or III that contain very high wildfire hazard potential; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Limited to areas designated under <ref>section 6591a(b) of this title</ref> as of <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Roads</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permanent roads</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A project under this section shall not include the establishment of permanent roads.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary may carry out necessary maintenance and repairs on existing permanent roads for the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall decommission any temporary road constructed under a project under this section not later than 3 years after the date on which the project is completed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extraordinary circumstances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall apply the extraordinary circumstances procedures under section 220.6 of title 36, code of Federal regulations <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002833">1</ref> (or successor regulations), when using the categorical exclusion under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any Federal land on which, by Act of Congress or Presidential proclamation, the removal of vegetation is restricted or prohibited;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a congressionally designated wilderness study area; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an area in which activities under subsection (a) would be inconsistent with the applicable land and resource management plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest management plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All projects and activities carried out under this section shall be consistent with the land and resource management plan established under <ref>section 1604 of this title</ref> for the unit of the National Forest System containing the projects and activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice and scoping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct public notice and scoping for any project or action proposed in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accountability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall prepare an annual report on the use of categorical exclusions under this section that includes a description of all acres (or other appropriate unit) treated through projects carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit the reports required under paragraph (1) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title VI, § 605</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1062</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6591e.</num>
<heading> Categorical exclusion for greater sage-grouse and mule deer habitat</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered vegetation management activity</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “covered vegetation management activity” means any activity described in subparagraph (B) that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is carried out on National Forest System land administered by the Forest Service; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is carried out on public land administered by the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with respect to public land, meets the objectives of the order of the Secretary of the Interior numbered 3336 and dated <date date="2015-01-05">January 5, 2015</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> conforms to an applicable forest plan or land use plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> protects, restores, or improves greater sage-grouse or mule deer habitat in a sagebrush steppe ecosystem as described in—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Circular 1416 of the United States Geological Survey entitled “Restoration Handbook for Sagebrush Steppe Ecosystems with Emphasis on Greater Sage-Grouse Habitat—Part 1. Concepts for Understanding and Applying Restoration” (2015); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the habitat guidelines for mule deer published by the Mule Deer Working Group of the Western Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> will not permanently impair—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the natural state of the treated area;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> outstanding opportunities for solitude;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> outstanding opportunities for primitive, unconfined recreation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> economic opportunities consistent with multiple-use management; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> the identified values of a unit of the National Landscape Conservation System;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> restores native vegetation following a natural disturbance;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> prevents the expansion into greater sage-grouse or mule deer habitat of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> juniper, pinyon pine, or other associated conifers; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> nonnative or invasive vegetation;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> reduces the risk of loss of greater sage-grouse or mule deer habitat from wildfire or any other natural disturbance; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> provides emergency stabilization of soil resources after a natural disturbance; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<chapeau> provides for the conduct of restoration treatments that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> maximize the retention of old-growth and large trees, as appropriate for the forest type;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> consider the best available scientific information to maintain or restore the ecological integrity, including maintaining or restoring structure, function, composition, and connectivity;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> are developed and implemented through a collaborative process that—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> includes multiple interested persons representing diverse interests; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<subitem class="indent5">
<num>(AA)</num>
<content> is transparent and nonexclusive; or</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent5">
<num>(BB)</num>
<content> meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under subsections (c) through (f) of <ref>section 7125 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> may include the implementation of a proposal that complies with the eligibility requirements of the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program under <ref>section 7303(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An activity referred to in subparagraph (A) is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> manual cutting and removal of juniper trees, pinyon pine trees, other associated conifers, or other nonnative or invasive vegetation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> mechanical mastication, cutting, or mowing, mechanical piling and burning, chaining, broadcast burning, or yarding;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> removal of cheat grass, medusa head rye, or other nonnative, invasive vegetation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> collection and seeding or planting of native vegetation using a manual, mechanical, or aerial method;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> seeding of nonnative, noninvasive, ruderal vegetation only for the purpose of emergency stabilization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> targeted use of an herbicide, subject to the condition that the use shall be in accordance with applicable legal requirements, Federal agency procedures, and land use plans;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> targeted livestock grazing to mitigate hazardous fuels and control noxious and invasive weeds;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> temporary removal of wild horses or burros in the area in which the activity is being carried out to ensure treatment objectives are met;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> in coordination with the affected permit holder, modification or adjustment of permissible usage under an annual plan of use of a grazing permit issued by the Secretary concerned to achieve restoration treatment objectives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> installation of new, or modification of existing, fencing or water sources intended to control use or improve wildlife habitat; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> necessary maintenance of, repairs to, rehabilitation of, or reconstruction of an existing permanent road or construction of temporary roads to accomplish the activities described in this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “covered vegetation management activity” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any activity conducted in a wilderness area or wilderness study area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any activity for the construction of a permanent road or permanent trail;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any activity conducted on Federal land on which, by Act of Congress or Presidential proclamation, the removal of vegetation is restricted or prohibited;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any activity conducted in an area in which activities under subparagraph (B) would be inconsistent with the applicable land and resource management plan; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any activity conducted in an inventoried roadless area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary concerned</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary road</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “temporary road” means a road that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> authorized—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by a contract, permit, lease, other written authorization; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> pursuant to an emergency operation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not intended to be part of the permanent transportation system of a Federal department or agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not necessary for long-term resource management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> designed in accordance with standards appropriate for the intended use of the road, taking into consideration—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> safety;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the cost of transportation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> impacts to land and resources; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> managed to minimize—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> erosion; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the introduction or spread of invasive species.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Categorical exclusion</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary concerned shall develop a categorical exclusion (as defined in section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) for covered vegetation management activities carried out to protect, restore, or improve habitat for greater sage-grouse or mule deer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing and administering the categorical exclusion under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to National Forest System land, apply the extraordinary circumstances procedures under section 220.6 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), in determining whether to use the categorical exclusion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> with respect to public land, apply the extraordinary circumstances procedures under section 46.215 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), in determining whether to use the categorical exclusion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the relative efficacy of landscape-scale habitat projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the likelihood of continued declines in the populations of greater sage-grouse and mule deer in the absence of landscape-scale vegetation management; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the need for habitat restoration activities after wildfire or other natural disturbances.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of covered vegetative management activities within the range of greater sage-grouse and mule deer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the categorical exclusion developed under subsection (b) is used to implement a covered vegetative management activity in an area within the range of both greater sage-grouse and mule deer, the covered vegetative management activity shall protect, restore, or improve habitat concurrently for both greater sage-grouse and mule deer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Long-term monitoring and maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before commencing any covered vegetation management activity that is covered by the categorical exclusion under subsection (b), the Secretary concerned shall develop a long-term monitoring and maintenance plan, covering at least the 20-year period beginning on the date of commencement, to ensure that management of the treated area does not degrade the habitat gains secured by the covered vegetation management activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposal of vegetative material</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to applicable local restrictions, any vegetative material resulting from a covered vegetation management activity that is covered by the categorical exclusion under subsection (b) may be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> used for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fuel wood; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other products; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> piled or burned, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment for temporary roads</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1)(B)(xi), any temporary road constructed in carrying out a covered vegetation management activity that is covered by the categorical exclusion under subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be used by the Secretary concerned for the covered vegetation management activity for not more than 2 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> shall be decommissioned by the Secretary concerned not later than 3 years after the earlier of the date on which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the temporary road is no longer needed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the project is completed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A treatment under paragraph (1) shall include reestablishing native vegetative cover—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as soon as practicable; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 10 years after the date of completion of the applicable covered vegetation management activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project size</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A covered vegetation management activity that is covered by the categorical exclusion under subsection (b) may not exceed 4,500 acres.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A covered vegetation management activity carried out on National Forest System land that is covered by the categorical exclusion under subsection (b) shall be limited to areas designated under <ref>section 6591a(b) of this title</ref>, as of <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–148, title VI, § 606</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8611</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6592.</num>
<heading> Wildfire risk reduction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, for the activities described in subsection (c), $3,369,200,000 for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the Federal land or Indian forest land or rangeland that has been identified as having a very high wildfire hazard potential, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall, by not later than <date date="2027-09-30">September 30, 2027</date>, conduct restoration treatments and improve the Fire Regime Condition Class of 10,000,000 acres that are located in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the wildland-urban interface; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a public drinking water source area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amounts made available under subsection (a) for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> $20,000,000 shall be made available for entering into an agreement with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to establish and operate a program that makes use of the Geostationary Operational Environmental Satellite Program to rapidly detect and report wildfire starts in all areas in which the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture has financial responsibility for wildland fire protection and prevention, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> $600,000,000 shall be made available for the salaries and expenses of Federal wildland firefighters in accordance with subsection (d), of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $120,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $480,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior to acquire technology and infrastructure for each Type I and Type II incident management team to maintain interoperability with respect to the radio frequencies used by any responding agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $30,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture to provide financial assistance to States, Indian Tribes, and units of local government to establish and operate Reverse-911 telecommunication systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $50,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a pilot program to provide to local governments financial assistance for the acquisition of slip-on tanker units to establish fleets of vehicles that can be quickly converted to be operated as fire engines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> $1,200,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior, to develop and publish, not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, and every 5 years thereafter, a map depicting at-risk communities (as defined in <ref>section 6511 of this title</ref>), including Tribal at-risk communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> preplanning fire response workshops that develop—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> potential operational delineations; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> select potential control locations; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> workforce training for staff, non-Federal firefighters, and Native village fire crews for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> wildland firefighting; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> increasing the pace and scale of vegetation treatments, including training on how to prepare and implement large landscape treatments; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> of which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $50,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $50,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> $20,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into an agreement with a Southwest Ecological Restoration Institute established under the Southwest Forest Health and Wildfire Prevention Act of 2004 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 6701</ref> et seq.)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to compile and display existing data, including geographic data, for hazardous fuel reduction or wildfire prevention treatments undertaken by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, including treatments undertaken with funding provided under this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to compile and display existing data, including geographic data, for large wildfires, as defined by the National Wildfire Coordinating Group, that occur in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> to facilitate coordination and use of existing and future interagency fuel treatment data, including geographic data, for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assessing and planning cross-boundary fuel treatments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> monitoring the effects of treatments on wildfire outcomes and ecosystem restoration services, using the data compiled under subparagraphs (A) and (B);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> to publish a report every 5 years showing the extent to which treatments described in subparagraph (A) and previous wildfires affect the boundaries of wildfires, categorized by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Federal land management agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> region of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> treatment type; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to carry out other related activities of a Southwest Ecological Restoration Institute, as authorized by the Southwest Forest Health and Wildfire Prevention Act of 2004 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 6701</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> $20,000,000 shall be available for activities conducted under the Joint Fire Science Program, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture for collaboration and collaboration-based activities, including facilitation, certification of collaboratives, and planning and implementing projects under the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program established under <ref>section 7303 of this title</ref> in accordance with subsection (e);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> $500,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conducting mechanical thinning and timber harvesting in an ecologically appropriate manner that maximizes the retention of large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote fire-resilient stands; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> precommercial thinning in young growth stands for wildlife habitat benefits to provide subsistence resources; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> of which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $400,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> $500,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture, in cooperation with States, to award community wildfire defense grants to at-risk communities in accordance with subsection (f);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> $500,000,000 shall be made available for planning and conducting prescribed fires and related activities, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $250,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $250,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<chapeau> $500,000,000 shall be made available for developing or improving potential control locations, in accordance with paragraph (7)(A)(i)(II), including installing fuelbreaks (including fuelbreaks studied under subsection (i)), with a focus on shaded fuelbreaks when ecologically appropriate, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $250,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $250,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> $200,000,000 shall be made available for contracting or employing crews of laborers to modify and remove flammable vegetation on Federal land and for using materials from treatments, to the extent practicable, to produce biochar and other innovative wood products, including through the use of existing locally based organizations that engage young adults, Native youth, and veterans in service projects, such as youth and conservation corps, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<chapeau> $200,000,000 shall be made available for post-fire restoration activities that are implemented not later than 3 years after the date that a wildland fire is contained, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<chapeau> $8,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide feedstock to firewood banks; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide financial assistance for the operation of firewood banks; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture for the procurement and placement of wildfire detection and real-time monitoring equipment, such as sensors, cameras, and other relevant equipment, in areas at risk of wildfire or post-burned areas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wildland firefighters</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall, using the amounts made available under subsection (c)(2), coordinate with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to develop a distinct “wildland firefighter” occupational series.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any individual employed as a wildland firefighter on the date on which the occupational series established under paragraph (1) takes effect may elect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to remain in the occupational series in which the individual is employed; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to be included in the “wildland firefighter” occupational series established under that paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permanent employees; increase in salary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Using the amounts made available under subsection (c)(2), beginning <date date="2021-10-01">October 1, 2021</date>, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> seek to convert not fewer than 1,000 seasonal wildland firefighters to wildland firefighters that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are full-time, permanent, year-round Federal employees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reduce hazardous fuels on Federal land not fewer than 800 hours per year; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase the base salary of a Federal wildland firefighter by the lesser of an amount that is commensurate with an increase of $20,000 per year or an amount equal to 50 percent of the base salary, if the Secretary concerned, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, makes a written determination that the position of the Federal wildland firefighter is located within a specified geographic area in which it is difficult to recruit or retain a Federal wildland firefighter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National wildfire coordinating group</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Using the amounts made available under subsection (c)(2), not later than <date date="2022-10-01">October 1, 2022</date>, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop and adhere to recommendations for mitigation strategies for wildland firefighters to minimize exposure due to line-of-duty environmental hazards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish programs for permanent, temporary, seasonal, and year-round wildland firefighters to recognize and address mental health needs, including post-traumatic stress disorder care.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaborative forest landscape restoration program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, using the amounts made available under subsection (c)(10)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> solicit new project proposals under the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program established under <ref>section 7303 of this title</ref> (referred to in this subsection as the “Program”);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide up to 5 years of additional funding of any proposal originally selected for funding under the Program prior to <date date="2018-09-30">September 30, 2018</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that has been approved for an extension of funding by the Secretary of Agriculture prior to <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that has been recommended for an extension of funding by the advisory panel established under <ref>section 7303(e) of this title</ref> prior to <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, that the Secretary of Agriculture subsequently approves; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> select project proposals for funding under the Program in a manner that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> gives priority to a project proposal that will treat acres that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have been identified as having very high wildfire hazard potential; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> are located in—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the wildland-urban interface; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a public drinking water source area;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> takes into consideration—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the cost per acre of Federal land or Indian forest land or rangeland acres described in subparagraph (A) to be treated; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of acres described in subparagraph (A) to be treated;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> gives priority to a project proposal that is proposed by a collaborative that has successfully accomplished treatments consistent with a written plan that included a proposed schedule of completing those treatments, which is not limited to an earlier proposal funded under the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> discontinues funding for a project that fails to achieve the results included in a project proposal submitted under paragraph (1) for more than 2 consecutive years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community wildfire defense grant program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, using amounts made available under subsection (c)(12), establish a program, which shall be separate from the program established under <ref>section 5133 of title 42</ref>, under which the Secretary of Agriculture, in cooperation with the States, shall award grants to at-risk communities, including Indian Tribes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to develop or revise a community wildfire protection plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out projects described in a community wildfire protection plan that is not more than 10 years old.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In awarding grants under the program described in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Agriculture shall give priority to an at-risk community that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in an area identified by the Secretary of Agriculture as having high or very high wildfire hazard potential;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a low-income community; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a community impacted by a severe disaster.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community wildfire defense grants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A grant—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> awarded under paragraph (1)(A) shall be for not more than $250,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> awarded under paragraph (1)(B) shall be for not more than $10,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing requirement</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), the non-Federal cost (including the administrative cost) of carrying out a project using funds from a grant awarded under the program described in paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> not less than 10 percent for a grant awarded under paragraph (1)(A); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> not less than 25 percent for a grant awarded under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of Agriculture may waive the cost-sharing requirement under clause (i) for a project that serves an underserved community.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary of Agriculture shall not award a grant under paragraph (1) to an at-risk community that is located in a county or community that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is located in the continental United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> has not adopted an ordinance or regulation that requires the construction of new roofs on buildings to adhere to standards that are similar to, or more stringent than—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the roof construction standards established by the National Fire Protection Association; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an applicable model building code established by the International Code Council.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out projects using amounts made available under this section, the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, as applicable, shall prioritize funding for projects—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for which any applicable processes under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) have been completed on <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that reduce the likelihood of experiencing uncharacteristically severe effects from a potential wildfire by focusing on areas strategically important for reducing the risks associated with wildfires;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that maximize the retention of large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote fire-resilient stands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that do not include the establishment of permanent roads;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> for which funding would be committed to decommission all temporary roads constructed to carry out the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> that fully maintain or contribute toward the restoration of the structure and composition of old growth stands consistent with the characteristics of that forest type, taking into account the contribution of the old growth stand to landscape fire adaption and watershed health, unless the old growth stand is part of a science-based ecological restoration project authorized by the Secretary concerned that meets applicable protection and old growth enhancement objectives, as determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"> The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall complete and submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives an annual report describing the number of acres of land on which projects carried out using funds made available under this section improved the Fire Regime Condition Class of the land described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wildfire prevention study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall initiate a study of the construction and maintenance of a system of strategically placed fuelbreaks to control wildfires in western States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The study under paragraph (1) shall review—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a full suite of manual, chemical, and mechanical treatments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of the system described in that paragraph in reducing wildfire risk and protecting communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the date of completion of the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Agriculture shall determine whether to initiate the preparation of a programmatic environmental impact statement implementing the system described in that paragraph in appropriate locations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring, maintenance, and treatment plan and strategy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall establish a 5-year monitoring, maintenance, and treatment plan that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describes activities under subsection (c) that the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior will take to reduce the risk of wildfire by conducting restoration treatments and improving the Fire Regime Condition Class of 10,000,000 acres of Federal land or Tribal Forest land or rangeland that is identified as having very high wildfire hazard potential, not including annual treatments otherwise scheduled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establishes a process for prioritizing treatments in areas and communities at the highest risk of catastrophic wildfires;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> includes an innovative plan and process—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to leverage public-private partnerships and resources, shared stewardship agreements, good neighbor agreements, and similar contracting authorities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to prioritize projects for which any applicable processes under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) have been completed as of <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to streamline subsequent projects based on existing statutory or regulatory authorities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to develop interagency teams to increase coordination and efficiency under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref>) [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> establishes a process for coordinating prioritization and treatment with State and local entities and affected stakeholders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 5 years after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, in coordination with State and local governments, shall publish a long-term, outcome-based monitoring, maintenance, and treatment strategy—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to maintain forest health improvements and wildfire risk reduction accomplished under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to continue treatment at levels necessary to address the 20,000,000 acres needing priority treatment over the 10-year period beginning on the date of publication of the strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to proactively conduct treatment at a level necessary to minimize the risk of wildfire to surrounding at-risk communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized hazardous fuels projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A project carried out using funding authorized under paragraphs (11)(A)(i), (13), or (14) of subsection (c) shall be considered an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project pursuant to <ref>section 6512 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title VIII, § 40803</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6592a.</num>
<heading> Ecosystem restoration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, for the activities described in subsection (b), $2,130,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the amounts made available under subsection (a) for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> $300,000,000 shall be made available, in accordance with subsection (c), to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> entering into contracts, including stewardship contracts or agreements, the purpose of each of which shall be to restore ecological health on not fewer than 10,000 acres of Federal land, including Indian forest land or rangeland, and for salaries and expenses associated with preparing and executing those contracts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> establishing a Working Capital Fund that may be accessed by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to fund requirements of contracts described in clause (i), including cancellation and termination costs, consistent with <ref>section 6591c(h) of this title</ref>, and periodic payments over the span of the contract period; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> of which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $50,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior to enter into contracts described in subparagraph (A)(i);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $150,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into contracts described in subparagraph (A)(i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available until expended to the Secretary of the Interior, notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, to establish the Working Capital Fund described in subparagraph (A)(ii);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> $200,000,000 shall be made available to provide to States and Indian Tribes for implementing restoration projects on Federal land pursuant to good neighbor agreements entered into under <ref>section 2113a of this title</ref> or agreements entered into under <ref>section 3115a(b) of title 25</ref>, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $40,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $160,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $400,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture to provide financial assistance to facilities that purchase and process byproducts from ecosystem restoration projects in accordance with subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> $400,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior to provide grants to States, territories of the United States, and Indian Tribes for implementing voluntary ecosystem restoration projects on private or public land, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prioritizes funding cross-boundary projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requires matching funding from the State, territory of the United States, or Indian Tribe to be eligible to receive the funding;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $50,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture to award grants to States and Indian Tribes to establish rental programs for portable skidder bridges, bridge mats, or other temporary water crossing structures, to minimize stream bed disturbance on non-Federal land and Federal land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> $200,000,000 shall be made available for invasive species detection, prevention, and eradication, including conducting research and providing resources to facilitate detection of invasive species at points of entry and awarding grants for eradication of invasive species on non-Federal land and on Federal land, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to restore, prepare, or adapt recreation sites on Federal land, including Indian forest land or rangeland, in accordance with subsection (e);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> $200,000,000 shall be made available to restore native vegetation and mitigate environmental hazards on mined land on Federal and non-Federal land, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> $200,000,000 shall be made available to establish and implement a national revegetation effort on Federal and non-Federal land, including to implement the National Seed Strategy for Rehabilitation and Restoration, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $70,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $130,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> $80,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior, to establish a collaborative-based, landscape-scale restoration program to restore water quality or fish passage on Federal land, including Indian forest land or rangeland, in accordance with subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ecological health restoration contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of list of projects to congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Until the date on which all of the amounts made available to carry out subsection (b)(1)(A)(i) are expended, not later than 90 days before the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a list of projects to be funded under that subsection in the subsequent fiscal year, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a detailed description of each project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an estimate of the cost, including salaries and expenses, for the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternate allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Appropriations Acts may provide for alternate allocation of amounts made available under subsection (b)(1), consistent with the allocations under subparagraph (B) of that subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lack of alternate allocations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If Congress has not enacted legislation establishing alternate allocations described in paragraph (2) by the date on which the Act making full-year appropriations for the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies for the applicable fiscal year is enacted into law, amounts made available under subsection (b)(1)(B) shall be allocated by the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wood products infrastructure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> develop a ranking system that categorizes units of Federal land, including Indian forest land or rangeland, with regard to treating areas at risk of unnaturally severe wildfire or insect or disease infestation, as being—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> very low priority for ecological restoration involving vegetation removal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> low priority for ecological restoration involving vegetation removal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> medium priority for ecological restoration involving vegetation removal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> high priority for ecological restoration involving vegetation removal; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> very high priority for ecological restoration involving vegetation removal;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> determine, for a unit identified under paragraph (1) as being high or very high priority for ecological restoration involving vegetation removal, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a sawmill or other wood-processing facility exists in close proximity to, or a forest worker is seeking to conduct restoration treatment work on or in close proximity to, the unit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the presence of a sawmill or other wood-processing facility would substantially decrease or does substantially decrease the cost of conducting ecological restoration projects involving vegetation removal;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in accordance with any conditions the Secretary of Agriculture determines to be necessary, using the amounts made available under subsection (b)(3), provide financial assistance, including a low-interest loan or a loan guarantee, to an entity seeking to establish, reopen, retrofit, expand, or improve a sawmill or other wood-processing facility in close proximity to a unit of Federal land that has been identified under paragraph (1) as high or very high priority for ecological restoration, if the presence of a sawmill or other wood-processing facility would substantially decrease or does substantially decrease the cost of conducting ecological restoration projects involving vegetation removal on the unit of Federal land, including Indian forest land or rangeland, as determined under paragraph (2)(B); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent practicable, when allocating funding to units of Federal land for ecological restoration projects involving vegetation removal, give priority to a unit of Federal land that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has been identified under paragraph (1) as being high or very high priority for ecological restoration involving vegetation removal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> has a sawmill or other wood-processing facility—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> that, as determined under paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> exists in close proximity to the unit; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> does substantially decrease the cost of conducting ecological restoration projects involving vegetation removal on the unit; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that has received financial assistance under paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recreation sites</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Site restoration and improvements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts made available under subsection (b)(7), $45,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior and $35,000,000 shall be made available the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002834">1</ref> Secretary of Agriculture to restore, prepare, or adapt recreation sites on Federal land, including Indian forest land or rangeland, that have experienced or may likely experience visitation and use beyond the carrying capacity of the sites.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public use recreation cabins</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Of the amounts made available under subsection (b)(7), $20,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the operation, repair, reconstruction, and construction of public use recreation cabins on National Forest System land; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to the extent necessary, the repair or reconstruction of historic buildings that are to be outleased under <ref>section 306121 of title 54</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the amount described in subparagraph (A), $5,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture for associated salaries and expenses in carrying out that subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary of Agriculture may enter into a lease or cooperative agreement with a State, Indian Tribe, local government, or private entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to carry out the activities described in subparagraph (A); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to manage the renting of a cabin or building described in subparagraph (A) to the public.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A project shall not be eligible for funding under this subsection if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> funding for the project would be used for deferred maintenance, as defined by Federal Accounting Standards Advisory Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture has identified the project for funding from the National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund established by <ref>section 200402(a) of title 54</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaborative-based, aquatic-focused, landscape-scale restoration program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior and using the amounts made available under subsection (b)(10)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> solicit collaboratively developed proposals that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are for 5-year projects to restore fish passage or water quality on Federal land and non-Federal land to the extent allowed under <ref>section 1011a(a) of this title</ref>, including Indian forest land or rangeland;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contain proposed accomplishments and proposed non-Federal funding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> request not more than $5,000,000 in funding made available under subsection (b)(10);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> select project proposals for funding in a manner that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> gives priority to a project proposal that would result in the most miles of streams being restored for the lowest amount of Federal funding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> discontinues funding for a project that fails to achieve the results included in a proposal submitted under paragraph (1) for more than 2 consecutive years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> publish a list of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all of the priority watersheds on National Forest System land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the condition of each priority watershed on <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the condition of each priority watershed on the date that is 5 years after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title VIII, § 40804</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6592b.</num>
<heading> Establishment of fuel breaks in forests and other wildland vegetation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of Secretary concerned</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands (as defined in <ref>section 1702 of title 43</ref>) administered by the Bureau of Land Management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Categorical exclusion established</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Forest management activities described in subsection (c) are a category of actions designated as being categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) if the categorical exclusion is documented through a supporting record and decision memorandum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forest management activities designated for categorical exclusion</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The category of forest management activities designated under subsection (b) for a categorical exclusion are forest management activities described in paragraph (2) that are carried out by the Secretary concerned on public lands (as defined in <ref>section 1702 of title 43</ref>) administered by the Bureau of Land Management or National Forest System land the primary purpose of which is to establish and maintain linear fuel breaks that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> up to 1,000 feet in width contiguous with or incorporating existing linear features, such as roads, water infrastructure, transmission and distribution lines, and pipelines of any length on Federal land; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> intended to reduce the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire on Federal land or catastrophic wildfire for an adjacent at-risk community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (3), the forest management activities that may be carried out pursuant to the categorical exclusion established under subsection (b) are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> mowing or masticating;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> thinning by manual and mechanical cutting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> piling, yarding, and removal of slash or hazardous fuels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> selling of vegetation products, including timber, firewood, biomass, slash, and fenceposts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> targeted grazing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> application of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> pesticide;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> biopesticide; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> herbicide;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> seeding of native species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> controlled burns and broadcast burning; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> burning of piles, including jackpot piles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excluded activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A forest management activity described in paragraph (2) may not be carried out pursuant to the categorical exclusion established under subsection (b) if the activity is conducted—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on Federal land on which the removal of vegetation is prohibited or restricted by Act of Congress, Presidential proclamation (including the applicable implementation plan), or regulation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in a wilderness study area; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in an area in which carrying out the activity would be inconsistent with the applicable land management plan or resource management plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extraordinary circumstances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary concerned shall apply the extraordinary circumstances procedures under section 220.6 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), in determining whether to use a categorical exclusion under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage and location limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Treatments of vegetation in linear fuel breaks covered by the categorical exclusion established under subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not contain treatment units in excess of 3,000 acres;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> shall be located primarily in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the wildland-urban interface or a public drinking water source area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if located outside the wildland-urban interface or a public drinking water source area, an area within Condition Class 2 or 3 in Fire Regime Group I, II, or III that contains very high wildfire hazard potential; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an insect or disease area designated by the Secretary concerned as of <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall consider the best available scientific information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Roads</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permanent roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A project under this section shall not include the establishment of permanent roads.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary concerned may carry out necessary maintenance and repairs on existing permanent roads for the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary roads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary concerned shall decommission any temporary road constructed under a project under this section not later than 3 years after the date on which the project is completed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public collaboration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To encourage meaningful public participation during the preparation of a project under this section, the Secretary concerned shall facilitate, during the preparation of each project—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> collaboration among State and local governments and Indian Tribes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> participation of interested persons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title VIII, § 40806</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6592c.</num>
<heading> Emergency actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized emergency action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “authorized emergency action” means an action carried out pursuant to an emergency situation determination issued under this section to mitigate the harm to life, property, or important natural or cultural resources on National Forest System land or adjacent land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency situation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “emergency situation” means a situation on National Forest System land for which immediate implementation of 1 or more authorized emergency actions is necessary to achieve 1 or more of the following results:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Relief from hazards threatening human health and safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Mitigation of threats to natural resources on National Forest System land or adjacent land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency situation determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “emergency situation determination” means a determination made by the Secretary under subsection (b)(1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Land and resource management plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “land and resource management plan” means a plan developed under <ref>section 1604 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Forest System land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “National Forest System land” means land of the National Forest System (as defined in <ref>section 1609(a) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized emergency actions to respond to emergency situations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may make a determination that an emergency situation exists with respect to National Forest System land.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An emergency situation determination shall not be subject to objection under the predecisional administrative review processes under part 218 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis of determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An emergency situation determination shall be based on an examination of the relevant information.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized emergency actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After making an emergency situation determination with respect to National Forest System land, the Secretary may carry out authorized emergency actions on that National Forest System land in order to achieve reliefs from hazards threatening human health and safety or mitigation of threats to natural resources on National Forest System land or adjacent land, including through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the salvage of dead or dying trees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the harvest of trees damaged by wind or ice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the commercial and noncommercial sanitation harvest of trees to control insects or disease, including trees already infested with insects or disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the reforestation or replanting of fire-impacted areas through planting, control of competing vegetation, or other activities that enhance natural regeneration and restore forest species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the removal of hazardous trees in close proximity to roads and trails;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the removal of hazardous fuels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the restoration of water sources or infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the reconstruction of existing utility lines; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the replacement of underground cables.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to land and resource management plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any authorized emergency action carried out under paragraph (2) on National Forest System land shall be conducted consistent with the applicable land and resource management plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental analysis</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental assessment or environmental impact statement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that an authorized emergency action requires an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement pursuant to <ref>section 4332(2) of title 42</ref>, the Secretary shall study, develop, and describe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the proposed agency action, taking into account the probable environmental consequences of the authorized emergency action and mitigating foreseeable adverse environmental effects, to the extent practicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the alternative of no action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide notice of each authorized emergency action that the Secretary determines requires an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement under paragraph (1), in accordance with applicable regulations and administrative guidelines.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide an opportunity for public comment during the preparation of any environmental assessment or environmental impact statement under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection prohibits the Secretary from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> making an emergency situation determination, including a determination that an emergency exists pursuant to section 218.21(a) of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> taking an emergency action under section 220.4(b) of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative review of authorized emergency actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An authorized emergency action carried out under this section shall not be subject to objection under the predecisional administrative review processes established under <ref>section 6515 of this title</ref> and section 428 of the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 6515</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 112–74</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review of emergency actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A court shall not enjoin an authorized emergency action under this section if the court determines that the plaintiff is unable to demonstrate that the claim of the plaintiff is likely to succeed on the merits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification and guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide notification and guidance to each local field office of the Forest Service to ensure awareness of, compliance with, and appropriate use of the authorized emergency action authority under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title VIII, § 40807</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6592d.</num>
<heading> Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chiefs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Chiefs” means the Chief of the Forest Service and the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible activity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible activity” means an activity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to reduce the risk of wildfire;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to protect water quality and supply; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to improve wildlife habitat for at-risk species.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership program established under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wildland-urban interface</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “wildland-urban interface” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 6511 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership program to improve the health and resilience of forest landscapes across National Forest System land and State, Tribal, and private land.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall administer the Program by coordinating eligible activities conducted on National Forest System land and State, Tribal, or private land across a forest landscape to improve the health and resilience of the forest landscape by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assisting producers and landowners in implementing eligible activities on eligible private or Tribal land using the applicable programs and authorities administered by the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service under title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.), not including the conservation reserve program established under subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle D of that title (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3831</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conducting eligible activities on National Forest System land or assisting landowners in implementing eligible activities on State, Tribal, or private land using the applicable programs and authorities administered by the Chief of the Forest Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of eligible activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The appropriate Regional Forester and State Conservationist shall jointly submit to the Chiefs on an annual basis proposals for eligible activities under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In evaluating and selecting proposals submitted under subsection (c), the Chiefs shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> criteria including whether the proposal—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduces wildfire risk in a municipal watershed or the wildland-urban interface;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was developed through a collaborative process with participation from diverse stakeholders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increases forest workforce capacity or forest business infrastructure and development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> leverages existing authorities and non-Federal funding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> provides measurable outcomes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> supports established State and regional priorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other criteria relating to the merits of the proposals as the Chiefs determine to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> public notice on the websites of the Forest Service and the Natural Resources Conservation Service describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the solicitation of proposals under subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the criteria for selecting proposals in accordance with subsection (d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information relating to the Program and activities funded under the Program to States, Indian Tribes, units of local government, and private landowners.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An eligible activity may not be carried out under the Program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in a wilderness area or designated wilderness study area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in an inventoried roadless area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> on any Federal land on which, by Act of Congress or Presidential proclamation, the removal of vegetation is restricted or prohibited; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in an area in which the eligible activity would be inconsistent with the applicable land and resource management plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accountability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report providing recommendations to Congress relating to the Program, including a review of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> funding mechanisms for the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> staff capacity to carry out the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> privacy laws applicable to the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> data collection under the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> monitoring and outcomes under the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> such other matters as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each of fiscal years 2022 and 2023, the Chiefs shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report describing projects for which funding is provided under the Program, including the status and outcomes of those projects.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the Program $90,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 and 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the funds described in paragraph (1), the Secretary may obligate available funds from accounts used to carry out the existing Joint Chiefs’ Landscape Restoration Partnership prior to <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, to carry out the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds made available under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Of the funds made available under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 40 percent shall be allocated to carry out eligible activities through the Natural Resources Conservation Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less than 40 percent shall be allocated to carry out eligible activities through the Forest Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the remaining funds shall be allocated by the Chiefs to the Natural Resources Conservation Service or the Forest Service—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to carry out eligible activities; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for other purposes, such as technical assistance, project development, or local capacity building.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title VIII, § 40808</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1114</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>