<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 81A—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL FOREST ORGANIZATIONAL CAMP FEE IMPROVEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6231.</num>
<heading> Findings, purpose, and definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Organizational camps, such as those administered by the Boy Scouts, Girl Scouts, and faith-based and community-based organizations, provide a valuable service to young people, individuals with a disability, and their families by promoting physical, mental, and spiritual health through activities conducted in a natural environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The 192,000,0000 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002823">1</ref> acres of national forests and grasslands of the National Forest System managed for multiple uses by the Forest Service provides an ideal setting for such organizational camps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Federal Government should charge land use fees for the occupancy and use of National Forest System lands by such organizational camps that, while based on the fair market value of the land in use, also recognize the benefits provided to society by such organizational camps, do not preclude the ability of such organizational camps from utilizing these lands, and permit capital investment in, and maintenance of, camp facilities by such organizational camps or their sponsoring organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Organizational camps should—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that their facilities meet applicable building and safety codes, including fire and health codes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have annual inspections as required by local law, including at a minimum inspections for fire and food safety; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> have in place safety plans that address fire and medical emergencies and encounters with wildlife.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to establish a land use fee system that provides for an equitable return to the Federal Government for the occupancy and use of National Forest System lands by organizational camps that serve young people or individuals with a disability.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “organizational camp” means a public or semipublic camp that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is developed on National Forest System lands by a nonprofit organization or governmental entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides a valuable service to the public by using such lands as a setting to introduce young people or individuals with a disability to activities that they may not otherwise experience and to educate them on natural resource issues; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not have as its primary purpose raising revenue through commercial activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “individual with a disability” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 705(20) of title 29</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “children at risk” means children who are raised in poverty or in single-parent homes or are subject to such circumstances as parental drug abuse, homelessness, or child abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “change in control” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for a corporation, the sale or transfer of a controlling interest in the corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a partnership or limited liability company, the sale or transfer of a controlling interest in the partnership or limited liability company; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for an individual, the sale or transfer or an organizational camp subject to this chapter to another party.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6232.</num>
<heading> Fees for occupancy and use of National Forest System lands and facilities by organizational camps</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Land use fee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Percentage of land value</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall charge an annual land use fee for each organizational camp for its occupancy and use of National Forest System lands equal to 5 percent of the product of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The total number of acres of National Forest System lands authorized for the organizational camp.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The estimated per-acre market value of land and buildings in the county where the camp is located, as reported in the most recent Census of Agriculture conducted by the National Agricultural Statistics Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The land use fee determined under paragraph (1) for an organizational camp shall be adjusted annually by the annual compounded rate of change between the two most recent Censuses of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in fees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type of participants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall reduce the land use fee determined under paragraph (1) proportionate to the number of individuals with a disability and children at risk who annually attend the organizational camp.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">After making the reduction required by subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall reduce the remaining land use fee amount by up to 60 percent, proportionate to the number of persons who annually attend the organizational camp who participate in youth programs through organized and supervised social, citizenship, character-building, or faith-based activities oriented to outdoor-recreation experiences.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation to minimum fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The reductions made under this paragraph may not reduce the land use fee for an organizational camp below the minimum land use fee required to be charged under paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of determining the amount of the land use fee reduction required under subparagraph (A) or (B), the Secretary may not take into consideration the existence of sponsorships or scholarships to assist persons in attending the organizational camp.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum land use fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall charge a minimum land use fee under paragraph (1) that represents, on average, the Secretary’s cost annually to administer an organizational camp special use authorization in the National Forest Region in which the organizational camp is located. Notwithstanding paragraph (3) or subsection (d), the minimum land use fee shall not be subject to a reduction or waiver.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Facility use fee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Percentage of facilities value</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If an organizational camp uses a Government-owned facility on National Forest System lands pursuant to <ref>section 580d of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall charge, in addition to the land use fee imposed under subsection (a), a facility use fee equal to 5 percent of the value of the authorized facilities, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in fees prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (d), the facility use fees determined under paragraph (1) shall not be subject to a reduction or waiver.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fee related to receipt of other revenues</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an organizational camp derives revenue from the use of National Forest System lands or authorized facilities described in subsection (b) for purposes other than to introduce young people or individuals with a disability to activities that they may not otherwise experience and to educate them on natural resource issues, the Secretary shall charge, in addition to the land use fee imposed under subsection (a) and the facility use fee imposed under subsection (b), an additional fee equal to 5 percent of that revenue.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Work-in-lieu program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsections (a)(4) and (b)(2), <ref>section 539f of this title</ref> shall apply to the use fees imposed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6233.</num>
<heading> Implementation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prompt implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue direction regarding implementation of this chapter by interim directive within 180 days after <date date="2003-02-20">February 20, 2003</date>. The Secretary shall implement this chapter beginning with the first billing cycle for organizational camp special use authorizations occurring more than 180 days after <date date="2003-02-20">February 20, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Phase-in of use fee increases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In issuing any direction regarding implementation of this chapter under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider whether to phase-in any significant increases in annual land or facility use fees for organizational camps.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6234.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as specifically provided by this chapter, nothing in this chapter supersedes or otherwise affects any provision of law, regulation, or policy regarding the issuance or administration of authorizations for organizational camps regarding the occupancy and use of National Forest System lands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6235.</num>
<heading> Deposit and expenditure of use fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit and availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless subject to <ref>section 580d of this title</ref>, use fees collected by the Secretary under this chapter shall be deposited in a special account in the Treasury and shall remain available to the Secretary for expenditure, without further appropriation until expended, for the purposes described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request of the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Secretary from the special account such amounts as the Secretary may request. The Secretary shall accept and use such amounts in accordance with subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Use fees deposited pursuant to subsection (a) and transferred to the Secretary under subsection (b) shall be expended for monitoring of Forest Service special use authorizations, administration of the Forest Service’s special program, interpretive programs, environmental analysis, environmental restoration, and similar purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6236.</num>
<heading> Ministerial issuance, or amendment authorization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NEPA exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The ministerial issuance or amendment of an organizational camp special use authorization shall not be subject to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the ministerial issuance or amendment of an authorization occurs only when the issuance or amendment of the authorization would not change the physical environment or the activities, facilities, or program of the operations governed by the authorization, and at least one of the following apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authorization is issued upon a change in control of the holder of an existing authorization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The holder, upon expiration of an authorization, is issued a new authorization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The authorization is amended—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to effectuate administrative changes, such as modification of the land use fee or conversion to a new special use authorization form; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to include nondiscretionary environmental standards or to conform with current law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>