<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 25—</num>
<heading>JELLYFISH OR SEA NETTLES, OTHER SUCH PESTS, AND SEAWEED IN COASTAL WATERS: CONTROL OR ELIMINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1201.</num>
<heading> Declaration of purposes; Secretary’s cooperation with and assistance to States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of conserving and protecting the fish and shellfish resources in the coastal waters of the United States and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and promoting and safeguarding water-based recreation for present and future generations in these waters, the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to cooperate with, and provide assistance to, the States in controlling and eliminating jellyfish, commonly referred to as “sea nettles”, and other such pests and in conducting research for the purposes of controlling floating seaweed in such waters.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–720, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1149</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1202.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary; studies, research, and investigations; control measures; execution of program; other actions; costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary, in cooperation with the States and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, is authorized (1) to conduct, directly or by contract, such studies, research, and investigations, as he deems desirable, to determine the abundance and distribution of jellyfish and other such pests and their effects on fish and shellfish and water-based recreation, (2) to conduct studies of control measures of such pests and of floating seaweed, (3) to carry out, based on studies made pursuant to this chapter, a program of controlling or eliminating such pests and such seaweed, and (4) to take such other actions as the Secretary deems desirable: <i>Provided</i>, That the costs of such actions shall be borne equally by the Federal Government and by the States and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, acting jointly or severally.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–720, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1203.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $500,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1968-06-30">June 30, 1968</date>, $750,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1969-06-30">June 30, 1969</date>, $1,000,000 for the period beginning <date date="1969-07-01">July 1, 1969</date>, and ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, and $400,000 for each of the fiscal years ending <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, and <date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–720, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–451</ref>, <date date="1970-10-14">Oct. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–604</ref>, <date date="1972-10-31">Oct. 31, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1204.</num>
<heading> Compacts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress consents to any compact or agreement between any two or more States for the purpose of carrying out a program of research, study, investigation, and control of jellyfish and other such pests in the coastal waters of the United States. The right to alter, amend, or repeal this section or the consent granted herein is expressly reserved.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–720, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1205.</num>
<heading> General authority of Secretary for conducting studies, research, and investigations unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to alter, amend, repeal, modify, or diminish the present general authority of the Secretary of Commerce to conduct studies, research, and investigations related to the mission of the Department of Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–720, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1149</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>