<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5C—</num>
<heading>CONSERVATION PROGRAMS ON GOVERNMENT LANDS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>CONSERVATION PROGRAMS ON MILITARY INSTALLATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 670.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Military installation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “military installation”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any land or interest in land owned by the United States and administered by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department, except land under the jurisdiction of the Assistant Secretary of the Army having responsibility for civil works;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes all public lands withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under public land laws and reserved for use by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not include any land described in subparagraph (A) or (B) that is subject to an approved recommendation for closure under the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State-owned National Guard installation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State-owned National Guard installation” means land owned and operated by a State when such land is used for training the National Guard pursuant to chapter 5 of title 32, with funds provided by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department, even though such land is not under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State fish and wildlife agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State fish and wildlife agency” means the one or more agencies of State government that are responsible under State law for managing fish or wildlife resources.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States” means the States, the District of Columbia, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 100</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX, § 2911</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2021</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title III, § 312(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670a.</num>
<heading> Cooperative plan for conservation and rehabilitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary of Defense</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to provide for the conservation and rehabilitation of natural resources on military installations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated natural resources management plan</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> To facilitate the program, the Secretary of each military department shall prepare and implement an integrated natural resources management plan for each military installation in the United States under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, unless the Secretary determines that the absence of significant natural resources on a particular installation makes preparation of such a plan inappropriate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may, subject to the availability of appropriations, develop and implement an integrated natural resources management plan for a State-owned National Guard installation. Such a plan shall be developed and implemented in coordination with the chief executive officer of the State in which the State-owned National Guard installation is located. Such a plan is deemed, for purposes of any other provision of law, to be for lands or other geographical areas owned or controlled by the Department of Defense, or designated for its use.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative preparation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of a military department shall prepare each integrated natural resources management plan for which the Secretary is responsible in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the head of each appropriate State fish and wildlife agency for the State in which the military installation or State-owned National Guard installation concerned is located. Consistent with paragraph (4), the resulting plan for the military installation or State-owned National Guard installation shall reflect the mutual agreement of the parties concerning conservation, protection, and management of fish and wildlife resources.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Consistent with the use of military installations and State-owned National Guard installations to ensure the preparedness of the Armed Forces, the Secretaries of the military departments shall carry out the program required by this subsection to provide for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the conservation and rehabilitation of natural resources on such installations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the use of natural and nature-based features to maintain or improve military installation resilience;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the sustainable multipurpose use of the resources on such installations, which shall include hunting, fishing, trapping, and nonconsumptive uses; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> subject to safety requirements and military security, public access to military installations to facilitate the use.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a State-owned National Guard installation, such program shall be carried out in coordination with the chief executive officer of the State in which the installation is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> affects any provision of a Federal law governing the conservation or protection of fish and wildlife resources; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enlarges or diminishes the responsibility and authority of any State for the protection and management of fish and resident wildlife; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except as specifically provided in the other provisions of this section and in <ref>section 670b of this title</ref>, authorizes the Secretary of a military department to require a Federal license or permit to hunt, fish, or trap on a military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required elements of plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Consistent with the use of military installations and State-owned National Guard installations to ensure the preparedness of the Armed Forces, each integrated natural resources management plan prepared under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> shall, to the extent appropriate and applicable, provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fish and wildlife management, land management, forest management, and fish- and wildlife-oriented recreation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fish and wildlife habitat enhancement or modifications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> wetland protection, enhancement, and restoration, where necessary for support of fish, wildlife, or plants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> integration of, and consistency among, the various activities conducted under the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> establishment of specific natural resource management goals and objectives and time frames for proposed action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> sustainable use by the public of natural resources to the extent that the use is not inconsistent with the needs of fish and wildlife resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> public access to the installation that is necessary or appropriate for the use described in subparagraph (F), subject to requirements necessary to ensure safety and military security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> enforcement of applicable natural resource laws (including regulations);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> no net loss in the capability of installation lands to support the military mission of the installation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> such other activities as the Secretary of the military department determines appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> must be reviewed as to operation and effect by the parties thereto on a regular basis, but not less often than every 5 years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> may, in the case of a military installation, stipulate the issuance of special State hunting and fishing permits to individuals and require payment of nominal fees therefor, which fees shall be utilized for the protection, conservation, and management of fish and wildlife, including habitat improvement and related activities in accordance with the integrated natural resources management plan; except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Commanding Officer of the installation or persons designated by that Officer are authorized to enforce such special hunting and fishing permits and to collect, spend, administer, and account for fees for the permits, acting as agent or agents for the State if the integrated natural resources management plan so provides, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the fees collected under this paragraph may not be expended with respect to other than the military installation on which collected, unless the military installation is subsequently closed, in which case the fees may be transferred to another military installation to be used for the same purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibitions on sale and lease of lands unless effects compatible with plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After an integrated natural resources management plan is agreed to under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no sale of land, or forest products from land, that is within a military installation covered by that plan may be made under section 2665(a) or (b) of title 10; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no leasing of land that is within the installation may be made under section 2667 of such title 10;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless the effects of that sale or leasing are compatible with the purposes of the plan.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation and enforcement of integrated natural resources management plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With regard to the implementation and enforcement of integrated natural resources management plans agreed to under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> neither Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 nor any successor circular thereto applies to the procurement of services that are necessary for that implementation and enforcement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> priority shall be given to the entering into of contracts for the procurement of such implementation and enforcement services with Federal and State agencies having responsibility for the conservation or management of fish or wildlife.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Integrated natural resources management plans agreed to under the authority of this section and <ref>section 670b of this title</ref> shall not be deemed to be, nor treated as, cooperative agreements to which chapter 63 of title 31 applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviews and reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of Defense</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall review the extent to which integrated natural resources management plans were prepared or were in effect and implemented in accordance with this subchapter in the preceding year, and submit a report on the findings of the review to the committees. Each report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of integrated natural resources management plans in effect in the year covered by the report, including the date on which each plan was issued in final form or most recently revised;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amounts expended on conservation activities conducted pursuant to the plans in the year covered by the report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the extent to which the plans comply with this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than March 1 of each year and in consultation with the heads of State fish and wildlife agencies, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit a report to the committees on the amounts expended by the Department of the Interior and the State fish and wildlife agencies in the year covered by the report on conservation activities conducted pursuant to integrated natural resources management plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Committees” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Resources and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program for invasive species management for military installations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of invasive species management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Defense shall, to the extent practicable and conducive to military readiness, incorporate in integrated natural resources management plans for military installations the management, control, and eradication of invasive species—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that are not native to the ecosystem of the military installation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the introduction of which cause or may cause harm to military readiness, the environment, or human health and safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this subsection in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 101</ref>, formerly § 1, <date date="1960-09-15">Sept. 15, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 1052</ref>; renumbered title I, § 101, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–452</ref>, §§ 1(1), 3(1), (2), <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1369</ref>, 1375; <ref>Pub. L. 97–396, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–561, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX</ref>, §§ 2904(a)–(b)(4), (c), 2906, 2907, 2913(2)–(4), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2017</ref>, 2018, 2020, 2022; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(19)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 311(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1352</ref>, 1353; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 387</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670a–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX, § 2912</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2022</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670b.</num>
<heading> Migratory game birds; hunting permits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated natural resources management plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior and the appropriate State agency is authorized to carry out a program for the conservation, restoration and management of migratory game birds on military installations, including the issuance of special hunting permits and the collection of fees therefor, in accordance with an integrated natural resources management plan mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior and the appropriate State agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Possession of a special permit for hunting migratory game birds issued pursuant to this subchapter shall not relieve the permittee of the requirements of the Migratory Bird Hunting Stamp Act as amended [<ref>16 U.S.C. 718</ref> et seq.] nor of the requirements pertaining to State law set forth in <ref>Public Law 85–337</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 102</ref>, formerly § 2, <date date="1960-09-15">Sept. 15, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 1053</ref>; renumbered title I, § 102, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 3(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX</ref>, §§ 2904(b)(5), 2913(5), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2018</ref>, 2022; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670c.</num>
<heading> Program for public outdoor recreation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense is also authorized to carry out a program for the development, enhancement, operation, and maintenance of public outdoor recreation resources at military installations in accordance with an integrated natural resources management plan mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the appropriate State agency designated by the State in which the installations are located.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access for disabled veterans, military dependents with disabilities, and other persons with disabilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In developing facilities and conducting programs for public outdoor recreation at military installations, consistent with the primary military mission of the installations, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure, to the extent reasonably practicable, that outdoor recreation opportunities (including fishing, hunting, trapping, wildlife viewing, boating, and camping) made available to the public also provide access for persons described in paragraph (2) when topographic, vegetative, and water resources allow access for such persons without substantial modification to the natural environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Persons referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Disabled veterans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Military dependents with disabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Other persons with disabilities, when access to a military installation for such persons and other civilians is not otherwise restricted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this subsection in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, national service, military, and veterans organizations, and sporting organizations in the private sector that participate in outdoor recreation projects for persons described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance of donations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In connection with the facilities and programs for public outdoor recreation at military installations, in particular the requirement under subsection (b) to provide access for persons described in paragraph (2) of such subsection, the Secretary of Defense may accept—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the voluntary services of individuals and organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> donations of property, whether real or personal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of volunteers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A volunteer under subsection (c) shall not be considered to be a Federal employee and shall not be subject to the provisions of law relating to Federal employment, including those relating to hours of work, rates of compensation, leave, unemployment compensation, and Federal employee benefits, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the purposes of the tort claims provisions of chapter 171 of title 28, the volunteer shall be considered to be a Federal employee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the purposes of subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5, relating to compensation to Federal employees for work injuries, the volunteer shall be considered to be an employee, as defined in <ref>section 8101(1)(B) of title 5</ref>, and the provisions of such subchapter shall apply.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 103</ref>, formerly § 3, <date date="1960-09-15">Sept. 15, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 1053</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–465, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-08-08">Aug. 8, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 661</ref>; renumbered title I, § 103, <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX</ref>, §§ 2904(b)(6), 2913(6), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2018</ref>, 2022; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670c–1.</num>
<heading> Cooperative and interagency agreements for land management on installations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary of military department</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of a military department may enter into cooperative agreements with States, local governments, Indian tribes, nongovernmental organizations, and individuals, and into interagency agreements with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, to provide for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The maintenance and improvement of natural resources on, or to benefit natural and historic research on, military installations and State-owned National Guard installations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The maintenance and improvement of natural resources located off of a military installation or State-owned National Guard installation if the purpose of the cooperative agreement or interagency agreement is to relieve or eliminate current or anticipated challenges that could restrict, impede, or otherwise interfere with, whether directly or indirectly, current or anticipated military activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiyear agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for a fiscal year may be obligated to cover the cost of goods and services provided under a cooperative agreement or interagency agreement entered into under subsection (a) or through an agency agreement under <ref>section 1535 of title 31</ref> during any 18-month period beginning in that fiscal year, without regard to whether the agreement crosses fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a cooperative agreement under subsection (a)(2), such funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be paid in a lump sum and include an amount intended to cover the future costs of the natural resource maintenance and improvement activities provided for under the agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may be placed by the recipient in an interest-bearing or other investment account, and any interest or income shall be applied for the same purposes as the principal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If any funds are placed by a recipient in an interest-bearing or other investment account under paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of Defense shall report biennially to the congressional defense committees on the disposition of such funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds; agreement under other laws</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Cooperative agreements and interagency agreements entered into under this section shall be subject to the availability of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, a cooperative agreement under this section may be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit or use of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 103a</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2845(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1664</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX, § 2908</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2021</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title III, § 313, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1352</ref>, 1353; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1691</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670d.</num>
<heading> Liability for funds; accounting to Comptroller General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Defense is held free from any liability to pay into the Treasury of the United States upon the operation of the program or programs authorized by this subchapter any funds which may have been or may hereafter be collected, received or expended pursuant to, and for the purposes of, this subchapter, and which collections, receipts and expenditures have been properly accounted for to the Comptroller General of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 104</ref>, formerly § 4, <date date="1960-09-15">Sept. 15, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 1053</ref>; renumbered title I, § 104, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 3(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670e.</num>
<heading> Applicability to other laws; national forest lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing herein contained shall be construed to modify, amend or repeal any provision of <ref>Public Law 85–337</ref>, nor as applying to national forest lands administered pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 9 of the Act of June 7, 1924</ref> (<ref>43 Stat. 655</ref>), nor <ref>section 315m of title 43</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 105</ref>, formerly § 5, <date date="1960-09-15">Sept. 15, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 1053</ref>; renumbered title I, § 105, <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1375</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670e–1.</num>
<heading> Federal enforcement of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All Federal laws relating to the management of natural resources on Federal land may be enforced by the Secretary of Defense with respect to violations of the laws that occur on military installations within the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 106</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX, § 2909(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670e–2.</num>
<heading> Natural resources management services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent practicable using available resources, the Secretary of each military department shall ensure that sufficient numbers of professionally trained natural resources management personnel and natural resources law enforcement personnel are available and assigned responsibility to perform tasks necessary to carry out this subchapter, including the preparation and implementation of integrated natural resources management plans.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 107</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX, § 2910</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670f.</num>
<heading> Appropriations and expenditures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures of collected funds under integrated natural resources management plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall expend such funds as may be collected in accordance with the integrated natural resources management plans agreed to under sections 670a and 670b of this title and cooperative agreements agreed to under <ref>section 670c–1 of this title</ref> and for no other purpose. All funds that are so collected shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to Secretary of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense not to exceed $1,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2019, to carry out this subchapter, including the enhancement of fish and wildlife habitat and the development of public recreation and other facilities, and to carry out such functions and responsibilities as the Secretary may have under cooperative agreements entered into under <ref>section 670c–1 of this title</ref>. The Secretary of Defense shall, to the greatest extent practicable, enter into agreements to utilize the services, personnel, equipment, and facilities, with or without reimbursement, of the Secretary of the Interior in carrying out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Department of the Interior, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior not to exceed $3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2019, to carry out such functions and responsibilities as the Secretary may have under integrated natural resources management plans to which such Secretary is a party under this section, including those for the enhancement of fish and wildlife habitat and the development of public recreation and other facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of other conservation or rehabilitation authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Interior may each use any authority available to him under other laws relating to fish, wildlife, or plant conservation or rehabilitation for purposes of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 108</ref>, formerly § 6, as added <ref>Pub. L. 90–465, § 2</ref>, <date date="1968-08-08">Aug. 8, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 661</ref>; renumbered title I, § 106, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–452</ref>, §§ 1(2), 3(1), (4), (5), <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1369</ref>, 1375; <ref>Pub. L. 95–420, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-10-05">Oct. 5, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–396, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–561</ref>, §§ 1(a), 3(b), <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3149</ref>, 3151; <ref>Pub. L. 100–653, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3827</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2845(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1664</ref>; renumbered § 108, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX</ref>, §§ 2904(b)(7), (8), 2909(1), 2914(a), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2018</ref>, 2021, 2022; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1428</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title III, § 313</ref>, title X, § 1091(c)(1), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 729</ref>, 876.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CONSERVATION PROGRAMS ON PUBLIC LANDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 670g.</num>
<heading> Wildlife, fish, and game conservation and rehabilitation programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each, in cooperation with the State agencies and in accordance with comprehensive plans developed pursuant to <ref>section 670h of this title</ref>, plan, develop, maintain, and coordinate programs for the conservation and rehabilitation of wildlife, fish, and game. Such conservation and rehabilitation programs shall include, but not be limited to, specific habitat improvement projects and related activities and adequate protection for species of fish, wildlife, and plants considered threatened or endangered.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall implement the conservation and rehabilitation programs required under subsection (a) of this section on public land under his jurisdiction. The Secretary of the Interior shall adopt, modify, and implement the conservation and rehabilitation programs required under such subsection (a) on public land under the jurisdiction of the Chairman, but only with the prior written approval of the Atomic Energy Commission, and on public land under the jurisdiction of the Administrator, but only with the prior written approval of the Administrator. The Secretary of Agriculture shall implement such conservation and rehabilitation programs on public land under his jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1369</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–396, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670h.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive plans for conservation and rehabilitation programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Interior shall develop, in consultation with the State agencies, a comprehensive plan for conservation and rehabilitation programs to be implemented on public land under his jurisdiction and the Secretary of Agriculture shall do the same in connection with public land under his jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Interior shall develop, with the prior written approval of the Atomic Energy Commission, a comprehensive plan for conservation and rehabilitation programs to be implemented on public land under the jurisdiction of the Chairman and develop, with the prior written approval of the Administrator, a comprehensive plan for such programs to be implemented on public land under the jurisdiction of the Administrator. Each such plan shall be developed after the Secretary of the Interior makes, with the prior written approval of the Chairman or the Administrator, as the case may be, and in consultation with the State agencies, necessary studies and surveys of the land concerned to determine where conservation and rehabilitation programs are most needed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency with overall land use and management plans; hunting, trapping, and fishing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each comprehensive plan developed pursuant to this section shall be consistent with any overall land use and management plans for the lands involved. In any case in which hunting, trapping, or fishing (or any combination thereof) of resident fish and wildlife is to be permitted on public land under a comprehensive plan, such hunting, trapping, and fishing shall be conducted in accordance with applicable laws and regulations of the State in which such land is located.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements by State agencies for implementation of programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each State agency may enter into a cooperative agreement with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior with respect to those conservation and rehabilitation programs to be implemented under this subchapter within the State on public land which is under his jurisdiction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to those conservation and rehabilitation programs to be implemented under this subchapter within the State on public land which is under his jurisdiction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior and the Chairman or the Administrator, as the case may be, with respect to those conservation and rehabilitation programs to be implemented under this subchapter within the State on public land under the jurisdiction of the Chairman or the Administrator; except that before entering into any cooperative agreement which affects public land under the jurisdiction of the Chairman, the Secretary of the Interior shall obtain the prior written approval of the Atomic Energy Commission and before entering into any cooperative agreement which affects public lands under the jurisdiction of the Administrator, the Secretary of the Interior shall obtain the prior written approval of the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Conservation and rehabilitation programs developed and implemented pursuant to this subchapter shall be deemed as supplemental to wildlife, fish, and game-related programs conducted by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to other provisions of law. Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as limiting the authority of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, to manage the national forests or other public lands for wildlife and fish and other purposes in accordance with the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 (<ref>74 Stat. 215</ref>; <ref>16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>) or other applicable authority.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any conservation and rehabilitation program included within a cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection may be modified in a manner mutually agreeable to the State agency and the Secretary concerned (and the Chairman or the Administrator, as the case may be, if public land under his jurisdiction is involved). Before modifying any cooperative agreement which affects public land under the jurisdiction of the Chairman, the Secretary of the Interior shall obtain the prior written approval of the Atomic Energy Commission and before modifying any cooperative agreement which affects public land under the jurisdiction of the Administrator, the Secretary of the Interior shall obtain the prior written approval of the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Each cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specify those areas of public land within the State on which conservation and rehabilitation programs will be implemented;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for fish and wildlife habitat improvements or modifications, or both;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide for range rehabilitation where necessary for support of wildlife;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide adequate protection for fish and wildlife officially classified as threatened or endangered pursuant to <ref>section 1533 of this title</ref> or considered to be threatened, rare, or endangered by the State agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> require the control of off-road vehicle traffic;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> if the issuance of public land area management stamps is agreed to pursuant to <ref>section 670i(a) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contain such terms and conditions as are required under <ref>section 670i(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> require the maintenance of accurate records and the filing of annual reports by the State agency to the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, or both, as the case may be, setting forth the amount and disposition of the fees collected for such stamps; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> authorize the Secretary concerned and the Comptroller General of the United States, or their authorized representatives, to have access to such records for purposes of audit and examination; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> contain such other terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned and the State agency deem necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">A cooperative agreement may also provide for arrangements under which the Secretary concerned may authorize officers and employees of the State agency to enforce, or to assist in the enforcement of, <ref>section 670j(a) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Except where limited under a comprehensive plan or pursuant to cooperative agreement, hunting, fishing, and trapping shall be permitted with respect to resident fish and wildlife in accordance with applicable laws and regulations of the State in which such land is located on public land which is the subject of a conservation and rehabilitation program implemented under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, shall prescribe such regulations as are deemed necessary to control, in a manner consistent with the applicable comprehensive plan and cooperative agreement, the public use of public land which is the subject of any conservation and rehabilitation program implemented by him under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State agency agreements not cooperative agreements under other provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Agreements entered into by State agencies under the authority of this section shall not be deemed to be, or treated as, cooperative agreements to which chapter 63 of title 31 applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 202</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1369</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–396, § 4</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670i.</num>
<heading> Public land management area stamps for hunting, trapping, and fishing on public lands subject to programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements to require stamps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any State agency may agree with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (or with the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, if within the State concerned all conservation and rehabilitation programs under this subchapter will be implemented by him) that no individual will be permitted to hunt, trap, or fish on any public land within the State which is subject to a conservation and rehabilitation program implemented under this subchapter unless at the time such individual is engaged in such activity he has on his person a valid public land management area stamp issued pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any agreement made pursuant to subsection (a) of this section to require the issuance of public land management area stamps shall be subject to the following conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Such stamps shall be issued, sold, and the fees therefor collected, by the State agency or by the authorized agents of such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notice of the requirement to possess such stamps shall be displayed prominently in all places where State hunting, trapping, or fishing licenses are sold. To the maximum extent practicable, the sale of such stamps shall be combined with the sale of such State hunting, trapping, and fishing licenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except for expenses incurred in the printing, issuing, or selling of such stamps, the fees collected for such stamps by the State agency shall be utilized in carrying out conservation and rehabilitation programs implemented under this subchapter in the State concerned. Such fees may be used by the State agency to acquire lands or interests therein from willing sellers or donors to provide public access to program lands that have no existing public access for enhancement of outdoor recreation and wildlife conservation: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior maintain such access, or ensure that maintenance is provided for such access, through or to lands within their respective jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The purchase of any such stamp shall entitle the purchaser thereof to hunt, trap, and fish on any public land within such State which is the subject of a conservation or rehabilitation program implemented under this subchapter except to the extent that the public use of such land is limited pursuant to a comprehensive plan or cooperative agreement; but the purchase of any such stamp shall not be construed as (A) eliminating the requirement for the purchase of a migratory bird hunting stamp as set forth in <ref>section 718a of this title</ref>, or (B) relieving the purchaser from compliance with any applicable State game and fish laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The amount of the fee to be charged for such stamps, the age at which the individual is required to acquire such a stamp, and the expiration date for such stamps shall be mutually agreed upon by the State agency and the Secretary or Secretaries concerned; except that each such stamp shall be void not later than one year after the date of issuance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Each such stamp must be validated by the purchaser thereof by signing his name across the face of the stamp.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Any individual to whom a stamp is sold pursuant to this section shall upon request exhibit such stamp for inspection to any officer or employee of the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture, or to any other person who is authorized to enforce <ref>section 670j(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1371</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–653, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3826</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670j.</num>
<heading> Enforcement provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations and penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any person who hunts, traps, or fishes on any public land which is subject to a conservation and rehabilitation program implemented under this subchapter without having on his person a valid public land management area stamp, if the possession of such a stamp is required, shall be fined not more than $1,000, or imprisoned for not more than six months, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who knowingly violates or fails to comply with any regulations prescribed under <ref>section 670h(c)(5) of this title</ref> shall be fined not more than $500, or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement powers and proceedings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purpose of enforcing subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may designate any employee of their respective departments, and any State officer or employee authorized under a cooperative agreement to enforce such subsection (a), to (i) carry firearms; (ii) execute and serve any warrant or other process issued by a court or officer of competent jurisdiction; (iii) make arrests without warrant or process for a misdemeanor he has reasonable grounds to believe is being committed in his presence or view; (iv) search without warrant or process any person, place, or conveyance as provided by law; and (v) seize without warrant or process any evidentiary item as provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon the sworn information by a competent person, any United States magistrate judge or court of competent jurisdiction may issue process for the arrest of any person charged with committing any offense under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any person charged with committing any offense under subsection (a) of this section may be tried and sentenced by any United States magistrate judge designated for that purpose by the court by which he was appointed, in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as provided for in <ref>section 3401 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Seizure and forfeiture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All guns, traps, nets, and other equipment, vessels, vehicles, and other means of transportation used by any person when engaged in committing an offense under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to forfeiture to the United States and may be seized and held pending the prosecution of any person arrested for committing such offense. Upon conviction for such offense, such forfeiture may be adjudicated as a penalty in addition to any other provided for committing such offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of customs laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All provisions of law relating to the seizure, forfeiture, and condemnation of a vessel for violation of the customs laws, the disposition of such vessel or the proceeds from the sale thereof, and the remission or mitigation of such forfeitures, shall apply to the seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this section, insofar as such provisions of law are applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions of this section; except that all powers, rights, and duties conferred or imposed by the customs laws upon any officer or employee of the Department of the Treasury shall, for the purposes of this section, be exercised or performed by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, or by such persons as he may designate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1372</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(10)</ref>, (c), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1354</ref>, 1355.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670k.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Chairman” means the Chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “off-road vehicle” means any motorized vehicle designed for, or capable of, cross-country travel on or immediately over land, water, sand, snow, ice, marsh, swampland, or other natural terrain; but such term does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any registered motorboat at the option of each State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any military, fire, emergency, or law enforcement vehicle when used for emergency purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any vehicle the use of which is expressly authorized by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture under a permit, lease, license, or contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “public land” means all lands, under the respective jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Chairman, and the Administrator, except land which is, or hereafter may be, within or designated as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a military reservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a unit of the National Park System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an area within the national wildlife refuge system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an Indian reservation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an area within an Indian reservation or land held in trust by the United States for an Indian or Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “State agency” means the agency or agencies of a State responsible for the administration of the fish and game laws of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “conservation and rehabilitation programs” means to utilize those methods and procedures which are necessary to protect, conserve, and enhance wildlife, fish, and game resources to the maximum extent practicable on public lands subject to this subchapter consistent with any overall land use and management plans for the lands involved. Such methods and procedures shall include, but shall not be limited to, all activities associated with scientific resources management such as protection, research, census, law enforcement, habitat management, propagation, live trapping and transplantation, and regulated taking in conformance with the provisions of this subchapter. Nothing in this term shall be construed as diminishing the authority or jurisdiction of the States with respect to the management of resident species of fish, wildlife, or game, except as otherwise provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 205</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1373</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670l.</num>
<heading> Stamp requirements not applicable to Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management lands; authorized fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision in this subchapter, <ref>section 670i of this title</ref> shall not apply to land which is, or hereafter may be, within or designated as Forest Service land or as Bureau of Land Management land of any State in which all Federal lands therein comprise 60 percent or more of the total area of such State; except that in any such State, any appropriate State agency may agree with the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, or both, as the case may be, to collect a fee as specified in such agreement at the point of sale of regular licenses to hunt, trap, or fish in such State, the proceeds of which shall be utilized in carrying out conservation and rehabilitation programs implemented under this subchapter in the State concerned and for no other purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 206</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1374</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(12)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670m.</num>
<heading> Indian rights; State or Federal jurisdiction regulating Indian rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall enlarge or diminish or in any way affect (1) the rights of Indians or Indian tribes to the use of water or natural resources or their rights to fish, trap, or hunt wildlife as secured by statute, agreement, treaty, Executive order, or court decree; or (2) existing State or Federal jurisdiction to regulate those rights either on or off reservations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 207</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1374</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670n.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1355</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670o.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions and responsibilities of Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1998 through 2003, to enable the Secretary of the Interior to carry out his functions and responsibilities under this subchapter, including data collection, research, planning, and conservation and rehabilitation programs on public lands. Such funds shall be in addition to those authorized for wildlife, range, soil, and water management pursuant to <ref>section 1748 of title 43</ref>, or other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions and responsibilities of Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1998 through 2003, to enable the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out his functions and responsibilities under this subchapter. Such funds shall be in addition to those provided under other provisions of law. In requesting funds under this subsection the Secretary shall take into account fish and wildlife program needs, including those for projects, identified in the State comprehensive plans as contained in the program developed pursuant to the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974, as amended (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1601–161</ref>0).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of other conservation or rehabilitation authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may each use any authority available to him under other laws relating to fish, wildlife, or plant conservation or rehabilitation for purposes of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may each make purchases and contracts for property and services from, or provide assistance to, the State agencies concerned, if such property, services or assistance is required to implement those projects and programs carried out on, or of benefit to, Federal lands and identified in the comprehensive plans or cooperative agreements developed under <ref>section 670h of this title</ref>, without regard to division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3901, 3905, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41. Contract authority provided in this section is effective only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 208</ref>, formerly § 209, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1374</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–420, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-10-05">Oct. 5, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–396, § 5</ref>, <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–561, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–653, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3827</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX, § 2914(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2023</ref>; renumbered § 208 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(14)</ref>, (d), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>