<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 42—</num>
<heading>EMERGENCY CONSERVATION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2201.</num>
<heading> Emergency conservation program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this chapter as the “Secretary”) is authorized to make payments to agricultural producers who carry out emergency measures to control wind erosion on farmlands or to rehabilitate farmlands damaged by wind erosion, floods, hurricanes, wildfires, or other natural disasters when, as a result of the foregoing, new conservation problems have been created that (1) if not treated, will impair or endanger the land, (2) materially affect the productive capacity of the land, (3) represent damage that is unusual in character and, except for wind erosion, is not the type that would recur frequently in the same area, and (4) will be so costly to rehabilitate that Federal assistance is or will be required to return the land to productive agricultural use.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repair or replacement of fencing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to a payment to an agricultural producer under subsection (a) for the repair or replacement of fencing, the Secretary shall give the agricultural producer the option of receiving not more than 25 percent of the payment, determined by the Secretary based on the applicable percentage of the fair market value of the cost of the repair or replacement, before the agricultural producer carries out the repair or replacement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the funds provided under paragraph (1) are not expended by the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the agricultural producer receives those funds, the funds shall be returned within a reasonable timeframe, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1978-08-04">Aug. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2202.</num>
<heading> Payments to agricultural producers for carrying out water conservation or water enhancing measures; criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make payments to agricultural producers who carry out emergency water conservation or water enhancing measures (including measures carried out to assist confined livestock) during periods of severe drought as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1978-08-04">Aug. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–82, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1989-08-14">Aug. 14, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2202a.</num>
<heading> Cost-share requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-share rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the maximum cost-share payment under sections 2201 and 2202 of this title shall not exceed 75 percent of the total allowable cost, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a), a payment to a limited resource farmer or rancher, a socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher (as defined in subsection (a) of <ref>section 2279 of title 7</ref>), or a beginning farmer or rancher under section 2201 or 2202 of this title shall not exceed 90 percent of the total allowable cost, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The total payment under sections 2201 and 2202 of this title for a single event may not exceed 50 percent of the agriculture value of the land, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 402A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2202b.</num>
<heading> Payment limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The maximum payment made under the emergency conservation program to an agricultural producer under sections 2201 and 2202 of this title shall not exceed $500,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 402B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2203.</num>
<heading> Emergency watershed program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to undertake emergency watershed protection measures, including the purchase of floodplain easements, for runoff retardation and soil-erosion prevention, in cooperation with landowners and land users, as the Secretary deems necessary to safeguard lives and property from floods, drought, and the products of erosion on any watershed whenever fire, flood, or any other natural occurrence is causing or has caused a sudden impairment of that watershed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Floodplain easements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification and termination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may modify or terminate a floodplain easement administered by the Secretary under this section if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the current owner agrees to the modification or termination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary determines that the modification or termination—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> will address a compelling public need for which there is no practicable alternative; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is in the public interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As consideration for termination of an easement and associated agreements under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall enter into compensatory arrangements as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of a modification under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as a condition of the modification, the current owner shall enter into a compensatory arrangement (as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary) to incur the costs of modification; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the modification will not adversely affect the floodplain functions and values for which the easement was acquired;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any adverse impacts will be mitigated by enrollment and restoration of other land that provides greater floodplain functions and values at no additional cost to the Federal Government; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the modification will result in equal or greater environmental and economic values to the United States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1978-08-04">Aug. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 382</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title II, § 2506</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(a)(2)(A)</ref>, (d), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4571</ref>, 4572.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2204.</num>
<heading> Funding and administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such funds as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Set-aside for fencing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts made available under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, 25 percent shall be set aside until April 1 of that fiscal year for the repair or replacement of fencing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this chapter, the Secretary may use the facilities, services, and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commodity Credit Corporation shall not make any expenditures to carry out the provisions of this chapter unless funds specifically appropriated for such purpose have been transferred to it.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1978-08-04">Aug. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(a)(2)(A)</ref>, (e), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4571</ref>, 4572.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2205.</num>
<heading> Regulations for implementation of provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to prescribe such regulations as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1978-08-04">Aug. 4, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2206.</num>
<heading> Emergency forest restoration program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency measures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “emergency measures” means those measures that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> are necessary to address damage caused by a natural disaster to natural resources on nonindustrial private forest land, and the damage, if not treated—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> would impair or endanger the natural resources on the land; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> would materially affect future use of the land; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would restore forest health and forest-related resources on the land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Natural disaster</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “natural disaster” includes wildfires, hurricanes or excessive winds, drought, ice storms or blizzards, floods, or other resource-impacting events, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonindustrial private forest land</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “nonindustrial private forest land” means rural land, as determined by the Secretary, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has existing tree cover (or had tree cover immediately before the natural disaster and is suitable for growing trees); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is owned by any nonindustrial private individual, group, association, corporation, or other private legal entity, that has definitive decision-making authority over the land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make payments to an owner of nonindustrial private forest land who carries out emergency measures to restore the land after the land is damaged by a natural disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a payment under subsection (b), an owner must demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the nonindustrial private forest land on which the emergency measures are carried out had tree cover immediately before the natural disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost share requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments made under subsection (b) shall not exceed 75 percent of the total cost of the emergency measures carried out by an owner of nonindustrial private forest land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such funds as may be necessary to carry out this section. Amounts so appropriated shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–334, title IV, § 407</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8203(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1290</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 8203(a), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2051; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2403(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>