<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 10B—</num>
<heading>STATE TAXATION OF INCOME FROM INTERSTATE COMMERCE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>NET INCOME TAXES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 381.</num>
<heading> Imposition of net income tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No State, or political subdivision thereof, shall have power to impose, for any taxable year ending after <date date="1959-09-14">September 14, 1959</date>, a net income tax on the income derived within such State by any person from interstate commerce if the only business activities within such State by or on behalf of such person during such taxable year are either, or both, of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the solicitation of orders by such person, or his representative, in such State for sales of tangible personal property, which orders are sent outside the State for approval or rejection, and, if approved, are filled by shipment or delivery from a point outside the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the solicitation of orders by such person, or his representative, in such State in the name of or for the benefit of a prospective customer of such person, if orders by such customer to such person to enable such customer to fill orders resulting from such solicitation are orders described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic corporations; persons domiciled in or residents of a State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to the imposition of a net income tax by any State, or political subdivision thereof, with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any corporation which is incorporated under the laws of such State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any individual who, under the laws of such State, is domiciled in, or a resident of, such State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sales or solicitation of orders for sales by independent contractors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), a person shall not be considered to have engaged in business activities within a State during any taxable year merely by reason of sales in such State, or the solicitation of orders for sales in such State, of tangible personal property on behalf of such person by one or more independent contractors, or by reason of the maintenance, of an office in such State by one or more independent contractors whose activities on behalf of such person in such State consist solely of making sales, or soliciting orders for sales, or tangible personal property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “independent contractor” means a commission agent, broker, or other independent contractor who is engaged in selling, or soliciting orders for the sale of, tangible personal property for more than one principal and who holds himself out as such in the regular course of his business activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “representative” does not include an independent contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–272, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 382.</num>
<heading> Assessment of net income taxes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No State, or political subdivision thereof, shall have power to assess, after <date date="1959-09-14">September 14, 1959</date>, any net income tax which was imposed by such State or political subdivision, as the case may be, for any taxable year ending on or before such date, on the income derived within such State by any person from interstate commerce, if the imposition of such tax for a taxable year ending after such date is prohibited by <ref>section 381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collections</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (a) shall not be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to invalidate the collection, on or before <date date="1959-09-14">September 14, 1959</date>, of any net income tax imposed for a taxable year ending on or before such date, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to prohibit the collection, after <date date="1959-09-14">September 14, 1959</date>, of any net income tax which was assessed on or before such date for a taxable year ending on or before such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–272, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 383.</num>
<heading> “Net income tax” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “net income tax” means any tax imposed on, or measured by, net income.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–272, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 384.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this chapter or the application of such provision to persons or circumstances other than those to which it is held invalid, shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–272, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>DISCRIMINATORY TAXES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 391.</num>
<heading> Tax on or with respect to generation or transmission of electricity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No State, or political subdivision thereof, may impose or assess a tax on or with respect to the generation or transmission of electricity which discriminates against out-of-State manufacturers, producers, wholesalers, retailers, or consumers of that electricity. For purposes of this section a tax is discriminatory if it results, either directly or indirectly, in a greater tax burden on electricity which is generated and transmitted in interstate commerce than on electricity which is generated and transmitted in intrastate commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–272, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XXI, § 2121(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>