<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>STATISTICAL AND COMMERCIAL INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 171.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 90–620, § 3</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1308</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 172.</num>
<heading> Transfer of duties of Department of Labor; special investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The duties of the Department of Labor, or Bureau of Labor, “to ascertain, at as early a date as possible, and whenever industrial changes shall make it essential, the cost of producing articles at the time dutiable in the United States, in leading countries where such articles are produced, by fully specified units of production, and under a classification showing the different elements of cost, or approximate cost, of such articles of production, including the wages paid in such industries per day, week, month, or year, or by the piece; and hours employed per day; and the profits of manufacturers and producers of such articles; and the comparative cost of living, and the kind of living; what articles are controlled by trusts or other combinations of capital, business operations, or labor, and what effect said trusts, or other combinations of capital, business operations, or labor have on production and prices”, are, as of <date date="1912-08-23">August 23, 1912</date>, transferred to and shall be discharged by the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, and it shall be also the duty of said Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce to make such special investigation and report on particular subjects when required to do so by the President or either House of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 173, 174.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–826, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 175.</num>
<heading> Additional duties of Bureau</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the province and duty of the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, under the direction of the Secretary of Commerce, to foster, promote, and develop the various manufacturing industries of the United States, and markets for the same at home and abroad, domestic and foreign, by gathering, compiling, publishing, and supplying all available and useful information concerning such industries and such markets, and by such other methods and means as may be prescribed by the Secretary of Commerce or provided by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 5</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 827</ref>; <ref>Apr. 5, 1906, ch. 1366, § 3</ref>, <ref>34 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 957</ref>, title XI, § 1131(23), <ref>60 Stat. 1037</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 176.</num>
<heading> Collection of commercial statistics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A purpose of the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce is the collection, arrangement, and classification of such statistical information as may be procured, showing, or tending to show, each year the condition of the manufactures, domestic trade, currency, and banks of the several States and Territories.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 335; <ref>Feb. 27, 1877, ch. 69, § 1</ref>, <ref>19 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 176a.</num>
<heading> Confidential nature of information furnished Bureau</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any statistical information furnished in confidence to the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce by individuals, corporations, and firms shall be held to be confidential, and shall be used only for the statistical purposes for which it is supplied. Except as provided in subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, the Director of the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce shall not permit anyone other than the sworn employees of the Bureau to examine such individual reports, nor shall he permit any statistics of domestic commerce to be published in such manner as to reveal the identity of the individual, corporation, or firm furnishing such data.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Jan. 27, 1938, ch. 11, § 1</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title V, § 526(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5553</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 176b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 21</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 862</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 177.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–826, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 178.</num>
<heading> Collection of statistics of foreign and interstate commerce and transportation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the officer in charge of the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce to gather and collate statistics and facts relating to commerce with foreign nations and among the several States, the railroad systems of this and other countries, the construction and operation of railroads, the actual cost of such construction and operation of railroads, the actual cost of transporting freight and passengers on railroads, and on canals, rivers, and other navigable waters of the United States, the charges imposed for such transportation of freight and passengers, and the tonnage transported.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1875, ch. 129, § 1</ref>, <ref>18 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 10</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>May 29, 1928, ch. 901, § 1(105)</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 994</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–826, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 180.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Feb. 28, 1933, ch. 131, § 1</ref>, <ref>47 Stat. 1349</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 181.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–826, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182.</num>
<heading> Statistics of manufactures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce shall collect, digest, and arrange, for the use of Congress, the statistics of the manufactures of the United States, their localities, sources of raw material, markets, exchanges with the producing regions of the country, transportation of products, wages, and such other conditions as are found to affect their prosperity.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 342; <ref>Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Mar. 1, 1919, ch. 86</ref>, <ref>40 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 183.</num>
<heading> Report of statistics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall make a report to Congress on the first Monday of January in each year, containing the results of the information collected during the preceding year, by the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, upon the condition of the manufactures, domestic trade, currency, and banks of the several States and Territories.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 259; <ref>Feb. 27, 1877, ch. 69, § 1</ref>, <ref>19 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 9</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 184 to 187.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–826, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 188.</num>
<heading> Publication of commercial information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall publish official notifications, from time to time, of such commercial information communicated to him by diplomatic and consular officers, as he may deem important to the public interests, in such newspapers, not to exceed three in number, as he may select.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 211; <ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 10</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 189, 189a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–412, § 3(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1970-09-25">Sept. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 864</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 190.</num>
<heading> Discussions in commercial reports of partisan questions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No part of the consular and other commercial reports of the Department of Commerce, including circular letters to chambers of commerce, discussing partisan political, religious, or moral questions shall be published.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 25, 1885, ch. 150</ref>, <ref>23 Stat. 324</ref>; <ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 10</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 191.</num>
<heading> Terms of measure, weight, and money in commercial reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All terms of measure, weight, and money in the diplomatic, consular, and other commercial reports prepared, printed, published, and distributed by the Department of Commerce shall be reduced to and expressed in terms of measure, weight, and coin of the United States, as well as in the foreign terms.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 9, 1903, ch. 530</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 813</ref>; <ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 10</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 192, 192a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–412, § 3(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1970-09-25">Sept. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 864</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 193.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–826, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 953</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 194, 195.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 196.</num>
<heading> Payments for rent of offices in foreign countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31 shall not apply to advance payments for rent of offices in foreign countries by the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1925, ch. 556, § 1</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 197 to 197d.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 957</ref>, title XI, § 1131(54), <ref>60 Stat. 1039</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 197e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 647</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 197f.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 957</ref>, title XI, § 1131(54), <ref>60 Stat. 1039</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 198.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 851, § 4</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 1111</ref></heading>
</section>
</chapter>