<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 28—</num>
<heading>DISCLOSURE OF AUTOMOBILE INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1231.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The term “manufacturer” shall mean any person engaged in the manufacturing or assembling of new automobiles, including any person importing new automobiles for resale and any person who acts for and is under the control of such manufacturer, assembler, or importer in connection with the distribution of new automobiles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The term “person” means an individual, partnership, corporation, business trust, or any organized group of persons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The term “automobile” includes any passenger car or station wagon.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The term “new automobile” means an automobile the equitable or legal title to which has never been transferred by a manufacturer, distributor, or dealer to an ultimate purchaser.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The term “dealer” shall mean any person resident or located in the United States or any Territory thereof or in the District of Columbia engaged in the sale or the distribution of new automobiles to the ultimate purchaser.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> The term “final assembly point” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a new automobile manufactured or assembled in the United States, or in any Territory of the United States, the plant, factory, or other place at which a new automobile is produced or assembled by a manufacturer and from which such automobile is delivered to a dealer in such a condition that all component parts necessary to the mechanical operation of such automobile are included with such automobile, whether or not such component parts are permanently installed in or on such automobile; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a new automobile imported into the United States, the port of importation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The term “ultimate purchaser” means, with respect to any new automobile, the first person, other than a dealer purchasing in his capacity as a dealer, who in good faith purchases such new automobile for purposes other than resale.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The term “commerce” shall mean commerce among the several States of the United States or with foreign nations, or in any Territory of the United States or in the District of Columbia, or among the Territories or between any Territory and any State or foreign nation, or between the District of Columbia and any State or Territory or foreign nation. New automobiles delivered to, or for further delivery to, ultimate purchasers within the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Trust Territories of the Pacific, the Canal Zone, Wake Island, Midway Island, Kingman Reef, Johnson Island, or within any other place under the jurisdiction of the United States shall be deemed to have been distributed in commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–506, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 325</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–359</ref>, <date date="1972-07-28">July 28, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232.</num>
<heading> Label and entry requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Every manufacturer of new automobiles distributed in commerce shall, prior to the delivery of any new automobile to any dealer, or at or prior to the introduction date of new models delivered to a dealer prior to such introduction date, securely affix to the windshield, or side window of such automobile a label on which such manufacturer shall endorse clearly, distinctly and legibly true and correct entries disclosing the following information concerning such automobile—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> the make, model, and serial or identification number or numbers;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> the final assembly point;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> the name, and the location of the place of business, of the dealer to whom it is to be delivered;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> the name of the city or town at which it is to be delivered to such dealer;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> the method of transportation used in making delivery of such automobile, if driven or towed from final assembly point to place of delivery;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the retail price of such automobile suggested by the manufacturer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the retail delivered price suggested by the manufacturer for each accessory or item of optional equipment, physically attached to such automobile at the time of its delivery to such dealer, which is not included within the price of such automobile as stated pursuant to paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount charged, if any, to such dealer for the transportation of such automobile to the location at which it is delivered to such dealer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the total of the amounts specified pursuant to paragraphs (1), (2), and (3);</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> if one or more safety ratings for such automobile have been assigned and formally published or released by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration under the New Car Assessment Program, information about safety ratings that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> includes a graphic depiction of the number of stars, or other applicable rating, that corresponds to each such assigned safety rating displayed in a clearly differentiated fashion indicating the maximum possible safety rating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> refers to safety rating categories that may include frontal impact crash tests, side impact crash tests, and rollover resistance tests (whether or not such automobile has been assigned a safety rating for such tests);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> contains information describing the nature and meaning of the crash test data presented and a reference to additional vehicle safety resources, including http://www.safecar.gov; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002305">1</ref> and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> is presented in a legible, visible, and prominent fashion and covers at least—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent3">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 8 percent of the total area of the label; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an area with a minimum length of 4½ inches and a minimum height of 3½ inches; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> if an automobile has not been tested by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration under the New Car Assessment Program, or safety ratings for such automobile have not been assigned in one or more rating categories, a statement to that effect.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–506, § 3</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 326</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title X, § 10307(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title I, § 31314</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title IV, § 401(g)(7)(A)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 534</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1233.</num>
<heading> Violations and penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to affix required label</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any manufacturer of automobiles distributed in commerce who willfully fails to affix to any new automobile manufactured or imported by him the label required by <ref>section 1232 of this title</ref> shall be fined not more than $1,000. Such failure with respect to each automobile shall constitute a separate offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to endorse required label</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any manufacturer of automobiles distributed in commerce who willfully fails to endorse clearly, distinctly and legibly any label as required by <ref>section 1232 of this title</ref>, or who makes a false endorsement of any such label, shall be fined not more than $1,000. Such failure or false endorsement with respect to each automobile shall constitute a separate offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal, alteration, or illegibility of required label</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who willfully removes, alters, or renders illegible any label affixed to a new automobile pursuant to <ref>section 1232 of this title</ref>, or any endorsement thereon, prior to the time that such automobile is delivered to the actual custody and possession of the ultimate purchaser of such new automobile, except where the manufacturer relabels the automobile in the event the same is rerouted, repurchased, or reacquired by the manufacturer of such automobile, shall be fined not more than $1,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both. Such removal, alteration, or rendering illegible with respect to each automobile shall constitute a separate offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–506, § 4</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>