<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 94A—</num>
<heading>VISUAL DEPICTION PRIVACY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6851.</num>
<heading> Civil action relating to disclosure of intimate images</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial pornographic content</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “commercial pornographic content” means any material that is subject to the record keeping requirements under <ref>section 2257 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “consent” means an affirmative, conscious, and voluntary authorization made by the individual free from force, fraud, misrepresentation, or coercion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depicted individual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “depicted individual” means an individual whose body appears in whole or in part in an intimate visual depiction and who is identifiable by virtue of the person’s face, likeness, or other distinguishing characteristic, such as a unique birthmark or other recognizable feature, or from information displayed in connection with the visual depiction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “disclose” means to transfer, publish, distribute, or make accessible.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intimate visual depiction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “intimate visual depiction”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means a visual depiction, as that term is defined in <ref>section 2256(5) of title 18</ref>, that depicts—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the uncovered genitals, pubic area, anus, or post-pubescent female nipple of an identifiable individual; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the display or transfer of bodily sexual fluids—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> on to any part of the body of an identifiable individual;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> from the body of an identifiable individual; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> an identifiable individual engaging in sexually explicit conduct and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002561">1</ref></content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes any visual depictions described in subparagraph (A) produced while the identifiable individual was in a public place only if the individual did not—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> voluntarily display the content depicted; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> consent to the sexual conduct depicted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexually explicit conduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexually explicit conduct” has the meaning given the term in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <ref>section 2256(2) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of action</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (4), an individual whose intimate visual depiction is disclosed, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce or using any means or facility of interstate or foreign commerce, without the consent of the individual, where such disclosure was made by a person who knows that, or recklessly disregards whether, the individual has not consented to such disclosure, may bring a civil action against that person in an appropriate district court of the United States for relief as set forth in paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights on behalf of certain individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an individual who is under 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased, the legal guardian of the individual or representative of the identifiable individual’s estate, another family member, or any other person appointed as suitable by the court, may assume the identifiable individual’s’ <sup>1</sup> rights under this section, but in no event shall the defendant be named as such representative or guardian.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of an action under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the fact that the individual consented to the creation of the depiction shall not establish that the person consented to its distribution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the fact that the individual disclosed the intimate visual depiction to someone else shall not establish that the person consented to the further disclosure of the intimate visual depiction by the person alleged to have violated paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In a civil action filed under this section—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual may recover the actual damages sustained by the individual or liquidated damages in the amount of $150,000, and the cost of the action, including reasonable attorney’s fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the court may, in addition to any other relief available at law, order equitable relief, including a temporary restraining order, a preliminary injunction, or a permanent injunction ordering the defendant to cease display or disclosure of the visual depiction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation of anonymity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In ordering relief under subparagraph (A), the court may grant injunctive relief maintaining the confidentiality of a plaintiff using a pseudonym.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An identifiable individual may not bring an action for relief under this section relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an intimate image that is commercial pornographic content, unless that content was produced by force, fraud, misrepresentation, or coercion of the depicted individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a disclosure made in good faith—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to a law enforcement officer or agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as part of a legal proceeding;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> as part of medical education, diagnosis, or treatment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> in the reporting or investigation of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> unlawful content; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> unsolicited or unwelcome conduct;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a matter of public concern or public interest; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a disclosure reasonably intended to assist the identifiable individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIII, § 1309</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>