<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 106—</num>
<heading>POOL AND SPA SAFETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8001.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Of injury-related deaths, drowning is the second leading cause of death in children aged 1 to 14 in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In 2004, 761 children aged 14 and under died as a result of unintentional drowning.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Adult supervision at all aquatic venues is a critical safety factor in preventing children from drowning.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Research studies show that the installation and proper use of barriers or fencing, as well as additional layers of protection, could substantially reduce the number of childhood residential swimming pool drownings and near drownings.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1402</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8002.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> ASME/ANSI</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “ASME/ANSI” as applied to a safety standard means such a standard that is accredited by the American National Standards Institute and published by the American Society of Mechanical Engineers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Barrier</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “barrier” includes a natural or constructed topographical feature that prevents unpermitted access by children to a swimming pool, and, with respect to a hot tub, a lockable cover.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered entity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian Tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian Tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 5304(e) of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Main drain</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “main drain” means a submerged suction outlet typically located at the bottom of a pool or spa to conduct water to a recirculating pump.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safety vacuum release system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “safety vacuum release system” means a vacuum release system capable of providing vacuum release at a suction outlet caused by a high vacuum occurrence due to a suction outlet flow blockage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Swimming pool; spa</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “swimming pool” or “spa” means any outdoor or indoor structure intended for swimming or recreational bathing, including in-ground and above-ground structures, and includes hot tubs, spas, portable spas, and non-portable wading pools.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unblockable drain</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “unblockable drain” means a drain of any size and shape that a human body cannot sufficiently block to create a suction entrapment hazard.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2052(a) of this title</ref>, and includes the Northern Mariana Islands. For purposes of eligibility for the grants authorized under <ref>section 8004 of this title</ref>, such term shall also include any political subdivision of a State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1403</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1795</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 238(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3076</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–10, div. B, title V, § 1576(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-04-15">Apr. 15, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8003.</num>
<heading> Federal swimming pool and spa drain cover standard</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consumer product safety rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirements described in subsection (b) shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule issued by the Consumer Product Safety Commission under the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2051</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drain cover standard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective 1 year after <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>, each swimming pool or spa drain cover manufactured, distributed, or entered into commerce in the United States shall conform to the entrapment protection standards of the ASME/ANSI A112.19.8 performance standard, or any successor standard regulating such swimming pool or drain cover. If a successor standard is proposed, the American Society of Mechanical Engineers shall notify the Commission of the proposed revision. If the Commission determines that the proposed revision is in the public interest, it shall incorporate the revision into the standard after providing 30 days notice to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public pools</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required equipment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Beginning 1 year after <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> each public pool and spa in the United States shall be equipped with anti-entrapment devices or systems that comply with the ASME/ANSI A112.19.8 performance standard, or any successor standard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> each public pool and spa in the United States with a single main drain other than an unblockable drain shall be equipped, at a minimum, with 1 or more of the following devices or systems designed to prevent entrapment by pool or spa drains that meets the requirements of subparagraph (B):</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safety vacuum release system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">A safety vacuum release system which ceases operation of the pump, reverses the circulation flow, or otherwise provides a vacuum release at a suction outlet when a blockage is detected, that has been tested by an independent third party and found to conform to ASME/ANSI standard A112.19.17 or ASTM standard F2387.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suction-limiting vent system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">A suction-limiting vent system with a tamper-resistant atmospheric opening.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gravity drainage system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">A gravity drainage system that utilizes a collector tank.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(IV)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Automatic pump shut-off system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">An automatic pump shut-off system.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(V)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drain disablement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">A device or system that disables the drain.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(VI)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Any other system determined by the Commission to be equally effective as, or better than, the systems described in subclauses (I) through (V) of this clause at preventing or eliminating the risk of injury or death associated with pool drainage systems.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any device or system described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall meet the requirements of any ASME/ANSI or ASTM performance standard if there is such a standard for such a device or system, or any applicable consumer product safety standard.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public pool and spa defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “public pool and spa” means a swimming pool or spa that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> open to the public generally, whether for a fee or free of charge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> open exclusively to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> members of an organization and their guests;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> residents of a multi-unit apartment building, apartment complex, residential real estate development, or other multi-family residential area (other than a municipality, township, or other local government jurisdiction); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> patrons of a hotel or other public accommodations facility; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> operated by the Federal Government (or by a concessionaire on behalf of the Federal Government) for the benefit of members of the Armed Forces and their dependents or employees of any department or agency and their dependents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Violation of paragraph (1) shall be considered to be a violation of section 19(a)(1) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2068(a)(1)</ref>) and may also be enforced under section 17 of that Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2066</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1404</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1795</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 238(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3076</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8004.</num>
<heading> Swimming pool safety grant program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations authorized by subsection (e), the Commission shall carry out a grant program to provide assistance to eligible covered entities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for a grant under the program, a covered entity shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Commission that, as of the date on which the covered entity submits an application to the Commission for a grant under this section, the covered entity has enacted and provides for the enforcement of a statute that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in <ref>section 8005(a)(1)(A)(i) of this title</ref>, applies to all swimming pools constructed in the State or in the jurisdiction of the Indian Tribe (as the case may be) on or after such date; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meets the minimum State law requirements of <ref>section 8005 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit an application to the Commission at such time, in such form, and containing such additional information as the Commission may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of grant</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall determine the amount of a grant awarded under this section, and shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the population of the covered entity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the relative enforcement and implementation needs of the covered entity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> allocation of grant funds in a manner designed to provide the maximum benefit from the program in terms of protecting children from drowning or entrapment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of grant funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State or an Indian Tribe receiving a grant under this section shall use—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> at least 25 percent of amounts made available—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to hire and train personnel for implementation and enforcement of standards under the swimming pool and spa safety law of the State or Indian Tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to defray administrative costs associated with the hiring and training programs under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the remainder—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to educate pool owners, pool operators, and other members of the public about the standards under the swimming pool and spa safety law of the State or Indian Tribe and about the prevention of drowning or entrapment of children using swimming pools and spas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to defray administrative costs associated with the education programs under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission for fiscal year 2023 $2,500,000 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1405</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1796</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–10, div. B, title V, § 1576(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-04-15">Apr. 15, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. C, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. E, title V, § 501(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8005.</num>
<heading> Minimum State law requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safety standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State meets the minimum State law requirements of this section if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the State requires by statute—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the enclosure of all outdoor residential pools and spas by barriers to entry that will effectively prevent small children from gaining unsupervised and unfettered access to the pool or spa; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> that pools and spas built more than 1 year after the date of the enactment of such statute have—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> more than 1 drain;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 1 or more unblockable drains; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> no main drain; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the State meets such additional State law requirements for pools and spas as the Commission may establish after public notice and a 30-day public comment period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of minimum State law requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall use the minimum State law requirements under paragraph (1) solely for the purpose of determining the eligibility of a covered entity for a grant under <ref>section 8004 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not enforce any requirement under paragraph (1) except for the purpose of determining the eligibility of a covered entity for a grant under <ref>section 8004 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements to reflect national performance standards and Commission guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In establishing minimum State law requirements under paragraph (1)(B), the Commission shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consider current or revised national performance standards on pool and spa barrier protection and entrapment prevention; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that any such requirements are consistent with the guidelines contained in the Commission’s publication 362, entitled “Safety Barrier Guidelines for Home Pools”, the Commission’s publication entitled “Guidelines for Entrapment Hazards: Making Pools and Spas Safer”, and any other pool safety guidelines established by the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section prevents the Commission from promulgating standards regulating pool and spa safety or from relying on an applicable national performance standard.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basic access-related safety devices and equipment requirements to be considered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In establishing minimum State law requirements for swimming pools and spas under subsection (a)(1), the Commission shall consider the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A safety pool cover.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A gate with direct access to the swimming pool or spa that is equipped with a self-closing, self-latching device.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Doors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any door with direct access to the swimming pool or spa that is equipped with an audible alert device or alarm which sounds when the door is opened.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pool alarm</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A device designed to provide rapid detection of an entry into the water of a swimming pool or spa.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entrapment, entanglement, and evisceration prevention standards to be required</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In establishing additional minimum State law requirements for swimming pools and spas under subsection (a)(1), the Commission shall require, at a minimum, 1 or more of the following (except for pools constructed without a single main drain):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safety vacuum release system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A safety vacuum release system which ceases operation of the pump, reverses the circulation flow, or otherwise provides a vacuum release at a suction outlet when a blockage is detected, that has been tested by an independent third party and found to conform to ASME/ANSI standard A112.19.17 or ASTM standard F2387, or any successor standard.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suction-limiting vent system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A suction-limiting vent system with a tamper-resistant atmospheric opening.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gravity drainage system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A gravity drainage system that utilizes a collector tank.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Automatic pump shut-off system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An automatic pump shut-off system.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drain disablement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A device or system that disables the drain.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any other system determined by the Commission to be equally effective as, or better than, the systems described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of this paragraph at preventing or eliminating the risk of injury or death associated with pool drainage systems.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any device or system described in subparagraphs (B) through (E) of paragraph (1) shall meet the requirements of any ASME/ANSI or ASTM performance standard if there is such a standard for such a device or system, or any applicable consumer product safety standard.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “State” includes an Indian Tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1406</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1797</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. E, title V, § 501(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8006.</num>
<heading> Education and awareness program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall establish and carry out an education and awareness program to inform the public of methods to prevent drowning and entrapment in swimming pools and spas. In carrying out the program, the Commission shall develop—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> educational materials designed for swimming pool and spa manufacturers, service companies, and supply retail outlets, including guidance on barrier and drain cover inspection, maintenance, and replacement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> educational materials designed for swimming pool and spa owners and operators, consumers, States, and Indian Tribes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a national media campaign to promote awareness of swimming pool and spa safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission for fiscal year 2023 $2,500,000 to carry out the education and awareness program authorized by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1407</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1799</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8007.</num>
<heading> CPSC report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the last day of each fiscal year for which grants are made under <ref>section 8004 of this title</ref>, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report evaluating the implementation of the grant program authorized by that section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1408</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8008.</num>
<heading> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002579">1</ref> is applicable to the United States and its territories, including American Samoa, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the United States Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title XIV, § 1409</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 238(3)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3076</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>