<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 91A—</num>
<heading>PROMOTING A SAFE INTERNET FOR CHILDREN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6551.</num>
<heading> Internet safety</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, the issue of Internet safety includes issues regarding the use of the Internet in a manner that promotes safe online activity for children, protects children from cybercrimes, including crimes by online predators, and helps parents shield their children from material that is inappropriate for minors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–385, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6552.</num>
<heading> Public awareness campaign</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission shall carry out a nationwide program to increase public awareness and provide education regarding strategies to promote the safe use of the Internet by children. The program shall utilize existing resources and efforts of the Federal Government, State and local governments, nonprofit organizations, private technology and financial companies, Internet service providers, World Wide Web-based resources, and other appropriate entities, that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identifying, promoting, and encouraging best practices for Internet safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establishing and carrying out a national outreach and education campaign regarding Internet safety utilizing various media and Internet-based resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitating access to, and the exchange of, information regarding Internet safety to promote up-to-date knowledge regarding current issues; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> facilitating access to Internet safety education and public awareness efforts the Commission considers appropriate by States, units of local government, schools, police departments, nonprofit organizations, and other appropriate entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–385, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6553.</num>
<heading> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives not later than March 31 of each year that describes the activities carried out under section 6552 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002548">1</ref> of this title by the Commission during the preceding calendar year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–385, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6554.</num>
<heading> Online Safety and Technology working group</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 90 days after <date date="2008-10-10">October 10, 2008</date>, the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information shall establish an Online Safety and Technology working group comprised of representatives of relevant sectors of the business community, public interest groups, and other appropriate groups and Federal agencies to review and evaluate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the status of industry efforts to promote online safety through educational efforts, parental control technology, blocking and filtering software, age-appropriate labels for content or other technologies or initiatives designed to promote a safe online environment for children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the status of industry efforts to promote online safety among providers of electronic communications services and remote computing services by reporting apparent child pornography under section 13032 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002549">1</ref> of title 42, including any obstacles to such reporting;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the practices of electronic communications service providers and remote computing service providers related to record retention in connection with crimes against children; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the development of technologies to help parents shield their children from inappropriate material on the Internet.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 1 year after the working group is first convened, it shall submit a report to the Assistant Secretary, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes in detail its findings, including any information related to the effectiveness of such strategies and technologies and any information about the prevalence within industry of educational campaigns, parental control technologies, blocking and filtering software, labeling, or other technologies to assist parents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes recommendations as to what types of incentives could be used or developed to increase the effectiveness and implementation of such strategies and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chapter 10 of title 5 not to apply to working group</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the working group.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–385, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(76)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6555.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the Federal Trade Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Internet</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Internet” means collectively the myriad of computer and telecommunications facilities, including equipment and operating software, which comprise the interconnected world-wide network of networks that employ the Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol, or any predecessor successor <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002550">1</ref> protocols to such protocol, to communicate information of all kinds by wire or radio.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–385, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4104</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>