<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>MONOPOLIES AND COMBINATIONS IN RESTRAINT OF TRADE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1.</num>
<heading> Trusts, etc., in restraint of trade illegal; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every contract, combination in the form of trust or otherwise, or conspiracy, in restraint of trade or commerce among the several States, or with foreign nations, is declared to be illegal. Every person who shall make any contract or engage in any combination or conspiracy hereby declared to be illegal shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and, on conviction thereof, shall be punished by fine not exceeding $100,000,000 if a corporation, or, if any other person, $1,000,000, or by imprisonment not exceeding 10 years, or by both said punishments, in the discretion of the court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 1</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Aug. 17, 1937, ch. 690</ref>, title VIII, <ref>50 Stat. 693</ref>; <ref>July 7, 1955, ch. 281</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–528, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–145, § 2</ref>, <date date="1975-12-12">Dec. 12, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 801</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–588, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 215(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-06-22">June 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2.</num>
<heading> Monopolizing trade a felony; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person who shall monopolize, or attempt to monopolize, or combine or conspire with any other person or persons, to monopolize any part of the trade or commerce among the several States, or with foreign nations, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and, on conviction thereof, shall be punished by fine not exceeding $100,000,000 if a corporation, or, if any other person, $1,000,000, or by imprisonment not exceeding 10 years, or by both said punishments, in the discretion of the court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 2</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>July 7, 1955, ch. 281</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–528, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–588, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 215(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-06-22">June 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3.</num>
<heading> Trusts in Territories or District of Columbia illegal; combination a felony</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Every contract, combination in form of trust or otherwise, or conspiracy, in restraint of trade or commerce in any Territory of the United States or of the District of Columbia, or in restraint of trade or commerce between any such Territory and another, or between any such Territory or Territories and any State or States or the District of Columbia, or with foreign nations, or between the District of Columbia and any State or States or foreign nations, is declared illegal. Every person who shall make any such contract or engage in any such combination or conspiracy, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and, on conviction thereof, shall be punished by fine not exceeding $100,000,000 if a corporation, or, if any other person, $1,000,000, or by imprisonment not exceeding 10 years, or by both said punishments, in the discretion of the court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Every person who shall monopolize, or attempt to monopolize, or combine or conspire with any other person or persons, to monopolize any part of the trade or commerce in any Territory of the United States or of the District of Columbia, or between any such Territory and another, or between any such Territory or Territories and any State or States or the District of Columbia, or with foreign nations, or between the District of Columbia, and any State or States or foreign nations, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and, on conviction thereof, shall be punished by fine not exceeding $100,000,000 if a corporation, or, if any other person, $1,000,000, or by imprisonment not exceeding 10 years, or by both said punishments, in the discretion of the court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 3</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>July 7, 1955, ch. 281</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–528, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–588, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title IV, § 14102(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 215(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-06-22">June 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction of courts; duty of United States attorneys; procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The several district courts of the United States are invested with jurisdiction to prevent and restrain violations of sections 1 to 7 of this title; and it shall be the duty of the several United States attorneys, in their respective districts, under the direction of the Attorney General, to institute proceedings in equity to prevent and restrain such violations. Such proceedings may be by way of petition setting forth the case and praying that such violation shall be enjoined or otherwise prohibited. When the parties complained of shall have been duly notified of such petition the court shall proceed, as soon as may be, to the hearing and determination of the case; and pending such petition and before final decree, the court may at any time make such temporary restraining order or prohibition as shall be deemed just in the premises.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 4</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 291</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 1167</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5.</num>
<heading> Bringing in additional parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever it shall appear to the court before which any proceeding under <ref>section 4 of this title</ref> may be pending, that the ends of justice require that other parties should be brought before the court, the court may cause them to be summoned, whether they reside in the district in which the court is held or not; and subpoenas to that end may be served in any district by the marshal thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 5</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture of property in transit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any property owned under any contract or by any combination, or pursuant to any conspiracy (and being the subject thereof) mentioned in <ref>section 1 of this title</ref>, and being in the course of transportation from one State to another, or to a foreign country, shall be forfeited to the United States, and may be seized and condemned by like proceedings as those provided by law for the forfeiture, seizure, and condemnation of property imported into the United States contrary to law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 6</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6a.</num>
<heading> Conduct involving trade or commerce with foreign nations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Sections 1 to 7 of this title shall not apply to conduct involving trade or commerce (other than import trade or import commerce) with foreign nations unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> such conduct has a direct, substantial, and reasonably foreseeable effect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on trade or commerce which is not trade or commerce with foreign nations, or on import trade or import commerce with foreign nations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on export trade or export commerce with foreign nations, of a person engaged in such trade or commerce in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such effect gives rise to a claim under the provisions of sections 1 to 7 of this title, other than this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If sections 1 to 7 of this title apply to such conduct only because of the operation of paragraph (1)(B), then sections 1 to 7 of this title shall apply to such conduct only for injury to export business in the United States.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–290, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1982-10-08">Oct. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7.</num>
<heading> “Person” or “persons” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The word “person”, or “persons”, wherever used in sections 1 to 7 of this title shall be deemed to include corporations and associations existing under or authorized by the laws of either the United States, the laws of any of the Territories, the laws of any State, or the laws of any foreign country.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1890, ch. 647, § 8</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7a.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In sections 7a to 7a–3 of this title:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Antitrust Division</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Antitrust Division” means the United States Department of Justice Antitrust Division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Antitrust leniency agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “antitrust leniency agreement,” or “agreement,” means a leniency letter agreement, whether conditional or final, between a person and the Antitrust Division pursuant to the Corporate Leniency Policy of the Antitrust Division in effect on the date of execution of the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Antitrust leniency applicant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “antitrust leniency applicant,” or “applicant,” means, with respect to an antitrust leniency agreement, the person that has entered into the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claimant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “claimant” means a person or class, that has brought, or on whose behalf has been brought, a civil action alleging a violation of section 1 or 3 of this title or any similar State law, except that the term does not include a State or a subdivision of a State with respect to a civil action brought to recover damages sustained by the State or subdivision.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperating individual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cooperating individual” means, with respect to an antitrust leniency agreement, a current or former director, officer, or employee of the antitrust leniency applicant who is covered by the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2004-06-22">June 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–190, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-06-09">June 9, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–159, div. D, title III, § 4303(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-01">Oct. 1, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 742</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7a–1.</num>
<heading> Limitation on recovery</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (d), in any civil action alleging a violation of section 1 or 3 of this title, or alleging a violation of any similar State law, based on conduct covered by a currently effective antitrust leniency agreement, the amount of damages recovered by or on behalf of a claimant from an antitrust leniency applicant who satisfies the requirements of subsection (b), together with the amounts so recovered from cooperating individuals who satisfy such requirements, shall not exceed that portion of the actual damages sustained by such claimant which is attributable to the commerce done by the applicant in the goods or services affected by the violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c), an antitrust leniency applicant or cooperating individual satisfies the requirements of this subsection with respect to a civil action described in subsection (a) if the court in which the civil action is brought determines, after considering any appropriate pleadings from the claimant, that the applicant or cooperating individual, as the case may be, has provided satisfactory cooperation to the claimant with respect to the civil action, which cooperation shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> providing a full account to the claimant of all facts known to the applicant or cooperating individual, as the case may be, that are potentially relevant to the civil action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> furnishing all documents or other items potentially relevant to the civil action that are in the possession, custody, or control of the applicant or cooperating individual, as the case may be, wherever they are located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a cooperating individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> making himself or herself available for such interviews, depositions, or testimony in connection with the civil action as the claimant may reasonably require; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> responding completely and truthfully, without making any attempt either falsely to protect or falsely to implicate any person or entity, and without intentionally withholding any potentially relevant information, to all questions asked by the claimant in interviews, depositions, trials, or any other court proceedings in connection with the civil action; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an antitrust leniency applicant, using its best efforts to secure and facilitate from cooperating individuals covered by the agreement the cooperation described in clauses (i) and (ii) and subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timeliness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The court shall consider, in making the determination concerning satisfactory cooperation described in subsection (b), the timeliness of the applicant’s or cooperating individual’s cooperation with the claimant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation after expiration of stay or protective order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Antitrust Division does obtain a stay or protective order in a civil action based on conduct covered by an antitrust leniency agreement, once the stay or protective order, or a portion thereof, expires or is terminated, the antitrust leniency applicant and cooperating individuals shall provide without unreasonable delay any cooperation described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) that was prohibited by the expired or terminated stay or protective order, or the expired or terminated portion thereof, in order for the cooperation to be deemed satisfactory under such paragraphs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify, impair, or supersede the provisions of sections 15, 15a, and 15c of this title relating to the recovery of costs of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, and interest on damages, to the extent that such recovery is authorized by such sections.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2004-06-22">June 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–190, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-06-09">June 9, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1275</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7a–2.</num>
<heading> Rights, authorities, and liabilities not affected</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in sections 7a to 7a–3 of this title shall be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> affect the rights of the Antitrust Division to seek a stay or protective order in a civil action based on conduct covered by an antitrust leniency agreement to prevent the cooperation described in <ref>section 7a–1(b) of this title</ref> from impairing or impeding the investigation or prosecution by the Antitrust Division of conduct covered by the agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> create any right to challenge any decision by the Antitrust Division with respect to an antitrust leniency agreement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> affect, in any way, the joint and several liability of any party to a civil action described in <ref>section 7a–1(a) of this title</ref>, other than that of the antitrust leniency applicant and cooperating individuals as provided in <ref>section 7a–1(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2004-06-22">June 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–190, § 4</ref>, <date date="2010-06-09">June 9, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7a–3.</num>
<heading> Anti-retaliation protection for whistleblowers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Whistleblower protections for employees, contractors, subcontractors, and agents</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No employer may discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, harass, or in any other manner discriminate against a covered individual in the terms and conditions of employment of the covered individual because of any lawful act done by the covered individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to provide or cause to be provided to the Federal Government or a person with supervisory authority over the covered individual (or such other person working for the employer who has the authority to investigate, discover, or terminate misconduct) information relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any violation of, or any act or omission the covered individual reasonably believes to be a violation of, the antitrust laws; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any violation of, or any act or omission the covered individual reasonably believes to be a violation of, another criminal law committed in conjunction with a potential violation of the antitrust laws or in conjunction with an investigation by the Department of Justice of a potential violation of the antitrust laws; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to cause to be filed, testify in, participate in, or otherwise assist a Federal Government investigation or a Federal Government proceeding filed or about to be filed (with any knowledge of the employer) relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any violation of, or any act or omission the covered individual reasonably believes to be a violation of, the antitrust laws; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any violation of, or any act or omission the covered individual reasonably believes to be a violation of, another criminal law committed in conjunction with a potential violation of the antitrust laws or in conjunction with an investigation by the Department of Justice of a potential violation of the antitrust laws.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on protections</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any covered individual if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the covered individual planned and initiated a violation or attempted violation of the antitrust laws;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the covered individual planned and initiated a violation or attempted violation of another criminal law in conjunction with a violation or attempted violation of the antitrust laws; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the covered individual planned and initiated an obstruction or attempted obstruction of an investigation by the Department of Justice of a violation of the antitrust laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Antitrust laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “antitrust laws” means section 1 or 3 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered individual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “covered individual” means an employee, contractor, subcontractor, or agent of an employer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “employer” means a person, or any officer, employee, contractor, subcontractor, or agent of such person.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Government</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “Federal Government” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a Federal regulatory or law enforcement agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any Member of Congress or committee of Congress.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “person” has the same meaning as in subsection (a) of <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “violation”, with respect to the antitrust laws, shall not be construed to include a civil violation of any law that is not also a criminal violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A covered individual who alleges discharge or other discrimination by any employer in violation of subsection (a) may seek relief under subsection (c) by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Secretary of Labor has not issued a final decision within 180 days of the filing of the complaint and there is no showing that such delay is due to the bad faith of the claimant, bringing an action at law or equity for de novo review in the appropriate district court of the United States, which shall have jurisdiction over such an action without regard to the amount in controversy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A complaint filed with the Secretary of Labor under paragraph (1)(A) shall be governed under the rules and procedures set forth in <ref>section 42121(b) of title 49</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notification made under <ref>section 42121(b)(1) of title 49</ref> shall be made to any individual named in the complaint and to the employer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Burdens of proof</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An action brought under paragraph (1)(B) shall be governed by the legal burdens of proof set forth in <ref>section 42121(b) of title 49</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statute of limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A complaint under paragraph (1)(A) shall be filed with the Secretary of Labor not later than 180 days after the date on which the violation occurs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil actions to enforce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a person fails to comply with an order or preliminary order issued by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to the procedures set forth in <ref>section 42121(b) of title 49</ref>, the Secretary of Labor or the person on whose behalf the order was issued may bring a civil action to enforce the order in the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the violation occurred.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A covered individual prevailing in any action under subsection (b)(1) shall be entitled to all relief necessary to make the covered individual whole.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensatory damages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Relief for any action under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reinstatement with the same seniority status that the covered individual would have had, but for the discrimination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of back pay, with interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compensation for any special damages sustained as a result of the discrimination including litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable attorney’s fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights retained by whistleblowers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any covered individual under any Federal or State law, or under any collective bargaining agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 216</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–257, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8.</num>
<heading> Trusts in restraint of import trade illegal; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every combination, conspiracy, trust, agreement, or contract is declared to be contrary to public policy, illegal, and void when the same is made by or between two or more persons or corporations, either of whom, as agent or principal, is engaged in importing any article from any foreign country into the United States, and when such combination, conspiracy, trust, agreement, or contract is intended to operate in restraint of lawful trade, or free competition in lawful trade or commerce, or to increase the market price in any part of the United States of any article or articles imported or intended to be imported into the United States, or of any manufacture into which such imported article enters or is intended to enter. Every person who shall be engaged in the importation of goods or any commodity from any foreign country in violation of this section, or who shall combine or conspire with another to violate the same, is guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof in any court of the United States such person shall be fined in a sum not less than $100 and not exceeding $5,000, and shall be further punished by imprisonment, in the discretion of the court, for a term not less than three months nor exceeding twelve months.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349, § 73</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 570</ref>; <ref>Feb. 12, 1913, ch. 40</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction of courts; duty of United States attorneys; procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The several district courts of the United States are invested with jurisdiction to prevent and restrain violations of <ref>section 8 of this title</ref>; and it shall be the duty of the several United States attorneys, in their respective districts, under the direction of the Attorney General, to institute proceedings in equity to prevent and restrain such violations. Such proceedings may be by way of petitions setting forth the case and praying that such violations shall be enjoined or otherwise prohibited. When the parties complained of shall have been duly notified of such petition the court shall proceed, as soon as may be, to the hearing and determination of the case; and pending such petition and before final decree, the court may at any time make such temporary restraining order or prohibition as shall be deemed just in the premises.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349, § 74</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 570</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 291</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 1167</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10.</num>
<heading> Bringing in additional parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever it shall appear to the court before which any proceeding under <ref>section 9 of this title</ref> may be pending, that the ends of justice require that other parties should be brought before the court, the court may cause them to be summoned, whether they reside in the district in which the court is held or not; and subpoenas to that end may be served in any district by the marshal thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349, § 75</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture of property in transit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any property owned under any contract or by any combination, or pursuant to any conspiracy, and being the subject thereof, mentioned in <ref>section 8 of this title</ref>, imported into and being within the United States or being in the course of transportation from one State to another, or to or from a Territory or the District of Columbia, shall be forfeited to the United States, and may be seized and condemned by like proceedings as those provided by law for the forfeiture, seizure, and condemnation of property imported into the United States contrary to law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349, § 76</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 570</ref>; <ref>Feb. 12, 1913, ch. 40</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12.</num>
<heading> Definitions; short title</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> “Antitrust laws,” as used herein, includes the Act entitled “An Act to protect trade and commerce against unlawful restraints and monopolies,” approved July second, eighteen hundred and ninety; sections seventy-three to seventy-six, inclusive, of an Act entitled “An Act to reduce taxation, to provide revenue for the Government, and for other purposes,” of August twenty-seventh, eighteen hundred and ninety-four; an Act entitled “An Act to amend sections seventy-three and seventy-six of the Act of August twenty-seventh, eighteen hundred and ninety-four, entitled ‘An Act to reduce taxation, to provide revenue for the Government, and for other purposes,’ ” approved February twelfth, nineteen hundred and thirteen; and also this Act.<p class="indent0">“Commerce,” as used herein, means trade or commerce among the several States and with foreign nations, or between the District of Columbia or any Territory of the United States and any State, Territory, or foreign nation, or between any insular possessions or other places under the jurisdiction of the United States, or between any such possession or place and any State or Territory of the United States or the District of Columbia or any foreign nation, or within the District of Columbia or any Territory or any insular possession or other place under the jurisdiction of the United States: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this Act contained shall apply to the Philippine Islands.</p>
<p class="indent0">The word “person” or “persons” wherever used in this Act shall be deemed to include corporations and associations existing under or authorized by the laws of either the United States, the laws of any of the Territories, the laws of any State, or the laws of any foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This Act may be cited as the “Clayton Act”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 1</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 305(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title IV, § 14102(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13.</num>
<heading> Discrimination in price, services, or facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Price; selection of customers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in commerce, in the course of such commerce, either directly or indirectly, to discriminate in price between different purchasers of commodities of like grade and quality, where either or any of the purchases involved in such discrimination are in commerce, where such commodities are sold for use, consumption, or resale within the United States or any Territory thereof or the District of Columbia or any insular possession or other place under the jurisdiction of the United States, and where the effect of such discrimination may be substantially to lessen competition or tend to create a monopoly in any line of commerce, or to injure, destroy, or prevent competition with any person who either grants or knowingly receives the benefit of such discrimination, or with customers of either of them: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein contained shall prevent differentials which make only due allowance for differences in the cost of manufacture, sale, or delivery resulting from the differing methods or quantities in which such commodities are to such purchasers sold or delivered: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the Federal Trade Commission may, after due investigation and hearing to all interested parties, fix and establish quantity limits, and revise the same as it finds necessary, as to particular commodities or classes of commodities, where it finds that available purchasers in greater quantities are so few as to render differentials on account thereof unjustly discriminatory or promotive of monopoly in any line of commerce; and the foregoing shall then not be construed to permit differentials based on differences in quantities greater than those so fixed and established: <i>And provided further</i>, That nothing herein contained shall prevent persons engaged in selling goods, wares, or merchandise in commerce from selecting their own customers in bona fide transactions and not in restraint of trade: <i>And provided further</i>, That nothing herein contained shall prevent price changes from time to time where in response to changing conditions affecting the market for or the marketability of the goods concerned, such as but not limited to actual or imminent deterioration of perishable goods, obsolescence of seasonal goods, distress sales under court process, or sales in good faith in discontinuance of business in the goods concerned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Burden of rebutting prima-facie case of discrimination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon proof being made, at any hearing on a complaint under this section, that there has been discrimination in price or services or facilities furnished, the burden of rebutting the prima-facie case thus made by showing justification shall be upon the person charged with a violation of this section, and unless justification shall be affirmatively shown, the Commission is authorized to issue an order terminating the discrimination: <i>Provided, however</i>, That nothing herein contained shall prevent a seller rebutting the prima-facie case thus made by showing that his lower price or the furnishing of services or facilities to any purchaser or purchasers was made in good faith to meet an equally low price of a competitor, or the services or facilities furnished by a competitor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment or acceptance of commission, brokerage, or other compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in commerce, in the course of such commerce, to pay or grant, or to receive or accept, anything of value as a commission, brokerage, or other compensation, or any allowance or discount in lieu thereof, except for services rendered in connection with the sale or purchase of goods, wares, or merchandise, either to the other party to such transaction or to an agent, representative, or other intermediary therein where such intermediary is acting in fact for or in behalf, or is subject to the direct or indirect control, of any party to such transaction other than the person by whom such compensation is so granted or paid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment for services or facilities for processing or sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in commerce to pay or contact for the payment of anything of value to or for the benefit of a customer of such person in the course of such commerce as compensation or in consideration for any services or facilities furnished by or through such customer in connection with the processing, handling, sale, or offering for sale of any products or commodities manufactured, sold, or offered for sale by such person, unless such payment or consideration is available on proportionally equal terms to all other customers competing in the distribution of such products or commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Furnishing services or facilities for processing, handling, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to discriminate in favor of one purchaser against another purchaser or purchasers of a commodity bought for resale, with or without processing, by contracting to furnish or furnishing, or by contributing to the furnishing of, any services or facilities connected with the processing, handling, sale, or offering for sale of such commodity so purchased upon terms not accorded to all purchasers on proportionally equal terms.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowingly inducing or receiving discriminatory price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in commerce, in the course of such commerce, knowingly to induce or receive a discrimination in price which is prohibited by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 2</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref>June 19, 1936, ch. 592, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1526</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13a.</num>
<heading> Discrimination in rebates, discounts, or advertising service charges; underselling in particular localities; penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in commerce, in the course of such commerce, to be a party to, or assist in, any transaction of sale, or contract to sell, which discriminates to his knowledge against competitors of the purchaser, in that, any discount, rebate, allowance, or advertising service charge is granted to the purchaser over and above any discount, rebate, allowance, or advertising service charge available at the time of such transaction to said competitors in respect of a sale of goods of like grade, quality, and quantity; to sell, or contract to sell, goods in any part of the United States at prices lower than those exacted by said person elsewhere in the United States for the purpose of destroying competition, or eliminating a competitor in such part of the United States; or, to sell, or contract to sell, goods at unreasonably low prices for the purpose of destroying competition or eliminating a competitor.</p>
<p class="indent0">Any person violating any of the provisions of this section shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 19, 1936, ch. 592, § 3</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13b.</num>
<heading> Cooperative association; return of net earnings or surplus</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall prevent a cooperative association from returning to its members, producers, or consumers the whole, or any part of, the net earnings or surplus resulting from its trading operations, in proportion to their purchases or sales from, to, or through the association.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 19, 1936, ch. 592, § 4</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13c.</num>
<heading> Exemption of non-profit institutions from price discrimination provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in the Act approved <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, known as the Robinson-Patman Antidiscrimination Act, shall apply to purchases of their supplies for their own use by schools, colleges, universities, public libraries, churches, hospitals, and charitable institutions not operated for profit.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 26, 1938, ch. 283</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14.</num>
<heading> Sale, etc., on agreement not to use goods of competitor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in commerce, in the course of such commerce, to lease or make a sale or contract for sale of goods, wares, merchandise, machinery, supplies, or other commodities, whether patented or unpatented, for use, consumption, or resale within the United States or any Territory thereof or the District of Columbia or any insular possession or other place under the jurisdiction of the United States, or fix a price charged therefor, or discount from, or rebate upon, such price, on the condition, agreement, or understanding that the lessee or purchaser thereof shall not use or deal in the goods, wares, merchandise, machinery, supplies, or other commodities of a competitor or competitors of the lessor or seller, where the effect of such lease, sale, or contract for sale or such condition, agreement, or understanding may be to substantially lessen competition or tend to create a monopoly in any line of commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 3</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 731</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15.</num>
<heading> Suits by persons injured</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of recovery; prejudgment interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), any person who shall be injured in his business or property by reason of anything forbidden in the antitrust laws may sue therefor in any district court of the United States in the district in which the defendant resides or is found or has an agent, without respect to the amount in controversy, and shall recover threefold the damages by him sustained, and the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee. The court may award under this section, pursuant to a motion by such person promptly made, simple interest on actual damages for the period beginning on the date of service of such person’s pleading setting forth a claim under the antitrust laws and ending on the date of judgment, or for any shorter period therein, if the court finds that the award of such interest for such period is just in the circumstances. In determining whether an award of interest under this section for any period is just in the circumstances, the court shall consider only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether such person or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, made motions or asserted claims or defenses so lacking in merit as to show that such party or representative acted intentionally for delay, or otherwise acted in bad faith;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether, in the course of the action involved, such person or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, violated any applicable rule, statute, or court order providing for sanctions for dilatory behavior or otherwise providing for expeditious proceedings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whether such person or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, engaged in conduct primarily for the purpose of delaying the litigation or increasing the cost thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of damages payable to foreign states and instrumentalities of foreign states</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), any person who is a foreign state may not recover under subsection (a) an amount in excess of the actual damages sustained by it and the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a foreign state if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such foreign state would be denied, under <ref>section 1605(a)(2) of title 28</ref>, immunity in a case in which the action is based upon a commercial activity, or an act, that is the subject matter of its claim under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such foreign state waives all defenses based upon or arising out of its status as a foreign state, to any claims brought against it in the same action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such foreign state engages primarily in commercial activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such foreign state does not function, with respect to the commercial activity, or the act, that is the subject matter of its claim under this section as a procurement entity for itself or for another foreign state.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “commercial activity” shall have the meaning given it in <ref>section 1603(d) of title 28</ref>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “foreign state” shall have the meaning given it in <ref>section 1603(a) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–349, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-12">Sept. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1156</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–393</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15a.</num>
<heading> Suits by United States; amount of recovery; prejudgment interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the United States is hereafter injured in its business or property by reason of anything forbidden in the antitrust laws it may sue therefor in the United States district court for the district in which the defendant resides or is found or has an agent, without respect to the amount in controversy, and shall recover threefold the damages by it sustained and the cost of suit. The court may award under this section, pursuant to a motion by the United States promptly made, simple interest on actual damages for the period beginning on the date of service of the pleading of the United States setting forth a claim under the antitrust laws and ending on the date of judgment, or for any shorter period therein, if the court finds that the award of such interest for such period is just in the circumstances. In determining whether an award of interest under this section for any period is just in the circumstances, the court shall consider only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether the United States or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, made motions or asserted claims or defenses so lacking in merit as to show that such party or representative acted intentionally for delay or otherwise acted in bad faith;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether, in the course of the action involved, the United States or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, violated any applicable rule, statute, or court order providing for sanctions for dilatory behavior or otherwise providing for expeditious proceedings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whether the United States or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, engaged in conduct primarily for the purpose of delaying the litigation or increasing the cost thereof; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> whether the award of such interest is necessary to compensate the United States adequately for the injury sustained by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4A</ref>, as added <ref>July 7, 1955, ch. 283, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 282</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–349, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-12">Sept. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1156</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–588, § 5</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2880</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15b.</num>
<heading> Limitation of actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any action to enforce any cause of action under section 15, 15a, or 15c of this title shall be forever barred unless commenced within four years after the cause of action accrued. No cause of action barred under existing law on the effective date of this Act shall be revived by this Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4B</ref>, as added <ref>July 7, 1955, ch. 283, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 283</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 302(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15c.</num>
<heading> Actions by State attorneys general</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parens patriae; monetary relief; damages; prejudgment interest</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any attorney general of a State may bring a civil action in the name of such State, as parens patriae on behalf of natural persons residing in such State, in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the defendant, to secure monetary relief as provided in this section for injury sustained by such natural persons to their property by reason of any violation of sections 1 to 7 of this title. The court shall exclude from the amount of monetary relief awarded in such action any amount of monetary relief (A) which duplicates amounts which have been awarded for the same injury, or (B) which is properly allocable to (i) natural persons who have excluded their claims pursuant to subsection (b)(2) of this section, and (ii) any business entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall award the State as monetary relief threefold the total damage sustained as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, and the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee. The court may award under this paragraph, pursuant to a motion by such State promptly made, simple interest on the total damage for the period beginning on the date of service of such State’s pleading setting forth a claim under the antitrust laws and ending on the date of judgment, or for any shorter period therein, if the court finds that the award of such interest for such period is just in the circumstances. In determining whether an award of interest under this paragraph for any period is just in the circumstances, the court shall consider only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether such State or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, made motions or asserted claims or defenses so lacking in merit as to show that such party or representative acted intentionally for delay or otherwise acted in bad faith;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether, in the course of the action involved, such State or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, violated any applicable rule, statute, or court order providing for sanctions for dilatory behavior or other wise providing for expeditious proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether such State or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, engaged in conduct primarily for the purpose of delaying the litigation or increasing the cost thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice; exclusion election; final judgment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any action brought under subsection (a)(1) of this section, the State attorney general shall, at such times, in such manner, and with such content as the court may direct, cause notice thereof to be given by publication. If the court finds that notice given solely by publication would deny due process of law to any person or persons, the court may direct further notice to such person or persons according to the circumstances of the case.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person on whose behalf an action is brought under subsection (a)(1) may elect to exclude from adjudication the portion of the State claim for monetary relief attributable to him by filing notice of such election with the court within such time as specified in the notice given pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The final judgment in an action under subsection (a)(1) shall be res judicata as to any claim under <ref>section 15 of this title</ref> by any person on behalf of whom such action was brought and who fails to give such notice within the period specified in the notice given pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dismissal or compromise of action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An action under subsection (a)(1) shall not be dismissed or compromised without the approval of the court, and notice of any proposed dismissal or compromise shall be given in such manner as the court directs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorneys’ fees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any action under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount of the plaintiffs’ attorney’s fee, if any, shall be determined by the court; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the court may, in its discretion, award a reasonable attorney’s fee to a prevailing defendant upon a finding that the State attorney general has acted in bad faith, vexatiously, wantonly, or for oppressive reasons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4C</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1394</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–349, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-12">Sept. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15d.</num>
<heading> Measurement of damages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any action under <ref>section 15c(a)(1) of this title</ref>, in which there has been a determination that a defendant agreed to fix prices in violation of sections 1 to 7 of this title, damages may be proved and assessed in the aggregate by statistical or sampling methods, by the computation of illegal overcharges, or by such other reasonable system of estimating aggregate damages as the court in its discretion may permit without the necessity of separately proving the individual claim of, or amount of damage to, persons on whose behalf the suit was brought.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4D</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15e.</num>
<heading> Distribution of damages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Monetary relief recovered in an action under <ref>section 15c(a)(1) of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be distributed in such manner as the district court in its discretion may authorize; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be deemed a civil penalty by the court and deposited with the State as general revenues;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">subject in either case to the requirement that any distribution procedure adopted afford each person a reasonable opportunity to secure his appropriate portion of the net monetary relief.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4E</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15f.</num>
<heading> Actions by Attorney General</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to State attorney general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Attorney General of the United States has brought an action under the antitrust laws, and he has reason to believe that any State attorney general would be entitled to bring an action under this Act based substantially on the same alleged violation of the antitrust laws, he shall promptly give written notification thereof to such State attorney general.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of files and other materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist a State attorney general in evaluating the notice or in bringing any action under this Act, the Attorney General of the United States shall, upon request by such State attorney general, make available to him, to the extent permitted by law, any investigative files or other materials which are or may be relevant or material to the actual or potential cause of action under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4F</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15g.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of sections 15c, 15d, 15e, and 15f of this title:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “State attorney general” means the chief legal officer of a State, or any other person authorized by State law to bring actions under <ref>section 15c of this title</ref>, and includes the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia, except that such term does not include any person employed or retained on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a contingency fee based on a percentage of the monetary relief awarded under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other contingency fee basis, unless the amount of the award of a reasonable attorney’s fee to a prevailing plaintiff is determined by the court under <ref>section 15c(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “natural persons” does not include proprietorships or partnerships.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4G</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15h.</num>
<heading> Applicability of parens patriae actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 15c, 15d, 15e, 15f, and 15g of this title shall apply in any State, unless such State provides by law for its nonapplicability in such State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 4H</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16.</num>
<heading> Judgments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prima facie evidence; collateral estoppel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A final judgment or decree heretofore or hereafter rendered in any civil or criminal proceeding brought by or on behalf of the United States under the antitrust laws to the effect that a defendant has violated said laws shall be prima facie evidence against such defendant in any action or proceeding brought by any other party against such defendant under said laws as to all matters respecting which said judgment or decree would be an estoppel as between the parties thereto: <i>Provided</i>, That this section shall not apply to consent judgments or decrees entered before any testimony has been taken. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to impose any limitation on the application of collateral estoppel, except that, in any action or proceeding brought under the antitrust laws, collateral estoppel effect shall not be given to any finding made by the Federal Trade Commission under the antitrust laws or under <ref>section 45 of this title</ref> which could give rise to a claim for relief under the antitrust laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent judgments and competitive impact statements; publication in Federal Register; availability of copies to the public</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any proposal for a consent judgment submitted by the United States for entry in any civil proceeding brought by or on behalf of the United States under the antitrust laws shall be filed with the district court before which such proceeding is pending and published by the United States in the Federal Register at least 60 days prior to the effective date of such judgment. Any written comments relating to such proposal and any responses by the United States thereto, shall also be filed with such district court and published by the United States in the Federal Register within such sixty-day period. Copies of such proposal and any other materials and documents which the United States considered determinative in formulating such proposal, shall also be made available to the public at the district court and in such other districts as the court may subsequently direct. Simultaneously with the filing of such proposal, unless otherwise instructed by the court, the United States shall file with the district court, publish in the Federal Register, and thereafter furnish to any person upon request, a competitive impact statement which shall recite—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the nature and purpose of the proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the practices or events giving rise to the alleged violation of the antitrust laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an explanation of the proposal for a consent judgment, including an explanation of any unusual circumstances giving rise to such proposal or any provision contained therein, relief to be obtained thereby, and the anticipated effects on competition of such relief;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the remedies available to potential private plaintiffs damaged by the alleged violation in the event that such proposal for the consent judgment is entered in such proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of the procedures available for modification of such proposal; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a description and evaluation of alternatives to such proposal actually considered by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of summaries in newspapers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States shall also cause to be published, commencing at least 60 days prior to the effective date of the judgment described in subsection (b) of this section, for 7 days over a period of 2 weeks in newspapers of general circulation of the district in which the case has been filed, in the District of Columbia, and in such other districts as the court may direct—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a summary of the terms of the proposal for consent judgment,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a summary of the competitive impact statement filed under subsection (b),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> and a list of the materials and documents under subsection (b) which the United States shall make available for purposes of meaningful public comment, and the place where such materials and documents are available for public inspection.</content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of public comments by Attorney General and publication of response</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the 60-day period as specified in subsection (b) of this section, and such additional time as the United States may request and the court may grant, the United States shall receive and consider any written comments relating to the proposal for the consent judgment submitted under subsection (b). The Attorney General or his designee shall establish procedures to carry out the provisions of this subsection, but such 60-day time period shall not be shortened except by order of the district court upon a showing that (1) extraordinary circumstances require such shortening and (2) such shortening is not adverse to the public interest. At the close of the period during which such comments may be received, the United States shall file with the district court and cause to be published in the Federal Register a response to such comments. Upon application by the United States, the district court may, for good cause (based on a finding that the expense of publication in the Federal Register exceeds the public interest benefits to be gained from such publication), authorize an alternative method of public dissemination of the public comments received and the response to those comments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public interest determination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before entering any consent judgment proposed by the United States under this section, the court shall determine that the entry of such judgment is in the public interest. For the purpose of such determination, the court shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the competitive impact of such judgment, including termination of alleged violations, provisions for enforcement and modification, duration of relief sought, anticipated effects of alternative remedies actually considered, whether its terms are ambiguous, and any other competitive considerations bearing upon the adequacy of such judgment that the court deems necessary to a determination of whether the consent judgment is in the public interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the impact of entry of such judgment upon competition in the relevant market or markets, upon the public generally and individuals alleging specific injury from the violations set forth in the complaint including consideration of the public benefit, if any, to be derived from a determination of the issues at trial.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the court to conduct an evidentiary hearing or to require the court to permit anyone to intervene.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure for public interest determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making its determination under subsection (e), the court may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> take testimony of Government officials or experts or such other expert witnesses, upon motion of any party or participant or upon its own motion, as the court may deem appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appoint a special master and such outside consultants or expert witnesses as the court may deem appropriate; and request and obtain the views, evaluations, or advice of any individual, group or agency of government with respect to any aspects of the proposed judgment or the effect of such judgment, in such manner as the court deems appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authorize full or limited participation in proceedings before the court by interested persons or agencies, including appearance amicus curiae, intervention as a party pursuant to the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, examination of witnesses or documentary materials, or participation in any other manner and extent which serves the public interest as the court may deem appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> review any comments including any objections filed with the United States under subsection (d) concerning the proposed judgment and the responses of the United States to such comments and objections; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> take such other action in the public interest as the court may deem appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of written or oral communications with the district court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 10 days following the date of the filing of any proposal for a consent judgment under subsection (b), each defendant shall file with the district court a description of any and all written or oral communications by or on behalf of such defendant, including any and all written or oral communications on behalf of such defendant by any officer, director, employee, or agent of such defendant, or other person, with any officer or employee of the United States concerning or relevant to such proposal, except that any such communications made by counsel of record alone with the Attorney General or the employees of the Department of Justice alone shall be excluded from the requirements of this subsection. Prior to the entry of any consent judgment pursuant to the antitrust laws, each defendant shall certify to the district court that the requirements of this subsection have been complied with and that such filing is a true and complete description of such communications known to the defendant or which the defendant reasonably should have known.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inadmissibility as evidence of proceedings before the district court and the competitive impact statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Proceedings before the district court under subsections (e) and (f) of this section, and the competitive impact statement filed under subsection (b) of this section, shall not be admissible against any defendant in any action or proceeding brought by any other party against such defendant under the antitrust laws or by the United States under <ref>section 15a of this title</ref> nor constitute a basis for the introduction of the consent judgment as prima facie evidence against such defendant in any such action or proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any civil or criminal proceeding is instituted by the United States to prevent, restrain, or punish violations of any of the antitrust laws, but not including an action under <ref>section 15a of this title</ref>, the running of the statute of limitations in respect to every private or State right of action arising under said laws and based in whole or in part on any matter complained of in said proceeding shall be suspended during the pendency thereof and for one year thereafter: <i>Provided, however</i>, That whenever the running of the statute of limitations in respect of a cause of action arising under section 15 or 15c of this title is suspended hereunder, any action to enforce such cause of action shall be forever barred unless commenced either within the period of suspension or within four years after the cause of action accrued.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 5</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>July 7, 1955, ch. 283, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–528, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 302(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–349, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-12">Sept. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1157</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-06-22">June 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17.</num>
<heading> Antitrust laws not applicable to labor organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The labor of a human being is not a commodity or article of commerce. Nothing contained in the antitrust laws shall be construed to forbid the existence and operation of labor, agricultural, or horticultural organizations, instituted for the purposes of mutual help, and not having capital stock or conducted for profit, or to forbid or restrain individual members of such organizations from lawfully carrying out the legitimate objects thereof; nor shall such organizations, or the members thereof, be held or construed to be illegal combinations or conspiracies in restraint of trade, under the antitrust laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 6</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 731</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18.</num>
<heading> Acquisition by one corporation of stock of another</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person engaged in commerce or in any activity affecting commerce shall acquire, directly or indirectly, the whole or any part of the stock or other share capital and no person subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission shall acquire the whole or any part of the assets of another person engaged also in commerce or in any activity affecting commerce, where in any line of commerce or in any activity affecting commerce in any section of the country, the effect of such acquisition may be substantially to lessen competition, or to tend to create a monopoly.</p>
<p class="indent0">No person shall acquire, directly or indirectly, the whole or any part of the stock or other share capital and no person subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission shall acquire the whole or any part of the assets of one or more persons engaged in commerce or in any activity affecting commerce, where in any line of commerce or in any activity affecting commerce in any section of the country, the effect of such acquisition, of such stocks or assets, or of the use of such stock by the voting or granting of proxies or otherwise, may be substantially to lessen competition, or to tend to create a monopoly.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to persons purchasing such stock solely for investment and not using the same by voting or otherwise to bring about, or in attempting to bring about, the substantial lessening of competition. Nor shall anything contained in this section prevent a corporation engaged in commerce or in any activity affecting commerce from causing the formation of subsidiary corporations for the actual carrying on of their immediate lawful business, or the natural and legitimate branches or extensions thereof, or from owning and holding all or a part of the stock of such subsidiary corporations, when the effect of such formation is not to substantially lessen competition.</p>
<p class="indent0">Nor shall anything herein contained be construed to prohibit any common carrier subject to the laws to regulate commerce from aiding in the construction of branches or short lines so located as to become feeders to the main line of the company so aiding in such construction or from acquiring or owning all or any part of the stock of such branch lines, nor to prevent any such common carrier from acquiring and owning all or any part of the stock of a branch or short line constructed by an independent company where there is no substantial competition between the company owning the branch line so constructed and the company owning the main line acquiring the property or an interest therein, nor to prevent such common carrier from extending any of its lines through the medium of the acquisition of stock or otherwise of any other common carrier where there is no substantial competition between the company extending its lines and the company whose stock, property, or an interest therein is so acquired.</p>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall be held to affect or impair any right heretofore legally acquired: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be held or construed to authorize or make lawful anything heretofore prohibited or made illegal by the antitrust laws, nor to exempt any person from the penal provisions thereof or the civil remedies therein provided.</p>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall apply to transactions duly consummated pursuant to authority given by the Secretary of Transportation, Federal Power Commission, Surface Transportation Board, the Securities and Exchange Commission in the exercise of its jurisdiction under <ref>section 79j of this title</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref> the United States Maritime Commission, or the Secretary of Agriculture under any statutory provision vesting such power in such Commission, Board, or Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 7</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Dec. 29, 1950, ch. 1184</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 1125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–349, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-12">Sept. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1157</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–443, § 9</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1984-10-04">Oct. 4, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 318(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–104, title VI, § 601(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18a.</num>
<heading> Premerger notification and waiting period</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as exempted pursuant to subsection (c), no person shall acquire, directly or indirectly, any voting securities or assets of any other person, unless both persons (or in the case of a tender offer, the acquiring person) file notification pursuant to rules under subsection (d)(1) and the waiting period described in subsection (b)(1) has expired, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the acquiring person, or the person whose voting securities or assets are being acquired, is engaged in commerce or in any activity affecting commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> as a result of such acquisition, the acquiring person would hold an aggregate total amount of the voting securities and assets of the acquired person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in excess of $200,000,000 (as adjusted and published for each fiscal year beginning after <date date="2004-09-30">September 30, 2004</date>, in the same manner as provided in <ref>section 19(a)(5) of this title</ref> to reflect the percentage change in the gross national product for such fiscal year compared to the gross national product for the year ending <date date="2003-09-30">September 30, 2003</date>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in excess of $50,000,000 (as so adjusted and published) but not in excess of $200,000,000 (as so adjusted and published); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any voting securities or assets of a person engaged in manufacturing which has annual net sales or total assets of $10,000,000 (as so adjusted and published) or more are being acquired by any person which has total assets or annual net sales of $100,000,000 (as so adjusted and published) or more;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any voting securities or assets of a person not engaged in manufacturing which has total assets of $10,000,000 (as so adjusted and published) or more are being acquired by any person which has total assets or annual net sales of $100,000,000 (as so adjusted and published) or more; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> any voting securities or assets of a person with annual net sales or total assets of $100,000,000 (as so adjusted and published) or more are being acquired by any person with total assets or annual net sales of $10,000,000 (as so adjusted and published) or more.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of a tender offer, the person whose voting securities are sought to be acquired by a person required to file notification under this subsection shall file notification pursuant to rules under subsection (d).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiting period; publication; voting securities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The waiting period required under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> begin on the date of the receipt by the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice (hereinafter referred to in this section as the “Assistant Attorney General”) of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the completed notification required under subsection (a), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if such notification is not completed, the notification to the extent completed and a statement of the reasons for such noncompliance,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">from both persons, or, in the case of a tender offer, the acquiring person; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> end on the thirtieth day after the date of such receipt (or in the case of a cash tender offer, the fifteenth day), or on such later date as may be set under subsection (e)(2) or (g)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General may, in individual cases, terminate the waiting period specified in paragraph (1) and allow any person to proceed with any acquisition subject to this section, and promptly shall cause to be published in the Federal Register a notice that neither intends to take any action within such period with respect to such acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “voting securities” means any securities which at present or upon conversion entitle the owner or holder thereof to vote for the election of directors of the issuer or, with respect to unincorporated issuers, persons exercising similar functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The amount or percentage of voting securities or assets of a person which are acquired or held by another person shall be determined by aggregating the amount or percentage of such voting securities or assets held or acquired by such other person and each affiliate thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exempt transactions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following classes of transactions are exempt from the requirements of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquisitions of goods or realty transferred in the ordinary course of business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acquisitions of bonds, mortgages, deeds of trust, or other obligations which are not voting securities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> acquisitions of voting securities of an issuer at least 50 per centum of the voting securities of which are owned by the acquiring person prior to such acquisition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> transfers to or from a Federal agency or a State or political subdivision thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> transactions specifically exempted from the antitrust laws by Federal statute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> transactions specifically exempted from the antitrust laws by Federal statute if approved by a Federal agency, if copies of all information and documentary material filed with such agency are contemporaneously filed with the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> transactions which require agency approval under <ref>section 1467a(e) of title 12</ref>, <ref>section 1828(c) of title 12</ref>, or <ref>section 1842 of title 12</ref>, except that a portion of a transaction is not exempt under this paragraph if such portion of the transaction (A) is subject to <ref>section 1843(k) of title 12</ref>; and (B) does not require agency approval under <ref>section 1842 of title 12</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> transactions which require agency approval under <ref>section 1843 of title 12</ref> or <ref>section 1464 of title 12</ref>, if copies of all information and documentary material filed with any such agency are contemporaneously filed with the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General at least 30 days prior to consummation of the proposed transaction, except that a portion of a transaction is not exempt under this paragraph if such portion of the transaction (A) is subject to <ref>section 1843(k) of title 12</ref>; and (B) does not require agency approval under <ref>section 1843 of title 12</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> acquisitions, solely for the purpose of investment, of voting securities, if, as a result of such acquisition, the securities acquired or held do not exceed 10 per centum of the outstanding voting securities of the issuer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> acquisitions of voting securities, if, as a result of such acquisition, the voting securities acquired do not increase, directly or indirectly, the acquiring person’s per centum share of outstanding voting securities of the issuer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> acquisitions, solely for the purpose of investment, by any bank, banking association, trust company, investment company, or insurance company, of (A) voting securities pursuant to a plan of reorganization or dissolution; or (B) assets in the ordinary course of its business; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> such other acquisitions, transfers, or transactions, as may be exempted under subsection (d)(2)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission, with the concurrence of the Assistant Attorney General and by rule in accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, consistent with the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall require that the notification required under subsection (a) be in such form and contain such documentary material and information relevant to a proposed acquisition as is necessary and appropriate to enable the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General to determine whether such acquisition may, if consummated, violate the antitrust laws; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> define the terms used in this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exempt, from the requirements of this section, classes of persons, acquisitions, transfers, or transactions which are not likely to violate the antitrust laws; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> prescribe such other rules as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional information; waiting period extensions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General may, prior to the expiration of the 30-day waiting period (or in the case of a cash tender offer, the 15-day waiting period) specified in subsection (b)(1) of this section, require the submission of additional information or documentary material relevant to the proposed acquisition, from a person required to file notification with respect to such acquisition under subsection (a) of this section prior to the expiration of the waiting period specified in subsection (b)(1) of this section, or from any officer, director, partner, agent, or employee of such person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> The Assistant Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall each designate a senior official who does not have direct responsibility for the review of any enforcement recommendation under this section concerning the transaction at issue, to hear any petition filed by such person to determine—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> whether the request for additional information or documentary material is unreasonably cumulative, unduly burdensome, or duplicative; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> whether the request for additional information or documentary material has been substantially complied with by the petitioning person.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Internal review procedures for petitions filed pursuant to clause (i) shall include reasonable deadlines for expedited review of such petitions, after reasonable negotiations with investigative staff, in order to avoid undue delay of the merger review process.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Not later than 90 days after <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, the Assistant Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall conduct an internal review and implement reforms of the merger review process in order to eliminate unnecessary burden, remove costly duplication, and eliminate undue delay, in order to achieve a more effective and more efficient merger review process.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Not later than 120 days after <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, the Assistant Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall issue or amend their respective industry guidance, regulations, operating manuals and relevant policy documents, to the extent appropriate, to implement each reform in this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 180 days after <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, the Assistant Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall each report to Congress—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> which reforms each agency has adopted under this subparagraph;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> which steps each has taken to implement such internal reforms; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the effects of such reforms.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General, in its or his discretion, may extend the 30-day waiting period (or in the case of a cash tender offer, the 15-day waiting period) specified in subsection (b)(1) of this section for an additional period of not more than 30 days (or in the case of a cash tender offer, 10 days) after the date on which the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General, as the case may be, receives from any person to whom a request is made under paragraph (1), or in the case of tender offers, the acquiring person, (A) all the information and documentary material required to be submitted pursuant to such a request, or (B) if such request is not fully complied with, the information and documentary material submitted and a statement of the reasons for such noncompliance. Such additional period may be further extended only by the United States district court, upon an application by the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General pursuant to subsection (g)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preliminary injunctions; hearings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a proceeding is instituted or an action is filed by the Federal Trade Commission, alleging that a proposed acquisition violates <ref>section 18 of this title</ref>, or <ref>section 45 of this title</ref>, or an action is filed by the United States, alleging that a proposed acquisition violates such <ref>section 18 of this title</ref>, or section 1 or 2 of this title, and the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General (1) files a motion for a preliminary injunction against consummation of such acquisition pendente lite, and (2) certifies the United States district court for the judicial district within which the respondent resides or carries on business, or in which the action is brought, that it or he believes that the public interest requires relief pendente lite pursuant to this subsection, then upon the filing of such motion and certification, the chief judge of such district court shall immediately notify the chief judge of the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which such district court is located, who shall designate a United States district judge to whom such action shall be assigned for all purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalty; compliance; power of court</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any person, or any officer, director, or partner thereof, who fails to comply with any provision of this section shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each day during which such person is in violation of this section. Such penalty may be recovered in a civil action brought by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If any person, or any officer, director, partner, agent, or employee thereof, fails substantially to comply with the notification requirement under subsection (a) or any request for the submission of additional information or documentary material under subsection (e)(1) of this section within the waiting period specified in subsection (b)(1) and as may be extended under subsection (e)(2), the United States district court—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may order compliance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall extend the waiting period specified in subsection (b)(1) and as may have been extended under subsection (e)(2) until there has been substantial compliance, except that, in the case of a tender offer, the court may not extend such waiting period on the basis of a failure, by the person whose stock is sought to be acquired, to comply substantially with such notification requirement or any such request; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may grant such other equitable relief as the court in its discretion determines necessary or appropriate,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">upon application of the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any information or documentary material filed with the Assistant Attorney General or the Federal Trade Commission pursuant to this section shall be exempt from disclosure under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>, and no such information or documentary material may be made public, except as may be relevant to any administrative or judicial action or proceeding. Nothing in this section is intended to prevent disclosure to either body of Congress or to any duly authorized committee or subcommittee of the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction with other laws</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any action taken by the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General or any failure of the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General to take any action under this section shall not bar any proceeding or any action with respect to such acquisition at any time under any other section of this Act or any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this section shall limit the authority of the Assistant Attorney General or the Federal Trade Commission to secure at any time from any person documentary material, oral testimony, or other information under the Antitrust Civil Process Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1311</ref> et seq.], the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.], or any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extensions of time</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the end of any period of time provided in this section falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal public holiday (as defined in <ref>section 6103(a) of title 5</ref>), then such period shall be extended to the end of the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, or legal public holiday.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 7A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1390</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(10)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title XII, § 1214</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title I, § 133(c)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title VI, § 630(a), (c), (d)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–108, 2762A–110.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18b.</num>
<heading> Mergers involving foreign government subsidies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “foreign entity of concern” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 18741 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounting for foreign government subsidies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person required to file a notification under <ref>section 18a of this title</ref> that received a subsidy from a foreign entity of concern shall include in such notification content regarding such subsidy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of antitrust regulators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission, with the concurrence of the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice, and in consultation with the Chairperson of the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, the Secretary of Commerce, the Chair of the United States International Trade Commission, the United States Trade Representative, and the heads of other appropriate agencies, and by rule in accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, shall require that the notification required under subsection (b) be in such form and contain such documentary material and information relevant to a proposed acquisition as is necessary and appropriate to enable the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice to determine whether such acquisition may, if consummated, violate the antitrust laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (b) shall take effect on the date on which the rule described in subsection (c) takes effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. GG, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 19.</num>
<heading> Interlocking directorates and officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> No person shall, at the same time, serve as a director or officer in any two corporations (other than banks, banking associations, and trust companies) that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engaged in whole or in part in commerce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by virtue of their business and location of operation, competitors, so that the elimination of competition by agreement between them would constitute a violation of any of the antitrust laws;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if each of the corporations has capital, surplus, and undivided profits aggregating more than $10,000,000 as adjusted pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1), simultaneous service as a director or officer in any two corporations shall not be prohibited by this section if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the competitive sales of either corporation are less than $1,000,000, as adjusted pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the competitive sales of either corporation are less than 2 per centum of that corporation’s total sales; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the competitive sales of each corporation are less than 4 per centum of that corporation’s total sales.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, “competitive sales” means the gross revenues for all products and services sold by one corporation in competition with the other, determined on the basis of annual gross revenues for such products and services in that corporation’s last completed fiscal year. For the purposes of this paragraph, “total sales” means the gross revenues for all products and services sold by one corporation over that corporation’s last completed fiscal year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The eligibility of a director or officer under the provisions of paragraph (1) shall be determined by the capital, surplus and undivided profits, exclusive of dividends declared but not paid to stockholders, of each corporation at the end of that corporation’s last completed fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “officer” means an officer elected or chosen by the Board of Directors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For each fiscal year commencing after <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, the $10,000,000 and $1,000,000 thresholds in this subsection shall be increased (or decreased) as of October 1 each year by an amount equal to the percentage increase (or decrease) in the gross national product, as determined by the Department of Commerce or its successor, for the year then ended over the level so established for the year ending <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>. As soon as practicable, but not later than January 31 of each year, the Federal Trade Commission shall publish the adjusted amounts required by this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When any person elected or chosen as a director or officer of any corporation subject to the provisions hereof is eligible at the time of his election or selection to act for such corporation in such capacity, his eligibility to act in such capacity shall not be affected by any of the provisions hereof by reason of any change in the capital, surplus and undivided profits, or affairs of such corporation from whatever cause, until the expiration of one year from the date on which the event causing ineligibility occurred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 8</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref>May 15, 1916, ch. 120</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 121</ref>; <ref>May 26, 1920, ch. 206</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 626</ref>; <ref>Mar. 9, 1928, ch. 165</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 253</ref>; <ref>Mar. 2, 1929, ch. 581</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 1536</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614, § 329</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 717</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–588, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2879</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–203, § 1</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 19a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614, § 329</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 717</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–588, § 3</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2880</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21.</num>
<heading> Enforcement provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission, Board, or Secretary authorized to enforce compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Authority to enforce compliance with sections 13, 14, 18, and 19 of this title by the persons respectively subject thereto is vested in the Surface Transportation Board where applicable to common carriers subject to jurisdiction under subtitle IV of title 49; in the Federal Communications Commission where applicable to common carriers engaged in wire or radio communication or radio transmission of energy; in the Secretary of Transportation where applicable to air carriers and foreign air carriers subject to part A of subtitle VII of title 49; in the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System where applicable to banks, banking associations, and trust companies; and in the Federal Trade Commission where applicable to all other character of commerce to be exercised as follows:</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of complaints for violations; hearing; intervention; filing of testimony; report; cease and desist orders; reopening and alteration of reports or orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Commission, Board, or Secretary vested with jurisdiction thereof shall have reason to believe that any person is violating or has violated any of the provisions of sections 13, 14, 18, and 19 of this title, it shall issue and serve upon such person and the Attorney General a complaint stating its charges in that respect, and containing a notice of a hearing upon a day and at a place therein fixed at least thirty days after the service of said complaint. The person so complained of shall have the right to appear at the place and time so fixed and show cause why an order should not be entered by the Commission, Board, or Secretary requiring such person to cease and desist from the violation of the law so charged in said complaint. The Attorney General shall have the right to intervene and appear in said proceeding and any person may make application, and upon good cause shown may be allowed by the Commission, Board, or Secretary, to intervene and appear in said proceeding by counsel or in person. The testimony in any such proceeding shall be reduced to writing and filed in the office of the Commission, Board, or Secretary. If upon such hearing the Commission, Board, or Secretary, as the case may be, shall be of the opinion that any of the provisions of said sections have been or are being violated, it shall make a report in writing, in which it shall state its findings as to the facts, and shall issue and cause to be served on such person an order requiring such person to cease and desist from such violations, and divest itself of the stock, or other share capital, or assets, held or rid itself of the directors chosen contrary to the provisions of sections 18 and 19 of this title, if any there be, in the manner and within the time fixed by said order. Until the expiration of the time allowed for filing a petition for review, if no such petition has been duly filed within such time, or, if a petition for review has been filed within such time then until the record in the proceeding has been filed in a court of appeals of the United States, as hereinafter provided, the Commission, Board, or Secretary may at any time, upon such notice and in such manner as it shall deem proper, modify or set aside, in whole or in part, any report or any order made or issued by it under this section. After the expiration of the time allowed for filing a petition for review, if no such petition has been duly filed within such time, the Commission, Board, or Secretary may at any time, after notice and opportunity for hearing, reopen and alter, modify, or set aside, in whole or in part, any report or order made or issued by it under this section, whenever in the opinion of the Commission, Board, or Secretary conditions of fact or of law have so changed as to require such action or if the public interest shall so require: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the said person may, within sixty days after service upon him or it of said report or order entered after such a reopening, obtain a review thereof in the appropriate court of appeals of the United States, in the manner provided in subsection (c) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of orders; jurisdiction; filing of petition and record of proceeding; conclusiveness of findings; additional evidence; modification of findings; finality of judgment and decree</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person required by such order of the commission, board, or Secretary to cease and desist from any such violation may obtain a review of such order in the court of appeals of the United States for any circuit within which such violation occurred or within which such person resides or carries on business, by filing in the court, within sixty days after the date of the service of such order, a written petition praying that the order of the commission, board, or Secretary be set aside. A copy of such petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the commission, board, or Secretary, and thereupon the commission, board, or Secretary shall file in the court the record in the proceeding, as provided in <ref>section 2112 of title 28</ref>. Upon such filing of the petition the court shall have jurisdiction of the proceeding and of the question determined therein concurrently with the commission, board, or Secretary until the filing of the record, and shall have power to make and enter a decree affirming, modifying, or setting aside the order of the commission, board, or Secretary, and enforcing the same to the extent that such order is affirmed, and to issue such writs as are ancillary to its jurisdiction or are necessary in its judgment to prevent injury to the public or to competitors pendente lite. The findings of the commission, board, or Secretary as to the facts, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive. To the extent that the order of the commission, board, or Secretary is affirmed, the court shall issue its own order commanding obedience to the terms of such order of the commission, board, or Secretary. If either party shall apply to the court for leave to adduce additional evidence, and shall show to the satisfaction of the court that such additional evidence is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to adduce such evidence in the proceeding before the commission, board, or Secretary, the court may order such additional evidence to be taken before the commission, board, or Secretary, and to be adduced upon the hearing in such manner and upon such terms and conditions as to the court may seem proper. The commission, board, or Secretary may modify its findings as to the facts, or make new findings, by reason of the additional evidence so taken, and shall file such modified or new findings, which if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive, and its recommendation, if any, for the modification or setting aside of its original order, with the return of such additional evidence. The judgment and decree of the court shall be final, except that the same shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court upon certiorari, as provided in <ref>section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusive jurisdiction of Court of Appeals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the filing of the record with its jurisdiction of the court of appeals to affirm, enforce, modify, or set aside orders of the commission, board, or Secretary shall be exclusive.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability under antitrust laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No order of the commission, board, or Secretary or judgment of the court to enforce the same shall in anywise relieve or absolve any person from any liability under the antitrust laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service of complaints, orders and other processes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Complaints, orders, and other processes of the commission, board, or Secretary under this section may be served by anyone duly authorized by the commission, board, or Secretary, either (1) by delivering a copy thereof to the person to be served, or to a member of the partnership to be served, or to the president, secretary, or other executive officer or a director of the corporation to be served; or (2) by leaving a copy thereof at the residence or the principal office or place of business of such person; or (3) by mailing by registered or certified mail a copy thereof addressed to such person at his or its residence or principal office or place of business. The verified return by the person so serving said complaint, order, or other process setting forth the manner of said service shall be proof of the same, and the return post office receipt for said complaint, order, or other process mailed by registered or certified mail as aforesaid shall be proof of the service of the same.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality of orders generally</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any order issued under subsection (b) shall become final—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upon the expiration of the time allowed for filing a petition for review, if no such petition has been duly filed within such time; but the commission, board, or Secretary may thereafter modify or set aside its order to the extent provided in the last sentence of subsection (b); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> upon the expiration of the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari, if the order of the commission, board, or Secretary has been affirmed, or the petition for review has been dismissed by the court of appeals, and no petition for certiorari has been duly filed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> upon the denial of a petition for certiorari, if the order of the commission, board, or Secretary has been affirmed or the petition for review has been dismissed by the court of appeals; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> upon the expiration of thirty days from the date of issuance of the mandate of the Supreme Court, if such Court directs that the order of the commission, board, or Secretary be affirmed or the petition for review be dismissed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality of orders modified by Supreme Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Supreme Court directs that the order of the commission, board, or Secretary be modified or set aside, the order of the commission, board, or Secretary rendered in accordance with the mandate of the Supreme Court shall become final upon the expiration of thirty days from the time it was rendered, unless within such thirty days either party has instituted proceedings to have such order corrected to accord with the mandate, in which event the order of the commission, board, or Secretary shall become final when so corrected.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality of orders modified by Court of Appeals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the order of the commission, board, or Secretary is modified or set aside by the court of appeals, and if (1) the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari has expired and no such petition has been duly filed, or (2) the petition for certiorari has been denied, or (3) the decision of the court has been affirmed by the Supreme Court then the order of the commission, board, or Secretary rendered in accordance with the mandate of the court of appeals shall become final on the expiration of thirty days from the time such order of the commission, board, or Secretary was rendered, unless within such thirty days either party has instituted proceedings to have such order corrected so that it will accord with the mandate, in which event the order of the commission, board, or Secretary shall become final when so corrected.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality of orders issued on rehearing ordered by Court of Appeals or Supreme Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Supreme Court orders a rehearing; or if the case is remanded by the court of appeals to the commission, board, or Secretary for a rehearing, and if (1) the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari has expired, and no such petition has been duly filed, or (2) the petition for certiorari has been denied, or (3) the decision of the court has been affirmed by the Supreme Court, then the order of the commission, board, or Secretary rendered upon such rehearing shall become final in the same manner as though no prior order of the commission, board, or Secretary had been rendered.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Mandate” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section the term “mandate”, in case a mandate has been recalled prior to the expiration of thirty days from the date of issuance thereof, means the final mandate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who violates any order issued by the commission, board, or Secretary under subsection (b) after such order has become final, and while such order is in effect, shall forfeit and pay to the United States a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each violation, which shall accrue to the United States and may be recovered in a civil action brought by the United States. Each separate violation of any such order shall be a separate offense, except that in the case of a violation through continuing failure or neglect to obey a final order of the commission, board, or Secretary each day of continuance of such failure or neglect shall be deemed a separate offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 11</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 734</ref>; <ref>June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title VII, § 702(d), formerly title VI, § 602(d), <ref>48 Stat. 1102</ref>; renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 98–549, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2804</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614, § 203(a)</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref>June 23, 1938, ch. 601, § 1107(g)</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1028</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(a)</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref>Dec. 29, 1950, ch. 1184</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 1125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–726, title XIV, § 1401(b)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-23">Aug. 23, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–791, § 4</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 943</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–107, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-07-23">July 23, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–443, § 9(m)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-04">Oct. 4, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(10)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 318(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21a.</num>
<heading> Actions and proceedings pending prior to <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>; additional and continuing violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing herein contained shall affect rights of action arising, or litigation pending, or orders of the Federal Trade Commission issued and in effect or pending on review, based on <ref>section 13 of this title</ref>, prior to <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That where, prior to <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, the Federal Trade Commission has issued an order requiring any person to cease and desist from a violation of <ref>section 13 of this title</ref>, and such order is pending on review or is in effect, either as issued or as affirmed or modified by a court of competent jurisdiction, and the Commission shall have reason to believe that such person has committed, used or carried on, since <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, or is committing, using or carrying on, any act, practice or method in violation of any of the provisions of said <ref>section 13 of this title</ref>, it may reopen such original proceedings and may issue and serve upon such person its complaint, supplementary to the original complaint, stating its charges in that respect. Thereupon the same proceedings shall be had upon such supplementary complaint as provided in <ref>section 21 of this title</ref>. If upon such hearing the Commission shall be of the opinion that any act, practice, or method charged in said supplementary complaint has been committed, used, or carried on since <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, or is being committed, used or carried on, in violation of said <ref>section 13 of this title</ref>, it shall make a report in writing in which it shall state its findings as to the facts and shall issue and serve upon such person its order modifying or amending its original order to include any additional violations of law so found. Thereafter the provisions of <ref>section 21 of this title</ref>, as to review and enforcement of orders of the Commission shall in all things apply to such modified or amended order. If upon review as provided in said <ref>section 21 of this title</ref> the court shall set aside such modified or amended order, the original order shall not be affected thereby, but it shall be and remain in force and effect as fully and to the same extent as if such supplementary proceedings had not been taken.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 19, 1936, ch. 592, § 2</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22.</num>
<heading> District in which to sue corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any suit, action, or proceeding under the antitrust laws against a corporation may be brought not only in the judicial district whereof it is an inhabitant, but also in any district wherein it may be found or transacts business; and all process in such cases may be served in the district of which it is an inhabitant, or wherever it may be found.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 12</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 23.</num>
<heading> Suits by United States; subpoenas for witnesses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any suit, action, or proceeding brought by or on behalf of the United States subpoenas for witnesses who are required to attend a court of the United States in any judicial district in any case, civil or criminal, arising under the antitrust laws may run into any other district: <i>Provided</i>, That in civil cases no writ of subpoena shall issue for witnesses living out of the district in which the court is held at a greater distance than one hundred miles from the place of holding the same without the permission of the trial court being first had upon proper application and cause shown.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 13</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 24.</num>
<heading> Liability of directors and agents of corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever a corporation shall violate any of the penal provisions of the antitrust laws, such violation shall be deemed to be also that of the individual directors, officers, or agents of such corporation who shall have authorized, ordered, or done any of the acts constituting in whole or in part such violation, and such violation shall be deemed a misdemeanor, and upon conviction therefor of any such director, officer, or agent he shall be punished by a fine of not exceeding $5,000 or by imprisonment for not exceeding one year, or by both, in the discretion of the court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 14</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 25.</num>
<heading> Restraining violations; procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The several district courts of the United States are invested with jurisdiction to prevent and restrain violations of this Act, and it shall be the duty of the several United States attorneys, in their respective districts, under the direction of the Attorney General, to institute proceedings in equity to prevent and restrain such violations. Such proceedings may be by way of petition setting forth the case and praying that such violation shall be enjoined or otherwise prohibited. When the parties complained of shall have been duly notified of such petition, the court shall proceed, as soon as may be, to the hearing and determination of the case; and pending such petition, and before final decree, the court may at any time make such temporary restraining order or prohibition as shall be deemed just in the premises. Whenever it shall appear to the court before which any such proceeding may be pending that the ends of justice require that other parties should be brought before the court, the court may cause them to be summoned whether they reside in the district in which the court is held or not, and subpoenas to that end may be served in any district by the marshal thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 15</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 26.</num>
<heading> Injunctive relief for private parties; exception; costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person, firm, corporation, or association shall be entitled to sue for and have injunctive relief, in any court of the United States having jurisdiction over the parties, against threatened loss or damage by a violation of the antitrust laws, including sections 13, 14, 18, and 19 of this title, when and under the same conditions and principles as injunctive relief against threatened conduct that will cause loss or damage is granted by courts of equity, under the rules governing such proceedings, and upon the execution of proper bond against damages for an injunction improvidently granted and a showing that the danger of irreparable loss or damage is immediate, a preliminary injunction may issue: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein contained shall be construed to entitle any person, firm, corporation, or association, except the United States, to bring suit for injunctive relief against any common carrier subject to the jurisdiction of the Surface Transportation Board under subtitle IV of title 49. In any action under this section in which the plaintiff substantially prevails, the court shall award the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, to such plaintiff.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 16</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 302(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 318(3)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 26a.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on the purchase of gasohol and synthetic motor fuel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on the use of credit instruments; sales, resales, and transfers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), it shall be unlawful for any person engaged in commerce, in the course of such commerce, directly or indirectly to impose any condition, restriction, agreement, or understanding that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> limits the use of credit instruments in any transaction concerning the sale, resale, or transfer of gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel of equivalent usability in any case in which there is no similar limitation on transactions concerning such person’s conventional motor fuel; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> otherwise unreasonably discriminates against or unreasonably limits the sale, resale, or transfer of gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel of equivalent usability in any case in which such synthetic or conventional motor fuel is sold for use, consumption, or resale within the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit fees; equivalent conventional motor fuel sales; labeling of pumps; product liability disclaimers; advertising support; furnishing facilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section or in any other provision of law in effect on <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, which is specifically applicable to the sale of petroleum products shall preclude any person referred to in subsection (a) from imposing a reasonable fee for credit on the sale, resale, or transfer of the gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel referred to in subsection (a) if such fee equals no more than the actual costs to such person of extending that credit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The prohibitions in this section shall not apply to any person who makes available sufficient supplies of gasohol and other synthetic motor fuels of equivalent usability to satisfy his customers’ needs for such products, if the gasohol and other synthetic fuels are made available on terms and conditions which are equivalent to the terms and conditions on which such person’s conventional motor fuel products are made available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preclude any person referred to in subsection (a) from requiring reasonable labeling of pumps dispensing the gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel referred to in subsection (a) to indicate, as appropriate, that such gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel is not manufactured, distributed, or sold by such person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> preclude such person from issuing appropriate disclaimers of product liability for damage resulting from use of the gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> require such person to provide advertising support for the gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> require such person to furnish or provide, at such person’s own expense, any additional pumps, tanks, or other related facilities required for the sale of the gasohol or other synthetic motor fuel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “United States” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, “United States” includes the several States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, and any insular possession or other place under the jurisdiction of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 26</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–493, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 26b.</num>
<heading> Application of antitrust laws to professional major league baseball</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major league baseball subject to antitrust laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsections (b) through (d), the conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons in the business of organized professional major league baseball directly relating to or affecting employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level are subject to the antitrust laws to the same extent such conduct, acts, practices, or agreements would be subject to the antitrust laws if engaged in by persons in any other professional sports business affecting interstate commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation of section</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No court shall rely on the enactment of this section as a basis for changing the application of the antitrust laws to any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements other than those set forth in subsection (a). This section does not create, permit or imply a cause of action by which to challenge under the antitrust laws, or otherwise apply the antitrust laws to, any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements that do not directly relate to or affect employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level, including but not limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons engaging in, conducting or participating in the business of organized professional baseball relating to or affecting employment to play baseball at the minor league level, any organized professional baseball amateur or first-year player draft, or any reserve clause as applied to minor league players;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the agreement between organized professional major league baseball teams and the teams of the National Association of Professional Baseball Leagues, commonly known as the “Professional Baseball Agreement”, the relationship between organized professional major league baseball and organized professional minor league baseball, or any other matter relating to organized professional baseball’s minor leagues;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons engaging in, conducting or participating in the business of organized professional baseball relating to or affecting franchise expansion, location or relocation, franchise ownership issues, including ownership transfers, the relationship between the Office of the Commissioner and franchise owners, the marketing or sales of the entertainment product of organized professional baseball and the licensing of intellectual property rights owned or held by organized professional baseball teams individually or collectively;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements protected by <ref>Public Law 87–331</ref> (15 U.S.C. § 1291 et seq.) (commonly known as the “Sports Broadcasting Act of 1961”);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the relationship between persons in the business of organized professional baseball and umpires or other individuals who are employed in the business of organized professional baseball by such persons; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons not in the business of organized professional major league baseball.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standing to sue</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Only a major league baseball player has standing to sue under this section. For the purposes of this section, a major league baseball player is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a person who is a party to a major league player’s contract, or is playing baseball at the major league level; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a person who was a party to a major league player’s contract or playing baseball at the major league level at the time of the injury that is the subject of the complaint; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a person who has been a party to a major league player’s contract or who has played baseball at the major league level, and who claims he has been injured in his efforts to secure a subsequent major league player’s contract by an alleged violation of the antitrust laws: <i>Provided however</i>, That for the purposes of this paragraph, the alleged antitrust violation shall not include any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons in the business of organized professional baseball relating to or affecting employment to play baseball at the minor league level, including any organized professional baseball amateur or first-year player draft, or any reserve clause as applied to minor league players; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a person who was a party to a major league player’s contract or who was playing baseball at the major league level at the conclusion of the last full championship season immediately preceding the expiration of the last collective bargaining agreement between persons in the business of organized professional major league baseball and the exclusive collective bargaining representative of major league baseball players.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conduct, acts, practices, or agreements subject to antitrust laws</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As used in this section, “person” means any entity, including an individual, partnership, corporation, trust or unincorporated association or any combination or association thereof. As used in this section, the National Association of Professional Baseball Leagues, its member leagues and the clubs of those leagues, are not “in the business of organized professional major league baseball”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In cases involving conduct, acts, practices, or agreements that directly relate to or affect both employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level and also relate to or affect any other aspect of organized professional baseball, including but not limited to employment to play baseball at the minor league level and the other areas set forth in subsection (b), only those components, portions or aspects of such conduct, acts, practices, or agreements that directly relate to or affect employment of major league players to play baseball at the major league level may be challenged under subsection (a) and then only to the extent that they directly relate to or affect employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> As used in subsection (a), interpretation of the term “directly” shall not be governed by any interpretation of section 151 et seq. of title 29, United States Code (as amended).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application to organized professional baseball of the nonstatutory labor exemption from the antitrust laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The scope of the conduct, acts, practices, or agreements covered by subsection (b) shall not be strictly or narrowly construed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 27</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–297, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 27.</num>
<heading> Effect of partial invalidity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any clause, sentence, paragraph, or part of this Act shall, for any reason, be adjudged by any court of competent jurisdiction to be in­valid, such judgment shall not affect, impair, or invalidate the remainder thereof, but shall be confined in its operation to the clause, sentence, paragraph, or part thereof directly involved in the controversy in which such judgment shall have been rendered.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 28</ref>, formerly § 26, <ref>38 Stat. 740</ref>; renumbered § 27, <ref>Pub. L. 96–493, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2568</ref>; renumbered § 28, <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title IV, § 14102(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 27a.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 28.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(11)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3358</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 29.</num>
<heading> Appeals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court of appeals; review by Supreme Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise expressly provided by this section, in every civil action brought in any district court of the United States under the Act entitled “An Act to protect trade and commerce against unlawful restraints and monopolies”, approved <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, or any other Acts having like purpose that have been or hereafter may be enacted, in which the United States is the complainant and equitable relief is sought, any appeal from a final judgement entered in any such action shall be taken to the court of appeals pursuant to sections 1291 and 2107 of title 28. Any appeal from an interlocutory order entered in any such action shall be taken to the court of appeals pursuant to sections 1292(a)(1) and 2107 of title 28 but not otherwise. Any judgment entered by the court of appeals in any such action shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court upon a writ of certiorari as provided in <ref>section 1254(1) of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct appeals to Supreme Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An appeal from a final judgment pursuant to subsection (a) shall lie directly to the Supreme Court, if, upon application of a party filed within fifteen days of the filing of a notice of appeal, the district judge who adjudicated the case enters an order stating that immediate consideration of the appeal by the Supreme Court is of general public importance in the administration of justice. Such order shall be filed within thirty days after the filing of a notice of appeal. When such an order is filed, the appeal and any cross appeal shall be docketed in the time and manner prescribed by the rules of the Supreme Court. The Supreme Court shall thereupon either (1) dispose of the appeal and any cross appeal in the same manner as any other direct appeal authorized by law, or (2) in its discretion, deny the direct appeal and remand the case to the court of appeals, which shall then have jurisdiction to hear and determine the same as if the appeal and any cross appeal therein had been docketed in the court of appeals in the first instance pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 11, 1903, ch. 544, § 2</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 291</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 1167</ref>; <ref>June 9, 1944, ch. 239</ref>, <ref>58 Stat. 272</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 17</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 989</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–528, § 5</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title IV, § 14102(f)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1922</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title IV, § 14102(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1921</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 32, 33.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II</ref>, §§ 209, 210, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 929</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 34.</num>
<heading> Definitions applicable to sections 34 to 36</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of sections 34 to 36 of this title—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “local government” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a city, county, parish, town, township, village, or any other general function governmental unit established by State law, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a school district, sanitary district, or any other special function governmental unit established by State law in one or more States,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “person” has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 12(a)</ref>], but does not include any local government as defined in paragraph (1) of this section, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “State” has the meaning given it in section 4G(2) of the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 15g(2)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–544, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 35.</num>
<heading> Recovery of damages, etc., for antitrust violations from any local government, or official or employee thereof acting in an official capacity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition in general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No damages, interest on damages, costs, or attorney’s fees may be recovered under section 4, 4A, or 4C of the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 15</ref>, 15a, or 15c) from any local government, or official or employee thereof acting in an official capacity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preconditions for attachment of prohibition; prima facie evidence for nonapplication of prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to cases commenced before the effective date of this Act unless the defendant establishes and the court determines, in light of all the circumstances, including the stage of litigation and the availability of alternative relief under the Clayton Act, that it would be inequitable not to apply this subsection to a pending case. In consideration of this section, existence of a jury verdict, district court judgment, or any stage of litigation subsequent thereto, shall be deemed to be prima facie evidence that subsection (a) shall not apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–544, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36.</num>
<heading> Recovery of damages, etc., for antitrust violations on claim against person based on official action directed by local government, or official or employee thereof acting in an official capacity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition in general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No damages, interest on damages, costs or attorney’s fees may be recovered under section 4, 4A, or 4C of the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 15</ref>, 15a, or 15c) in any claim against a person based on any official action directed by a local government, or official or employee thereof acting in an official capacity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplication of prohibition for cases commenced before effective date of provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to cases commenced before the effective date of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–544, § 4</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 37.</num>
<heading> Immunity from antitrust laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of antitrust laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), the antitrust laws, and any State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, shall not apply to charitable gift annuities or charitable remainder trusts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immunity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), any person subjected to any legal proceeding for damages, injunction, penalties, or other relief of any kind under the antitrust laws, or any State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, on account of setting or agreeing to rates of return or other terms for, negotiating, issuing, participating in, implementing, or otherwise being involved in the planning, issuance, or payment of charitable gift annuities or charitable remainder trusts shall have immunity from suit under the antitrust laws, including the right not to bear the cost, burden, and risk of discovery and trial, for the conduct set forth in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain annuities and trusts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any annuity treated as a charitable gift annuity, or any trust treated as a charitable remainder trust, either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in any filing by the donor with the Internal Revenue Service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any schedule, form, or written document provided by or on behalf of the donee to the donor;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be conclusively presumed for the purposes of this section and <ref>section 37a of this title</ref> to be respectively a charitable gift annuity or a charitable remainder trust, unless there has been a final determination by the Internal Revenue Service that, for fraud or otherwise, the donor’s annuity or trust did not qualify respectively as a charitable gift annuity or charitable remainder trust when created.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply with respect to the enforcement of a State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, with respect to charitable gift annuities, or charitable remainder trusts, created after the State enacts a statute, not later than <date date="1998-12-08">December 8, 1998</date>, that expressly provides that subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply with respect to such charitable gift annuities and such charitable remainder trusts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–63, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-12-08">Dec. 8, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–26, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-07-03">July 3, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 37a.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section and <ref>section 37 of this title</ref>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Antitrust laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “antitrust laws” has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>, except that such term includes <ref>section 45 of this title</ref> to the extent that such section 45 applies to unfair methods of competition.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Charitable remainder trust</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “charitable remainder trust” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 664(d) of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Charitable gift annuity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “charitable gift annuity” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 501(m)(5) of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “final determination” includes an Internal Revenue Service determination, after exhaustion of donor’s and donee’s administrative remedies, disallowing the donor’s charitable deduction for the year in which the initial contribution was made because of the donee’s failure to comply at such time with the requirements of section 501(m)(5) or 664(d), respectively, of title 26.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 15g(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–63, § 3</ref>, <date date="1995-12-08">Dec. 8, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–26, § 2(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-07-03">July 3, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 37b.</num>
<heading> Confirmation of antitrust status of graduate medical resident matching programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings and purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For over 50 years, most United States medical school seniors and the large majority of graduate medical education programs (popularly known as “residency programs”) have chosen to use a matching program to match medical students with residency programs to which they have applied. These matching programs have been an integral part of an educational system that has produced the finest physicians and medical researchers in the world.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Before such matching programs were instituted, medical students often felt pressure, at an unreasonably early stage of their medical education, to seek admission to, and accept offers from, residency programs. As a result, medical students often made binding commitments before they were in a position to make an informed decision about a medical specialty or a residency program and before residency programs could make an informed assessment of students’ qualifications. This situation was inefficient, chaotic, and unfair and it often led to placements that did not serve the interests of either medical students or residency programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The original matching program, now operated by the independent non-profit National Resident Matching Program and popularly known as “the Match”, was developed and implemented more than 50 years ago in response to widespread student complaints about the prior process. This Program includes on its board of directors individuals nominated by medical student organizations as well as by major medical education and hospital associations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Match uses a computerized mathematical algorithm, as students had recommended, to analyze the preferences of students and residency programs and match students with their highest preferences from among the available positions in residency programs that listed them. Students thus obtain a residency position in the most highly ranked program on their list that has ranked them sufficiently high among its preferences. Each year, about 85 percent of participating United States medical students secure a place in one of their top 3 residency program choices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Antitrust lawsuits challenging the matching process, regardless of their merit or lack thereof, have the potential to undermine this highly efficient, pro-competitive, and long-standing process. The costs of defending such litigation would divert the scarce resources of our country’s teaching hospitals and medical schools from their crucial missions of patient care, physician training, and medical research. In addition, such costs may lead to abandonment of the matching process, which has effectively served the interests of medical students, teaching hospitals, and patients for over half a century.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It is the purpose of this section to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> confirm that the antitrust laws do not prohibit sponsoring, conducting, or participating in a graduate medical education residency matching program, or agreeing to do so; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that those who sponsor, conduct or participate in such matching programs are not subjected to the burden and expense of defending against litigation that challenges such matching programs under the antitrust laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of antitrust laws to graduate medical education residency matching programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Antitrust laws</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “antitrust laws”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has the meaning given such term in subsection (a) of <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>, except that such term includes <ref>section 45 of this title</ref> to the extent such section 45 applies to unfair methods of competition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> includes any State law similar to the laws referred to in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Graduate medical education program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “graduate medical education program” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a residency program for the medical education and training of individuals following graduation from medical school;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a program, known as a specialty or subspecialty fellowship program, that provides more advanced training; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an institution or organization that operates, sponsors or participates in such a program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Graduate medical education residency matching program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “graduate medical education residency matching program” means a program (such as those conducted by the National Resident Matching Program) that, in connection with the admission of students to graduate medical education programs, uses an algorithm and matching rules to match students in accordance with the preferences of students and the preferences of graduate medical education programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Student</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “student” means any individual who seeks to be admitted to a graduate medical education program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confirmation of antitrust status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall not be unlawful under the antitrust laws to sponsor, conduct, or participate in a graduate medical education residency matching program, or to agree to sponsor, conduct, or participate in such a program. Evidence of any of the conduct described in the preceding sentence shall not be admissible in Federal court to support any claim or action alleging a violation of the antitrust laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to exempt from the antitrust laws any agreement on the part of 2 or more graduate medical education programs to fix the amount of the stipend or other benefits received by students participating in such programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on <date date="2004-04-10">April 10, 2004</date>, shall apply to conduct whether it occurs prior to, on, or after <date date="2004-04-10">April 10, 2004</date>, and shall apply to all judicial and administrative actions or other proceedings pending on <date date="2004-04-10">April 10, 2004</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–218, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2004-04-10">Apr. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 38.</num>
<heading> Association of marine insurance companies; application of antitrust laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “association” means any association, exchange, pool, combination, or other arrangement for concerted action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “marine insurance companies” means any persons, companies, or associations, authorized to write marine insurance or reinsurance under the laws of the United States or of a State, Territory, District, or possession thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in the “antitrust laws” as designated in <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>, shall be construed as declaring illegal an association entered into by marine insurance companies for the following purposes: To transact a marine insurance and reinsurance business in the United States and in foreign countries and to reinsure or otherwise apportion among its membership the risks undertaken by such association or any of the component members.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 5, 1920, ch. 250, § 29</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>