<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 71—</num>
<heading>PETROLEUM OVERCHARGE DISTRIBUTION AND RESTITUTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4501.</num>
<heading> Restitutionary amounts covered</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter (other than <ref>section 4504 of this title</ref>)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specifies the procedure for the disbursement of funds collected, including interest thereon, by the Secretary or the courts pursuant to the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.] or the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970 (and the regulations issued thereunder) as restitution for actual or alleged violations of such Acts or regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> subject to subsection (c), applies to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any amount of such funds held in escrow by the Secretary through accounts administered by the Secretary of the Treasury on or after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any amount of such funds determined at any time, pursuant to judicial or administrative proceedings (including any settlement agreement or declaratory judgment) instituted by the Secretary to enforce such Acts and regulations, to be amounts paid for such actual or alleged violations, including any such amounts held in escrow by any court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts described in subsection (a)(2) and held in an escrow account by a court before <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, may continue to be held by such court but shall be disbursed, together with any interest thereon, by the Secretary or, as appropriate, by the court only in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a)(2) does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any amount actually disbursed before <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, to any person or class of persons pursuant to <ref>section 155 of Public Law 97–377</ref> or any final judicial or administrative order or judgment (including any settlement agreement or declaratory judgment);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any amount to which any person or class of persons has an enforceable right, created or vested, or governed by the terms and conditions of the settlement approved on <date date="1986-07-07">July 7, 1986</date>, in In Re: the Department of Energy Stripper Well Exemption Litigation, M.D.L. No. 378, in the United States District Court for the District of Kansas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> any amount designated by judicial or administrative order or judgment (including any settlement agreement or declaratory judgment) for disbursement at any time to any specific person or class of persons—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identified in such order or judgment as injured by the violation or alleged violation of the Acts described in subsection (a)(1) (including the regulations thereunder); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identified in such order or judgment issued before <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, for indirect restitution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Escrow accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the amounts covered by subsection (a) shall be held in appropriate escrow accounts administered for the Secretary by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Consistent with the disbursement requirements of this chapter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall provide that amounts described in subsection (a) shall earn interest at the maximum rate earned on investments of Federal trust funds by the Secretary of the Treasury in short-term and long-term securities issued by the Federal Government (including minority bank investments).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3002</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1881</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4502.</num>
<heading> Identification and disbursement of restitutionary amounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all rulings, policies, or other statements (including any administrative order or settlement agreement) issued after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, by any office, official, or employee of the Department of Energy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all orders, including declaratory judgments, issued by any court after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall affect the settlement approved on <date date="1986-07-07">July 7, 1986</date>, in In Re: the Department of Energy Stripper Well Exemption Litigation, M.D.L. No. 378, in the United States District Court for the District of Kansas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (d) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3003(e)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title III, § 337]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–295</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repeal of subsections (b) to (d); equitable distribution of escrow remainder to claimants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section are repealed, and any rights that may have arisen are extinguished, on the date of the enactment of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999. After that date, the amount available for direct restitution to current and future refined petroleum product claimants under this chapter is reduced by the amounts specified in title II of that Act as being derived from amounts held in escrow under <ref>section 4501(d) of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall assure that the amount remaining in escrow to satisfy refined petroleum product claims for direct restitution is allocated equitably among the claimants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3003</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1882</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title III, § 337]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–295.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503.</num>
<heading> Deposit of remainder of excess amount into Treasury as indirect restitution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount that remains from the excess amount described in section 4502(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002511">1</ref> of this title after all disbursements have been made for a fiscal year under section 4502(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002511">1</ref> of this title shall be deposited by the Secretary of the Treasury into the general fund of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3004</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4504.</num>
<heading> Statute of limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), the commencement of a civil enforcement action shall be barred unless such action is commenced before the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> six years after the date of the violation upon which the action is based.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “commencement of a civil enforcement action” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the signing and issuance of a proposed remedial order against any person for filing with the Office of Hearings and Appeals of the Department of Energy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the filing of a complaint with the appropriate district court of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “civil enforcement action” means an administrative or judicial civil action by the Secretary under the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.] or the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970 (or the regulations issued thereunder) for the enforcement of any violation of such Acts or regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In computing the periods established in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1), there shall be excluded any period—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during which any person who is or may become the subject of a civil enforcement action is outside the United States, has absconded or concealed himself, or is not subject to legal process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during which facts material to the establishment and maintenance of a civil enforcement action could not be known;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> occurring before full compliance with any subpoena or special report order issued to any person under <ref>section 772 of this title</ref>, and such additional period (not to exceed 12 calendar months) after such compliance for the Secretary to consider the results thereof and commence a civil enforcement action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> during the pendency of any relevant criminal action under the Acts or regulations described in subsection (a)(1) during which a civil enforcement action is held in abeyance as a result of prosecutorial discretion and with or without a stay, and such additional period (not to exceed 12 calendar months) after a final judicial order or dismissal of such criminal action to commence a civil enforcement action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> before the issuance of an order that constitutes final agency action on a request for adjustment from any rule, regulation, or order under <ref>section 7194 of title 42</ref>, and such additional period (not to exceed 12 calendar months) to commence a civil enforcement action; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> of extension, to which the Secretary and the defendant have consented in writing, before the expiration of the time periods prescribed in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of subsection (a) shall not affect or apply to any civil enforcement action commenced before, on, or after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, and remanded by the Office of Hearings and Appeals, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, or the court for further action of any kind.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to any agency orders issued under the Acts or regulations described in subsection (a)(1) or to regulations issued under this chapter, other than a proposed remedial order subject to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expression of intent</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> It is the intent of the Congress that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary and the Administrator of the Economic Regulatory Administration shall, to the greatest extent possible and within the time frames specified on <date date="1986-09-12">September 12, 1986</date>, by such Administrator to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, commence civil enforcement actions with respect to all cases known by such Administrator as of <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, and designated by such Administrator as “prelitigation cases”, unless such an action is found not to be warranted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary and such Administrator not delay civil enforcement actions so as to cause the limitation in subsection (a)(1) to apply to any such case;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any negotiations for the purpose of settlement of alleged violations not delay the commencement of a civil enforcement action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Department of Justice cooperate in ensuring that activities necessary, including the enforcement of subpoenas, to commence civil enforcement actions are carried out in a timely manner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any failure to comply with the time frames described in paragraph (1)(A) shall not be considered for any purpose in any administrative or judicial proceeding subsequently commenced.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> End of investigations and audits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not initiate, after <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, any audit or investigation of alleged civil violations of the Acts or regulations described in subsection (a)(1) for the purpose of commencement of any civil enforcement action. Nothing in this subsection shall affect or apply to any audit or investigation conducted with respect to any civil enforcement action commenced (within the limitation established by subsection (a)(1)) before, on, or after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>. Nothing in this subsection shall limit the authority of the Secretary to continue any audit or investigation initiated before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any review of a final agency action determined under section 7193 or 7194 of title 42 may not be initiated in any court by any person subject to such action after—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 60 days after the effective date of that action; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 90 days after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever occurs later.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In order to ensure the expeditious, effective, and efficient resolution of all civil enforcement actions (whether or not in administrative or judicial litigation) and all cases pending at the Office of Hearings and Appeals under subpart V regulations, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maintain a personnel level for the compliance program of the Economic Regulatory Administration of 170 full-time equivalents for fiscal year 1987, subject to normal attrition and subject to the provisions of any appropriation Act enacted for such fiscal year concerning such program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintain for the remainder of the program an adequate mix of lawyers, auditors, technical, clerical, and administrative personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> By <date date="1987-07-01">July 1, 1987</date>, and by July 1 of each year thereafter, the Administrator of the Economic Regulatory Administration shall provide to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate the full-time equivalent level necessary for such compliance program for the next fiscal year and the basis for that level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall, in any fiscal year, provide a notice of at least 30 days to such Committees before initiating any reduction of force at the Economic Regulatory Administration. Such notice shall provide at least—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reasons for such reduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the impact on the mix of personnel and on all cases, whether or not in litigation, including the subpart V regulation proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the expected costs and savings for the applicable fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Economic Regulatory Administration shall keep such Committees fully and currently informed about the status (including delays, settlement negotiations, and other pertinent matters) of all enforcement cases (whether or not in litigation) and subpart V regulation proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3005</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4505.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on receipts and disbursements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit, not later than 60 days after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, a report to the committees referred to in subsection (d) containing a clear and complete statement of all receipts, disbursements, and commitments of restitutionary amounts, as of <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, by the Secretary pursuant to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any judicial or administrative proceeding (including any settlement agreement or declaratory judgment) instituted at any time by the Secretary to enforce the crude oil and petroleum product pricing and allocation regulations issued under the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.] or the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 155 of Public Law 97–377</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on collection of certain deficiency funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit a report each fiscal year, beginning in fiscal year 1987, to such committees on the status of collections by the Secretary of deficiency funds to be deposited into the M.D.L. No. 378 escrow account established by the United States District Court for the District of Kansas until all such deficiency funds have been paid. The Secretary shall, in a manner substantially similar to that required by <ref>section 155 of Public Law 97–377</ref> with respect to amounts disbursed under such section, monitor the disposition by the States of any funds disbursed to the States by the court pursuant to the opinion and order of such District Court, dated <date date="1986-07-07">July 7, 1986</date>, with respect to In Re: the Department of Energy Stripper Well Exemption Litigation, M.D.L. No. 378, including the use of such funds for administrative costs and attorneys fees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on amount estimated to be available for indirect restitution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit, on March 1 of each year beginning with 1987 and continuing until all the restitutionary amounts to which <ref>section 4501(a) of this title</ref> applies have been collected and disbursed as provided in this chapter, a report to such committees containing an estimate of the amount that will be determined under section 4502(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002512">1</ref> of this title to be the excess amount for purposes of section 4502(d)(1)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002512">1</ref> of this title for the fiscal year beginning the next October 1.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Receipt by committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports required by this chapter shall be transmitted to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3006</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4506.</num>
<heading> Termination</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), the provisions of this chapter (other than <ref>section 4504 of this title</ref>) shall terminate 90 days after the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determines that all of the restitutionary amounts to which <ref>section 4501(a) of this title</ref> applies have been collected and disbursed as provided in this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submits to Congress the final report required by <ref>section 4505 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such final report shall include the determination (and the justification thereof) described in paragraph (1)(A). Such report shall also be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirements of section 4502(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002513">1</ref> of this title shall continue to be applicable to the use of restitutionary amounts received under this chapter as long as such funds remain available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3007</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1887</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4507.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “subpart V regulations” means the provisions of Subpart V—Special Procedures for Distribution of Refunds (10 CFR 205.280–205.288) and any amendment made after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, and all precedents and decisions under such regulations, but only to the extent that such provisions, precedents, decisions, and amendments are consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “energy conservation programs” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the program under part A of the Energy Conservation and Existing Buildings Act of 1976 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6861</ref> and following);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the programs under part D of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (relating to primary and supplemental State energy conservation programs; <ref>42 U.S.C. 6321</ref> and following);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the program under part G of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (relating to energy conservation for schools and hospitals; <ref>42 U.S.C. 6371</ref> and following); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the program under the National Energy Extension Service Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 7001</ref> and following).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “person” includes refiners, retailers, resellers, farmer cooperatives, transportation entities, public and private utilities, school districts, Federal, State, and local governmental entities, farmers, and other individuals and their successors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3008</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1887</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>