<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29—</num>
<heading>MANUFACTURE, TRANSPORTATION, OR DISTRIBUTION OF SWITCHBLADE KNIVES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1241.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The term “interstate commerce” means commerce between any State, Territory, possession of the United States, or the District of Columbia, and any place outside thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The term “switchblade knife” means any knife having a blade which opens automatically—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by hand pressure applied to a button or other device in the handle of the knife, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by operation of inertia, gravity, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–623, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1242.</num>
<heading> Introduction, manufacture for introduction, transportation or distribution in interstate commerce; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly introduces, or manufactures for introduction, into interstate commerce, or transports or distributes in interstate commerce, any switchblade knife, shall be fined not more than $2,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–623, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1243.</num>
<heading> Manufacture, sale, or possession within specific jurisdictions; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within any Territory or possession of the United States, within Indian country (as defined in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>), or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States (as defined in <ref>section 7 of title 18</ref>), manufactures, sells, or possesses any switchblade knife, shall be fined not more than $2,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–623, § 3</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1244.</num>
<heading> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Sections 1242 and 1243 of this title shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any common carrier or contract carrier, with respect to any switchblade knife shipped, transported, or delivered for shipment in interstate commerce in the ordinary course of business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the manufacture, sale, transportation, distribution, possession, or introduction into interstate commerce, of switchblade knives pursuant to contract with the Armed Forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Armed Forces or any member or employee thereof acting in the performance of his duty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the possession, and transportation upon his person, of any switchblade knife with a blade three inches or less in length by any individual who has only one arm; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a knife that contains a spring, detent, or other mechanism designed to create a bias toward closure of the blade and that requires exertion applied to the blade by hand, wrist, or arm to overcome the bias toward closure to assist in opening the knife.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–623, § 4</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–83, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1245.</num>
<heading> Ballistic knives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition and penalties for possession, manufacture, sale, or importation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever in or affecting interstate commerce, within any Territory or possession of the United States, within Indian country (as defined in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>), or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States (as defined in <ref>section 7 of title 18</ref>), knowingly possesses, manufactures, sells, or imports a ballistic knife shall be fined as provided in title 18, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition and penalties for possession or use during commission of Federal crime of violence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever possesses or uses a ballistic knife in the commission of a Federal crime of violence shall be fined as provided in title 18, or imprisoned not less than five years and not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The exceptions provided in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of <ref>section 1244 of this title</ref> with respect to switchblade knives shall apply to ballistic knives under subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Ballistic knife” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “ballistic knife” means a knife with a detachable blade that is propelled by a spring-operated mechanism.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–623, § 7</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title X, § 10002</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–167</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6472</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>