<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 94—</num>
<heading>PRIVACY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DISCLOSURE OF NONPUBLIC PERSONAL INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6801.</num>
<heading> Protection of nonpublic personal information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privacy obligation policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Congress that each financial institution has an affirmative and continuing obligation to respect the privacy of its customers and to protect the security and confidentiality of those customers’ nonpublic personal information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial institutions safeguards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In furtherance of the policy in subsection (a), each agency or authority described in <ref>section 6805(a) of this title</ref>, other than the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, shall establish appropriate standards for the financial institutions subject to their jurisdiction relating to administrative, technical, and physical safeguards—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to insure the security and confidentiality of customer records and information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to the security or integrity of such records; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to protect against unauthorized access to or use of such records or information which could result in substantial harm or inconvenience to any customer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1093(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6802.</num>
<heading> Obligations with respect to disclosures of personal information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, a financial institution may not, directly or through any affiliate, disclose to a nonaffiliated third party any nonpublic personal information, unless such financial institution provides or has provided to the consumer a notice that complies with <ref>section 6803 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Opt out</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A financial institution may not disclose nonpublic personal information to a nonaffiliated third party unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such financial institution clearly and conspicuously discloses to the consumer, in writing or in electronic form or other form permitted by the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804 of this title</ref>, that such information may be disclosed to such third party;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the consumer is given the opportunity, before the time that such information is initially disclosed, to direct that such information not be disclosed to such third party; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the consumer is given an explanation of how the consumer can exercise that nondisclosure option.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection shall not prevent a financial institution from providing nonpublic personal information to a nonaffiliated third party to perform services for or functions on behalf of the financial institution, including marketing of the financial institution’s own products or services, or financial products or services offered pursuant to joint agreements between two or more financial institutions that comply with the requirements imposed by the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804 of this title</ref>, if the financial institution fully discloses the providing of such information and enters into a contractual agreement with the third party that requires the third party to maintain the confidentiality of such information.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limits on reuse of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, a nonaffiliated third party that receives from a financial institution nonpublic personal information under this section shall not, directly or through an affiliate of such receiving third party, disclose such information to any other person that is a nonaffiliated third party of both the financial institution and such receiving third party, unless such disclosure would be lawful if made directly to such other person by the financial institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on the sharing of account number information for marketing purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A financial institution shall not disclose, other than to a consumer reporting agency, an account number or similar form of access number or access code for a credit card account, deposit account, or transaction account of a consumer to any nonaffiliated third party for use in telemarketing, direct mail marketing, or other marketing through electronic mail to the consumer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsections (a) and (b) shall not prohibit the disclosure of nonpublic personal information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> as necessary to effect, administer, or enforce a transaction requested or authorized by the consumer, or in connection with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> servicing or processing a financial product or service requested or authorized by the consumer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maintaining or servicing the consumer’s account with the financial institution, or with another entity as part of a private label credit card program or other extension of credit on behalf of such entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a proposed or actual securitization, secondary market sale (including sales of servicing rights), or similar transaction related to a transaction of the consumer;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with the consent or at the direction of the consumer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to protect the confidentiality or security of the financial institution’s records pertaining to the consumer, the service or product, or the transaction therein; (B) to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims, or other liability; (C) for required institutional risk control, or for resolving customer disputes or inquiries; (D) to persons holding a legal or beneficial interest relating to the consumer; or (E) to persons acting in a fiduciary or representative capacity on behalf of the consumer;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to provide information to insurance rate advisory organizations, guaranty funds or agencies, applicable rating agencies of the financial institution, persons assessing the institution’s compliance with industry standards, and the institution’s attorneys, accountants, and auditors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to the extent specifically permitted or required under other provisions of law and in accordance with the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.], to law enforcement agencies (including the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002559">1</ref> a Federal functional regulator, the Secretary of the Treasury with respect to subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31, and chapter 2 of title I of <ref>Public Law 91–508</ref> (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1951–195</ref>9), a State insurance authority, or the Federal Trade Commission), self-regulatory organizations, or for an investigation on a matter related to public safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with the Fair Credit Reporting Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.], or (B) from a consumer report reported by a consumer reporting agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> in connection with a proposed or actual sale, merger, transfer, or exchange of all or a portion of a business or operating unit if the disclosure of nonpublic personal information concerns solely consumers of such business or unit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to comply with Federal, State, or local laws, rules, and other applicable legal requirements; to comply with a properly authorized civil, criminal, or regulatory investigation or subpoena or summons by Federal, State, or local authorities; or to respond to judicial process or government regulatory authorities having jurisdiction over the financial institution for examination, compliance, or other purposes as authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1093(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6803.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of institution privacy policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">At the time of establishing a customer relationship with a consumer and not less than annually during the continuation of such relationship, a financial institution shall provide a clear and conspicuous disclosure to such consumer, in writing or in electronic form or other form permitted by the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804 of this title</ref>, of such financial institution’s policies and practices with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disclosing nonpublic personal information to affiliates and nonaffiliated third parties, consistent with <ref>section 6802 of this title</ref>, including the categories of information that may be disclosed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disclosing nonpublic personal information of persons who have ceased to be customers of the financial institution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> protecting the nonpublic personal information of consumers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disclosures required by subsection (a) shall be made in accordance with the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The disclosure required by subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the policies and practices of the institution with respect to disclosing nonpublic personal information to nonaffiliated third parties, other than agents of the institution, consistent with <ref>section 6802 of this title</ref>, and including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the categories of persons to whom the information is or may be disclosed, other than the persons to whom the information may be provided pursuant to <ref>section 6802(e) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the policies and practices of the institution with respect to disclosing of nonpublic personal information of persons who have ceased to be customers of the financial institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the categories of nonpublic personal information that are collected by the financial institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the policies that the institution maintains to protect the confidentiality and security of nonpublic personal information in accordance with <ref>section 6801 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the disclosures required, if any, under <ref>section 1681a(d)(2)(A)(iii) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for certified public accountants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The disclosure requirements of subsection (a) do not apply to any person, to the extent that the person is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a certified public accountant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certified or licensed for such purpose by a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> subject to any provision of law, rule, or regulation issued by a legislative or regulatory body of the State, including rules of professional conduct or ethics, that prohibits disclosure of nonpublic personal information without the knowing and expressed consent of the consumer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to exempt or otherwise exclude any financial institution that is affiliated or becomes affiliated with a certified public accountant described in paragraph (1) from any provision of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “State” means any State or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, or the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Model forms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The agencies referred to in <ref>section 6804(a)(1) of this title</ref> shall jointly develop a model form which may be used, at the option of the financial institution, for the provision of disclosures under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Format</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A model form developed under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be comprehensible to consumers, with a clear format and design;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for clear and conspicuous disclosures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enable consumers easily to identify the sharing practices of a financial institution and to compare privacy practices among financial institutions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> be succinct, and use an easily readable type font.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A model form required to be developed by this subsection shall be issued in proposed form for public comment not later than 180 days after <date date="2006-10-13">October 13, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safe harbor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any financial institution that elects to provide the model form developed by the agencies under this subsection shall be deemed to be in compliance with the disclosures required under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to annual notice requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A financial institution that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides nonpublic personal information only in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(2) or (e) of <ref>section 6802 of this title</ref> or regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804(b) of this title</ref>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has not changed its policies and practices with regard to disclosing nonpublic personal information from the policies and practices that were disclosed in the most recent disclosure sent to consumers in accordance with this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall not be required to provide an annual disclosure under this section until such time as the financial institution fails to comply with any criteria described in paragraph (1) or (2).</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–351, title VI, § 609</ref>, title VII, § 728, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1983</ref>, 2003; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. G, title LXXV, § 75001</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1787</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6804.</num>
<heading> Rulemaking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rulemaking</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection and the Securities and Exchange Commission shall have authority to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter with respect to financial institutions and other persons subject to their respective jurisdiction under <ref>section 6805 of this title</ref> (and notwithstanding subtitle B of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 5511</ref> et seq.]), except that the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall not have authority to prescribe regulations with respect to the standards under <ref>section 6801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CFTC</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commodity Futures Trading Commission shall have authority to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter with respect to financial institutions and other persons subject to the jurisdiction of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission under <ref>section 7b–2 of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Trade Commission authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding the authority of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection under subparagraph (A), the Federal Trade Commission shall have authority to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter with respect to any financial institution that is a person described in section 1029(a) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 5519(a)</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to alter, affect, or otherwise limit the authority of a State insurance authority to adopt regulations to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination, consistency, and comparability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each of the agencies authorized under paragraph (1) to prescribe regulations shall consult and coordinate with the other such agencies and, as appropriate, and with <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002560">1</ref> representatives of State insurance authorities designated by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, for the purpose of assuring, to the extent possible, that the regulations prescribed by each such agency are consistent and comparable with the regulations prescribed by the other such agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures and deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such regulations shall be prescribed in accordance with applicable requirements of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to grant exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) may include such additional exceptions to subsections (a) through (d) of <ref>section 6802 of this title</ref> as are deemed consistent with the purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1093(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6805.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subtitle B of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 5511</ref> et seq.], this subchapter and the regulations prescribed thereunder shall be enforced by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Federal functional regulators, the State insurance authorities, and the Federal Trade Commission with respect to financial institutions and other persons subject to their jurisdiction under applicable law, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under <ref>section 1818 of title 12</ref>, by the appropriate Federal banking agency, as defined in <ref>section 1813(q) of title 12</ref>, in the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> national banks, Federal branches and Federal agencies of foreign banks, and any subsidiaries of such entities (except brokers, dealers, persons providing insurance, investment companies, and investment advisers);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> member banks of the Federal Reserve System (other than national banks), branches and agencies of foreign banks (other than Federal branches, Federal agencies, and insured State branches of foreign banks), commercial lending companies owned or controlled by foreign banks, organizations operating under section 25 or 25A of the Federal Reserve Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq., 611 et seq.], and bank holding companies and their nonbank subsidiaries or affiliates (except brokers, dealers, persons providing insurance, investment companies, and investment advisers);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> banks insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than members of the Federal Reserve System), insured State branches of foreign banks, and any subsidiaries of such entities (except brokers, dealers, persons providing insurance, investment companies, and investment advisers); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> savings associations the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and any subsidiaries of such savings associations (except brokers, dealers, persons providing insurance, investment companies, and investment advisers).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under the Federal Credit Union Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.], by the Board of the National Credit Union Administration with respect to any federally insured credit union, and any subsidiaries of such an entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.], by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to any broker or dealer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Under the Investment Company Act of 1940 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 80a–1</ref> et seq.], by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to investment companies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 80b–1</ref> et seq.], by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to investment advisers registered with the Commission under such Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Under State insurance law, in the case of any person engaged in providing insurance, by the applicable State insurance authority of the State in which the person is domiciled, subject to <ref>section 6701 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.], by the Federal Trade Commission for any other financial institution or other person that is not subject to the jurisdiction of any agency or authority under paragraphs (1) through (6) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Under subtitle E of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 5561</ref> et seq.], by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in the case of any financial institution and other covered person or service provider that is subject to the jurisdiction of the Bureau and any person subject to this subchapter, but not with respect to the standards under <ref>section 6801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement of section 6801</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the agencies and authorities described in subsection (a), other than the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, shall implement the standards prescribed under <ref>section 6801(b) of this title</ref> in the same manner, to the extent practicable, as standards prescribed pursuant to <ref>section 1831p–1(a) of title 12</ref> are implemented pursuant to such section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The agencies and authorities described in paragraphs (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7) of subsection (a) shall implement the standards prescribed under <ref>section 6801(b) of this title</ref> by rule with respect to the financial institutions and other persons subject to their respective jurisdictions under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Absence of State action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a State insurance authority fails to adopt regulations to carry out this subchapter, such State shall not be eligible to override, pursuant to <ref>section 1831x(g)(2)(B)(iii) of title 12</ref>, the insurance customer protection regulations prescribed by a Federal banking agency under <ref>section 1831x(a) of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The terms used in subsection (a)(1) that are not defined in this subchapter or otherwise defined in <ref>section 1813(s) of title 12</ref> shall have the same meaning as given in <ref>section 3101 of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1093(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2096</ref>, 2097.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6806.</num>
<heading> Relation to other provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b), nothing in this chapter shall be construed to modify, limit, or supersede the operation of the Fair Credit Reporting Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.], and no inference shall be drawn on the basis of the provisions of this chapter regarding whether information is transaction or experience information under section 603 of such Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1681a</ref>].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 506(c)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6807.</num>
<heading> Relation to State laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter and the amendments made by this subchapter shall not be construed as superseding, altering, or affecting any statute, regulation, order, or interpretation in effect in any State, except to the extent that such statute, regulation, order, or interpretation is inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Greater protection under State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, a State statute, regulation, order, or interpretation is not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter if the protection such statute, regulation, order, or interpretation affords any person is greater than the protection provided under this subchapter and the amendments made by this subchapter, as determined by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, after consultation with the agency or authority with jurisdiction under <ref>section 6805(a) of this title</ref> of either the person that initiated the complaint or that is the subject of the complaint, on its own motion or upon the petition of any interested party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1093(6)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6808.</num>
<heading> Study of information sharing among financial affiliates</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury, in conjunction with the Federal functional regulators and the Federal Trade Commission, shall conduct a study of information sharing practices among financial institutions and their affiliates. Such study shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the purposes for the sharing of confidential customer information with affiliates or with nonaffiliated third parties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the extent and adequacy of security protections for such information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the potential risks for customer privacy of such sharing of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the potential benefits for financial institutions and affiliates of such sharing of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the potential benefits for customers of such sharing of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the adequacy of existing laws to protect customer privacy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the adequacy of financial institution privacy policy and privacy rights disclosure under existing law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the feasibility of different approaches, including opt-out and opt-in, to permit customers to direct that confidential information not be shared with affiliates and nonaffiliated third parties; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the feasibility of restricting sharing of information for specific uses or of permitting customers to direct the uses for which information may be shared.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult with representatives of State insurance authorities designated by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, and also with financial services industry, consumer organizations and privacy groups, and other representatives of the general public, in formulating and conducting the study required by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or before <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress containing the findings and conclusions of the study required under subsection (a), together with such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as may be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 508</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6809.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal banking agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal banking agency” has the same meaning as given in <ref>section 1813 of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal functional regulator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal functional regulator” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the National Credit Union Administration Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Securities and Exchange Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial institution</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “financial institution” means any institution the business of which is engaging in financial activities as described in <ref>section 1843(k) of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons subject to CFTC regulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the term “financial institution” does not include any person or entity with respect to any financial activity that is subject to the jurisdiction of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission under the Commodity Exchange Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Farm credit institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the term “financial institution” does not include the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation or any entity chartered and operating under the Farm Credit Act of 1971 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other secondary market institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the term “financial institution” does not include institutions chartered by Congress specifically to engage in transactions described in <ref>section 6802(e)(1)(C) of this title</ref>, as long as such institutions do not sell or transfer nonpublic personal information to a nonaffiliated third party.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonpublic personal information</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “nonpublic personal information” means personally identifiable financial information—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provided by a consumer to a financial institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> resulting from any transaction with the consumer or any service performed for the consumer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> otherwise obtained by the financial institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such term does not include publicly available information, as such term is defined by the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), such term—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall include any list, description, or other grouping of consumers (and publicly available information pertaining to them) that is derived using any nonpublic personal information other than publicly available information; but</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not include any list, description, or other grouping of consumers (and publicly available information pertaining to them) that is derived without using any nonpublic personal information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonaffiliated third party</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “nonaffiliated third party” means any entity that is not an affiliate of, or related by common ownership or affiliated by corporate control with, the financial institution, but does not include a joint employee of such institution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affiliate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “affiliate” means any company that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another company.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Necessary to effect, administer, or enforce</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “as necessary to effect, administer, or enforce the transaction” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the disclosure is required, or is a usual, appropriate, or acceptable method, to carry out the transaction or the product or service business of which the transaction is a part, and record or service or maintain the consumer’s account in the ordinary course of providing the financial service or financial product, or to administer or service benefits or claims relating to the transaction or the product or service business of which it is a part, and includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> providing the consumer or the consumer’s agent or broker with a confirmation, statement, or other record of the transaction, or information on the status or value of the financial service or financial product; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the accrual or recognition of incentives or bonuses associated with the transaction that are provided by the financial institution or any other party;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the disclosure is required, or is one of the lawful or appropriate methods, to enforce the rights of the financial institution or of other persons engaged in carrying out the financial transaction, or providing the product or service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the disclosure is required, or is a usual, appropriate, or acceptable method, for insurance underwriting at the consumer’s request or for reinsurance purposes, or for any of the following purposes as they relate to a consumer’s insurance: Account administration, reporting, investigating, or preventing fraud or material misrepresentation, processing premium payments, processing insurance claims, administering insurance benefits (including utilization review activities), participating in research projects, or as otherwise required or specifically permitted by Federal or State law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the disclosure is required, or is a usual, appropriate or acceptable method, in connection with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the authorization, settlement, billing, processing, clearing, transferring, reconciling, or collection of amounts charged, debited, or otherwise paid using a debit, credit or other payment card, check, or account number, or by other payment means;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the transfer of receivables, accounts or interests therein; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the audit of debit, credit or other payment information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State insurance authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State insurance authority” means, in the case of any person engaged in providing insurance, the State insurance authority of the State in which the person is domiciled.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consumer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “consumer” means an individual who obtains, from a financial institution, financial products or services which are to be used primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, and also means the legal representative of such an individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “joint agreement” means a formal written contract pursuant to which two or more financial institutions jointly offer, endorse, or sponsor a financial product or service, and as may be further defined in the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Customer relationship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “time of establishing a customer relationship” shall be defined by the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 6804 of this title</ref>, and shall, in the case of a financial institution engaged in extending credit directly to consumers to finance purchases of goods or services, mean the time of establishing the credit relationship with the consumer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1443</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>FRAUDULENT ACCESS TO FINANCIAL INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6821.</num>
<heading> Privacy protection for customer information of financial institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on obtaining customer information by false pretenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be a violation of this subchapter for any person to obtain or attempt to obtain, or cause to be disclosed or attempt to cause to be disclosed to any person, customer information of a financial institution relating to another person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to an officer, employee, or agent of a financial institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to a customer of a financial institution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by providing any document to an officer, employee, or agent of a financial institution, knowing that the document is forged, counterfeit, lost, or stolen, was fraudulently obtained, or contains a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on solicitation of a person to obtain customer information from financial institution under false pretenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be a violation of this subchapter to request a person to obtain customer information of a financial institution, knowing that the person will obtain, or attempt to obtain, the information from the institution in any manner described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability to law enforcement agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this section shall be construed so as to prevent any action by a law enforcement agency, or any officer, employee, or agent of such agency, to obtain customer information of a financial institution in connection with the performance of the official duties of the agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability to financial institutions in certain cases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No provision of this section shall be construed so as to prevent any financial institution, or any officer, employee, or agent of a financial institution, from obtaining customer information of such financial institution in the course of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> testing the security procedures or systems of such institution for maintaining the confidentiality of customer information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> investigating allegations of misconduct or negligence on the part of any officer, employee, or agent of the financial institution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recovering customer information of the financial institution which was obtained or received by another person in any manner described in subsection (a) or (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability to insurance institutions for investigation of insurance fraud</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this section shall be construed so as to prevent any insurance institution, or any officer, employee, or agency of an insurance institution, from obtaining information as part of an insurance investigation into criminal activity, fraud, material misrepresentation, or material nondisclosure that is authorized for such institution under State law, regulation, interpretation, or order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability to certain types of customer information of financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this section shall be construed so as to prevent any person from obtaining customer information of a financial institution that otherwise is available as a public record filed pursuant to the securities laws (as defined in <ref>section 78c(a)(47) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability to collection of child support judgments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this section shall be construed to prevent any State-licensed private investigator, or any officer, employee, or agent of such private investigator, from obtaining customer information of a financial institution, to the extent reasonably necessary to collect child support from a person adjudged to have been delinquent in his or her obligations by a Federal or State court, and to the extent that such action by a State-licensed private investigator is not unlawful under any other Federal or State law or regulation, and has been authorized by an order or judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6822.</num>
<heading> Administrative enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), compliance with this subchapter shall be enforced by the Federal Trade Commission in the same manner and with the same power and authority as the Commission has under the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1692</ref> et seq.] to enforce compliance with such Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement by other agencies in certain cases</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Compliance with this subchapter shall be enforced under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1818</ref>], in the case of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> national banks, and Federal branches and Federal agencies of foreign banks, by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> member banks of the Federal Reserve System (other than national banks), branches and agencies of foreign banks (other than Federal branches, Federal agencies, and insured State branches of foreign banks), commercial lending companies owned or controlled by foreign banks, and organizations operating under section 25 or 25A of the Federal Reserve Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq., 611 et seq.], by the Board;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> banks insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than members of the Federal Reserve System and national nonmember banks) and insured State branches of foreign banks, by the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> savings associations the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, by the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Federal Credit Union Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.], by the Administrator of the National Credit Union Administration with respect to any Federal credit union.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations of this subchapter treated as violations of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purpose of the exercise by any agency referred to in paragraph (1) of its powers under any Act referred to in that paragraph, a violation of this subchapter shall be deemed to be a violation of a requirement imposed under that Act. In addition to its powers under any provision of law specifically referred to in paragraph (1), each of the agencies referred to in that paragraph may exercise, for the purpose of enforcing compliance with this subchapter, any other authority conferred on such agency by law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 522</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1447</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6823.</num>
<heading> Criminal penalty</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and intentionally violates, or knowingly and intentionally attempts to violate, <ref>section 6821 of this title</ref> shall be fined in accordance with title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enhanced penalty for aggravated cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever violates, or attempts to violate, <ref>section 6821 of this title</ref> while violating another law of the United States or as part of a pattern of any illegal activity involving more than $100,000 in a 12-month period shall be fined twice the amount provided in subsection (b)(3) or (c)(3) (as the case may be) of <ref>section 3571 of title 18</ref>, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 523</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6824.</num>
<heading> Relation to State laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter shall not be construed as superseding, altering, or affecting the statutes, regulations, orders, or interpretations in effect in any State, except to the extent that such statutes, regulations, orders, or interpretations are inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Greater protection under State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, a State statute, regulation, order, or interpretation is not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter if the protection such statute, regulation, order, or interpretation affords any person is greater than the protection provided under this subchapter as determined by the Federal Trade Commission, after consultation with the agency or authority with jurisdiction under <ref>section 6822 of this title</ref> of either the person that initiated the complaint or that is the subject of the complaint, on its own motion or upon the petition of any interested party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 524</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6825.</num>
<heading> Agency guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In furtherance of the objectives of this subchapter, each Federal banking agency (as defined in <ref>section 1813(z) of title 12</ref>), the National Credit Union Administration, and the Securities and Exchange Commission or self-regulatory organizations, as appropriate, shall review regulations and guidelines applicable to financial institutions under their respective jurisdictions and shall prescribe such revisions to such regulations and guidelines as may be necessary to ensure that such financial institutions have policies, procedures, and controls in place to prevent the unauthorized disclosure of customer financial information and to deter and detect activities proscribed under <ref>section 6821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 525</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6826.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to the Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Before the end of the 18-month period beginning on <date date="1999-11-12">November 12, 1999</date>, the Comptroller General, in consultation with the Federal Trade Commission, Federal banking agencies, the National Credit Union Administration, the Securities and Exchange Commission, appropriate Federal law enforcement agencies, and appropriate State insurance regulators, shall submit to the Congress a report on the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The efficacy and adequacy of the remedies provided in this subchapter in addressing attempts to obtain financial information by fraudulent means or by false pretenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any recommendations for additional legislative or regulatory action to address threats to the privacy of financial information created by attempts to obtain information by fraudulent means or false pretenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report by administering agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission and the Attorney General shall submit to Congress an annual report on number and disposition of all enforcement actions taken pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 526</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6827.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Customer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “customer” means, with respect to a financial institution, any person (or authorized representative of a person) to whom the financial institution provides a product or service, including that of acting as a fiduciary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Customer information of a financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “customer information of a financial institution” means any information maintained by or for a financial institution which is derived from the relationship between the financial institution and a customer of the financial institution and is identified with the customer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Document</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “document” means any information in any form.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial institution</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “financial institution” means any institution engaged in the business of providing financial services to customers who maintain a credit, deposit, trust, or other financial account or relationship with the institution.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain financial institutions specifically included</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “financial institution” includes any depository institution (as defined in <ref>section 461(b)(1)(A) of title 12</ref>), any broker or dealer, any investment adviser or investment company, any insurance company, any loan or finance company, any credit card issuer or operator of a credit card system, and any consumer reporting agency that compiles and maintains files on consumers on a nationwide basis (as defined in <ref>section 1681a(p) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Securities institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the terms “broker” and “dealer” have the same meanings as given in <ref>section 78c of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the term “investment adviser” has the same meaning as given in <ref>section 80b–2(a)(11) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the term “investment company” has the same meaning as given in <ref>section 80a–3 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain persons and entities specifically excluded</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “financial institution” does not include any person or entity with respect to any financial activity that is subject to the jurisdiction of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission under the Commodity Exchange Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.] and does not include the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation or any entity chartered and operating under the Farm Credit Act of 1971 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further definition by regulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal Trade Commission, after consultation with Federal banking agencies and the Securities and Exchange Commission, may prescribe regulations clarifying or describing the types of institutions which shall be treated as financial institutions for purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title V, § 527</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>