<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 118—</num>
<heading>SUSTAINABLE CHEMISTRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9301.</num>
<heading> National coordinating entity for sustainable chemistry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall convene an interagency entity (referred to in this chapter as the “Entity”) under the National Science and Technology Council with the responsibility to coordinate Federal programs and activities in support of sustainable chemistry, including those described in sections 9303 and 9304 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with existing groups</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In convening the Entity, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall consider overlap and possible coordination with existing committees, subcommittees, or other groups of the National Science and Technology Council, such as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Science; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> related groups or subcommittees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Co-chairs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Entity shall be co-chaired by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and a representative from the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the National Science Foundation, or the Department of Energy, as selected by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Entity shall include representatives, including subject matter experts, from the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the National Science Foundation, the Department of Energy, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Defense, the National Institutes of Health, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Food and Drug Administration, and other related Federal agencies, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Entity shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 261</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9302.</num>
<heading> Strategic plan for sustainable chemistry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Entity shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with relevant stakeholders, including representatives from industry, academia, national labs, the Federal Government, and international entities, to develop and update, as needed, a consensus definition of “sustainable chemistry” to guide the activities under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop a working framework of attributes characterizing, and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry, as described in subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assess the state of sustainable chemistry in the United States as a key benchmark from which progress under the activities described in this chapter can be measured, including assessing key sectors of the United States economy, key technology platforms, commercial priorities, and barriers to innovation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordinate and support Federal research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, commercialization, education, and training efforts in sustainable chemistry, including budget coordination and support for public-private partnerships, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> identify any Federal regulatory barriers to, and opportunities for, Federal agencies facilitating the development of incentives for development, consideration, and use of sustainable chemistry processes and products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> identify major scientific challenges, roadblocks, and hurdles to transformational progress in improving the sustainability of the chemical sciences; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> review, identify, and make effort to eliminate duplicative Federal funding and duplicative Federal research in sustainable chemistry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Characterizing and assessing sustainable chemistry</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Entity shall develop a working framework of attributes characterizing, and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry for the purposes of carrying out this chapter. In developing this framework, the Entity shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> seek advice and input from stakeholders as described in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consider existing definitions of, or frameworks characterizing and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry already in use at Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> consider existing definitions of, or frameworks characterizing and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry already in use by international organizations of which the United States is a member, such as the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> consider any other appropriate existing definitions of, or frameworks characterizing and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the duties described in subsections (a) and (b), the Entity shall consult with stakeholders qualified to provide advice and information to guide Federal activities related to sustainable chemistry through workshops, requests for information, or other mechanisms as necessary. The stakeholders shall include representatives from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> business and industry, including trade associations and small- and medium-sized enterprises from across the value chain;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the scientific community, including the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, scientific professional societies, national labs, and academia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the defense community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> State, tribal, and local governments, including nonregulatory State or regional sustainable chemistry programs, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> nongovernmental organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other appropriate organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Entity shall submit a report to the Committee on Environment and Public Works, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Agriculture, the Committee on Education and Labor, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives. In addition to the elements described in subsections (a) and (b), the report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of federally funded sustainable chemistry research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, commercialization, education, and training activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the financial resources allocated to sustainable chemistry initiatives by each participating agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the current state of sustainable chemistry in the United States, including the role that Federal agencies are playing in supporting it;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an analysis of the progress made toward achieving the goals and priorities of this chapter, and recommendations for future program activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an evaluation of steps taken and future strategies to avoid duplication of efforts, streamline interagency coordination, facilitate information sharing, and spread best practices among participating agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an evaluation of duplicative Federal funding and duplicative Federal research in sustainable chemistry, efforts undertaken by the Entity to eliminate duplicative funding and research, and recommendations on how to achieve these goals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to GAO</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Entity shall also submit the report described in paragraph (1) to the Comptroller General of the United States for consideration in future Congressional inquiries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Entity shall submit a report to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States that incorporates the information described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (D), (E), and (F) of paragraph (1) every 3 years, commencing after the initial report is submitted until the Entity terminates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 262</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9303.</num>
<heading> Agency activities in support of sustainable chemistry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The agencies participating in the Entity shall carry out activities in support of sustainable chemistry, as appropriate to the specific mission and programs of each agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The activities described in subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> incorporate sustainable chemistry into existing research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, commercialization, education, and training programs, that the agency determines to be relevant, including consideration of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> merit-based competitive grants to individual investigators and teams of investigators, including, to the extent practicable, early career investigators, for research and development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> grants to fund collaborative research and development partnerships among universities, industry, and nonprofit organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordination of sustainable chemistry research, development, demonstration, and technology transfer conducted at Federal laboratories and agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> incentive prize competitions and challenges in coordination with such existing Federal agency programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> grants, loans, and loan guarantees to aid in the technology transfer and commercialization of sustainable chemicals, materials, processes, and products;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> collect and disseminate information on sustainable chemistry research, development, technology transfer, and commercialization, including information on accomplishments and best practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> expand the education and training of students at appropriate levels of education, professional scientists and engineers, and other professionals involved in all aspects of sustainable chemistry and engineering appropriate to that level of education and training, including through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> partnerships with industry as described in <ref>section 9304 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> support for the integration of sustainable chemistry principles into chemistry and chemical engineering curriculum and research training, as appropriate to that level of education and training; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> support for integration of sustainable chemistry principles into existing or new professional development opportunities for professionals including teachers, faculty, and individuals involved in laboratory research (product development, materials specification and testing, life cycle analysis, and management);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> as relevant to an agency’s programs, examine methods by which the Federal agencies, in collaboration and consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, may facilitate the development or recognition of validated, standardized tools for performing sustainability assessments of chemistry processes or products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> through programs identified by an agency, support, including through technical assistance, participation, financial support, communications tools, awards, or other forms of support, outreach and dissemination of sustainable chemistry advances such as non-Federal symposia, forums, conferences, and publications in collaboration with, as appropriate, industry, academia, scientific and professional societies, and other relevant groups;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide for public input and outreach to be integrated into the activities described in this section by the convening of public discussions, through mechanisms such as public meetings, consensus conferences, and educational events, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> within each agency, develop or adapt metrics to track the outputs and outcomes of the programs supported by that agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> incentivize or recognize actions that advance sustainable chemistry products, processes, or initiatives, including through the establishment of a nationally recognized awards program through the Environmental Protection Agency to identify, publicize, and celebrate innovations in sustainable chemistry and chemical technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Financial support provided under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be available only for pre-competitive activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not be used to promote the sale of a specific product, process, or technology, or to disparage a specific product, process, or technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 263</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9304.</num>
<heading> Partnerships in sustainable chemistry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The agencies participating in the Entity may facilitate and support, through financial, technical, or other assistance, the creation of partnerships between institutions of higher education, nongovernmental organizations, consortia, or companies across the value chain in the chemical industry, including small- and medium-sized enterprises, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> create collaborative sustainable chemistry research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, and commercialization programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> train students and retrain professional scientists, engineers, and others involved in materials specification on the use of sustainable chemistry concepts and strategies by methods, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> developing or recognizing curricular materials and courses for undergraduate and graduate levels and for the professional development of scientists, engineers, and others involved in materials specification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> publicizing the availability of professional development courses in sustainable chemistry and recruiting professionals to pursue such courses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private sector participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be eligible for support under this section, a partnership in sustainable chemistry shall include at least one private sector organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of partnerships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In selecting partnerships for support under this section, the agencies participating in the Entity shall also consider the extent to which the applicants are willing and able to demonstrate evidence of support for, and commitment to, the goals outlined in the strategic plan and report described in <ref>section 9302 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Financial support provided under this section may not be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support or expand a regulatory chemical management program at an implementing agency under a State law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to construct or renovate a building or structure; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to promote the sale of a specific product, process, or technology, or to disparage a specific product, process, or technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 264</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9305.</num>
<heading> Prioritization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Entity shall focus its support for sustainable chemistry activities on those that achieve, to the highest extent practicable, the goals outlined in the chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 265</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9306.</num>
<heading> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to alter or amend any State law or action with regard to sustainable chemistry, as defined by the State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 266</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>