<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 67—</num>
<heading>ARCTIC RESEARCH AND POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4101.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Arctic, onshore and offshore, contains vital energy resources that can reduce the Nation’s dependence on foreign oil and improve the national balance of payments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Arctic is critical to national defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the renewable resources of the Arctic, specifically fish and other seafood, represent one of the Nation’s greatest commercial assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Arctic conditions directly affect global weather patterns and must be understood in order to promote better agricultural management throughout the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> industrial pollution not originating in the Arctic region collects in the polar air mass, has the potential to disrupt global weather patterns, and must be controlled through international cooperation and consultation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Arctic is a natural laboratory for research into human health and adaptation, physical and psychological, to climates of extreme cold and isolation and may provide information crucial for future defense needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> atmospheric conditions peculiar to the Arctic make the Arctic a unique testing ground for research into high latitude communications, which is likely to be crucial for future defense needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Arctic marine technology is critical to cost-effective recovery and transportation of energy resources and to the national defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the United States has important security, economic, and environmental interests in developing and maintaining a fleet of icebreaking vessels capable of operating effectively in the heavy ice regions of the Arctic;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> most Arctic-rim countries possess Arctic technologies far more advanced than those currently available in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Federal Arctic research is fragmented and uncoordinated at the present time, leading to the neglect of certain areas of research and to unnecessary duplication of effort in other areas of research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> improved logistical coordination and support for Arctic research and better dissemination of research data and information is necessary to increase the efficiency and utility of national Arctic research efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> a comprehensive national policy and program plan to organize and fund currently neglected scientific research with respect to the Arctic is necessary to fulfill national objectives in Arctic research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the Federal Government, in cooperation with State and local governments, should focus its efforts on the collection and characterization of basic data related to biological, materials, geophysical, social, and behavioral phenomena in the Arctic;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> research into the long-range health, environmental, and social effects of development in the Arctic is necessary to mitigate the adverse consequences of that development to the land and its residents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Arctic research expands knowledge of the Arctic, which can enhance the lives of Arctic residents, increase opportunities for international cooperation among Arctic-rim countries, and facilitate the formulation of national policy for the Arctic; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> the Alaskan Arctic provides an essential habitat for marine mammals, migratory waterfowl, and other forms of wildlife which are important to the Nation and which are essential to Arctic residents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish national policy, priorities, and goals and to provide a Federal program plan for basic and applied scientific research with respect to the Arctic, including natural resources and materials, physical, biological and health sciences, and social and behavioral sciences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to establish an Arctic Research Commission to promote Arctic research and to recommend Arctic research policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to designate the National Science Foundation as the lead agency responsible for implementing Arctic research policy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to establish an Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee to develop a national Arctic research policy and a five year plan to implement that policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–199, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4102.</num>
<heading> Arctic Research Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish an Arctic Research Commission (hereafter referred to as the “Commission”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission shall be composed of seven members appointed by the President, with the Director of the National Science Foundation serving as a nonvoting, ex officio member. The members appointed by the President shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> four members appointed from among individuals from academic or other research institutions with expertise in areas of research relating to the Arctic, including the physical, biological, health, environmental, social, and behavioral sciences;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one member appointed from among indigenous residents of the Arctic who are representative of the needs and interests of Arctic residents and who live in areas directly affected by Arctic resource development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> two members appointed from among individuals familiar with the Arctic and representative of the needs and interests of private industry undertaking resource development in the Arctic.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President shall designate one of the appointed members of the Commission to be chairperson of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of office; vacancies; hold-over status</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the term of office of each member of the Commission appointed under subsection (b)(1) shall be four years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Of the members of the Commission originally appointed under subsection (b)(1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one shall be appointed for a term of two years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> two shall be appointed for a term of three years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> two shall be appointed for a term of four years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any vacancy occurring in the membership of the Commission shall be filled, after notice of the vacancy is published in the Federal Register, in the manner provided by the preceding provisions of this section, for the remainder of the unexpired term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A member may serve after the expiration of the member’s term of office until the President appoints a successor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A member may serve consecutive terms beyond the member’s original appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation and travel expenses; Federal employee status; meetings; observer-designees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Members of the Commission may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>. A member of the Commission not presently employed for compensation shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the rate for GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> for each day the member is engaged in the actual performance of his duties as a member of the Commission, not to exceed 90 days of service each year. Except for the purposes of chapter 81 of title 5 (relating to compensation for work injuries) and chapter 171 of title 28 (relating to tort claims), a member of the Commission shall not be considered an employee of the United States for any purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission shall meet at the call of its Chairman or a majority of its members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each Federal agency referred to in <ref>section 4106(b) of this title</ref> may designate a representative to participate as an observer with the Commission. These representatives shall report to and advise the Commission on the activities relating to Arctic research of their agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Commission shall conduct at least one public meeting in the State of Alaska annually.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–609</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4103.</num>
<heading> Duties of Commission; publication of guidelines; report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and recommend an integrated national Arctic research policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in cooperation with the Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee established under <ref>section 4106 of this title</ref>, assist in establishing a national Arctic research program plan to implement the Arctic research policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitate cooperation between the Federal Government and State and local governments with respect to Arctic research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> review Federal research programs in the Arctic and recommend improvements in coordination among programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> recommend methods to improve logistical planning and support for Arctic research as may be appropriate and in accordance with the findings and purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> recommend methods for improving efficient sharing and dissemination of data and information on the Arctic among interested public and private institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> offer other recommendations and advice to the Interagency Committee established under <ref>section 4106 of this title</ref> as it may find appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> cooperate with the Governor of the State of Alaska and with agencies and organizations of that State which the Governor may designate with respect to the formulation of Arctic research policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> recommend to the Interagency Committee the means for developing international scientific cooperation in the Arctic; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> not later than <date date="1991-01-31">January 31, 1991</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, publish a statement of goals and objectives with respect to Arctic research to guide the Interagency Committee established under <ref>section 4106 of this title</ref> in the performance of its duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Not later than January 31 of each year, the Commission shall submit to the President and to the Congress a report describing the activities and accomplishments of the Commission during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–609, § 4</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4104.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of information from Federal agencies; withholding authorization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission may acquire from the head of any Federal agency unclassified data, reports, and other nonproprietary information with respect to Arctic research in the possession of the agency which the Commission considers useful in the discharge of its duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each agency shall cooperate with the Commission and furnish all data, reports, and other information requested by the Commission to the extent permitted by law; except that no agency need furnish any information which it is permitted to withhold under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of facilities and services; reimbursement; avoidance of duplication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With the consent of the appropriate agency head, the Commission may utilize the facilities and services of any Federal agency to the extent that the facilities and services are needed for the establishment and development of an Arctic research policy, upon reimbursement to be agreed upon by the Commission and the agency head and taking every feasible step to avoid duplication of effort.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations with Commission prior to major Federal actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All Federal agencies shall consult with the Commission before undertaking major Federal actions relating to Arctic research.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4105.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in accordance with the civil service laws and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, appoint and fix the compensation of an Executive Director and necessary additional staff personnel, but not to exceed a total of seven compensated personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procure temporary and intermittent services as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enter into contracts and procure supplies, services, and personal property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> enter into agreements with the General Services Administration for the procurement of necessary financial and administrative services, for which payment shall be made by reimbursement from funds of the Commission in amounts to be agreed upon by the Commission and the Administrator of the General Services Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> appoint, and accept without compensation the services of, scientists and engineering specialists to be advisors to the Commission. Each advisor may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>. Except for the purposes of chapter 81 of title 5 (relating to compensation for work injuries) and chapter 171 of title 28 (relating to tort claims), an advisor appointed under this paragraph shall not be considered an employee of the United States for any purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–609, § 5</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4106.</num>
<heading> Implementation of Arctic research policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Science Foundation and Director; functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Science Foundation is designated as the lead agency responsible for implementing Arctic research policy, and the Director of the National Science Foundation shall insure that the requirements of <ref>section 4107 of this title</ref> are fulfilled.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee; establishment; represented agencies; Chairperson</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President shall establish an Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee (hereinafter referred to as the “Interagency Committee”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Interagency Committee shall be composed of representatives of the following Federal agencies or offices:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the National Science Foundation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Department of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Department of Energy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Department of the Interior;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Department of State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Department of Transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Department of Health and Human Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Department of Homeland Security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the Environmental Protection Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> any other agency or office deemed appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The representative of the National Science Foundation shall serve as the Chairperson of the Interagency Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 902(g)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4107.</num>
<heading> Duties of Interagency Committee; report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Interagency Committee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> survey Arctic research conducted by Federal, State, and local agencies, universities, and other public and private institutions to help determine priorities for future Arctic research, including natural resources and materials, physical and biological sciences, and social and behavioral sciences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> work with the Commission to develop and establish an integrated national Arctic research policy that will guide Federal agencies in developing and implementing their research programs in the Arctic;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> consult with the Commission on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the development of the national Arctic research policy and the 5-year plan implementing the policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Arctic research programs of Federal agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommendations of the Commission on future Arctic research; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> guidelines for Federal agencies for awarding and administering Arctic research grants;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop a 5-year plan to implement the national policy, as provided for in <ref>section 4108 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide the necessary coordination, data, and assistance for the preparation of a single integrated, coherent, and multiagency budget request for Arctic research as provided for in <ref>section 4109 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> facilitate cooperation between the Federal Government and State and local governments in Arctic research, and recommend the undertaking of neglected areas of research in accordance with the findings and purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> coordinate and promote cooperative Arctic scientific research programs with other nations, subject to the foreign policy guidance of the Secretary of State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> cooperate with the Governor of the State of Alaska in fulfilling its responsibilities under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> promote Federal interagency coordination of all Arctic research activities, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> logistical planning and coordination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the sharing of data and information associated with Arctic research, subject to <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> provide public notice of its meetings and an opportunity for the public to participate in the development and implementation of national Arctic research policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than <date date="1986-01-31">January 31, 1986</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Interagency Committee shall submit to the Congress through the President, a brief, concise report containing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a statement of the activities and accomplishments of the Interagency Committee since its last report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement detailing with particularity the recommendations of the Commission with respect to Federal interagency activities in Arctic research and the disposition and responses to those recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–609, § 6</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4108.</num>
<heading> Arctic research plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Interagency Committee, in consultation with the Commission, the Governor of the State of Alaska, the residents of the Arctic, the private sector, and public interest groups, shall prepare a comprehensive 5-year program plan (hereinafter referred to as the “Plan”) for the overall Federal effort in Arctic research. The Plan shall be prepared and submitted to the President for transmittal to the Congress within one year after <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, and shall be revised biennially thereafter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Plan shall contain but need not be limited to the following elements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an assessment of national needs and problems regarding the Arctic and the research necessary to address those needs or problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement of the goals and objectives of the Interagency Committee for national Arctic research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a detailed listing of all existing Federal programs relating to Arctic research, including the existing goals, funding levels for each of the 5 following fiscal years, and the funds currently being expended to conduct the programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommendations for necessary program changes and other proposals to meet the requirements of the policy and goals as set forth by the Commission and in the Plan as currently in effect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of the actions taken by the Interagency Committee to coordinate the budget review process in order to ensure interagency coordination and cooperation in (A) carrying out Federal Arctic research programs, and (B) eliminating unnecessary duplication of effort among these programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4109.</num>
<heading> Coordination and review of budget requests; Office of Science and Technology Policy; Office of Management and Budget</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of Science and Technology Policy shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review all agency and department budget requests related to the Arctic transmitted pursuant to <ref>section 4107(a)(5) of this title</ref>, in accordance with the national Arctic research policy and the 5-year program under section 4107(a)(2) and <ref>section 4108 of this title</ref>, respectively; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consult closely with the Interagency Committee and the Commission to guide the Office of Science and Technology Policy’s efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office of Management and Budget shall consider all Federal agency requests for research related to the Arctic as one integrated, coherent, and multiagency request which shall be reviewed by the Office of Management and Budget prior to submission of the President’s annual budget request for its adherence to the Plan. The Commission shall, after submission of the President’s annual budget request, review the request and report to Congress on adherence to the Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Office of Management and Budget shall seek to facilitate planning for the design, procurement, maintenance, deployment, and operations of icebreakers needed to provide a platform for Arctic research by allocating all funds necessary to support icebreaking operations, except for recurring incremental costs associated with specific projects, to the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4110.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations; new spending authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for carrying out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any new spending authority (within the meaning of <ref>section 651 of title 2</ref>) which is provided under this chapter shall be effective for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as may be provided in appropriation Acts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4111.</num>
<heading> “Arctic” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “Arctic” means all United States and foreign territory north of the Arctic Circle and all United States territory north and west of the boundary formed by the Porcupine, Yukon, and Kuskokwim Rivers; all contiguous seas, including the Arctic Ocean and the Beaufort, Bering, and Chukchi Seas; and the Aleutian chain.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4112.</num>
<heading> Annual agency budget and spending report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual agency budgets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each agency represented on the Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee shall each include in their agency’s annual budget request to Congress a description of their agency’s projected Arctic research activities and associated budget for the fiscal year covered by the budget request.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning with fiscal year 2025 and annually thereafter until fiscal year 2034, not later than 60 days after the President’s budget request for such fiscal year is submitted to Congress, the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit an annual report to Congress summarizing each agency’s budget request related to Arctic research activities per the information submitted in accordance with paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5912(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>