<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 16C—</num>
<heading>ENERGY SUPPLY AND ENVIRONMENTAL COORDINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 791.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are (1) to provide for a means to assist in meeting the essential needs of the United States for fuels, in a manner which is consistent, to the fullest extent practicable, with existing national commitments to protect and improve the environment, and (2) to provide requirements for reports respecting energy resources.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 792.</num>
<heading> Coal conversion and allocation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powerplant and fuel burning installations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Federal Energy Administrator—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall, by order, prohibit any powerplant, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may, by order, prohibit any major fuel burning installation, other than a powerplant,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">from burning natural gas or petroleum products as its primary energy source, if the requirements of subsection (b) are met and if (A) the Federal Energy Administrator determines such powerplant or installation on <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, had, or thereafter acquires or is designed with, the capability and necessary plant equipment to burn coal, or (B) such powerplant or installation is required to meet a design or construction requirement under subsection (c).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prerequisites to issuance or effectiveness of orders prohibiting use of natural gas or petroleum products as primary energy source</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The requirements referred to in subsection (a) are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An order under subsection (a) may not be issued with respect to a powerplant or installation unless the Federal Energy Administrator finds (A) that the burning of coal by such plant or installation, in lieu of petroleum products or natural gas, is practicable and consistent with the purposes of this chapter, (B) that coal and coal transportation facilities will be available during the period the order is in effect, and (C) in the case of a powerplant, that the prohibition under subsection (a) will not impair the reliability of service in the area served by such plant. Such an order shall be rescinded or modified to the extent the Federal Energy Administrator determines that any requirement described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of this paragraph is no longer met; and such an order may at any time be modified if the Federal Energy Administrator determines that such order, as modified, complies with the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Before issuing an order under subsection (a) which is applicable to a powerplant or installation for a period ending on or before <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>, the Federal Energy Administrator (i) shall give notice to the public and afford interested persons an opportunity for written presentations of data, views, and arguments, (ii) shall consult with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and (iii) shall take into account the likelihood that the powerplant or installation will be permitted to burn coal after <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An order described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not become effective until the date which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency certifies pursuant to section 1857c–10(d)(1)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002283">1</ref> of title 42 is the earliest date that such plant or installation will be able to comply with the air pollution requirements which will be applicable to it. Such order shall not be effective for any period certified by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to section 1857c–10(d)(3)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002283">1</ref> of title 42.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Before issuing an order under subsection (a) which is applicable to a powerplant or installation after <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date> (or modifying an order to which paragraph (2) applies, so as to apply such order to a powerplant or installation after such date), the Federal Energy Administrator shall give notice to the public and afford interested persons an opportunity for oral and written presentations of data, views, and arguments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An order (or modification thereof) described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not become effective until (i) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency notifies the Federal Energy Administrator under section 1857c–10(d)(1)(B) <sup>1</sup> of title 42 that such plant or installation will be able on and after <date date="1975-07-01">July 1, 1975</date>, to burn coal and to comply with all applicable air pollution requirements without a compliance date extension under section 1857c–10(c) <sup>1</sup> of title 42, or (ii) if such notification is not given, the date which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency certifies pursuant to section 1857c–10(d)(1)(B) <sup>1</sup> of title 42 is the earliest date that such plant or installation will be able to comply with all applicable requirements of such 1857c–10 <sup>1</sup> of title 42. Such order (or modification) shall not be effective during any period certified by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under section 1857c–10(d)(3)(B) <sup>1</sup> of title 42.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction and design of powerplants or other major fuel burning installations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Energy Administrator may require that any powerplant or other major fuel burning installation in the early planning process (other than a combustion gas turbine or combined cycle unit) be designed and constructed so as to be capable of using coal as its primary energy source. No powerplant or other major fuel burning installation may be required under this subsection to be so designed and constructed, if the Administrator determines that (1) in the case of a powerplant to do so is likely to result in an impairment of reliability or adequacy of service, or (2) an adequate and reliable supply of coal is not expected to be available. In considering whether to impose a design and construction requirement under this subsection, the Federal Energy Administrator shall consider the existence and effects of any contractual commitment for the construction of such facilities and the capability of the owner to recover any capital investment made as a result of any requirement imposed under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of coal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Energy Administrator may, by rule or order, allocate coal (1) to any powerplant or major fuel-burning installation to which an order under subsection (a) has been issued, or (2) to any other person to the extent necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “powerplant” means a fossil-fuel fired electric generating unit which produces electric power for purposes of sale or exchange.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “coal” includes coal derivatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expiration of authority; effective dates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Authority to issue orders or rules under subsections (a) through (d) of this section shall expire at midnight, <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>. Such a rule or order may take effect at any time before <date date="1985-01-01">January 1, 1985</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Authority to amend, repeal, rescind, modify, or enforce such rules or orders shall expire at midnight, <date date="1984-12-31">December 31, 1984</date>; but the expiration of such authority shall not affect any administrative or judicial proceeding which relates to any act or omission which occurred prior to <date date="1985-01-01">January 1, 1985</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–163, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 875</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–70, § 7</ref>, <date date="1977-07-21">July 21, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 793.</num>
<heading> Protection of public health and environment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of low sulfur fuel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any allocation program provided for in <ref>section 792 of this title</ref> or in the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.],<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002284">1</ref> shall, to the maximum extent practicable, include measures to assure that available low sulfur fuel will be distributed on a priority basis to those areas of the United States designated by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency as requiring low sulfur fuel to avoid or minimize adverse impact on public health.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study of chronic effects of sulfur oxide emissions among exposed populations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to determine the health effects of emissions of sulfur oxides to the air resulting from any conversions to burning coal to which section 119 <sup>1</sup> of the Clean Air Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1857c–10</ref>] applies, the Department of Health and Human Services shall, through the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences and in cooperation with the Environmental Protection Agency, conduct a study of chronic effects among exposed populations. The sum of $3,500,000 is authorized to be appropriated for such a study. In order to assure that long-term studies can be conducted without interruption, such sums as are appropriated shall be available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major Federal actions significantly affecting the quality of the human environment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No action taken under the Clean Air Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.] shall be deemed a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment within the meaning of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No action under <ref>section 792 of this title</ref> for a period of one year after initiation of such action shall be deemed a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment within the meaning of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.]. However, before any action under <ref>section 792 of this title</ref> that has a significant impact on the environment is taken, if practicable, or in any event within sixty days after such action is taken, an environmental evaluation with analysis equivalent to that required under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</ref>], to the greatest extent practicable within this time constraint, shall be prepared and circulated to appropriate Federal, State, and local government agencies and to the public for a thirty-day comment period after which a public hearing shall be held upon request to review outstanding environmental issues. Such an evaluation shall not be required where the action in question has been preceded by compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act by the appropriate Federal agency. Any action taken under <ref>section 792 of this title</ref> which will be in effect for more than a one-year period or any action to extend an action taken under <ref>section 792 of this title</ref> to a total period of more than one year shall be subject to the full provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act, notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Importation of hydroelectric energy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to expedite the prompt construction of facilities for the importation of hydroelectric energy thereby helping to reduce the shortage of petroleum products in the United States, the Federal Power Commission is hereby authorized and directed to issue a Presidential permit pursuant to Executive Order 10485 of <date date="1953-09-03">September 3, 1953</date>, for the construction, operation, maintenance, and connection of facilities for the transmission of electric energy at the borders of the United States without preparing an environmental impact statement pursuant to section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4332</ref>] for facilities for the transmission of electric energy between Canada and the United States in the vicinity of Fort Covington, New York.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 7</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 794.</num>
<heading> Energy conservation study</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study of conservation methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Federal Energy Administrator shall conduct a study on potential methods of energy conservation and, not later than six months after <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, shall submit to Congress a report on the results of such study. The study shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the energy conservation potential of restricting exports of fuels or energy-intensive products, or goods, including an analysis of balance-of-payments and foreign relations implications of any such restrictions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> alternative requirements, incentives, or disincentives for increasing industrial recycling and resource recovery in order to reduce energy demand, including the economic costs and fuel consumption tradeoff which may be associated with such recycling and resource recovery in lieu of transportation and use of virgin materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> means for incentives or disincentives to increase efficiency of industrial use of energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency mass transportation assistance plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within ninety days of <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, the Secretary of Transportation, after consultation with the Federal Energy Administrator, shall submit to the Congress for appropriate action an “Emergency Mass Transportation Assistance Plan” for the purpose of conserving energy by expanding and improving public mass transportation systems and encouraging increased ridership as alternatives to automobile travel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations in plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Such plan shall include, but shall not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> recommendations for emergency temporary grants to assist States and local public bodies and agencies thereof in the payment of operating expenses incurred in connection with the provision of expanded mass transportation service in urban areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recommendations for additional emergency assistance for the purchase of buses and rolling stock for fixed rail, including the feasibility of accelerating the timetable for such assistance under <ref>section 142(a)(2) of title 23</ref> for the purpose of providing additional capacity for and encouraging increased use of public mass transportation systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recommendations for a program of demonstration projects to determine the feasibility of fare-free and low-fare urban mass transportation systems, including reduced rates for elderly and handicapped persons during nonpeak hours of transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommendations for additional emergency assistance for the construction of fringe and transportation corridor parking facilities to serve bus and other mass transportation passengers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> recommendations on the feasibility of providing tax incentives for persons who use public mass transportation systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 8</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 795.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress by <date date="1975-01-31">January 31, 1975</date></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall report to Congress not later than <date date="1975-01-31">January 31, 1975</date>, on the implementation of sections 3 through 7 of the Energy Supply and Environmental Coordination Act of 1974.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 9</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 796.</num>
<heading> Reporting of energy information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Federal Energy Administrator to request, acquire, and collect energy information; rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of assuring that the Federal Energy Administrator, the Congress, the States, and the public have access to and are able to obtain reliable energy information, the Federal Energy Administrator shall request, acquire, and collect such energy information as he determines to be necessary to assist in the formulation of energy policy or to carry out the purposes of this chapter or the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.].<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002285">1</ref> The Federal Energy Administrator shall promptly promulgate rules pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section requiring reports of such information to be submitted to the Federal Energy Administrator at least every ninety calendar days.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers of Federal Energy Administrator in obtaining energy information; verification of accuracy; compliance orders</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In order to obtain energy information for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of subsection (a), the Federal Energy Administrator is authorized—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to require, by rule, any person who is engaged in the production, processing, refining, transportation by pipeline, or distribution (at other than the retail level) of energy resources to submit reports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to sign and issue subpenas for the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, records, papers, and other documents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to require any person, by general or special order, to submit answers in writing to interrogatories, requests for reports or for other information; and such answers or other submissions shall be made within such reasonable period, and under oath or otherwise, as the Federal Energy Administrator may determine; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to administer oaths.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of verifying the accuracy of any energy information requested, acquired, or collected by the Federal Energy Administrator, the Federal Energy Administrator, or any officer or employer <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002286">2</ref> duly designated by him, upon presenting appropriate credentials and a written notice from the Federal Energy Administrator to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enter, at reasonable times, any business premise or facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> inspect, at reasonable times and in a reasonable manner, any such premise or facility, inventory and sample any stock of energy resources therein, and examine and copy books, records, papers, or other documents, relating to any such energy information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any United States district court within the jurisdiction of which any inquiry is carried on may, upon petition by the Attorney General at the request of the Federal Energy Administrator, in the case of refusal to obey a subpena or order of the Federal Energy Administrator issued under this section, issue an order requiring compliance therewith; and any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of initial report; quarterly reports; accounting practices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Federal Energy Administrator shall exercise the authorities granted to him under subsection (b)(1)(A) to develop, within thirty days after <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, as full and accurate a measure as is reasonably practicable of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> domestic reserves and production;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> imports; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> inventories;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">of crude oil, residual fuel oil, refined petroleum products, natural gas, and coal.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For each calendar quarter beginning with the first complete calendar quarter following <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, the Federal Energy Administrator shall develop and publish a report containing the following energy information:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Imports of crude oil, residual fuel oil, refined petroleum products (by product), natural gas, and coal, identifying (with respect to each such oil, product, gas, or coal) country of origin, arrival point, quantity received, and the geographic distribution within the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Domestic reserves and production of crude oil, natural gas, and coal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Refinery activities, showing for each refinery within the United States (i) the amounts of crude oil run by such refinery, (ii) amounts of crude oil allocated to such refinery pursuant to regulations and orders of the Federal Energy Administrator, his delegate pursuant to the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.],<sup>1</sup> or any other person authorized by law to issue regulations and orders with respect to the allocation of crude oil, (iii) percentage of refinery capacity utilized, and (iv) amounts of products refined from such crude oil.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Report of inventories, on a national, regional, and State-by-State basis—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of various refined petroleum products, related refiners, refineries, suppliers to refiners, share of market, and allocation fractions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> of various refined petroleum products, previous quarter deliveries and anticipated three-month available supplies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> of anticipated monthly supply of refined petroleum products, amount of set-aside for assignment by the State, anticipated State requirements, excess or shortfall of supply, and allocation fraction of base year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> of LPG by State and owner: quantities stored, and existing capacities, and previous priorities on types, inventories of suppliers, and changes in supplier inventories.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In order to carry out his responsibilities under subsection (a) of this section, the Federal Energy Administrator shall require, pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section, that persons engaged, in whole or in part, in the production of crude oil or natural gas—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> keep energy information in accordance with the accounting practices developed pursuant to section 503 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 6383</ref>], and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit reports with respect to energy information kept in accordance with such practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Administrator shall file quarterly reports with the President and the Congress compiled from accounts kept in accordance with such section 503 and submitted to the Administrator in accordance with this paragraph. Such reports shall present energy information in the categories specified in subsection (c) of such section 503 to the extent that such information may be compiled from such accounts. Such energy information shall be collected and such quarterly reports made for each calendar quarter which begins 6 months after the date on which the accounting practices developed pursuant to such section 503 are made effective.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidential information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon a showing satisfactory to the Federal Energy Administrator by any person that any energy information obtained under this section from such person would, if made public, divulge methods or processes entitled to protection as trade secrets or other proprietary information of such person, such information, or portion thereof, shall be confidential in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 1905 of title 18</ref>; except that such information, or part thereof, shall not be deemed confidential for purposes of disclosure, upon request, to (1) any delegate of the Federal Energy Administrator for the purpose of carrying out this chapter and the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.],<sup>1</sup> (2) the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Interior, the Federal Trade Commission, the Federal Power Commission, or the Government Accountability Office, when necessary to carry out those agencies’ duties and responsibilities under this and other statutes, and (3) the Congress, or any committee of Congress upon request of the Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “energy information” includes (A) all information in whatever form on (i) fuel reserves, exploration, extraction, and energy resources (including petrochemical feedstocks) wherever located; (ii) production, distribution, and consumption of energy and fuels wherever carried on; and (B) matters relating to energy and fuels, such as corporate structure and proprietary relationships, costs, prices, capital investment, and assets, and other matters directly related thereto, wherever they exist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “person” means any natural person, corporation, partnership, association, consortium, or any entity organized for a common business purpose, wherever situated, domiciled, or doing business, who directly or through other persons subject to their control does business in any part of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “United States” when used in the geographical sense means the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of energy information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Information obtained by the Administration under authority of this chapter shall be available to the public in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent nature of authority to gather energy information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority contained in this section is in addition to, independent of, not limited by, and not in limitation of, any other authority of the Federal Energy Administrator.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 11</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 262</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–163, title V</ref>, §§ 505(a), 506, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 960</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–620, title VII, § 762(d)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 797.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to violate any provision of <ref>section 792 of this title</ref> (relating to coal conversion and allocation) or <ref>section 796 of this title</ref> (relating to energy information) or to violate any rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant to any such provision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties; injunctions; declaratory judgments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whoever violates any provision of subsection (a) shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $2,500 for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whoever willfully violates any provision of subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $5,000 for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person to offer for sale or distribute in commerce any coal in violation of an order or regulation issued pursuant to <ref>section 792(d) of this title</ref>. Any person who knowingly and willfully violates this paragraph after having been subjected to a civil penalty for a prior violation of the same provision of any order or regulation issued pursuant to <ref>section 792(d) of this title</ref> shall be fined not more than $50,000, or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Whenever it appears to the Federal Energy Administrator or any person authorized by the Federal Energy Administrator to exercise authority under <ref>section 792 of this title</ref> or <ref>section 796 of this title</ref> that any individual or organization has engaged, is engaged, or is about to engage in acts or practices constituting a violation of subsection (a) the Federal Energy Administrator or such person may request the Attorney General to bring a civil action to enjoin such acts or practices, and upon a proper showing, a temporary restraining order or a preliminary or permanent injunction shall be granted without bond. In such action, the court may also issue mandatory injunctions commanding any person to comply with any provision, the violation of which is prohibited by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any person suffering legal wrong because of any act or practice arising out of any violation of subsection (a) may bring a civil action for appropriate relief, including an action for a declaratory judgment or writ of injunction. United States district courts shall have jurisdiction of actions under this paragraph without regard to the amount in controversy. Nothing in this paragraph shall authorize any person to recover damages.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 12</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 798.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For purposes of this chapter and the Clean Air Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.] the term “Federal Energy Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Energy Administration established by Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974 [<ref>15 U.S.C. 761</ref> et seq.]; except that until such Administrator takes office and after such Administration ceases to exist, such term means any officer of the United States designated as Federal Energy Administrator by the President for purposes of this chapter and section 119 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002287">1</ref> of the Clean Air Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1857c–10</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this chapter, the term “petroleum product” means crude oil, residual fuel oil, or any refined petroleum product (as defined in section 752(5) <sup>1</sup> of this title).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–319, § 14</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>