<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 43—</num>
<heading>NEWSPAPER PRESERVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1801.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the public interest of maintaining a newspaper press editorially and reportorially independent and competitive in all parts of the United States, it is hereby declared to be the public policy of the United States to preserve the publication of newspapers in any city, community, or metropolitan area where a joint operating arrangement has been heretofore entered into because of economic distress or is hereafter effected in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–353, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1802.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “antitrust law” means the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] and each statute defined by section 4 thereof [<ref>15 U.S.C. 44</ref>] as “Antitrust Acts” and all amendments to such Act and such statutes and any other Acts in pari materia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “joint newspaper operating arrangement” means any contract, agreement, joint venture (whether or not incorporated), or other arrangement entered into by two or more newspaper owners for the publication of two or more newspaper publications, pursuant to which joint or common production facilities are established or operated and joint or unified action is taken or agreed to be taken with respect to any one or more of the following: printing; time, method, and field of publication; allocation of production facilities; distribution; advertising solicitation; circulation solicitation; business department; establishment of advertising rates; establishment of circulation rates and revenue distribution: <i>Provided</i>, That there is no merger, combination, or amalgamation of editorial or reportorial staffs, and that editorial policies be independently determined.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “newspaper owner” means any person who owns or controls directly, or indirectly through separate or subsidiary corporations, one or more newspaper publications.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “newspaper publication” means a publication produced on newsprint paper which is published in one or more issues weekly (including as one publication any daily newspaper and any Sunday newspaper published by the same owner in the same city, community, or metropolitan area), and in which a substantial portion of the content is devoted to the dissemination of news and editorial opinion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “failing newspaper” means a newspaper publication which, regardless of its ownership or affiliations, is in probable danger of financial failure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “person” means any individual, and any partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity existing under or authorized by the law of the United States, any State or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–353, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1803.</num>
<heading> Antitrust exemptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint operating arrangements entered into prior to <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be unlawful under any antitrust law for any person to perform, enforce, renew, or amend any joint newspaper operating arrangement entered into prior to <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, if at the time at which such arrangement was first entered into, regardless of ownership or affiliations, not more than one of the newspaper publications involved in the performance of such arrangement was likely to remain or become a financially sound publication: <i>Provided</i>, That the terms of a renewal or amendment to a joint operating arrangement must be filed with the Department of Justice and that the amendment does not add a newspaper publication or newspaper publications to such arrangement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written consent for future joint operating arrangements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to enter into, perform, or enforce a joint operating arrangement, not already in effect, except with the prior written consent of the Attorney General of the United States. Prior to granting such approval, the Attorney General shall determine that not more than one of the newspaper publications involved in the arrangement is a publication other than a failing newspaper, and that approval of such arrangement would effectuate the policy and purpose of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Predatory practices not exempt</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in the chapter shall be construed to exempt from any antitrust law any predatory pricing, any predatory practice, or any other conduct in the otherwise lawful operations of a joint newspaper operating arrangement which would be unlawful under any antitrust law if engaged in by a single entity. Except as provided in this chapter, no joint newspaper operating arrangement or any party thereto shall be exempt from any antitrust law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–353, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1804.</num>
<heading> Reinstatement of joint operating arrangements previously adjudged unlawful under antitrust laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any final judgment rendered in any action brought by the United States under which a joint operating arrangement has been held to be unlawful under any antitrust law, any party to such final judgment may reinstitute said joint newspaper operating arrangement to the extent permissible under <ref>section 1803(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The provisions of <ref>section 1803 of this title</ref> shall apply to the determination of any civil or criminal action pending in any district court of the United State <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002413">1</ref> on <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, in which it is alleged that any such joint operating agreement is unlawful under any antitrust law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–353, § 5</ref>, <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>