<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 72—</num>
<heading>SEMICONDUCTOR RESEARCH</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COOPERATIVE RESEARCH PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4601.</num>
<heading> Findings, purposes, and definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that it is in the national economic and security interests of the United States for the Department of Defense to provide financial assistance to the industry consortium known as Sematech for research and development activities in the field of semiconductor manufacturing technology.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to encourage the semiconductor industry in the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to conduct research on advanced semiconductor manufacturing techniques; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to develop techniques to use manufacturing expertise for the manufacture of a variety of semiconductor products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in order to achieve the purpose set out in paragraph (1), to provide a grant program for the financial support of semiconductor research activities conducted by Sematech.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms “Semiconductor Technology Council” and “Council” mean the advisory council established by <ref>section 4603 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Sematech” means a consortium of firms in the United States semiconductor industry established for the purposes of (A) conducting research concerning advanced semiconductor manufacturing techniques, and (B) developing techniques to adapt manufacturing expertise to a variety of semiconductor products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title II, § 271</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1068</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title II, § 263(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4602.</num>
<heading> Grants to Sematech</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to make grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall make grants, in accordance with <ref>section 6304 of title 31</ref>, to Sematech in order to defray expenses incurred by Sematech in conducting research on and development of semiconductor manufacturing technology. The grants shall be made in accordance with a memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memorandum of understanding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with Sematech for the purposes of this subchapter. The memorandum of understanding shall require the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> That Sematech have—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a charter agreed to by all representatives of the semiconductor industry that are participating members of Sematech; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an annual operating plan that is developed in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Semiconductor Technology Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> That the total amount of funds made available to Sematech by Federal, State, and local government agencies for any fiscal year for the support of research and development activities of Sematech under this section may not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> That Sematech, in conducting research and development activities pursuant to the memorandum of understanding, cooperate with and draw on the expertise of the national laboratories of the Department of Energy and of colleges and universities in the United States in the field of semiconductor manufacturing technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> That an independent, commercial auditor be retained (A) to determine the extent to which the funds made available to Sematech by the United States for the research and development activities of Sematech have been expended in a manner that is consistent with the purposes of this subchapter, the charter of Sematech, and the annual operating plan of Sematech, and (B) to submit to the Secretary of Defense, Sematech, and the Comptroller General of the United States an annual report containing the findings and determinations of such auditor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> That (A) the Secretary of Defense be permitted to use intellectual property, trade secrets, and technical data owned and developed by Sematech in the same manner as a participant in Sematech and to transfer such intellectual property, trade secrets, and technical data to Department of Defense contractors for use in connection with Department of Defense requirements, and (B) the Secretary not be permitted to transfer such property to any person for commercial use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> That Sematech take all steps necessary to maximize the expeditious and timely transfer of technology developed and owned by Sematech to the participants in Sematech in accordance with the agreement between Sematech and those participants and for the purpose of improving manufacturing productivity of United States semiconductor firms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of memorandum of understanding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (b) shall not be considered to be a contract for the purpose of any law or regulation relating to the formation, content, and administration of contracts awarded by the Federal Government and subcontracts under such contracts, including chapter 271 of title 10, section 719 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (50 U.S.C. App. 2168),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002514">1</ref> and the Federal Acquisition Regulations, and such provisions of law and regulation shall not apply with respect to the memorandum of understanding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding for FY88</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts appropriated to the Defense Agencies for fiscal year 1988 for research, development, test, and evaluation, $100,000,000 may be obligated only to make grants under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title II, § 272</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1068</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title II, § 263(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(e)(7)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4603.</num>
<heading> Semiconductor Technology Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the Semiconductor Technology Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes and functions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The purposes of the Council are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To link assessment by the semiconductor industry of future market and national security needs to opportunities for technology development through cooperative public and private investment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To seek ways to respond to the technology challenges for semiconductors by fostering precompetitive cooperation among industry, the Federal Government, and institutions of higher education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To make available judgments, assessments, insights, and recommendations that relate to the opportunities for new research and development efforts and the potential to better rationalize and align industry and government contributions to semiconductor research and development.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Council shall carry out the following functions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Advise Sematech and the Secretary of Defense on appropriate technology goals and appropriate level of effort for the research and development activities of Sematech.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Review the emerging markets, technology developments, and core technology challenges for semiconductor research and development and semiconductor manufacturing and explore opportunities for improved coordination among industry, the Federal Government, and institutions of higher education regarding such developments and challenges.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Assess the effect on the appropriate role of Sematech of public and private sector international agreements in semiconductor research and development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Exchange views regarding the competitiveness of United States semiconductor technology and new or emerging semiconductor technologies that could affect national economic and security interests.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Exchange and update information and identify overlaps and gaps regarding the efforts of industry, the Federal Government, and institutions of higher education in semiconductor research and development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Assess technology progress relative to industry requirements and Federal Government requirements, responding as appropriate to the challenges in the national semiconductor technology roadmap developed by representatives of industry, the Federal Government, and institutions of higher education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Make recommendations regarding the semiconductor technology development efforts that should be supported by Federal agencies and industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Appoint subgroups as appropriate in connection with the updating of the semiconductor technology roadmap.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Publish and submit to Congress by March 31 of each year an annual report addressing the semiconductor technology challenges and developments for industry, government, and institutions of higher education and the relationship among the challenges and developments for each, including an evaluation of the role of Sematech.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall be composed of 16 members as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics who shall be Cochairman of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Energy responsible for science and technology matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Commerce for Technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Assistant to the President for Economic Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Science Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Ten members appointed by the President as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Four individuals who are eminent in the semiconductor device industry, one of whom shall be Cochairman of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Two individuals who are eminent in the semiconductor equipment and materials industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Three individuals who are eminent in the semiconductor user industry, including representatives from the telecommunications and computer industries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> One individual who is eminent in an academic institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of the Council appointed under subsection (c)(7) shall be appointed for a term of three years, except that of the members first appointed, two shall be appointed for a term of one year, five shall be appointed for a term of two years, and three shall be appointed for a term of three years, as designated by the President at the time of appointment. A member of the Council may serve after the expiration of the member’s term until a successor has taken office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A vacancy in the Council shall not affect its powers but, in the case of a member appointed under subsection (c)(7), shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be appointed for the remainder of such term.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Eleven members of the Council shall constitute a quorum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall meet at the call of a Cochairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each member of the Council shall serve without compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of duties for the Council, members of the Council shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chapter 10 of title 5</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1013 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to the Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support for Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall use Federal funds made available to Sematech as needed for general and administrative support in accomplishing the Council’s purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title II, § 273</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1070</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–245, title I, § 103(e)</ref>, <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title II, § 263(b)</ref>, (c)(3)–(e), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1608</ref>, 1610; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 717</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(72)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4603a.</num>
<heading> Study and report by Semiconductor Technology Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study and report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1989-02-01">February 1, 1989</date>, and annually thereafter for each fiscal year in which appropriated funds are expended for Sematech the Semiconductor Technology Council established under <ref>section 4603(a) of this title</ref> shall conduct a study and submit a report to the Governmental Affairs Committee and the Armed Services Committee of the Senate and to appropriate committees of the House of Representatives concerning Federal participation in Sematech. The study and report shall be conducted under the direction of the Under Secretary of Commerce for Technology.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Council recommendations and report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall include in the report submitted under subsection (a) the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identification of potential sources of Federal funding from department and agency budgets for Sematech and recommendations concerning methods and terms of Federal financial participation in Sematech, including grants, loans, loan guarantees, and contributions in kind. The feasibility of methods of Federal recoupment shall also be considered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> definition and assessment of continued Federal participation in Sematech including, but not limited to, issues of technology research and development, civilian and defense industrial base objectives and initiatives, and commercialization. The report shall include a summary of the most recent plans, milestones, and cost estimates for Sematech, including any changes and alterations, and shall comment on Sematech’s accomplishments and shortfalls in the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordination of inter-agency participation, including all matters pertaining to Federal funding and decisionmaking, and other issues regarding Federal participation in Sematech; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other issues and questions the Council deems appropriate shall be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5422</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–245, title I, § 103(e)</ref>, <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title II, § 263(g)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4604.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 714</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4605.</num>
<heading> Export of semiconductor manufacturing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any export of materials, equipment, and technology developed by Sematech in whole or in part with financial assistance provided under <ref>section 4602(a) of this title</ref> shall be subject to the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. App. 2401 et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002515">1</ref> and shall not be subject to the Arms Export Control Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title II, § 275</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4606.</num>
<heading> Protection of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Freedom of Information Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 552 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to information obtained by the Federal Government on a confidential basis under <ref>section 4602(b)(5) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intellectual property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, intellectual property, trade secrets, and technical data owned and developed by Sematech or any of the participants in Sematech may not be disclosed by any officer or employee of the Department of Defense except as provided in the provision included in the memorandum of understanding pursuant to <ref>section 4602(b)(5) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title II, § 276</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY SEMICONDUCTOR TECHNOLOGY RESEARCH EXCELLENCE INITIATIVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4621.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Semiconductors and related microelectronic devices are key components in computers, telecommunications equipment, advanced defense systems, and other equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Aggregate sales of such equipment, in excess of $230,000,000,000 annually, comprise a significant portion of the gross national product of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The leadership position of the United States in advanced technology is threatened by (A) competition from foreign businesses which is promoted and facilitated by the increasingly active involvement of foreign governments, and (B) other changes in the nature of foreign competition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The principal cause of the relative shift in strength of the United States and its semiconductor competitors is the establishment of a long-term goal by a major foreign competitor to achieve world superiority in semiconductor research and manufacturing technology and the pursuit of such goal by that competitor by effectively marshalling all of the government, industry, and academic resources needed to achieve that goal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Although the United States semiconductor industry leads all other principal United States industries in terms of its reinvestment in research and development, that has been insufficient by worldwide standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Electronic equipment is essential to protect the national security of the United States, as is evidenced by the allocation of approximately 35 percent of the total research, development, and procurement budgets of the Department of Defense to electronics research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Armed Forces of the United States will eventually depend extensively on foreign semiconductor technology unless significant steps are taken, and taken at an early date, to retain United States leadership in semiconductor technology research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> It is in the interests of the national security and national economy of the United States for the United States to regain its traditional world leadership in the field of semiconductors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The most effective means of regaining that leadership is through a joint research effort of the Federal Government and private industry of the United States to improve semiconductor manufacturing technology and to develop practical uses for such technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> In order to meet the national defense needs of the United States and to insure the continued vitality of a commercial manufacturing base in the United States, it is essential that priority be given to the development, demonstration, and advancement of the semiconductor technology base in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The national laboratories of the Department of Energy are a major national research resource, and the extensive involvement of such laboratories in the semiconductor research initiatives of the Federal Government and private industry would be an effective use of such laboratories and would help insure the success of such initiatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3141</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4622.</num>
<heading> Establishment of semiconductor manufacturing technology research initiative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall initiate and carry out a program (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Initiative”) of research on semiconductor manufacturing technology and on the practical applications of such technology. The Secretary may carry out the Initiative in a way that complements the activities of a consortium of United States semiconductor manufacturers, materials manufacturers, and equipment manufacturers, established for the purpose of conducting research concerning advanced semiconductor manufacturing techniques and developing techniques to adopt manufacturing expertise to a variety of semiconductor products.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3142</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4623.</num>
<heading> Participation of national laboratories of Department of Energy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mission of national laboratories</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each national laboratory of the Department of Energy may participate in research and development projects under the Initiative in conjunction with the Department of Defense or with any consortium, college, or university carrying out any project for or in cooperation with any consortium referred to in <ref>section 4622 of this title</ref>, to the extent that such participation is consistent with the missions of the national laboratory.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy may enter into such agreements with the Secretary of Defense, with any consortium referred to in <ref>section 4622 of this title</ref>, and with any college or university as may be necessary to provide for the active participation of the national laboratories of the Department of Energy in the Initiative.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research and development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">One or more national laboratories of the Department of Energy shall participate in the Initiative by conducting research and development activities relating to research on the development of semiconductor manufacturing technologies. Such activities may include research and development relating to materials fabrication, materials characterization, design and modeling of devices, and new processing equipment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3143</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4624.</num>
<heading> Personnel exchanges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy may authorize temporary exchanges of personnel between the national laboratories of the Department of Energy and any domestic firm or any consortium referred to in <ref>section 4622 of this title</ref> that is participating in the Initiative. The exchange of personnel shall be subject to such restrictions, limitations, terms, and conditions that the Secretary of Energy considers necessary in the interest of national security.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3144</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4625.</num>
<heading> Other Department of Energy resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Energy may make available to the Department of Defense, to any other department or agency of the Federal Government, and to any consortium that has entered into an agreement in furtherance of the Initiative any facilities, personnel, equipment, services, and other resources of the Department of Energy for the purpose of conducting research and development projects under the Initiative consistent with <ref>section 4623(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make facilities available under this section only to the extent that the cost of the use of such facilities is reimbursed by the user.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3145</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4626.</num>
<heading> Budgeting for semiconductor manufacturing technology research</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent the Secretary considers appropriate and necessary, the Secretary of Energy, in preparing the research and development budget of the Department of Energy to be included in the annual budget submitted to the Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, shall provide for programs, projects, and activities that encourage the development of new technology in the field of semiconductors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget categories</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The programs, projects, and activities described in subsection (a) shall be included in the budget for general science and research activities of the Department of Energy, except that any programs, projects, and activities that directly support and directly benefit the defense activities of the Department shall be included in the budget for atomic energy defense activities of the Department of Energy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3146</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4627.</num>
<heading> Cost-sharing agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The director of each national laboratory of the Department of Energy that is participating in the Initiative or the contractor operating any such national laboratory, in carrying out programs under a contract with the Department of Energy, may include in any research and development agreement entered into with a domestic firm in connection with such Initiative a cooperative provision for the domestic firm to pay a portion of the cost of the research and development activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than an amount equal to 1 percent of any national laboratory’s annual budget shall be received from nonappropriated funds derived from contracts entered into under the Initiative in any fiscal year, except to the extent approved in advance by the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No Department of Energy national laboratory may receive more than $10,000,000 of nonappropriated funds under any cooperative research and development agreement entered into under this subsection in connection with the Initiative, except to the extent approved in advance by the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3147</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4628.</num>
<heading> Department of Energy oversight of cooperative agreements relating to Initiative</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provisions relating to disapproval and modification of agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary of Energy desires an opportunity to disapprove or require the modification of any agreement under <ref>section 4627 of this title</ref>, the agreement shall provide a 90-day period within which such action may be taken, beginning on the date the agreement is submitted to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record of agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each national laboratory shall maintain a record of all agreements entered into under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3148</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4629.</num>
<heading> Avoidance of duplication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the Initiative, the Secretary of Energy shall ensure that unnecessary duplicative research is not performed at the research facilities (including the national laboratories of the Department of Energy) that are participating in the Initiative.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3149</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4630.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Energy for fiscal year 1988 the sum of $25,000,000 for general science and research activities of the Department of Energy under the Initiative.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3150</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4631.</num>
<heading> Technology transfer</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall adopt procedures to provide for timely and efficient transfer of semiconductor technology developed under the Initiative pursuant to applicable laws, Executive orders, and regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan for commercialization enhancement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than one year after the date on which funds are first appropriated to conduct the Initiative, the Secretary of Energy shall transmit to the committees of Congress named in paragraph (2) a plan for the transfer of semiconductor technology and information generated by the Initiative.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The committees of Congress referred to in paragraph (1) are the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3151</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 5(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4582</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4632.</num>
<heading> Semiconductor research and development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “National Advisory Committee on Semiconductor Research and Development Act of 1988”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings and purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> semiconductor technology is playing an ever-increasing role in United States industrial and commercial products and processes, making secure domestic sources of state-of-the-art semiconductors highly desirable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> modern weapons systems are highly dependent on leading edge semiconductor devices, and it is counter to the national security interest to be heavily dependent upon foreign sources for this technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> governmental responsibilities related to the semiconductor industry are divided among many Federal departments and agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> joint industry-government consideration of semiconductor industry problems is needed at this time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The purposes of this section are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to establish the National Advisory Committee on Semiconductors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to assign to such Committee the responsibility for devising and promulgating a national semiconductor strategy, including research and development, the implementation of which will assure the continued leadership of the United States in semiconductor technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Creation of Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby created in the executive branch of the Government an independent advisory body to be known as the National Advisory Committee on Semiconductors (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Committee”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collect and analyze information on the needs and capabilities of industry, the Federal Government, and the scientific and research communities related to semiconductor technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify the components of a successful national semiconductor strategy in accordance with subsection (b)(2)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> analyze options, establish priorities, and recommend roles for participants in the national strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assess the roles for government and national laboratories and other laboratories supported largely for government purposes in contributing to the semiconductor technology base of the Nation, as well as to access the effective use of the resources of United States private industry, United States universities, and private-public research and development efforts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> provide results and recommendations to agencies of the Federal Government involved in legislative, policymaking, administrative, management, planning, and technology activities that affect or are part of a national semiconductor strategy, and to the industry and other nongovernmental groups or organizations affected by or contributing to that strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In fulfilling this responsibility, the Committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> monitor the competitiveness of the United States semiconductor technology base;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determine technical areas where United States semiconductor technology is deficient relative to international competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identify new or emerging semiconductor technologies that will impact the national defense or United States competitiveness or both;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> develop research and development strategies, tactics, and plans whose execution will assure United States semiconductor competitiveness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> recommend appropriate actions that support the national semiconductor strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership and procedures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Committee shall be composed of 13 members, 7 of whom shall constitute a quorum.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Energy, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and the Director of the National Science Foundation, or their designees, shall serve as members of the Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The President, acting through the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, shall appoint, as additional members of the Committee, 4 members from outside the Federal Government who are eminent in the semiconductor industry, and 4 members from outside the Federal Government who are eminent in the fields of technology, defense, and economic development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> One of the members appointed under subparagraph (C), as designated by the President at the time of appointment, shall be chairman of the Committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funding and administrative support for the Committee shall be provided to the Office of Science and Technology Policy through an arrangement with an appropriate agency or organization designated by the Committee, in accordance with a memorandum of understanding entered into between them.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Members of the Committee, other than full-time employees of the Federal Government, while attending meetings of the Committee or otherwise performing duties at the request of the Chairman while away from their homes or regular places of business, shall be allowed travel expenses in accordance with subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Chairman shall call the first meeting of the Committee not later than 90 days after <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> At the close of each fiscal year the Committee shall submit to the President and the Congress a report on its activities conducted during such year and its planned activities for the coming year, including specific findings and recommendations with respect to the national semiconductor strategy devised and promulgated under subsection (b)(2)(B). The first report shall include an analysis of those technical areas, including manufacturing, which are of importance to the United States semiconductor industry, and shall make specific recommendations regarding the appropriate Federal role in correcting any deficiencies identified by the analysis. Each report shall include an estimate of the length of time the Committee must continue before the achievement of its purposes and the issuance of its final report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the purposes of this section such sums as may be necessary for the fiscal years 1988, 1989, 1990, 1991, 1992, and 1993.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5142</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–245, title I, § 105(f)</ref>, <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 12</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>