<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 70—</num>
<heading>COMPREHENSIVE SMOKELESS TOBACCO HEALTH EDUCATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4401.</num>
<heading> Public education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish and carry out a program to inform the public of any dangers to human health resulting from the use of smokeless tobacco products. In carrying out such program the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop educational programs and materials and public service announcements respecting the dangers to human health from the use of smokeless tobacco;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make such programs, materials, and announcements available to States, local governments, school systems, the media, and such other entities as the Secretary determines appropriate to further the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> conduct and support research on the effect of smokeless tobacco on human health; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> collect, analyze, and disseminate information and studies on smokeless tobacco and health.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In developing programs, materials, and announcements under paragraph (1) the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Education, medical and public health entities, consumer groups, representatives of manufacturers of smokeless tobacco products, and other appropriate entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may provide technical assistance and may make grants to States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assist in the development of educational programs and materials and public service announcements respecting the dangers to human health from the use of smokeless tobacco,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist in the distribution of such programs, materials, and announcements throughout the States, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to establish 18 as the minimum age for the purchase of smokeless tobacco.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–252, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 30</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4402.</num>
<heading> Smokeless tobacco warning</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture, package, sell, offer to sell, distribute, or import for sale or distribution within the United States any smokeless tobacco product unless the product package bears, in accordance with the requirements of this chapter, one of the following labels:<p class="indent1" role="listItem">WARNING: This product can cause mouth cancer.</p>
<p class="indent1" role="listItem">WARNING: This product can cause gum disease and tooth loss.</p>
<p class="indent1">WARNING: This product is not a safe alternative to cigarettes.</p>
<p class="indent1">WARNING: Smokeless tobacco is addictive.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each label statement required by paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> located on the 2 principal display panels of the package, and each label statement shall comprise at least 30 percent of each such display panel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in 17-point conspicuous and legible type and in black text on a white background, or white text on a black background, in a manner that contrasts by typography, layout, or color, with all other printed material on the package, in an alternating fashion under the plan submitted under subsection (b)(3), except that if the text of a label statement would occupy more than 70 percent of the area specified by subparagraph (A), such text may appear in a smaller type size, so long as at least 60 percent of such warning area is occupied by the label statement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The label statements required by paragraph (1) shall be introduced by each tobacco product manufacturer, packager, importer, distributor, or retailer of smokeless tobacco products concurrently into the distribution chain of such products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The provisions of this subsection do not apply to a tobacco product manufacturer or distributor of any smokeless tobacco product that does not manufacture, package, or import smokeless tobacco products for sale or distribution within the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> A retailer of smokeless tobacco products shall not be in violation of this subsection for packaging that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contains a warning label;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is supplied to the retailer by a license- or permit-holding tobacco product manufacturer, importer, or distributor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is not altered by the retailer in a way that is material to the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required labels</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any tobacco product manufacturer, packager, importer, distributor, or retailer of smokeless tobacco products to advertise or cause to be advertised within the United States any smokeless tobacco product unless its advertising bears, in accordance with the requirements of this section, one of the labels specified in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each label statement required by subsection (a) in smokeless tobacco advertising shall comply with the standards set forth in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For press and poster advertisements, each such statement and (where applicable) any required statement relating to tar, nicotine, or other constituent yield shall comprise at least 20 percent of the area of the advertisement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The word “WARNING” shall appear in capital letters, and each label statement shall appear in conspicuous and legible type.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The text of the label statement shall be black on a white background, or white on a black background, in an alternating fashion under the plan submitted under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The label statements shall be enclosed by a rectangular border that is the same color as the letters of the statements and that is the width of the first downstroke of the capital “W” of the word “WARNING” in the label statements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The text of such label statements shall be in a typeface pro rata to the following requirements: 45-point type for a whole-page broadsheet newspaper advertisement; 39-point type for a half-page broadsheet newspaper advertisement; 39-point type for a whole-page tabloid newspaper advertisement; 27-point type for a half-page tabloid newspaper advertisement; 31.5-point type for a double page spread magazine or whole-page magazine advertisement; 22.5-point type for a 28 centimeter by 3 column advertisement; and 15-point type for a 20 centimeter by 2 column advertisement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> The label statements shall be in English, except that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an advertisement that appears in a newspaper, magazine, periodical, or other publication that is not in English, the statements shall appear in the predominant language of the publication; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of any other advertisement that is not in English, the statements shall appear in the same language as that principally used in the advertisement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The label statements specified in subsection (a)(1) shall be randomly displayed in each 12-month period, in as equal a number of times as is possible on each brand of the product and be randomly distributed in all areas of the United States in which the product is marketed in accordance with a plan submitted by the tobacco product manufacturer, importer, distributor, or retailer and approved by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The label statements specified in subsection (a)(1) shall be rotated quarterly in alternating sequence in advertisements for each brand of smokeless tobacco product in accordance with a plan submitted by the tobacco product manufacturer, importer, distributor, or retailer to, and approved by, the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall review each plan submitted under subparagraphs (A) and (B) and approve it if the plan—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> will provide for the equal distribution and display on packaging and the rotation required in advertising under this subsection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assures that all of the labels required under this section will be displayed by the tobacco product manufacturer, importer, distributor, or retailer at the same time.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> This paragraph applies to a retailer only if that retailer is responsible for or directs the label statements under this section, unless the retailer displays, in a location open to the public, an advertisement that does not contain a warning label or has been altered by the retailer in a way that is material to the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, through a rulemaking under <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, adjust the format and type sizes for the label statements required by this section; the text, format, and type sizes of any required tar, nicotine yield, or other constituent disclosures; or the text, format, and type sizes for any other disclosures required under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.]. The text of any such label statements or disclosures shall be required to appear only within the 20 percent area of advertisements provided by paragraph (2). The Secretary shall promulgate regulations which provide for adjustments in the format and type sizes of any text required to appear in such area to ensure that the total text required to appear by law will fit within such area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Television and radio advertising</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is unlawful to advertise smokeless tobacco on any medium of electronic communications subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Communications Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to revise warning label statements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, by a rulemaking conducted under <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, adjust the format, type size, and text of any of the label requirements, require color graphics to accompany the text, increase the required label area from 30 percent up to 50 percent of the front and rear panels of the package, or establish the format, type size, and text of any other disclosures required under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, if the Secretary finds that such a change would promote greater public understanding of the risks associated with the use of smokeless tobacco products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–252, § 3</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 30</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 204(a), 205(a), <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1846</ref>, 1848.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4403.</num>
<heading> Ingredient reporting</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each person who manufactures, packages, or imports smokeless tobacco products shall annually provide the Secretary with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of the ingredients added to tobacco in the manufacture of smokeless tobacco products which does not identify the company which uses the ingredients or the brand of smokeless tobacco which contains the ingredients; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a specification of the quantity of nicotine contained in each such product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person or group of persons required to provide information by this subsection may designate an individual or entity to provide the information required by this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> At such times as the Secretary considers appropriate, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress a report, based on the information provided under subsection (a), respecting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of research activities and proposed research activities on the health effects of ingredients added to tobacco in the manufacture of smokeless tobacco products and the findings of such research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information pertaining to any such ingredient which in the judgment of the Secretary poses a health risk to users of smokeless tobacco; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other information which the Secretary determines to be in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any information provided to the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be treated as a trade secret or confidential information subject to <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> and shall not be revealed, except as provided in paragraph (1), to any person other than those authorized by the Secretary in carrying out their official duties under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) does not authorize the withholding of information provided under subsection (a) of this section from any duly authorized subcommittee or committee of the Congress. If a subcommittee or committee of the Congress requests the Secretary to provide it such information, the Secretary shall make the information available to the subcommittee or committee and shall, at the same time, notify in writing the person who provided the information of such request.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall establish written procedures to assure the confidentiality of information provided under subsection (a) of this section. Such procedures shall include the designation of a duly authorized agent to serve as custodian of such information. The agent—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall take physical possession of the information and, when not in use by any person authorized to have access to such information, shall store it in a locked cabinet or file; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall maintain a complete record of any person who inspects or uses the information.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such procedures shall require that any person permitted access to the information shall be instructed in writing not to disclose the information to anyone who is not entitled to have access to the information.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–252, § 4</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 32</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4404.</num>
<heading> Enforcement, regulations, and construction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A violation of <ref>section 4402 of this title</ref> or the regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter shall be considered a violation of <ref>section 45 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who is found to violate any provision of section 4402 or 4403(a) of this title shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall on conviction thereof be subject to a fine of not more than $10,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations under <ref>section 4402 of this title</ref></heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Regulations issued by the Federal Trade Commission under <ref>section 4402 of this title</ref> shall be issued in accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 180 days after <date date="1986-02-27">February 27, 1986</date>, the Federal Trade Commission shall promulgate such regulations as it may require to implement <ref>section 4402 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter (other than the requirements of sections 4402 and 4403 of this title) shall be construed to limit, restrict, or expand the authority of the Federal Trade Commission with respect to unfair or deceptive acts or practices in the advertising of smokeless tobacco products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–252, § 5</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 33</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4405.</num>
<heading> Injunctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The several district courts of the United States are vested with jurisdiction, for cause shown, to prevent and restrain violations of sections 4402 and 4403 of this title upon application of the Federal Trade Commission in the case of a violation of <ref>section 4402 of this title</ref> or upon application of the Attorney General of the United States acting through the several United States attorneys in their several districts in the case of a violation of section 4402 or 4403 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–252, § 6</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 33</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4406.</num>
<heading> Preemption</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act (and the amendments made by that Act), no statement relating to the use of smokeless tobacco products and health, other than the statements required by <ref>section 4402 of this title</ref>, shall be required by any Federal agency to appear on any package or in any advertisement (unless the advertisement is an outdoor billboard advertisement) of a smokeless tobacco product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No statement relating to the use of smokeless tobacco products and health, other than the statements required by <ref>section 4402 of this title</ref>, shall be required by any State or local statute or regulation to be included on any package or in any advertisement (unless the advertisement is an outdoor billboard advertisement) of a smokeless tobacco product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on liability law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall relieve any person from liability at common law or under State statutory law to any other person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–252, § 7</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1849</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4407.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4408.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “smokeless tobacco” has the meaning given such term by <ref>section 387(18) of title 21</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “commerce” means (A) commerce between any State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, or Johnston Island and any place outside thereof; (B) commerce between points in any State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, or Johnston Island, but through any place outside thereof; or (C) commerce wholly within the District of Columbia, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, or Johnston Island.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, includes the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, Johnston Island, and installations of the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “package” means a pack, box, carton, pouch, or container of any kind in which smokeless tobacco products are offered for sale, sold, or otherwise distributed to consumers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “sale or distribution” includes sampling or any other distribution not for sale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–252, § 9</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>