<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 110—</num>
<heading>ONLINE SHOPPER PROTECTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8401.</num>
<heading> Findings; declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Internet has become an important channel of commerce in the United States, accounting for billions of dollars in retail sales every year. Over half of all American adults have now either made an online purchase or an online travel reservation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Consumer confidence is essential to the growth of online commerce. To continue its development as a marketplace, the Internet must provide consumers with clear, accurate information and give sellers an opportunity to fairly compete with one another for consumers’ business.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An investigation by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation found abundant evidence that the aggressive sales tactics many companies use against their online customers have undermined consumer confidence in the Internet and thereby harmed the American economy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Committee showed that, in exchange for “bounties” and other payments, hundreds of reputable online retailers and websites shared their customers’ billing information, including credit card and debit card numbers, with third party sellers through a process known as “data pass”. These third party sellers in turn used aggressive, misleading sales tactics to charge millions of American consumers for membership clubs the consumers did not want.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Third party sellers offered membership clubs to consumers as they were in the process of completing their initial transactions on hundreds of websites. These third party “post-transaction” offers were designed to make consumers think the offers were part of the initial purchase, rather than a new transaction with a new seller.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Third party sellers charged millions of consumers for membership clubs without ever obtaining consumers’ billing information, including their credit or debit card information, directly from the consumers. Because third party sellers acquired consumers’ billing information from the initial merchant through “data pass”, millions of consumers were unaware they had been enrolled in membership clubs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The use of a “data pass” process defied consumers’ expectations that they could only be charged for a good or a service if they submitted their billing information, including their complete credit or debit card numbers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Third party sellers used a free trial period to enroll members, after which they periodically charged consumers until consumers affirmatively canceled the memberships. This use of “free-to-pay conversion” and “negative option” sales took advantage of consumers’ expectations that they would have an opportunity to accept or reject the membership club offer at the end of the trial period.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–345, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-12-29">Dec. 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8402.</num>
<heading> Prohibitions against certain unfair and deceptive Internet sales practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for certain Internet-based sales</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any post-transaction third party seller to charge or attempt to charge any consumer’s credit card, debit card, bank account, or other financial account for any good or service sold in a transaction effected on the Internet, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> before obtaining the consumer’s billing information, the post-transaction third party seller has clearly and conspicuously disclosed to the consumer all material terms of the transaction, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the goods or services being offered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the fact that the post-transaction third party seller is not affiliated with the initial merchant, which may include disclosure of the name of the post-transaction third party in a manner that clearly differentiates the post-transaction third party seller from the initial merchant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the cost of such goods or services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the post-transaction third party seller has received the express informed consent for the charge from the consumer whose credit card, debit card, bank account, or other financial account will be charged by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> obtaining from the consumer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the full account number of the account to be charged; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the consumer’s name and address and a means to contact the consumer; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requiring the consumer to perform an additional affirmative action, such as clicking on a confirmation button or checking a box that indicates the consumer’s consent to be charged the amount disclosed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on data-pass used to facilitate certain deceptive Internet sales transactions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for an initial merchant to disclose a credit card, debit card, bank account, or other financial account number, or to disclose other billing information that is used to charge a customer of the initial merchant, to any post-transaction third party seller for use in an Internet-based sale of any goods or services from that post-transaction third party seller.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application with other law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to supersede, modify, or otherwise affect the requirements of the Electronic Funds <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002592">1</ref> Transfer Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1693</ref> et seq.) or any regulation promulgated thereunder.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial merchant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “initial merchant” means a person that has obtained a consumer’s billing information directly from the consumer through an Internet transaction initiated by the consumer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Post-transaction third party seller</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “post-transaction third party seller” means a person that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sells, or offers for sale, any good or service on the Internet;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> solicits the purchase of such goods or services on the Internet through an initial merchant after the consumer has initiated a transaction with the initial merchant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> is not—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the initial merchant;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a subsidiary or corporate affiliate of the initial merchant; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a successor of an entity described in clause (i) or (ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–345, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-29">Dec. 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8403.</num>
<heading> Negative option marketing on the Internet</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to charge or attempt to charge any consumer for any goods or services sold in a transaction effected on the Internet through a negative option feature (as defined in the Federal Trade Commission’s Telemarketing Sales Rule in part 310 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations), unless the person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides text that clearly and conspicuously discloses all material terms of the transaction before obtaining the consumer’s billing information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtains a consumer’s express informed consent before charging the consumer’s credit card, debit card, bank account, or other financial account for products or services through such transaction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provides simple mechanisms for a consumer to stop recurring charges from being placed on the consumer’s credit card, debit card, bank account, or other financial account.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–345, § 4</ref>, <date date="2010-12-29">Dec. 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3620</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8404.</num>
<heading> Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Violation of this chapter or any regulation prescribed under this chapter shall be treated as a violation of a rule under section 18 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 57a</ref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices. The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this chapter in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.) were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who violates this chapter or any regulation prescribed under this chapter shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated in and made part of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority preserved</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–345, § 5</ref>, <date date="2010-12-29">Dec. 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3620</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8405.</num>
<heading> Enforcement by State attorneys general</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (e), the attorney general of a State, or other authorized State officer, alleging a violation of this chapter or any regulation issued under this chapter that affects or may affect such State or its residents may bring an action on behalf of the residents of the State in any United States district court for the district in which the defendant is found, resides, or transacts business, or wherever venue is proper under <ref>section 1391 of title 28</ref>, to obtain appropriate injunctive relief.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to Commission required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State shall provide prior written notice to the Federal Trade Commission of any civil action under subsection (a) together with a copy of its complaint, except that if it is not feasible for the State to provide such prior notice, the State shall provide such notice immediately upon instituting such action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intervention by the Commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission may intervene in such civil action and upon intervening—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be heard on all matters arising in such civil action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> file petitions for appeal of a decision in such civil action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to prevent the attorney general of a State, or other authorized State officer, from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, or other authorized State officer, by the laws of such State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to prohibit the attorney general of a State, or other authorized State officer, from proceeding in State or Federal court on the basis of an alleged violation of any civil or criminal statute of that State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No separate suit shall be brought under this section if, at the time the suit is brought, the same alleged violation is the subject of a pending action by the Federal Trade Commission or the United States under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–345, § 6</ref>, <date date="2010-12-29">Dec. 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>