<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2E—</num>
<heading>OMNIBUS SMALL BUSINESS CAPITAL FORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 80c.</num>
<heading> Liaison between Securities and Exchange Commission and Small Business Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Studies on needs, problems, and costs of businesses; availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Securities and Exchange Commission shall gather, analyze, and make available to the public, information with respect to the capital formation needs, and the problems and costs involved with new, small, medium-sized, and independent businesses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of studies to Small Business Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall make the results of such studies available to the Small Business Administration and otherwise have regular communication and liaison with such Administration in these matters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–477, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80c–1.</num>
<heading> Annual government-business forum on capital formation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility of Securities and Exchange Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pursuant to the consultation called for in <ref>section 80c of this title</ref>, the Securities and Exchange Commission (acting through the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and in consultation with the Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee) shall conduct an annual Government-business forum to review the current status of problems and programs relating to small business capital formation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation in forum planning</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall invite other Federal agencies, such as the Department of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Small Business Administration, organizations representing State securities commissioners, and leading small business and professional organizations concerned with capital formation, to participate in the planning for such forums.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of statements and reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may request any of the Federal departments, agencies, or organizations such as those specified in subsection (b), or other groups or individuals, to prepare statements and reports to be delivered at such forums. Such departments and agencies shall cooperate in this effort.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal of proceedings and findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A summary of the proceedings of such forums and any findings or recommendations thereof shall be prepared and transmitted to the participants, appropriate committees of the Congress, and others who may be interested in the subject matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of findings and recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review the findings and recommendations of the forum; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> each time the forum submits a finding or recommendation to the Commission, promptly issue a public statement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assessing the finding or recommendation of the forum; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> disclosing the action, if any, the Commission intends to take with respect to the finding or recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–477, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–284, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–174, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80c–2.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For fiscal year 1982, and for each of the three succeeding fiscal years, there are hereby authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out the provisions and purposes of this chapter. Any sums so appropriated shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–477, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 80c–3.</num>
<heading> Reduction of costs of small securities issues</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Securities and Exchange Commission shall use its best efforts to identify and reduce the costs of raising capital in connection with the issuance of securities by firms whose aggregate outstanding securities and other indebtedness have a market value of $25,000,000 or less, through such means as studies, giving appropriate publicity to improved technology developments in fields such as printing, communications, and filing, and giving special attention to the effect of existing and proposed regulatory changes upon the small companies wishing to raise capital and independent broker-dealers which are in a key position with respect to the costs of underwriting and making markets in the securities of smaller companies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commission shall report on these efforts at the annual Government-business forum required by <ref>section 80c–1 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–477, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>