<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 89—</num>
<heading>PROFESSIONAL BOXING SAFETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Boxer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “boxer” means an individual who fights in a professional boxing match.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Boxing commission</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002543">1</ref> The term “boxing commission” means an entity authorized under State law to regulate professional boxing matches.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Boxer registry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “boxer registry” means any entity certified by the Association of Boxing Commissions for the purposes of maintaining records and identification of boxers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licensee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “licensee” means an individual who serves as a trainer, second, or cut man for a boxer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manager</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “manager” means a person who receives compensation for service as an agent or representative of a boxer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matchmaker</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “matchmaker” means a person that proposes, selects, and arranges the boxers to participate in a professional boxing match.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Physician</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “physician” means a doctor of medicine legally authorized to practice medicine by the State in which the physician performs such function or action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Professional boxing match</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “professional boxing match” means a boxing contest held in the United States between individuals for financial compensation. Such term does not include a boxing contest that is regulated by an amateur sports organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promoter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “promoter” means the person primarily responsible for organizing, promoting, and producing a professional boxing match. The term “promoter” does not include a hotel, casino, resort, or other commercial establishment hosting or sponsoring a professional boxing match unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the hotel, casino, resort, or other commercial establishment is primarily responsible for organizing, promoting, and producing the match; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there is no other person primarily responsible for organizing, promoting, and producing the match.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the 50 States, Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States, including the Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of the contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “effective date of the contract” means the day upon which a boxer becomes legally bound by the contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Boxing service provider</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “boxing service provider” means a promoter, manager, sanctioning body, licensee, or matchmaker.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “contract provision” means any legal obligation between a boxer and a boxing service provider.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctioning organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “sanctioning organization” means an organization that sanctions professional boxing matches in the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> between boxers who are residents of different States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that are advertised, otherwise promoted, or broadcast (including closed circuit television) in interstate commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “suspension” includes within its meaning the revocation of a boxing license.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 2</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to improve and expand the system of safety precautions that protects the welfare of professional boxers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist State boxing commissions to provide proper oversight for the professional boxing industry in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 3</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Boxing matches in States without boxing commissions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No person may arrange, promote, organize, produce, or fight in a professional boxing match held in a State that does not have a boxing commission unless the match is supervised by a boxing commission from another State and subject to the most recent version of the recommended regulatory guidelines certified and published by the Association of Boxing Commissions as well as any additional relevant professional boxing regulations and requirements of such other State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter, if no State commission is available to supervise a boxing match according to subsection (a), then—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the match may not be held unless it is supervised by an association of boxing commissions to which at least a majority of the States belong; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any reporting or other requirement relating to a supervising commission allowed under this section shall be deemed to refer to the entity described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 4</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3310</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 7(e)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 328</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Safety standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No person may arrange, promote, organize, produce, or fight in a professional boxing match without meeting each of the following requirements or an alternative requirement in effect under regulations of a boxing commission that provides equivalent protection of the health and safety of boxers:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A physical examination of each boxer by a physician certifying whether or not the boxer is physically fit to safely compete, copies of which must be provided to the boxing commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise expressly provided under regulation of a boxing commission promulgated subsequent to <date date="1996-10-09">October 9, 1996</date>, an ambulance or medical personnel with appropriate resuscitation equipment continuously present on site.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A physician continuously present at ringside.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Health insurance for each boxer to provide medical coverage for any injuries sustained in the match.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Registration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each boxer shall register with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the boxing commission of the State in which such boxer resides; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a boxer who is a resident of a foreign country, or a State in which there is no boxing commission, the boxing commission of any State that has such a commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification card</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A boxing commission shall issue to each professional boxer who registers in accordance with subsection (a), an identification card that contains each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A recent photograph of the boxer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The social security number of the boxer (or, in the case of a foreign boxer, any similar citizen identification number or professional boxer number from the country of residence of the boxer).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A personal identification number assigned to the boxer by a boxing registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Renewal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each professional boxer shall renew his or her identification card at least once every 4 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each professional boxer shall present his or her identification card to the appropriate boxing commission not later than the time of the weigh-in for a professional boxing match.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Health and safety disclosures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that a boxing commission should, upon issuing an identification card to a boxer under subsection (b)(1), make a health and safety disclosure to that boxer as that commission considers appropriate. The health and safety disclosure should include the health and safety risks associated with boxing, and, in particular, the risk and frequency of brain injury and the advisability that a boxer periodically undergo medical procedures designed to detect brain injury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 6</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3310</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 7(c)</ref>, (f), <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 328</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each boxing commission shall establish each of the following procedures:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Procedures to evaluate the professional records and physician’s certification of each boxer participating in a professional boxing match in the State, and to deny authorization for a boxer to fight where appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Procedures to ensure that, except as provided in subsection (b), no boxer is permitted to box while under suspension from any boxing commission due to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a recent knockout or series of consecutive losses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an injury, requirement for a medical procedure, or physician denial of certification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> failure of a drug test;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the use of false aliases, or falsifying, or attempting to falsify, official identification cards or documents; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> unsportsmanlike conduct or other inappropriate behavior inconsistent with generally accepted methods of competition in a professional boxing match.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Procedures to review a suspension where appealed by a boxer, licensee, manager, matchmaker, promoter, or other boxing service provider, including an opportunity for a boxer to present contradictory evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Procedures to revoke a suspension where a boxer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> was suspended under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) of this subsection, and has furnished further proof of a sufficiently improved medical or physical condition; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> furnishes proof under subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (2) that a suspension was not, or is no longer, merited by the facts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension in another State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A boxing commission may allow a boxer who is under suspension in any State to participate in a professional boxing match—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for any reason other than those listed in subsection (a) if such commission notifies in writing and consults with the designated official of the suspending State’s boxing commission prior to the grant of approval for such individual to participate in that professional boxing match; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the boxer appeals to the Association of Boxing Commissions, and the Association of Boxing Commissions determines that the suspension of such boxer was without sufficient grounds, for an improper purpose, or not related to the health and safety of the boxer or the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 7</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 7(b)</ref>, (d), <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 328</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 48 business hours after the conclusion of a professional boxing match, the supervising boxing commission shall report the results of such boxing match and any related suspensions to each boxer registry.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 8</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307a.</num>
<heading> Contract requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 2 years after <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, the Association of Boxing Commissions (ABC) shall develop and shall approve by a vote of no less than a majority of its member State boxing commissioners, guidelines for minimum contractual provisions that should be included in bout agreements and boxing contracts. It is the sense of the Congress that State boxing commissions should follow these ABC guidelines.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307b.</num>
<heading> Protection from coercive contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A contract provision shall be considered to be in restraint of trade, contrary to public policy, and unenforceable against any boxer to the extent that it—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a coercive provision described in subparagraph (B) and is for a period greater than 12 months; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is a coercive provision described in subparagraph (B) and the other boxer under contract to the promoter came under that contract pursuant to a coercive provision described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A coercive provision described in this subparagraph is a contract provision that grants any rights between a boxer and a promoter, or between promoters with respect to a boxer, if the boxer is required to grant such rights, or a boxer’s promoter is required to grant such rights with respect to a boxer to another promoter, as a condition precedent to the boxer’s participation in a professional boxing match against another boxer who is under contract to the promoter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This subsection shall only apply to contracts entered into after <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No subsequent contract provision extending any rights or compensation covered in paragraph (1) shall be enforceable against a boxer if the effective date of the contract containing such provision is earlier than 3 months before the expiration of the relevant time period set forth in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promotional rights under mandatory bout contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No boxing service provider may require a boxer to grant any future promotional rights as a requirement of competing in a professional boxing match that is a mandatory bout under the rules of a sanctioning organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection from coercive contracts with broadcasters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) of this section applies to any contract between a commercial broadcaster and a boxer, or granting any rights with respect to that boxer, involving a broadcast in or affecting interstate commerce, regardless of the broadcast medium. For the purpose of this subsection, any reference in subsection (a)(1)(B) to “promoter” shall be considered a reference to “commercial broadcaster”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 10</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307c.</num>
<heading> Sanctioning organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objective criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 2 years after <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, the Association of Boxing Commissions shall develop and shall approve by a vote of no less than a majority of its member State boxing commissioners, guidelines for objective and consistent written criteria for the ratings of professional boxers. It is the sense of the Congress that sanctioning bodies and State boxing commissions should follow these ABC guidelines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeals process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A sanctioning organization shall not be entitled to receive any compensation, directly or indirectly, in connection with a boxing match, until it provides the boxers with notice that the sanctioning organization shall, within 7 days after receiving a request from a boxer questioning that organization’s rating of the boxer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to the boxer a written explanation of the organization’s criteria, its rating of the boxer, and the rationale or basis for its rating (including a response to any specific questions submitted by the boxer); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit a copy of its explanation to the Association of Boxing Commissions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of change in rating</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A sanctioning organization shall not be entitled to receive any compensation, directly or indirectly, in connection with a boxing match, until, with respect to a change in the rating of a boxer previously rated by such organization in the top 10 boxers, the organization—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> posts a copy, within 7 days of such change, on its Internet website or home page, if any, including an explanation of such change, for a period of not less than 30 days; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides a copy of the rating change and explanation to an association to which at least a majority of the State boxing commissions belong.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public disclosure</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Trade Commission filing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A sanctioning organization shall not be entitled to receive any compensation directly or indirectly in connection with a boxing match unless, not later than January 31 of each year, it submits to the Federal Trade Commission and to the ABC—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a complete description of the organization’s ratings criteria, policies, and general sanctioning fee schedule;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the bylaws of the organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the appeals procedure of the organization for a boxer’s rating; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a list and business address of the organization’s officials who vote on the ratings of boxers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Format; updates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A sanctioning organization shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide the information required under paragraph (1) in writing, and, for any document greater than 2 pages in length, also in electronic form; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promptly notify the Federal Trade Commission of any material change in the information submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Trade Commission to make information available to public</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal Trade Commission shall make information received under this subsection available to the public. The Commission may assess sanctioning organizations a fee to offset the costs it incurs in processing the information and making it available to the public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Internet alternative</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In lieu of submitting the information required by paragraph (1) to the Federal Trade Commission, a sanctioning organization may provide the information to the public by maintaining a website on the Internet that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is readily accessible by the general public using generally available search engines and does not require a password or payment of a fee for full access to all the information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contains all the information required to be submitted to the Federal Trade Commission by paragraph (1) in an easy to search and use format; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is updated whenever there is a material change in the information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 11</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307d.</num>
<heading> Required disclosures to State boxing commissions by sanctioning organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A sanctioning organization shall not be entitled to receive any compensation directly or indirectly in connection with a boxing match until it provides to the boxing commission responsible for regulating the match in a State a statement of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all charges, fees, and costs the organization will assess any boxer participating in that match;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all payments, benefits, complimentary benefits, and fees the organization will receive for its affiliation with the event, from the promoter, host of the event, and all other sources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such additional information as the commission may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 12</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 324</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307e.</num>
<heading> Required disclosures for promoters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosures to the boxing commissions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A promoter shall not be entitled to receive any compensation directly or indirectly in connection with a boxing match until it provides to the boxing commission responsible for regulating the match in a State a statement of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a copy of any agreement in writing to which the promoter is a party with any boxer participating in the match;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement made under penalty of perjury that there are no other agreements, written or oral, between the promoter and the boxer with respect to that match; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all fees, charges, and expenses that will be assessed by or through the promoter on the boxer pertaining to the event, including any portion of the boxer’s purse that the promoter will receive, and training expenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all payments, gifts, or benefits the promoter is providing to any sanctioning organization affiliated with the event; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any reduction in a boxer’s purse contrary to a previous agreement between the promoter and the boxer or a purse bid held for the event.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosures to the boxer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A promoter shall not be entitled to receive any compensation directly or indirectly in connection with a boxing match until it provides to the boxer it promotes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amounts of any compensation or consideration that a promoter has contracted to receive from such match;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all fees, charges, and expenses that will be assessed by or through the promoter on the boxer pertaining to the event, including any portion of the boxer’s purse that the promoter will receive, and training expenses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any reduction in a boxer’s purse contrary to a previous agreement between the promoter and the boxer or a purse bid held for the event.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be available to State Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A promoter shall make information required to be disclosed under this section available to the chief law enforcement officer of the State in which the match is to be held upon request of such officer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 13</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 324</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307f.</num>
<heading> Required disclosures for judges and referees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A judge or referee shall not be entitled to receive any compensation, directly or indirectly, in connection with a boxing match until it provides to the boxing commission responsible for regulating the match in a State a statement of all consideration, including reimbursement for expenses, that will be received from any source for participation in the match.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307g.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Neither a boxing commission or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002544">1</ref> an Attorney General may disclose to the public any matter furnished by a promoter under <ref>section 6307e of this title</ref> except to the extent required in a legal, administrative, or judicial proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of contrary State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a State law governing a boxing commission requires that information that would be furnished by a promoter under <ref>section 6307e of this title</ref> shall be made public, then a promoter is not required to file such information with such State if the promoter files such information with the ABC.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 15</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307h.</num>
<heading> Judges and referees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person may arrange, promote, organize, produce, or fight in a professional boxing match unless all referees and judges participating in the match have been certified and approved by the boxing commission responsible for regulating the match in the State where the match is held.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 16</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6308.</num>
<heading> Conflicts of interest</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No member or employee of a boxing commission, no person who administers or enforces State boxing laws, and no member of the Association of Boxing Commissions may belong to, contract with, or receive any compensation from, any person who sanctions, arranges, or promotes professional boxing matches or who otherwise has a financial interest in an active boxer currently registered with a boxer registry. For purposes of this section, the term “compensation” does not include funds held in escrow for payment to another person in connection with a professional boxing match. The prohibition set forth in this section shall not apply to any contract entered into, or any reasonable compensation received, by a boxing commission to supervise a professional boxing match in another State as described in <ref>section 6303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Firewall between promoters and managers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It is unlawful for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a promoter to have a direct or indirect financial interest in the management of a boxer; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a manager—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to have a direct or indirect financial interest in the promotion of a boxer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to be employed by or receive compensation or other benefits from a promoter, except for amounts received as consideration under the manager’s contract with the boxer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not prohibit a boxer from acting as his own promoter or manager; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> only applies to boxers participating in a boxing match of 10 rounds or more.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctioning organizations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no officer or employee of a sanctioning organization may receive any compensation, gift, or benefit, directly or indirectly, from a promoter, boxer, or manager.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) does not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the receipt of payment by a promoter, boxer, or manager of a sanctioning organization’s published fee for sanctioning a professional boxing match or reasonable expenses in connection therewith if the payment is reported to the responsible boxing commission; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the receipt of a gift or benefit of de minimis value.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 17</ref>, formerly § 9, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3311</ref>; renumbered § 17 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–210</ref>, §§ 4(1), 5, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>, 325.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6309.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Injunctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Attorney General of the United States has reasonable cause to believe that a person is engaged in a violation of this chapter, the Attorney General may bring a civil action in the appropriate district court of the United States requesting such relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order, against the person, as the Attorney General determines to be necessary to restrain the person from continuing to engage in, sanction, promote, or otherwise participate in a professional boxing match in violation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Managers, promoters, matchmakers, and licensees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any manager, promoter, matchmaker, and licensee who knowingly violates, or coerces or causes any other person to violate, any provision of this chapter, other than section 6307a(b),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002545">1</ref> 6307b, 6307c, 6307d, 6307e, 6307f, or 6307h of this title, shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined not more than $20,000, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation of antiexploitation, sanctioning organization, or disclosure provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any person who knowingly violates any provision of section 6307a(b),<sup>1</sup> 6307b, 6307c, 6307d, 6307e, 6307f, or 6307h of this title shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $100,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if a violation occurs in connection with a professional boxing match the gross revenues for which exceed $2,000,000, an additional amount which bears the same ratio to $100,000 as the amount of such revenues compared to $2,000,000, or both.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflict of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any member or employee of a boxing commission, any person who administers or enforces State boxing laws, and any member of the Association of Boxing Commissions who knowingly violates <ref>section 6308(a) of this title</ref> shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined not more than $20,000, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Boxers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any boxer who knowingly violates any provision of this chapter shall, upon conviction, be fined not more than $1,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the chief law enforcement officer of any State has reason to believe that a person or organization is engaging in practices which violate any requirement of this chapter, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of its residents in an appropriate district court of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to enjoin the holding of any professional boxing match which the practice involves;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to enforce compliance with this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to obtain the fines provided under subsection (b) or appropriate restitution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to obtain such other relief as the court may deem appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private right of action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any boxer who suffers economic injury as a result of a violation of any provision of this chapter may bring an action in the appropriate Federal or State court and recover the damages suffered, court costs, and reasonable attorneys fees and expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement against Federal Trade Commission, State Attorneys General, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter authorizes the enforcement of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any provision of this chapter against the Federal Trade Commission, the United States Attorney General, or the chief legal officer of any State for acting or failing to act in an official capacity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subsection (d) of this section against a State or political subdivision of a State, or any agency or instrumentality thereof; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content><ref>section 6307b of this title</ref> against a boxer acting in his capacity as a boxer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 18</ref>, formerly § 10, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3312</ref>; renumbered § 18 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–210</ref>, §§ 4(1), 6, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>, 326.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6310.</num>
<heading> Notification of supervising boxing commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each promoter who intends to hold a professional boxing match in a State that does not have a boxing commission shall, not later than 14 days before the intended date of that match, provide written notification to the supervising boxing commission designated under <ref>section 6303 of this title</ref>. Such notification shall contain each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Assurances that, with respect to that professional boxing match, all applicable requirements of this chapter will be met.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The name of any person who, at the time of the submission of the notification—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is under suspension from a boxing commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will be involved in organizing or participating in the event.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For any individual listed under paragraph (2), the identity of the boxing commission that issued the suspension described in paragraph (2)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 19</ref>, formerly § 11, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3312</ref>; renumbered § 19, <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6311.</num>
<heading> Studies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor shall conduct a study on the feasibility and cost of a national pension system for boxers, including potential funding sources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Health, safety, and equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study to develop recommendations for health, safety, and equipment standards for boxers and for professional boxing matches.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="1996-10-09">October 9, 1996</date>, the Secretary of Labor shall submit a report to the Congress on the findings of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a). Not later than 180 days after <date date="1996-10-09">October 9, 1996</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit a report to the Congress on the findings of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 20</ref>, formerly § 12, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3313</ref>; renumbered § 20, <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6312.</num>
<heading> Professional boxing matches conducted on Indian reservations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 5304(e) of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “reservation” means the geographically defined area over which a tribal organization exercises governmental jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “tribal organization” has the same meaning as in section 5304(<i>l</i>) of title 25.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a tribal organization of an Indian tribe may, upon the initiative of the tribal organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> regulate professional boxing matches held within the reservation under the jurisdiction of that tribal organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carry out that regulation or enter into a contract with a boxing commission to carry out that regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards and licensing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a tribal organization regulates professional boxing matches pursuant to paragraph (1), the tribal organization shall, by tribal ordinance or resolution, establish and provide for the implementation of health and safety standards, licensing requirements, and other requirements relating to the conduct of professional boxing matches that are at least as restrictive as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the otherwise applicable standards and requirements of a State in which the reservation is located; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the most recently published version of the recommended regulatory guidelines certified and published by the Association of Boxing Commissions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 21</ref>, formerly § 13, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3313</ref>; renumbered § 21, <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6313.</num>
<heading> Relationship with State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit a State from adopting or enforcing supplemental or more stringent laws or regulations not inconsistent with this chapter, or criminal, civil, or administrative fines for violations of such laws or regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–272, § 22</ref>, formerly § 14, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3313</ref>; renumbered § 22, <ref>Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>