<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 87A—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL DO-NOT-CALL REGISTRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6151.</num>
<heading> National Do-Not-Call Registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission is authorized under <ref>section 6102(a)(3)(A) of this title</ref> to implement and enforce a national do-not-call registry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ratification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The do-not-call registry provision of the Telemarketing Sales Rule (16 C.F.R. 310.4(b)(1)(iii)), which was promulgated by the Federal Trade Commission, effective <date date="2003-03-31">March 31, 2003</date>, is ratified.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–82, § 1</ref>, <date date="2003-09-29">Sept. 29, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1006</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6152.</num>
<heading> Telemarketing Sales Rule; do-not-call registry fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission shall assess and collect an annual fee pursuant to this section in order to implement and enforce the “do-not-call” registry as provided for in section 310.4(b)(1)(iii) of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, or any other regulation issued by the Commission under <ref>section 6102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual fees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall charge each person who accesses the “do-not-call” registry an annual fee that is equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $54 for each area code of data accessed from the registry; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $14,850 for access to every area code of data contained in the registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall not charge a fee to any person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for accessing the first 5 area codes of data; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for accessing area codes of data in the registry if the person is permitted to access, but is not required to access, the “do-not-call” registry under section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002542">1</ref> 310 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, section 64.1200 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any other Federal regulation or law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of access</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall allow each person who pays the annual fee described in paragraph (1), each person excepted under paragraph (2) from paying the annual fee, and each person excepted from paying an annual fee under section 310.4(b)(1)(iii)(B) of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, to access the area codes of data in the “do-not-call” registry for which the person has paid during that person’s annual period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “annual period” means the 12-month period beginning on the first day of the month in which a person pays the fee described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional fees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall charge a person required to pay an annual fee under subsection (b) an additional fee for each additional area code of data the person wishes to access during that person’s annual period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For each additional area code of data to be accessed during the person’s annual period, the Commission shall charge—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $54 for access to such data if access to the area code of data is first requested during the first 6 months of the person’s annual period; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $27 for access to such data if access to the area code of data is first requested after the first 6 months of the person’s annual period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of fees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal year 2009</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The dollar amount described in subsection (b) or (c) is the amount to be charged for fiscal year 2009.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal years after 2009</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For each fiscal year beginning after fiscal year 2009, each dollar amount in subsection (b)(1) and (c)(2) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the dollar amount in paragraph (b)(1) or (c)(2), whichever is applicable, multiplied by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the percentage (if any) by which the CPI for the most recently ended 12-month period ending on June 30 exceeds the baseline CPI.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rounding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any increase under subparagraph (B) shall be rounded to the nearest dollar.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Changes less than 1 percent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall not adjust the fees under this section if the change in the CPI is less than 1 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than September 1 of each year the Commission shall publish in the Federal Register the adjustments to the applicable fees, if any, made under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CPI</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “CPI” means the average of the monthly consumer price index (for all urban consumers published by the Department of Labor).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Baseline CPI</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “baseline CPI” means the CPI for the 12-month period ending <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition against fee sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person may enter into or participate in an arrangement (as such term is used in section 310.8(c) of the Commission’s regulations (16 C.F.R. 310.8(c))) to share any fee required by subsection (b) or (c), including any arrangement to divide the costs to access the registry among various clients of a telemarketer or service provider.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Handling of fees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall deposit and credit as offsetting collections any fee collected under this section in the account “Federal Trade Commission—Salaries and Expenses”, and such sums shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No amount shall be collected as a fee under this section for any fiscal year except to the extent provided in advance by appropriations Acts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–10, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-03-11">Mar. 11, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 557</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–188, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-02-15">Feb. 15, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6153.</num>
<heading> Federal Communications Commission do-not-call regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2003-03-11">March 11, 2003</date>, the Federal Communications Commission shall issue a final rule pursuant to the rulemaking proceeding that it began on <date date="2002-09-18">September 18, 2002</date>, under the Telephone Consumer Protection Act (<ref>47 U.S.C. 227</ref> et seq.). In issuing such rule, the Federal Communications Commission shall consult and coordinate with the Federal Trade Commission to maximize consistency with the rule promulgated by the Federal Trade Commission (16 CFR 310.4(b)).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–10, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-03-11">Mar. 11, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6154.</num>
<heading> Reporting requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Biennial reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Federal Trade Commission, in consultation with the Federal Communications Commission, shall transmit a report to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Energy and Commerce that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of consumers who have placed their telephone numbers on the registry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of persons paying fees for access to the registry and the amount of such fees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the impact on the “do-not-call” registry of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 5-year reregistration requirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> new telecommunications technology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> number portability and abandoned telephone numbers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the impact of the established business relationship exception on businesses and consumers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>, the Federal Trade Commission, in consultation with the Federal Communications Commission, shall transmit a report to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Energy and Commerce that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of do-not-call outreach and enforcement efforts with regard to senior citizens and immigrant communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the impact of the exceptions to the do-not-call registry on businesses and consumers, including an analysis of the effectiveness of the registry and consumer perceptions of the registry’s effectiveness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the impact of abandoned calls made by predictive dialing devices on do-not-call enforcement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–10, § 4</ref>, <date date="2003-03-11">Mar. 11, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 557</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–188, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-02-15">Feb. 15, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6155.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of expiration date</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No automatic removal of numbers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Telephone numbers registered on the national “do-not-call” registry of the Telemarketing Sales Rule (16 CFR 310.4(b)(1)(iii)) since the establishment of the registry and telephone numbers registered on such registry after <date date="2003-03-11">March 11, 2003</date>, shall not be removed from such registry except as provided for in subsection (b) or upon the request of the individual to whom the telephone number is assigned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of invalid, disconnected, and reassigned telephone numbers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission shall periodically check telephone numbers registered on the national “do-not-call” registry against national or other appropriate databases and shall remove from such registry those telephone numbers that have been disconnected and reassigned. Nothing in this section prohibits the Federal Trade Commission from removing invalid telephone numbers from the registry at any time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–10, § 5</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–187, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-02-15">Feb. 15, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 633</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>