<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 86—</num>
<heading>CHILDREN’S BICYCLE HELMET SAFETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6001.</num>
<heading> Establishment of program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration may, in accordance with <ref>section 6002 of this title</ref>, make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and nonprofit organizations for programs that require or encourage individuals under the age of 16 to wear approved bicycle helmets. In making those grants, the Administrator shall allow grantees to use wide discretion in designing programs that effectively promote increased bicycle helmet use.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount provided by a grant under this section shall not exceed 80 percent of the cost of the program for which the grant is made. In crediting the recipient State, political subdivision, or nonprofit organization for the non-Federal share of the cost of such a program (other than planning and administration), the aggregate of all expenditures made by such State, political subdivision, or nonprofit organization (exclusive of Federal funds) for the purposes described in <ref>section 6002 of this title</ref> (other than expenditures for planning and administration) shall be available for such crediting, without regard to whether such expenditures were actually made in connection with such program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–267, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6002.</num>
<heading> Purposes for grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A grant made under <ref>section 6001 of this title</ref> may be used by a grantee to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enforce a law that requires individuals under the age of 16 to wear approved bicycle helmets on their heads while riding on bicycles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide assistance, to individuals under the age of 16 who may not be able to afford approved bicycle helmets, to enable such individuals to acquire such helmets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop and administer a program to educate individuals under the age of 16 and their families on the importance of wearing such helmets in order to improve bicycle safety; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carry out any combination of the activities described in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Administrator shall review grant applications for compliance with this section prior to awarding grants.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–267, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6003.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1997-05-01">May 1, 1997</date>, the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall report to Congress on the effectiveness of the grant program established by <ref>section 6001 of this title</ref>. The report shall include a list of grant recipients, a summary of the types of programs implemented by the grantees, and any recommendation by the Administrator regarding how the program should be changed in the future.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–267, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6004.</num>
<heading> Standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Bicycle helmets manufactured 9 months or more after <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, shall conform to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any interim standard described under subsection (b), pending the establishment of a final standard pursuant to subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the final standard, once it has been established under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The interim standards are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The American National Standards Institute standard designated as “Z90.4–1984”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Snell Memorial Foundation standard designated as “B–90”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) standard designated as “F 1447”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other standard that the Commission determines is appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final standard</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, the Commission shall begin a proceeding under <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref> to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review the requirements of the interim standards set forth in subsection (a) and establish a final standard based on such requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> include in the final standard a provision to protect against the risk of helmets coming off the heads of bicycle riders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include in the final standard provisions that address the risk of injury to children; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> include additional provisions as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Sections 7, 9, and 30(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002540">1</ref> of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2056</ref>, 2058, 2079(d)) shall not apply to the proceeding under this subsection and section 11 of such Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2060</ref>) shall not apply with respect to any standard issued under such proceeding. The final standard shall take effect 1 year from the date it is issued.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to meet standards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to meet interim standard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Until the final standard takes effect, a bicycle helmet that does not conform to an interim standard as required under subsection (a)(1) shall be considered in violation of a consumer product safety standard promulgated under the Consumer Product Safety Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 2051</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status of final standard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The final standard developed under subsection (c) shall be considered a consumer product safety standard promulgated under the Consumer Product Safety Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–267, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6005.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to carry out the grant program authorized by this chapter, there are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1995, $3,000,000 for fiscal year 1996, and $4,000,000 for fiscal year 1997.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–267, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 728</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6006.</num>
<heading> “Approved bicycle helmet” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “approved bicycle helmet” means a bicycle helmet that meets—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any interim standard described in <ref>section 6004(b) of this title</ref>, pending establishment of a final standard under <ref>section 6004(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the final standard, once it is established under <ref>section 6004(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–267, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1994-06-16">June 16, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 728</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>