<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL WEATHER SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 311.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312.</num>
<heading> Employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Weather Service shall consist of such civilian employees as Congress may annually provide for and as may be necessary to properly perform the duties devolving on said Service by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 1, 1890, ch. 1266, § 4</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 653</ref>; <date date="1898-07-08">July 8, 1898</date>, No. 57, <ref>30 Stat. 752</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 313.</num>
<heading> Duties of Secretary of Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall have charge of the forecasting of weather, the issue of storm warnings, the display of weather and flood signals for the benefit of agriculture, commerce, and navigation, the gauging and reporting of rivers, the maintenance and operation of seacoast telegraph lines and the collection and transmission of marine intelligence for the benefit of commerce and navigation, the reporting of temperature and rain-fall conditions for the cotton interests, the display of frost and cold-wave signals, the distribution of meteorological information in the interests of agriculture and commerce, and the taking of such meteorological observations as may be necessary to establish and record the climatic conditions of the United States, or as are essential for the proper execution of the foregoing duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 1, 1890, ch. 1266, § 3</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 653</ref>; <ref>May 20, 1926, ch. 344, § 5</ref> (e), <ref>44 Stat. 571</ref>; <ref>June 23, 1938, ch. 601</ref>, title XI, § 1107(k), <ref>52 Stat. 1029</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. IV, § 8, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2421, <ref>54 Stat. 1236</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 313a.</num>
<heading> Establishment of meteorological observation stations in the Arctic region</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to improve the weather forecasting service of the United States and to promote safety and efficiency in civil air navigation to the highest possible degree, the Secretary of Commerce shall, in addition to his other functions and duties, take such action as may be necessary in the development of an international basic meteorological reporting network in the Arctic region of the Western Hemisphere, including the establishment, operation, and maintenance of such reporting stations in cooperation with the State Department and other United States governmental departments and agencies, with the meteorological services of foreign countries and with persons engaged in air commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 12, 1946, ch. 4, § 1</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 4</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 313b.</num>
<heading> Institute for Aviation Weather Prediction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall establish an Institute for Aviation Weather Prediction. The Institute shall provide forecasts, weather warnings, and other weather services to the United States aviation community. The Institute shall expand upon the activities of the aviation unit currently at the National Severe Storms Forecast Center in Kansas City, Missouri, and shall be established in the Kansas City <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002162">1</ref> Missouri <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002162">1</ref> area. The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall provide a full and fair opportunity for employees at the National Severe Storms Center to assume comparable duties and responsibilities within the Institute.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–588, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5119</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 313c.</num>
<heading> Authorized activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, through the United States Weather Research Program, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve the capability to accurately forecast inland flooding (including inland flooding influenced by coastal and ocean storms) through research and modeling;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop, test, and deploy a new flood warning index that will give the public and emergency management officials fuller, clearer, and more accurate information about the risks and dangers posed by expected floods;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> train emergency management officials, National Weather Service personnel, meteorologists, and others as appropriate regarding improved forecasting techniques for inland flooding, risk management techniques, and use of the inland flood warning index developed under paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conduct outreach and education activities for local meteorologists and the public regarding the dangers and risks associated with inland flooding and the use and understanding of the inland flood warning index developed under paragraph (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> assess, through research and analysis of previous trends, among other activities—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the long-term trends in frequency and severity of inland flooding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> how shifts in climate, development, and erosion patterns might make certain regions vulnerable to more continual or escalating flood damage in the future.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–253, § 2</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1731</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 313d.</num>
<heading> NIDIS program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary, through the National Weather Service and other appropriate weather and climate programs in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall establish a National Integrated Drought Information System to better inform and provide for more timely decisionmaking to reduce drought related impacts and costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Integrated Drought Information System shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> provide an effective drought early warning system that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collects and integrates information on the key indicators of drought and drought impacts, including precipitation, soil moisture, and evaporative demand, in order to make usable, reliable, and timely forecasts of drought and assessments of the severity of drought conditions and impacts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides such information, forecasts, and assessments on both national and regional levels;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> communicate drought forecasts, drought conditions, and drought impacts on an ongoing basis to public and private entities engaged in drought planning and preparedness, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> decisionmakers at the Federal, regional, State, tribal, and local levels of government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the private sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide timely data, information, and products that reflect local, regional, watershed, and State differences in drought conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordinate, and integrate, through interagency agreements as practicable, Federal research and monitoring in support of a drought early warning information system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> utilize existing forecasting and assessment programs and partnerships, including forecast communication coordinators and cooperative institutes, and improvements in seasonal precipitation and temperature, subseasonal precipitation and temperature, and low flow water prediction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> continue ongoing research and monitoring activities related to drought, including research activities relating to the prediction, length, severity, and impacts of drought and the role of extreme weather events and climate variability in drought.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Integrated Drought Information System may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> engage with the private sector to improve drought monitoring, forecast, and communication if the Under Secretary determines the partnership is appropriate, cost-effective, and beneficial to the public and decisionmakers described in subsection (b)(2)(A);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> facilitate the development of 1 or more academic cooperative partnerships to assist with National Integrated Drought Information System functions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> utilize and support, as appropriate, monitoring by citizen scientists, including by developing best practices to facilitate maximum data integration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall consult with relevant Federal, regional, State, tribal, and local government agencies, research institutions, and the private sector in the development and sustainment of the National Integrated Drought Information System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation from other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Federal agency shall cooperate as appropriate with the Under Secretary in carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Soil moisture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2019-01-07">January 7, 2019</date>, the Under Secretary, acting through the National Integrated Drought Information System, shall develop a strategy for a national coordinated soil moisture monitoring network.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–430, § 3</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–86, § 2</ref>, <date date="2014-03-06">Mar. 6, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1015</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–423, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-07">Jan. 7, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5454</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 314.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 315.</num>
<heading> Changes or assignment to duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to make such changes or assignment to duty in the personnel or detailed force of the National Weather Service for limiting or reducing expenses as he may deem necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1895, ch. 169</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 737</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. IV, § 8, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2421, <ref>54 Stat. 1236</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 316.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 317.</num>
<heading> Appropriations and estimates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The appropriations for the support of the National Weather Service shall be made with those of the other bureaus of the Department of Commerce, and it shall be the duty of the Secretary of Commerce to prepare future estimates for the National Weather Service which shall be specially developed and extended in the interests of agriculture.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 1, 1890, ch. 1266, § 9</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 653</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. IV, § 8, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2421, <ref>54 Stat. 1236</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 318.</num>
<heading> Weather signals on mail cars</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, in cooperation with the United States Postal Service, may arrange a plan by which there shall be displayed on all cars and other conveyances used for transporting United States mail suitable flags or other signals to indicate weather forecasts, cold-wave warnings, frost warnings, and so forth, to be furnished by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 25, 1896, ch. 140</ref>, <ref>29 Stat. 108</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. IV, § 8, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2421, <ref>54 Stat. 1236</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 319.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 320.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 1(34)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 702</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 321.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 25, 1951, ch. 562, § 1(15)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 638</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 322.</num>
<heading> Odd jobs for part-time employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">National Weather Service part-time employees, appointed by designation or otherwise under regulations of the Director of the Office of Personnel Management for observational work, may perform odd jobs in the installation, repair, improvement, alteration, cleaning, or removal of Government property and receive compensation therefor under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 1, 1943, ch. 182</ref>, title III, <ref>57 Stat. 300</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 323.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 25, 1947, ch. 327, § 1</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 449</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 324.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 325.</num>
<heading> Authority for certain functions and activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations now or hereafter provided for the National Weather Service shall be available for (a) furnishing food and shelter, without repayment therefor, to employees of the Government assigned to Arctic stations; (b) equipment and maintenance of meteorological offices and stations, and maintenance and operation of meteorological facilities outside the United States by contract or otherwise; (c) repairing, altering, and improving of buildings occupied by the National Weather Service, and care and preservation of grounds, including the construction of necessary outbuildings and sidewalks on public streets abutting National Weather Service grounds; (d) arranging for communication services at rates to be fixed by the Secretary of Commerce by agreement with the companies performing the services when determined to be advantageous to the Government; and (e) purchasing tabulating cards and continuous form tabulating paper.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 2, 1948, ch. 373, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 286</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, 1970 eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 326.</num>
<heading> Maintenance of printing office in Washington, D.C.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When so specified in appropriation Acts, the National Weather Service is authorized to maintain a printing office in the city of Washington for the printing of weather maps, bulletins, circulars, forms, and other publications: <i>Provided</i>, That no printing shall be done by the National Weather Service which could be done at the Government Publishing Office without impairing the service of said Service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 2, 1948, ch. 373, § 2</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 286</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 327.</num>
<heading> Employees for conduct of meteorological investigations in Arctic region; appointment and compensation; extra compensation to other Government employees for taking observations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to (a) appoint employees for the conduct of meteorological investigations in the Arctic region without regard to the civil service laws and fix their compensation without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, and sections 5542, 5543, 5545, and 5546 of title 5, at base rates not to exceed the maximum scheduled rate for GS–12, and (b) grant extra compensation to employees of other Government agencies for taking and transmitting meteorological observations without regard to <ref>section 5533 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 2, 1948, ch. 373, § 3</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–397, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-03-28">Mar. 28, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–448, title IV, § 401(m)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 491</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 328.</num>
<heading> Transfer from other Government Departments of surplus equipment and supplies for Arctic stations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to approval of the President, and without charge to the National Weather Service, the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Air Force, and the Secretary of the Navy are authorized to transfer to the National Weather Service equipment and supplies which are surplus to the needs of their respective Departments and necessary for the establishment, maintenance, and operation of Arctic weather stations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 2, 1948, ch. 373, § 4</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 286</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, 1970 eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref>79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref>84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 329.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</chapter>