<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 59—</num>
<heading>RETAIL POLICIES FOR NATURAL GAS UTILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3201.</num>
<heading> Purposes; coverage</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to encourage—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conservation of energy supplied by gas utilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the optimization of the efficiency of use of facilities and resources by gas utility systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> equitable rates to gas consumers of natural gas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Volume of total retail sales</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter applies to each gas utility in any calendar year, and to each proceeding relating to each gas utility in such year, if the total sales of natural gas by such utility for purposes other than resale exceeded 10 billion cubic feet during any calendar year beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>, and before the immediately preceding calendar year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of wholesale sales</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirements of this chapter do not apply to the operations of a gas utility, or to proceedings respecting such operations, to the extent that such operations or proceedings relate to sales of natural gas for purposes of resale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> List of covered utilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before the beginning of each calendar year, the Secretary shall publish a list identifying each gas utility to which this chapter applies during such calendar year. Promptly after publication of such list, each State regulatory authority shall notify the Secretary of each gas utility on the list for which such State regulatory authority has ratemaking authority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3202.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “gas consumer” means any person, State agency, or Federal agency, to which natural gas is sold other than for purposes of resale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “gas utility” means any person, State agency, or Federal agency, engaged in the local distribution of natural gas, and the sale of natural gas to any ultimate consumer of natural gas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “State regulated gas utility” means any gas utility with respect to which a State regulatory authority has ratemaking authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “nonregulated gas utility” means any gas utility other than a State regulated gas utility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “rate” means any (A) price, rate, charge, or classification made, demanded, observed, or received with respect to sale of natural gas to a gas consumer, (B) any rule, regulation, or practice respecting any such rate, charge, or classification, and (C) any contract pertaining to the sale of natural gas to a gas consumer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “ratemaking authority” means authority to fix, modify, approve, or disapprove rates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “sale” when used with respect to natural gas, includes an exchange of natural gas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “State regulatory authority” means any State agency which has ratemaking authority with respect to the sale of natural gas by any gas utility (other than by such State agency).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “integrated resource planning” means, in the case of a gas utility, planning by the use of any standard, regulation, practice, or policy to undertake a systematic comparison between demand-side management measures and the supply of gas by a gas utility to minimize life-cycle costs of adequate and reliable utility services to gas consumers. Integrated resource planning shall take into account necessary features for system operation such as diversity, reliability, dispatchability, and other factors of risk and shall treat demand and supply to gas consumers on a consistent and integrated basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The term “demand-side management” includes energy conservation, energy efficiency, and load management techniques.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 115(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3203.</num>
<heading> Adoption of certain standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption of standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date> (or after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, in the case of standards under paragraphs (3),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002481">1</ref> and (4) of subsection (b)), each State regulatory authority (with respect to each gas utility for which it has ratemaking authority) and each nonregulated gas utility shall provide public notice and conduct a hearing respecting the standards established by subsection (b), and, on the basis of such hearing, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt the standard established by subsection (b)(1), if, and to the extent, such authority or nonregulated utility determines that such adoption is appropriate and is consistent with otherwise applicable State law, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt the standards established by paragraphs (2), (3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002482">2</ref> (4), (5), and (6) of subsection (b), if, and to the extent, such authority or nonregulated utility determines that such adoption is appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter, is otherwise appropriate, and is consistent with otherwise applicable State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of any determination under paragraphs (1) and (2) and any review of such determination in any court under <ref>section 3207 of this title</ref>, the purposes of this chapter supplement State law. Nothing in this subsection prohibits any State regulatory authority or non­regulated utility from making any determination that it is not appropriate to implement any such standard, pursuant to its authority under otherwise applicable State law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following Federal standards are hereby established:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures for termination of natural gas service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No gas utility may terminate natural gas service to any gas consumer except pursuant to procedures described in <ref>section 3204(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advertising</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No gas utility may recover from any person other than the shareholders (or other owners) of such utility any direct or indirect expenditure by such utility for promotional or political advertising as defined in <ref>section 3204(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integrated resource planning</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each gas utility shall employ, in order to provide adequate and reliable service to its gas customers at the lowest system cost. All plans or filings of a State regulated gas utility before a State regulatory authority to meet the requirements of this paragraph shall (A) be updated on a regular basis, (B) provide the opportunity for public participation and comment, (C) provide for methods of validating predicted performance, and (D) contain a requirement that the plan be implemented after approval of the State regulatory authority. Subsection (c) shall not apply to this paragraph to the extent that it could be construed to require the State regulatory authority to extend the record of a State proceeding in submitting reports to the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments in conservation and demand management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rates charged by any State regulated gas utility shall be such that the utility’s prudent investments in, and expenditures for, energy conservation and load shifting programs and for other demand-side management measures which are consistent with the findings and purposes of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 are at least as profitable (taking into account the income lost due to reduced sales resulting from such programs) as prudent investments in, and expenditures for, the acquisition or construction of supplies and facilities. This objective requires that (A) regulators link the utility’s net revenues, at least in part, to the utility’s performance in implementing cost-effective programs promoted by this section; and (B) regulators ensure that, for purposes of recovering fixed costs, including its authorized return, the utility’s performance is not affected by reductions in its retail sales volumes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy efficiency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each natural gas utility shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> integrate energy efficiency resources into the plans and planning processes of the natural gas utility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adopt policies that establish energy efficiency as a priority resource in the plans and planning processes of the natural gas utility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate design modifications to promote energy efficiency investments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The rates allowed to be charged by a natural gas utility shall align utility incentives with the deployment of cost-effective energy efficiency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy options</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In complying with subparagraph (A), each State regulatory authority and each nonregulated utility shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> separating fixed-cost revenue recovery from the volume of transportation or sales service provided to the customer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> providing to utilities incentives for the successful management of energy efficiency programs, such as allowing utilities to retain a portion of the cost-reducing benefits accruing from the programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> promoting the impact on adoption of energy efficiency as 1 of the goals of retail rate design, recognizing that energy efficiency must be balanced with other objectives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> adopting rate designs that encourage energy efficiency for each customer class.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">For purposes of applying the provisions of this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002483">3</ref> to this paragraph, any reference in this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002483">3</ref> to <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, shall be treated as a reference to <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedural requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State regulatory authority (with respect to each gas utility for which it has ratemaking authority) and each nonregulated gas utility, within the 2-year period specified in subsection (a), shall adopt, pursuant to subsection (a), each of the standards established by subsection (b), or, with respect to any such standard which is not adopted, such authority or nonregulated gas utility shall state in writing that it has determined not to adopt such standard, together with the reasons for such determination. Such statement of reasons shall be available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Small business impacts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If a State regulatory authority implements a standard established by subsection (b)(3) or (4), such authority shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consider the impact that implementation of such standard would have on small businesses engaged in the design, sale, supply, installation, or servicing of energy conservation, energy efficiency, or other demand-side management measures, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> implement such standard so as to assure that utility actions would not provide such utilities with unfair competitive advantages over such small businesses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 115(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2803</ref>, 2804; <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title V, § 532(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1666</ref>, 1667.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3204.</num>
<heading> Special rules for standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures for termination of gas service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The procedures for termination of service referred to in <ref>section 3203(b)(1) of this title</ref> are procedures prescribed by the State regulatory authority (with respect to gas utilities for which it has ratemaking authority) or the nonregulated gas utility which provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no gas service to a gas consumer may be terminated unless reasonable prior notice (including notice of rights and remedies) is given to such consumer and such consumer has a reasonable opportunity to dispute the reasons for such termination, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> during any period when termination of service to a gas consumer would be especially dangerous to health, as determined by the State regulatory authority (with respect to each gas utility for which it has ratemaking authority) or nonregulated gas utility, and such consumer establishes that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> he is unable to pay for such service in accordance with the requirements of the utility’s billing, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> he is able to pay for such service but only in installments,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">such service may not be terminated.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such procedures shall take into account the need to include reasonable provisions for elderly and handicapped consumers.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advertising</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section and <ref>section 3203 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “advertising” means the commercial use, by a gas utility, of any media, including newspaper, printed matter, radio, and television, in order to transmit a message to a substantial number of members of the public or to such utility’s gas consumers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “political advertising” means any advertising for the purpose of influencing public opinion with respect to legislative, administrative, or electoral matters, or with respect to any controversial issue of public importance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “promotional advertising” means any advertising for the purpose of encouraging any person to select or use the service or additional service of a gas utility or the selection or installation of any appliance or equipment designed to use such utility’s service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section and <ref>section 3203 of this title</ref>, the terms “political advertising” and “promotional advertising” do not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advertising which informs natural gas consumers how they can conserve natural gas or can reduce peak demand for natural gas,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> advertising required by law or regulation, including advertising required under part 1 of title II of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 8211</ref> et seq.],</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> advertising regarding service interruptions, safety measures, or emergency conditions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> advertising concerning employment opportunities with such utility,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> advertising which promotes the use of energy efficient appliances, equipment or services, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any explanation or justification of existing or proposed rate schedules, or notification of hearings thereon.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3205.</num>
<heading> Federal participation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intervention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the authorities vested in the Secretary pursuant to any other provision of law, the Secretary, on his own motion, may intervene as a matter of right in any proceeding before a State regulatory authority which relates to gas utility rates or rate design. Such intervention shall be solely for the purpose of advocating policies or methods which carry out the purposes set forth in <ref>section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall have the same rights as any other party to a proceeding before a State regulatory authority which relates to gas utility rates or rate design.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonregulated gas utilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, on his own motion, may, to the same extent as provided in subsections (a) through (b), intervene as a matter of right in any proceeding which relates to rates or rate design of nonregulated gas utilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3206.</num>
<heading> Gas utility rate design proposals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary, in consultation with the Commission and, after affording an opportunity for consultation and comment by representatives of the State regulatory commissions, gas utilities, and gas consumers, shall study and report to Congress on gas utility rate design within 18 months after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>. Such study shall address the effect (both separately and in combination) of the following factors upon the items listed in paragraph (2): incremental pricing; marginal cost pricing; end user gas consumption taxes; wellhead natural gas pricing policies; demand-commodity rate design; declining block rates; interruptible service; seasonal rate differentials; and end user rate schedules.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The items referred to in paragraph (1) are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> natural gas pipeline and local distribution company load factors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> rates to each class of user, including residential, commercial, and industrial users;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the change in total costs resulting from gas utility designs (including capital and operating costs) to gas consumers or classes thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> demand for, and consumption of, natural gas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> end use profiles of natural gas pipelines and local distribution companies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> competition with alternative fuels.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Based upon the study prepared pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall develop proposals to improve gas utility rate design and to encourage conservation of natural gas. Such proposals shall include any comments and recommendations of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmission to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The proposals prepared under subsection (b), shall be transmitted, together with any legislative recommendations, to each House of Congress not later than 6 months after the date of submission of the study under subsection (a). Such proposals shall be accompanied by an analyses <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002484">1</ref> of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the projected savings (if any) in consumption of natural gas, and other energy resources,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> changes (if any) in the cost of natural gas to consumers, which are likely to result from the implementation nationally of each of such proposals, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the effects of the proposals on other provisions of this Act on gas utility rate structures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for public participation in the conduct of the study under subsection (a), and the preparation of proposals under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3207.</num>
<heading> Judicial review and enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation of Federal jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no court of the United States shall have jurisdiction over any action arising under any provision of this chapter except for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an action over which a court of the United States has jurisdiction under paragraph (2), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> review in the Supreme Court of the United States in accordance with sections 1257 and 1258 of title 28.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may bring an action in any appropriate court of the United States to enforce his right to intervene under <ref>section 3205 of this title</ref>, and such court shall have jurisdiction to grant appropriate relief.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any person may bring an action to enforce the requirements of this chapter in the appropriate State court. Such action in a State court shall be pursuant to applicable State procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the Secretary to appeal or otherwise seek judicial review of the decisions of a State regulatory authority or nonregulated gas utility or to become a party to any action to obtain such review or appeal. The Secretary may participate as an amicus curiae in any judicial review of an action arising under the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3208.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other applicable law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter prohibits any State regulatory authority or nonregulated gas utility from adopting, pursuant to State law, any standard or rule affecting gas utilities which is different from any standard established by this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3209.</num>
<heading> Reports respecting standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State authorities and nonregulated utilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, and annually thereafter for 10 years, each State regulatory authority (with respect to each gas utility for which it has ratemaking authority), and each nonregulated gas utility, shall report to the Secretary, in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe, respecting its consideration of the standards established by this chapter. Such report shall include a summary of the determinations made and actions taken with respect to each of such standards on a utility-by-utility basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, and annually thereafter for 10 years, the Secretary shall submit a report to the President and the Congress containing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the reports submitted under subsection (a),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> his analysis of such reports, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> his actions under this chapter, and his recommendations for such further Federal actions, including any legislation, regarding retail gas utility rates (and other practices) as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3210.</num>
<heading> Prior and pending proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, proceedings commenced by any State regulatory authority (with respect to gas utilities for which it has ratemaking authority) and any nonregulated gas utility before <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, and actions taken before such date in such proceedings shall be treated as complying with the requirements of this chapter if such proceedings and actions substantially conform to such requirements. For purposes of this chapter, any such proceeding or action commenced before <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, but not completed before such date shall comply with the requirements of this chapter, to the maximum extent practicable, with respect to so much of such proceeding or action as takes place after such date.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3211.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit or affect any authority of the Secretary or the Commission under any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>