<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 93—</num>
<heading>INSURANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6701.</num>
<heading> Operation of State law</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State regulation of the business of insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to express the intent of Congress with reference to the regulation of the business of insurance” and approved <date date="1945-03-09">March 9, 1945</date> (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1011</ref> et seq.) (commonly referred to as the “McCarran-Ferguson Act”) remains the law of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory insurance licensing requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person shall engage in the business of insurance in a State as principal or agent unless such person is licensed as required by the appropriate insurance regulator of such State in accordance with the relevant State insurance law, subject to subsections (c), (d), and (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affiliations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no State may, by statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action, prevent or restrict a depository institution, or an affiliate thereof, from being affiliated directly or indirectly or associated with any person, as authorized or permitted by this Act or any other provision of Federal law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to affiliations between depository institutions, or any affiliate thereof, and any insurer, paragraph (1) does not prohibit—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any State from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> collecting, reviewing, and taking actions (including approval and disapproval) on applications and other documents or reports concerning any proposed acquisition of, or a change or continuation of control of, an insurer domiciled in that State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> exercising authority granted under applicable State law to collect information concerning any proposed acquisition of, or a change or continuation of control of, an insurer engaged in the business of insurance in, and regulated as an insurer by, such State;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">during the 60-day period preceding the effective date of the acquisition or change or continuation of control, so long as the collecting, reviewing, taking actions, or exercising authority by the State does not have the effect of discriminating, intentionally or unintentionally, against a depository institution or an affiliate thereof, or against any other person based upon an association of such person with a depository institution;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any State from requiring any person that is acquiring control of an insurer domiciled in that State to maintain or restore the capital requirements of that insurer to the level required under the capital regulations of general applicability in that State to avoid the requirement of preparing and filing with the insurance regulatory authority of that State a plan to increase the capital of the insurer, except that any determination by the State insurance regulatory authority with respect to such requirement shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of notification under subparagraph (A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any State from restricting a change in the ownership of stock in an insurer, or a company formed for the purpose of controlling such insurer, after the conversion of the insurer from mutual to stock form so long as such restriction does not have the effect of discriminating, intentionally or unintentionally, against a depository institution or an affiliate thereof, or against any other person based upon an association of such person with a depository institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), and except with respect to insurance sales, solicitation, and cross marketing activities, which shall be governed by paragraph (2), no State may, by statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action, prevent or restrict a depository institution or an affiliate thereof from engaging directly or indirectly, either by itself or in conjunction with an affiliate, or any other person, in any activity authorized or permitted under this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance sales</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In accordance with the legal standards for preemption set forth in the decision of the Supreme Court of the United States in Barnett Bank of Marion County N.A. v. Nelson, 517 U.S. 25 (1996), no State may, by statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action, prevent or significantly interfere with the ability of a depository institution, or an affiliate thereof, to engage, directly or indirectly, either by itself or in conjunction with an affiliate or any other person, in any insurance sales, solicitation, or crossmarketing activity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain State laws preserved</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a State may impose any of the following restrictions, or restrictions that are substantially the same as but no more burdensome or restrictive than those in each of the following clauses:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Restrictions prohibiting the rejection of an insurance policy by a depository institution or an affiliate of a depository institution, solely because the policy has been issued or underwritten by any person who is not associated with such depository institution or affiliate when the insurance is required in connection with a loan or extension of credit.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Restrictions prohibiting a requirement for any debtor, insurer, or insurance agent or broker to pay a separate charge in connection with the handling of insurance that is required in connection with a loan or other extension of credit or the provision of another traditional banking product by a depository institution, or any affiliate of a depository institution, unless such charge would be required when the depository institution or affiliate is the licensed insurance agent or broker providing the insurance.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> Restrictions prohibiting the use of any advertisement or other insurance promotional material by a depository institution or any affiliate of a depository institution that would cause a reasonable person to believe mistakenly that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Federal Government or a State is responsible for the insurance sales activities of, or stands behind the credit of, the institution or affiliate; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a State, or the Federal Government guarantees any returns on insurance products, or is a source of payment on any insurance obligation of or sold by the institution or affiliate;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Restrictions prohibiting the payment or receipt of any commission or brokerage fee or other valuable consideration for services as an insurance agent or broker to or by any person, unless such person holds a valid State license regarding the applicable class of insurance at the time at which the services are performed, except that, in this clause, the term “services as an insurance agent or broker” does not include a referral by an unlicensed person of a customer or potential customer to a licensed insurance agent or broker that does not include a discussion of specific insurance policy terms and conditions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Restrictions prohibiting any compensation paid to or received by any individual who is not licensed to sell insurance, for the referral of a customer that seeks to purchase, or seeks an opinion or advice on, any insurance product to a person that sells or provides opinions or advice on such product, based on the purchase of insurance by the customer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<chapeau> Restrictions prohibiting the release of the insurance information of a customer (defined as information concerning the premiums, terms, and conditions of insurance coverage, including expiration dates and rates, and insurance claims of a customer contained in the records of the depository institution or an affiliate thereof) to any person other than an officer, director, employee, agent, or affiliate of a depository institution, for the purpose of soliciting or selling insurance, without the express consent of the customer, other than a provision that prohibits—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a transfer of insurance information to an unaffiliated insurer in connection with transferring insurance in force on existing insureds of the depository institution or an affiliate thereof, or in connection with a merger with or acquisition of an unaffiliated insurer; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the release of information as otherwise authorized by State or Federal law.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Restrictions prohibiting the use of health information obtained from the insurance records of a customer for any purpose, other than for its activities as a licensed agent or broker, without the express consent of the customer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<chapeau> Restrictions prohibiting the extension of credit or any product or service that is equivalent to an extension of credit, lease or sale of property of any kind, or furnishing of any services or fixing or varying the consideration for any of the foregoing, on the condition or requirement that the customer obtain insurance from a depository institution or an affiliate of a depository institution, or a particular insurer, agent, or broker, other than a prohibition that would prevent any such depository institution or affiliate—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> from engaging in any activity described in this clause that would not violate section 106 of the Bank Holding Company Act Amendments of 1970 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1971</ref> et seq.], as interpreted by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> from informing a customer or prospective customer that insurance is required in order to obtain a loan or credit, that loan or credit approval is contingent upon the procurement by the customer of acceptable insurance, or that insurance is available from the depository institution or an affiliate of the depository institution.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> Restrictions requiring, when an application by a consumer for a loan or other extension of credit from a depository institution is pending, and insurance is offered or sold to the consumer or is required in connection with the loan or extension of credit by the depository institution or any affiliate thereof, that a written disclosure be provided to the consumer or prospective customer indicating that the customer’s choice of an insurance provider will not affect the credit decision or credit terms in any way, except that the depository institution may impose reasonable requirements concerning the creditworthiness of the insurer and scope of coverage chosen.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<chapeau> Restrictions requiring clear and conspicuous disclosure, in writing, where practicable, to the customer prior to the sale of any insurance policy that such policy—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is not a deposit;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is not insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> is not guaranteed by any depository institution or, if appropriate, an affiliate of any such institution or any person soliciting the purchase of or selling insurance on the premises thereof; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> where appropriate, involves investment risk, including potential loss of principal.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> Restrictions requiring that, when a customer obtains insurance (other than credit insurance or flood insurance) and credit from a depository institution, or any affiliate of such institution, or any person soliciting the purchase of or selling insurance on the premises thereof, the credit and insurance transactions be completed through separate documents.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> Restrictions prohibiting, when a customer obtains insurance (other than credit insurance or flood insurance) and credit from a depository institution or an affiliate of such institution, or any person soliciting the purchase of or selling insurance on the premises thereof, inclusion of the expense of insurance premiums in the primary credit transaction without the express written consent of the customer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiii)</num>
<content> Restrictions requiring maintenance of separate and distinct books and records relating to insurance transactions, including all files relating to and reflecting consumer complaints, and requiring that such insurance books and records be made available to the appropriate State insurance regulator for inspection upon reasonable notice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> OCC deference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3"><ref>Section 6714(e) of this title</ref> does not apply with respect to any State statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action regarding insurance sales, solicitation, or cross marketing activities described in subparagraph (A) that was issued, adopted, or enacted before <date date="1998-09-03">September 3, 1998</date>, and that is not described in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondiscrimination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subsection (e) does not apply with respect to any State statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action regarding insurance sales, solicitation, or cross marketing activities described in subparagraph (A) that was issued, adopted, or enacted before <date date="1998-09-03">September 3, 1998</date>, and that is not described in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to limit the applicability of the decision of the Supreme Court in Barnett Bank of Marion County N.A. v. Nelson, 517 U.S. 25 (1996) with respect to any State statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action that is not referred to or described in subparagraph (B); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to create any inference with respect to any State statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action that is not described in this paragraph.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance activities other than sales</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">State statutes, regulations, interpretations, orders, and other actions shall not be preempted under paragraph (1) to the extent that they—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> relate to, or are issued, adopted, or enacted for the purpose of regulating the business of insurance in accordance with the Act entitled “An Act to express the intent of Congress with reference to the regulation of the business of insurance” and approved <date date="1945-03-09">March 9, 1945</date> (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1011</ref> et seq.) (commonly referred to as the “McCarran-Ferguson Act”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> apply only to persons that are not depository institutions, but that are directly engaged in the business of insurance (except that they may apply to depository institutions engaged in providing savings bank life insurance as principal to the extent of regulating such insurance);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> do not relate to or directly or indirectly regulate insurance sales, solicitations, or cross marketing activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> are not prohibited under subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial activities other than insurance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No State statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action shall be preempted under paragraph (1) to the extent that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> it does not relate to, and is not issued and adopted, or enacted for the purpose of regulating, directly or indirectly, insurance sales, solicitations, or cross marketing activities covered under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> it does not relate to, and is not issued and adopted, or enacted for the purpose of regulating, directly or indirectly, the business of insurance activities other than sales, solicitations, or cross marketing activities, covered under paragraph (3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> it does not relate to securities investigations or enforcement actions referred to in subsection (f); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> it—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> does not distinguish by its terms between depository institutions, and affiliates thereof, engaged in the activity at issue and other persons engaged in the same activity in a manner that is in any way adverse with respect to the conduct of the activity by any such depository institution or affiliate engaged in the activity at issue;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as interpreted or applied, does not have, and will not have, an impact on depository institutions, or affiliates thereof, engaged in the activity at issue, or any person who has an association with any such depository institution or affiliate, that is substantially more adverse than its impact on other persons engaged in the same activity that are not depository institutions or affiliates thereof, or persons who do not have an association with any such depository institution or affiliate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> does not effectively prevent a depository institution or affiliate thereof from engaging in activities authorized or permitted by this Act or any other provision of Federal law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> does not conflict with the intent of this Act generally to permit affiliations that are authorized or permitted by Federal law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondiscrimination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in any restrictions described in subsection (d)(2)(B), no State may, by statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action, regulate the insurance activities authorized or permitted under this Act or any other provision of Federal law of a depository institution, or affiliate thereof, to the extent that such statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> distinguishes by its terms between depository institutions, or affiliates thereof, and other persons engaged in such activities, in a manner that is in any way adverse to any such depository institution, or affiliate thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as interpreted or applied, has or will have an impact on depository institutions, or affiliates thereof, that is substantially more adverse than its impact on other persons providing the same products or services or engaged in the same activities that are not depository institutions, or affiliates thereof, or persons or entities affiliated therewith;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> effectively prevents a depository institution, or affiliate thereof, from engaging in insurance activities authorized or permitted by this Act or any other provision of Federal law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conflicts with the intent of this Act generally to permit affiliations that are authorized or permitted by Federal law between depository institutions, or affiliates thereof, and persons engaged in the business of insurance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsections (c) and (d) shall not be construed to affect—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the jurisdiction of the securities commission (or any agency or office performing like functions) of any State, under the laws of such State—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to investigate and bring enforcement actions, consistent with <ref>section 77r(c) of this title</ref>, with respect to fraud or deceit or unlawful conduct by any person, in connection with securities or securities transactions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to require the registration of securities or the licensure or registration of brokers, dealers, or investment advisers (consistent with <ref>section 80b–3a of this title</ref>), or the associated persons of a broker, dealer, or investment adviser (consistent with such <ref>section 80b–3a of this title</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> State laws, regulations, orders, interpretations, or other actions of general applicability relating to the governance of corporations, partnerships, limited liability companies, or other business associations incorporated or formed under the laws of that State or domiciled in that State, or the applicability of the antitrust laws of any State or any State law that is similar to the antitrust laws if such laws, regulations, orders, interpretations, or other actions are not inconsistent with the purposes of this Act to authorize or permit certain affiliations and to remove barriers to such affiliations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affiliate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “affiliate” means any company that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another company.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Antitrust laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “antitrust laws” has the meaning given the term in subsection (a) of <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>, and includes <ref>section 45 of this title</ref> (to the extent that such section 45 relates to unfair methods of competition).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depository institution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “depository institution”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1813 of title 12</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes any foreign bank that maintains a branch, agency, or commercial lending company in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insurer” means any person engaged in the business of insurance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>STATE REGULATION OF INSURANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6711.</num>
<heading> Functional regulation of insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The insurance activities of any person (including a national bank exercising its power to act as agent under <ref>section 92 of title 12</ref>) shall be functionally regulated by the States, subject to <ref>section 6701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6712.</num>
<heading> Insurance underwriting in national banks</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 6713 of this title</ref>, a national bank and the subsidiaries of a national bank may not provide insurance in a State as principal except that this prohibition shall not apply to authorized products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized products</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, a product is authorized if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as of <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, the Comptroller of the Currency had determined in writing that national banks may provide such product as principal, or national banks were in fact lawfully providing such product as principal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no court of relevant jurisdiction had, by final judgment, overturned a determination of the Comptroller of the Currency that national banks may provide such product as principal; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the product is not title insurance, or an annuity contract the income of which is subject to tax treatment under <ref>section 72 of title 26</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “insurance” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any product regulated as insurance as of <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, in accordance with the relevant State insurance law, in the State in which the product is provided;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> any product first offered after <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State insurance regulator determines shall be regulated as insurance in the State in which the product is provided because the product insures, guarantees, or indemnifies against liability, loss of life, loss of health, or loss through damage to or destruction of property, including, but not limited to, surety bonds, life insurance, health insurance, title insurance, and property and casualty insurance (such as private passenger or commercial automobile, homeowners, mortgage, commercial multiperil, general liability, professional liability, workers’ compensation, fire and allied lines, farm owners multiperil, aircraft, fidelity, surety, medical malpractice, ocean marine, inland marine, and boiler and machinery insurance); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is not a product or service of a bank that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a deposit product;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a loan, discount, letter of credit, or other extension of credit;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a trust or other fiduciary service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a qualified financial contract (as defined in or determined pursuant to <ref>section 1821(e)(8)(D)(i) of title 12</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> a financial guaranty, except that this subparagraph (B) shall not apply to a product that includes an insurance component such that if the product is offered or proposed to be offered by the bank as principal—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> it would be treated as a life insurance contract under <ref>section 7702 of title 26</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the event that the product is not a letter of credit or other similar extension of credit, a qualified financial contract, or a financial guaranty, it would qualify for treatment for losses incurred with respect to such product under <ref>section 832(b)(5) of title 26</ref>, if the bank were subject to tax as an insurance company under section 831 of that title; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any annuity contract, the income on which is subject to tax treatment under <ref>section 72 of title 26</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, providing insurance (including reinsurance) outside the United States that insures, guarantees, or indemnifies insurance products provided in a State, or that indemnifies an insurance company with regard to insurance products provided in a State, shall be considered to be providing insurance as principal in that State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6713.</num>
<heading> Title insurance activities of national banks and their affiliates</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No national bank may engage in any activity involving the underwriting or sale of title insurance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondiscrimination parity exception</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including <ref>section 6701 of this title</ref>), in the case of any State in which banks organized under the laws of such State are authorized to sell title insurance as agent, a national bank may sell title insurance as agent in such State, but only in the same manner, to the same extent, and under the same restrictions as such State banks are authorized to sell title insurance as agent in such State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with “wildcard” provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State law which authorizes State banks to engage in any activities in such State in which a national bank may engage shall not be treated as a statute which authorizes State banks to sell title insurance as agent, for purposes of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grandfathering with consistent regulation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) and notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), a national bank, and a subsidiary of a national bank, may conduct title insurance activities which such national bank or subsidiary was actively and lawfully conducting before <date date="1999-11-12">November 12, 1999</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance affiliate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a national bank which has an affiliate which provides insurance as principal and is not a subsidiary of the bank, the national bank and any subsidiary of the national bank may not engage in the underwriting of title insurance pursuant to paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance subsidiary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a national bank which has a subsidiary which provides insurance as principal and has no affiliate other than a subsidiary which provides insurance as principal, the national bank may not directly engage in any activity involving the underwriting of title insurance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Affiliate” and “subsidiary” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the terms “affiliate” and “subsidiary” have the same meanings as in <ref>section 1841 of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this Act or any other Federal law shall be construed as superseding or affecting a State law which was in effect before <date date="1999-11-12">November 12, 1999</date>, and which prohibits title insurance from being offered, provided, or sold in such State, or from being underwritten with respect to real property in such State, by any person whatsoever.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6714.</num>
<heading> Expedited and equalized dispute resolution for Federal regulators</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing in Court of Appeals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a regulatory conflict between a State insurance regulator and a Federal regulator regarding insurance issues, including whether a State law, rule, regulation, order, or interpretation regarding any insurance sales or solicitation activity is properly treated as preempted under Federal law, the Federal or State regulator may seek expedited judicial review of such determination by the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the State is located or in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit by filing a petition for review in such court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Appeals in which a petition for review is filed in accordance with subsection (a) shall complete all action on such petition, including rendering a judgment, before the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which such petition is filed, unless all parties to such proceeding agree to any extension of such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supreme Court review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any request for certiorari to the Supreme Court of the United States of any judgment of a United States Court of Appeals with respect to a petition for review under this section shall be filed with the Supreme Court of the United States as soon as practicable after such judgment is issued.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statute of limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No petition may be filed under this section challenging an order, ruling, determination, or other action of a Federal regulator or State insurance regulator after the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the first public notice is made of such order, ruling, determination or other action in its final form; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date on which such order, ruling, determination, or other action takes effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standard of review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The court shall decide a petition filed under this section based on its review on the merits of all questions presented under State and Federal law, including the nature of the product or activity and the history and purpose of its regulation under State and Federal law, without unequal deference.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6715.</num>
<heading> Certain State affiliation laws preempted for insurance companies and affiliates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 6701(c)(2) of this title</ref>, no State may, by law, regulation, order, interpretation, or otherwise—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prevent or significantly interfere with the ability of any insurer, or any affiliate of an insurer (whether such affiliate is organized as a stock company, mutual holding company, or otherwise), to become a financial holding company or to acquire control of a depository institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> limit the amount of an insurer’s assets that may be invested in the voting securities of a depository institution (or any company which controls such institution), except that the laws of an insurer’s State of domicile may limit the amount of such investment to an amount that is not less than 5 percent of the insurer’s admitted assets; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prevent, significantly interfere with, or have the authority to review, approve, or disapprove a plan of reorganization by which an insurer proposes to reorganize from mutual form to become a stock insurer (whether as a direct or indirect subsidiary of a mutual holding company or otherwise) unless such State is the State of domicile of the insurer.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6716.</num>
<heading> Interagency consultation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the intention of the Congress that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, as the umbrella supervisor for financial holding companies, and the State insurance regulators, as the functional regulators of companies engaged in insurance activities, coordinate efforts to supervise companies that control both a depository institution and a company engaged in insurance activities regulated under State law. In particular, Congress believes that the Board and the State insurance regulators should share, on a confidential basis, information relevant to the supervision of companies that control both a depository institution and a company engaged in insurance activities, including information regarding the financial health of the consolidated organization and information regarding transactions and relationships between insurance companies and affiliated depository institutions. The appropriate Federal banking agencies for depository institutions should also share, on a confidential basis, information with the relevant State insurance regulators regarding transactions and relationships between depository institutions and affiliated companies engaged in insurance activities. The purpose of this section is to encourage this coordination and confidential sharing of information, and to thereby improve both the efficiency and the quality of the supervision of financial holding companies and their affiliated depository institutions and companies engaged in insurance activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Examination results and other information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information of the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the request of the appropriate insurance regulator of any State, the Board may provide any information of the Board regarding the financial condition, risk management policies, and operations of any financial holding company that controls a company that is engaged in insurance activities and is regulated by such State insurance regulator, and regarding any transaction or relationship between such an insurance company and any affiliated depository institution. The Board may provide any other information to the appropriate State insurance regulator that the Board believes is necessary or appropriate to permit the State insurance regulator to administer and enforce applicable State insurance laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Banking agency information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the request of the appropriate insurance regulator of any State, the appropriate Federal banking agency may provide any information of the agency regarding any transaction or relationship between a depository institution supervised by such Federal banking agency and any affiliated company that is engaged in insurance activities regulated by such State insurance regulator. The appropriate Federal banking agency may provide any other information to the appropriate State insurance regulator that the agency believes is necessary or appropriate to permit the State insurance regulator to administer and enforce applicable State insurance laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State insurance regulator information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Upon the request of the Board or the appropriate Federal banking agency, a State insurance regulator may provide any examination or other reports, records, or other information to which such insurance regulator may have access with respect to a company which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is engaged in insurance activities and regulated by such insurance regulator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is an affiliate of a depository institution or financial holding company.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before making any determination relating to the initial affiliation of, or the continuing affiliation of, a depository institution or financial holding company with a company engaged in insurance activities, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall consult with the appropriate State insurance regulator of such company and take the views of such insurance regulator into account in making such determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall limit in any respect the authority of the appropriate Federal banking agency with respect to a depository institution or bank holding company or any affiliate thereof under any provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality and privilege</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appropriate Federal banking agency shall not provide any information or material that is entitled to confidential treatment under applicable Federal banking agency regulations, or other applicable law, to a State insurance regulator unless such regulator agrees to maintain the information or material in confidence and to take all reasonable steps to oppose any effort to secure disclosure of the information or material by the regulator. The appropriate Federal banking agency shall treat as confidential any information or material obtained from a State insurance regulator that is entitled to confidential treatment under applicable State regulations, or other applicable law, and take all reasonable steps to oppose any effort to secure disclosure of the information or material by the Federal banking agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privilege</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provision pursuant to this section of information or material by a Federal banking agency or State insurance regulator shall not constitute a waiver of, or otherwise affect, any privilege to which the information or material is otherwise subject.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate Federal banking agency; depository institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “appropriate Federal banking agency” and “depository institution” have the same meanings as in <ref>section 1813 of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board and financial holding company</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “Board” and “financial holding company” have the same meanings as in <ref>section 1841 of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6717.</num>
<heading> Definition of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>REDOMESTICATION OF MUTUAL INSURERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6731.</num>
<heading> General application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter shall only apply to a mutual insurance company in a State which has not enacted a law which expressly establishes reasonable terms and conditions for a mutual insurance company domiciled in such State to reorganize into a mutual holding company.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6732.</num>
<heading> Redomestication of mutual insurers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redomestication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A mutual insurer organized under the laws of any State may transfer its domicile to a transferee domicile as a step in a reorganization in which, pursuant to the laws of the transferee domicile and consistent with the standards in subsection (f), the mutual insurer becomes a stock insurer that is a direct or indirect subsidiary of a mutual holding company.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resulting domicile</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon complying with the applicable law of the transferee domicile governing transfers of domicile and completion of a transfer pursuant to this section, the mutual insurer shall cease to be a domestic insurer in the transferor domicile and, as a continuation of its corporate existence, shall be a domestic insurer of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licenses preserved</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The certificate of authority, agents’ appointments and licenses, rates, approvals and other items that a licensed State allows and that are in existence immediately prior to the date that a redomesticating insurer transfers its domicile pursuant to this subchapter shall continue in full force and effect upon transfer, if the insurer remains duly qualified to transact the business of insurance in such licensed State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effectiveness of outstanding policies and contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">All outstanding insurance policies and annuities contracts of a redomesticating insurer shall remain in full force and effect and need not be endorsed as to the new domicile of the insurer, unless so ordered by the State insurance regulator of a licensed State, and then only in the case of outstanding policies and contracts whose owners reside in such licensed State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forms</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Applicable State law may require a redomesticating insurer to file new policy forms with the State insurance regulator of a licensed State on or before the effective date of the transfer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a redomesticating insurer may use existing policy forms with appropriate endorsements to reflect the new domicile of the redomesticating insurer until the new policy forms are approved for use by the State insurance regulator of such licensed State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A redomesticating insurer shall give notice of the proposed transfer to the State insurance regulator of each licensed State and shall file promptly any resulting amendments to corporate documents required to be filed by a foreign licensed mutual insurer with the insurance regulator of each such licensed State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedural requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No mutual insurer may redomesticate to another State and reorganize into a mutual holding company pursuant to this section unless the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile determines that the plan of reorganization of the insurer includes the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval by board of directors and policyholders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The reorganization is approved by at least a majority of the board of directors of the mutual insurer and at least a majority of the policyholders who vote after notice, disclosure of the reorganization and the effects of the transaction on policyholder contractual rights, and reasonable opportunity to vote, in accordance with such notice, disclosure, and voting procedures as are approved by the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continued voting control by policyholders; review of public stock offering</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After the consummation of a reorganization, the policyholders of the reorganized insurer shall have the same voting rights with respect to the mutual holding company as they had before the reorganization with respect to the mutual insurer. With respect to an initial public offering of stock, the offering shall be conducted in compliance with applicable securities laws and in a manner approved by the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of stock or grant of options to officers and directors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">During the applicable period provided for under the State law of the transferee domicile following completion of an initial public offering, or for a period of six months if no such applicable period is provided, neither a stock holding company nor the converted insurer shall award any stock options or stock grants to persons who are elected officers or directors of the mutual holding company, the stock holding company, or the converted insurer, except with respect to any such awards or options to which a person is entitled as a policyholder and as approved by the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policyholder rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon reorganization into a mutual holding company, the contractual rights of the policyholders are preserved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fair and equitable treatment of policyholders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The reorganization is approved as fair and equitable to the policyholders by the insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6733.</num>
<heading> Effect on State laws restricting redomestication</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Unless otherwise permitted by this subchapter, State laws of any transferor domicile that conflict with the purposes and intent of this subchapter are preempted, including but not limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any law that has the purpose or effect of impeding the activities of, taking any action against, or applying any provision of law or regulation to, any insurer or an affiliate of such insurer because that insurer or any affiliate plans to redomesticate, or has redomesticated, pursuant to this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any law that has the purpose or effect of impeding the activities of, taking action against, or applying any provision of law or regulation to, any insured or any insurance licensee or other intermediary because such person has procured insurance from or placed insurance with any insurer or affiliate of such insurer that plans to redomesticate, or has redomesticated, pursuant to this subchapter, but only to the extent that such law would treat such insured licensee or other intermediary differently than if the person procured insurance from, or placed insurance with, an insured licensee or other intermediary which had not redomesticated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any law that has the purpose or effect of terminating, because of the redomestication of a mutual insurer pursuant to this subchapter, any certificate of authority, agent appointment or license, rate approval, or other approval, of any State insurance regulator or other State authority in existence immediately prior to the redomestication in any State other than the transferee domicile.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Differential treatment prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No State law, regulation, interpretation, or functional equivalent thereof, of a State other than a transferee domicile may treat a redomesticating or redomesticated insurer or any affiliate thereof any differently than an insurer operating in that State that is not a redomesticating or redomesticated insurer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Laws prohibiting operations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If any licensed State fails to issue, delays the issuance of, or seeks to revoke an original or renewal certificate of authority of a redomesticated insurer promptly following redomestication, except on grounds and in a manner consistent with its past practices regarding the issuance of certificates of authority to foreign insurers that are not redomesticating, then the redomesticating insurer shall be exempt from any State law of the licensed State to the extent that such State law or the operation of such State law would make unlawful, or regulate, directly or indirectly, the operation of the redomesticated insurer, except that such licensed State may require the redomesticated insurer to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> comply with the unfair claim settlement practices law of the licensed State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pay, on a nondiscriminatory basis, applicable premium and other taxes which are levied on licensed insurers or policyholders under the laws of the licensed State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> register with and designate the State insurance regulator as its agent solely for the purpose of receiving service of legal documents or process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> submit to an examination by the State insurance regulator in any licensed State in which the redomesticated insurer is doing business to determine the insurer’s financial condition, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile has not begun an examination of the redomesticated insurer and has not scheduled such an examination to begin before the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date of the redomestication; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any such examination is coordinated to avoid unjustified duplication and repetition;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> comply with a lawful order issued in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a delinquency proceeding commenced by the State insurance regulator of any licensed State if there has been a judicial finding of financial impairment under paragraph (7); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a voluntary dissolution proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> comply with any State law regarding deceptive, false, or fraudulent acts or practices, except that if the licensed State seeks an injunction regarding the conduct described in this paragraph, such injunction must be obtained from a court of competent jurisdiction as provided in <ref>section 6734(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> comply with an injunction issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, upon a petition by the State insurance regulator alleging that the redomesticating insurer is in hazardous financial condition or is financially impaired;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> participate in any insurance insolvency guaranty association on the same basis as any other insurer licensed in the licensed State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> require a person acting, or offering to act, as an insurance licensee for a redomesticated insurer in the licensed State to obtain a license from that State, except that such State may not impose any qualification or requirement that discriminates against a nonresident insurance licensee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6734.</num>
<heading> Other provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The appropriate United States district court shall have exclusive jurisdiction over litigation arising under this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002552">1</ref> involving any redomesticating or redomesticated insurer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this section,<sup>1</sup> or the application thereof to any person or circumstances, is held invalid, the remainder of the section,<sup>1</sup> and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1420</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6735.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court of competent jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “court of competent jurisdiction” means a court authorized pursuant to <ref>section 6734(a) of this title</ref> to adjudicate litigation arising under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domicile</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “domicile” means the State in which an insurer is incorporated, chartered, or organized.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance licensee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insurance licensee” means any person holding a license under State law to act as insurance agent, subagent, broker, or consultant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “institution” means a corporation, joint stock company, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, association, trust, partnership, or any similar entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licensed State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “licensed State” means any State, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands in which the redomesticating insurer has a certificate of authority in effect immediately prior to the redomestication.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mutual insurer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “mutual insurer” means a mutual insurer organized under the laws of any State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” means an individual, institution, government or governmental agency, State or political subdivision of a State, public corporation, board, association, estate, trustee, or fiduciary, or other similar entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policyholder</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “policyholder” means the owner of a policy issued by a mutual insurer, except that, with respect to voting rights, the term means a member of a mutual insurer or mutual holding company granted the right to vote, as determined under applicable State law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redomesticated insurer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “redomesticated insurer” means a mutual insurer that has redomesticated pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redomesticating insurer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “redomesticating insurer” means a mutual insurer that is redomesticating pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redomestication or transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “redomestication” or “transfer” means the transfer of the domicile of a mutual insurer from one State to another State pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State insurance regulator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State insurance regulator” means the principal insurance regulatory authority of a State, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State law” means the statutes of any State, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands and any regulation, order, or requirement prescribed pursuant to any such statute.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transferee domicile</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “transferee domicile” means the State to which a mutual insurer is redomesticating pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transferor domicile</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “transferor domicile” means the State from which a mutual insurer is redomesticating pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1420</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF REGISTERED AGENTS AND BROKERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6751.</num>
<heading> National Association of Registered Agents and Brokers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the National Association of Registered Agents and Brokers (referred to in this subchapter as the “Association”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Association shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be a nonprofit corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not be an agent or instrumentality of the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be an independent organization that may not be merged with or into any other private or public entity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, be subject to, and have all the powers conferred upon, a nonprofit corporation by the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act (D.C. Code, sec. 29–301.01 et seq.) or any successor thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 321</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 13</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6752.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of the Association shall be to provide a mechanism through which licensing, continuing education, and other nonresident insurance producer qualification requirements and conditions may be adopted and applied on a multi-state basis without affecting the laws, rules, and regulations, and preserving the rights of a State, pertaining to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> licensing, continuing education, and other qualification requirements of insurance producers that are not members of the Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> resident or nonresident insurance producer appointment requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> supervising and disciplining resident and nonresident insurance producers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establishing licensing fees for resident and nonresident insurance producers so that there is no loss of insurance producer licensing revenue to the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> prescribing and enforcing laws and regulations regulating the conduct of resident and nonresident insurance producers.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 322</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 13</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6753.</num>
<heading> Membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any insurance producer licensed in its home State shall, subject to paragraphs (2) and (4), be eligible to become a member of the Association.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility for suspension or revocation of license</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (3), an insurance producer is not eligible to become a member of the Association if a State insurance regulator has suspended or revoked the insurance license of the insurance producer in that State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resumption of eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (2) shall cease to apply to any insurance producer if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State insurance regulator reissues or renews the license of the insurance producer in the State in which the license was suspended or revoked, or otherwise terminates or vacates the suspension or revocation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the suspension or revocation expires or is subsequently overturned by a court of competent jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal history record check required</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An insurance producer who is an individual shall not be eligible to become a member of the Association unless the insurance producer has undergone a criminal history record check that complies with regulations prescribed by the Attorney General of the United States under subparagraph (K).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal history record check requested by home State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An insurance producer who is licensed in a State and who has undergone a criminal history record check during the 2-year period preceding the date of submission of an application to become a member of the Association, in compliance with a requirement to undergo such criminal history record check as a condition for such licensure in the State, shall be deemed to have undergone a criminal history record check for purposes of subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal history record check requested by Association</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Association shall, upon request by an insurance producer licensed in a State, submit fingerprints or other identification information obtained from the insurance producer, and a request for a criminal history record check of the insurance producer, to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The board of directors of the Association (referred to in this subchapter as the “Board”) shall prescribe procedures for obtaining and utilizing fingerprints or other identification information and criminal history record information, including the establishment of reasonable fees to defray the expenses of the Association in connection with the performance of a criminal history record check and appropriate safeguards for maintaining confidentiality and security of the information. Any fees charged pursuant to this clause shall be separate and distinct from those charged by the Attorney General pursuant to subparagraph (I).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A submission under subparagraph (C)(i) shall include such fingerprints or other identification information as is required by the Attorney General concerning the person about whom the criminal history record check is requested, and a statement signed by the person authorizing the Attorney General to provide the information to the Association and for the Association to receive the information.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information by Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Upon receiving a submission under subparagraph (C)(i) from the Association, the Attorney General shall search all criminal history records of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, including records of the Criminal Justice Information Services Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, that the Attorney General determines appropriate for criminal history records corresponding to the fingerprints or other identification information provided under subparagraph (D) and provide all criminal history record information included in the request to the Association.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on permissible uses of information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any information provided to the Association under subparagraph (E) may only—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be used for purposes of determining compliance with membership criteria established by the Association;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> be disclosed to State insurance regulators, or Federal or State law enforcement agencies, in conformance with applicable law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> be disclosed, upon request, to the insurance producer to whom the criminal history record information relates.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty for improper use or disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Whoever knowingly uses any information provided under subparagraph (E) for a purpose not authorized in subparagraph (F), or discloses any such information to anyone not authorized to receive it, shall be fined not more than $50,000 per violation as determined by a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(H)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reliance on information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Neither the Association nor any of its Board members, officers, or employees shall be liable in any action for using information provided under subparagraph (E) as permitted under subparagraph (F) in good faith and in reasonable reliance on its accuracy.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General may charge a reasonable fee for conducting the search and providing the information under subparagraph (E), and any such fee shall be collected and remitted by the Association to the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(J)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> requiring a State insurance regulator to perform criminal history record checks under this section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> limiting any other authority that allows access to criminal history records.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(K)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Attorney General shall prescribe regulations to carry out this paragraph, which shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> appropriate protections for ensuring the confidentiality of information provided under subparagraph (E); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> procedures providing a reasonable opportunity for an insurance producer to contest the accuracy of information regarding the insurance producer provided under subparagraph (E).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(L)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility for membership</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Association may, under reasonably consistently applied standards, deny membership to an insurance producer on the basis of criminal history record information provided under subparagraph (E), or where the insurance producer has been subject to disciplinary action, as described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of applicants denied membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Association shall notify any insurance producer who is denied membership on the basis of criminal history record information provided under subparagraph (E) of the right of the insurance producer to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> obtain a copy of all criminal history record information provided to the Association under subparagraph (E) with respect to the insurance producer; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> challenge the denial of membership based on the accuracy and completeness of the information.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(M)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “criminal history record check” means a national background check of criminal history records of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to establish membership criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Association may establish membership criteria that bear a reasonable relationship to the purposes for which the Association was established.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of classes and categories of membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classes of membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association may establish separate classes of membership, with separate criteria, if the Association reasonably determines that performance of different duties requires different levels of education, training, experience, or other qualifications.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Business entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall establish a class of membership and membership criteria for business entities. A business entity that applies for membership shall be required to designate an individual Association member responsible for the compliance of the business entity with Association standards and the insurance laws, standards, and regulations of any State in which the business entity seeks to do business on the basis of Association membership.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Categories</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate categories for insurance producers permitted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Association may establish separate categories of membership for insurance producers and for other persons or entities within each class, based on the types of licensing categories that exist under State laws.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate treatment for depository institutions prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No special categories of membership, and no distinct membership criteria, shall be established for members that are depository institutions or for employees, agents, or affiliates of depository institutions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association may establish criteria for membership which shall include standards for personal qualifications, education, training, and experience. The Association shall not establish criteria that unfairly limit the ability of a small insurance producer to become a member of the Association, including imposing discriminatory membership fees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In establishing criteria under paragraph (1), the Association shall not adopt any qualification less protective to the public than that contained in the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (referred to in this subchapter as the “NAIC”) Producer Licensing Model Act in effect as of <date date="2015-01-12">January 12, 2015</date>, and shall consider the highest levels of insurance producer qualifications established under the licensing laws of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance from States</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Association may request a State to provide assistance in investigating and evaluating the eligibility of a prospective member for membership in the Association.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of information sharing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A submission under subsection (a)(4)(C)(i) made by an insurance producer licensed in a State shall include a statement signed by the person about whom the assistance is requested authorizing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the State to share information with the Association; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Association to receive the information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed as requiring or authorizing any State to adopt new or additional requirements concerning the licensing or evaluation of insurance producers.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association may, based on reasonably consistently applied standards, deny membership to any State-licensed insurance producer for failure to meet the membership criteria established by the Association.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Association members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Membership in the Association shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> authorize an insurance producer to sell, solicit, or negotiate insurance in any State for which the member pays the licensing fee set by the State for any line or lines of insurance specified in the home State license of the insurance producer, and exercise all such incidental powers as shall be necessary to carry out such activities, including claims adjustments and settlement to the extent permissible under the laws of the State, risk management, employee benefits advice, retirement planning, and any other insurance-related consulting activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be the equivalent of a nonresident insurance producer license for purposes of authorizing the insurance producer to engage in the activities described in subparagraph (A) in any State where the member pays the licensing fee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be the equivalent of a nonresident insurance producer license for the purpose of subjecting an insurance producer to all laws, regulations, provisions or other action of any State concerning revocation, suspension, or other enforcement action related to the ability of a member to engage in any activity within the scope of authority granted under this subsection and to all State laws, regulations, provisions, and actions preserved under paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to alter, modify, or supercede any requirement established by <ref>section 1033 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agent for remitting fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall act as an agent for any member for purposes of remitting licensing fees to any State pursuant to paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of action</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Association shall notify the States (including State insurance regulators) and the NAIC when an insurance producer has satisfied the membership criteria of this section. The States (including State insurance regulators) shall have 10 business days after the date of the notification in order to provide the Association with evidence that the insurance producer does not satisfy the criteria for membership in the Association.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ongoing disclosures required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On an ongoing basis, the Association shall disclose to the States (including State insurance regulators) and the NAIC a list of the States in which each member is authorized to operate. The Association shall immediately notify the States (including State insurance regulators) and the NAIC when a member is newly authorized to operate in one or more States, or is no longer authorized to operate in one or more States on the basis of Association membership.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation of consumer protection and market conduct regulation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No provision of this section shall be construed as altering or affecting the applicability or continuing effectiveness of any law, regulation, provision, or other action of any State, including those described in subparagraph (B), to the extent that the State law, regulation, provision, or other action is not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter related to market entry for nonresident insurance producers, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preserved regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The laws, regulations, provisions, or other actions of any State referred to in subparagraph (A) include laws, regulations, provisions, or other actions that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> regulate market conduct, insurance producer conduct, or unfair trade practices;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> establish consumer protections; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> require insurance producers to be appointed by a licensed or authorized insurer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Biennial renewal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Membership in the Association shall be renewed on a biennial basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing education</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall establish, as a condition of membership, continuing education requirements which shall be comparable to the continuing education requirements under the licensing laws of a majority of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State continuing education requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A member may not be required to satisfy continuing education requirements imposed under the laws, regulations, provisions, or actions of any State other than the home State of the member.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reciprocity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall not require a member to satisfy continuing education requirements that are equivalent to any continuing education requirements of the home State of the member that have been satisfied by the member during the applicable licensing period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on the Association</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall not directly or indirectly offer any continuing education courses for insurance producers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Probation, suspension and revocation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disciplinary action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Association may place an insurance producer that is a member of the Association on probation or suspend or revoke the membership of the insurance producer in the Association, or assess monetary fines or penalties, as the Association determines to be appropriate, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the insurance producer fails to meet the applicable membership criteria or other standards established by the Association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the insurance producer has been subject to disciplinary action pursuant to a final adjudicatory proceeding under the jurisdiction of a State insurance regulator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an insurance license held by the insurance producer has been suspended or revoked by a State insurance regulator; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the insurance producer has been convicted of a crime that would have resulted in the denial of membership pursuant to subsection (a)(4)(L)(i) at the time of application, and the Association has received a copy of the final disposition from a court of competent jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations of Association standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall have the power to investigate alleged violations of Association standards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall immediately notify the States (including State insurance regulators) and the NAIC when the membership of an insurance producer has been placed on probation or has been suspended, revoked, or otherwise terminated, or when the Association has assessed monetary fines or penalties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consumer complaints</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Association shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> refer any complaint against a member of the Association from a consumer relating to alleged misconduct or violations of State insurance laws to the State insurance regulator where the consumer resides and, when appropriate, to any additional State insurance regulator, as determined by standards adopted by the Association; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make any related records and information available to each State insurance regulator to whom the complaint is forwarded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Telephone and other access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall maintain a toll-free number for purposes of this subsection and, as practicable, other alternative means of communication with consumers, such as an Internet webpage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final disposition of investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">State insurance regulators shall provide the Association with information regarding the final disposition of a complaint referred pursuant to paragraph (1)(A), but nothing shall be construed to compel a State to release confidential investigation reports or other information protected by State law to the Association.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Association may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> share documents, materials, or other information, including confidential and privileged documents, with a State, Federal, or international governmental entity or with the NAIC or other appropriate entity referred to <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002553">1</ref> paragraphs (3) and (4), provided that the recipient has the authority and agrees to maintain the confidentiality or privileged status of the document, material, or other information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> limit the sharing of information as required under this subchapter with the NAIC or any other non-governmental entity, in circumstances under which the Association determines that the sharing of such information is unnecessary to further the purposes of this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish a central clearinghouse, or utilize the NAIC or another appropriate entity, as determined by the Association, as a central clearinghouse, for use by the Association and the States (including State insurance regulators), through which members of the Association may disclose their intent to operate in 1 or more States and pay the licensing fees to the appropriate States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish a database, or utilize the NAIC or another appropriate entity, as determined by the Association, as a database, for use by the Association and the States (including State insurance regulators) for the collection of regulatory information concerning the activities of insurance producers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall take effect on the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on <date date="2015-01-12">January 12, 2015</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date of incorporation of the Association.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 323</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 13</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6754.</num>
<heading> Board of directors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a board of directors of the Association, which shall have authority to govern and supervise all activities of the Association.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall have such of the powers and authority of the Association as may be specified in the bylaws of the Association.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002554">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Board shall consist of 13 members who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, in accordance with the procedures established under Senate Resolution 116 of the 112th Congress, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 8 shall be State insurance commissioners appointed in the manner provided in paragraph (2), 1 of whom shall be designated by the President to serve as the chairperson of the Board until the Board elects one such State insurance commissioner Board member to serve as the chairperson of the Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 3 shall have demonstrated expertise and experience with property and casualty insurance producer licensing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 2 shall have demonstrated expertise and experience with life or health insurance producer licensing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State insurance regulator representatives</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Before making any appointments pursuant to paragraph (1)(A), the President shall request a list of recommended candidates from the States through the NAIC, which shall not be binding on the President. If the NAIC fails to submit a list of recommendations not later than 15 business days after the date of the request, the President may make the requisite appointments without considering the views of the NAIC.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Political affiliation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not more than 4 Board members appointed under paragraph (1)(A) shall belong to the same political party.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Former State insurance commissioners</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If, after offering each currently serving State insurance commissioner an appointment to the Board, fewer than 8 State insurance commissioners have accepted appointment to the Board, the President may appoint the remaining State insurance commissioner Board members, as required under paragraph (1)(A), of the appropriate political party as required under subparagraph (B), from among individuals who are former State insurance commissioners.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A former State insurance commissioner appointed as described in clause (i) may not be employed by or have any present direct or indirect financial interest in any insurer, insurance producer, or other entity in the insurance industry, other than direct or indirect ownership of, or beneficial interest in, an insurance policy or annuity contract written or sold by an insurer.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service through term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a Board member appointed under paragraph (1)(A) ceases to be a State insurance commissioner during the term of the Board member, the Board member shall cease to be a Board member.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private sector representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In making any appointment pursuant to subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (1), the President may seek recommendations for candidates from groups representing the category of individuals described, which shall not be binding on the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State insurance commissioner defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “State insurance commissioner” means a person who serves in the position in State government, or on the board, commission, or other body that is the primary insurance regulatory authority for the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided under paragraph (2), the term of service for each Board member shall be 2 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1-year terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term of service shall be 1 year, as designated by the President at the time of the nomination of the subject Board members for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 4 of the State insurance commissioner Board members initially appointed under paragraph (1)(A),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002555">2</ref> of whom not more than 2 shall belong to the same political party;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 1 of the Board members initially appointed under paragraph (1)(B); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002556">3</ref> and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 1 of the Board members initially appointed under paragraph (1)(C).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002557">4</ref></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expiration of term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A Board member may continue to serve after the expiration of the term to which the Board member was appointed for the earlier of 2 years or until a successor is appointed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mid-term appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A Board member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the predecessor of the Board member was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Successive terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Board members may be reappointed to successive terms.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The appointment of initial Board members shall be made no later than 90 days after <date date="2015-01-12">January 12, 2015</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Board shall meet—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the call of the chairperson;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as requested in writing to the chairperson by not fewer than 5 Board members; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as otherwise provided by the bylaws of the Association.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority of all Board members shall constitute a quorum.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Decisions of the Board shall require the approval of a majority of all Board members present at a meeting, a quorum being present.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall hold its first meeting not later than 45 days after the date on which all initial Board members have been appointed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction on confidential information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Board members appointed pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C) of subsection (c)(1) shall not have access to confidential information received by the Association in connection with complaints, investigations, or disciplinary proceedings involving insurance producers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ethics and conflicts of interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board shall issue and enforce an ethical conduct code to address permissible and prohibited activities of Board members and Association officers, employees, agents, or consultants. The code shall, at a minimum, include provisions that prohibit any Board member or Association officer, employee, agent or consultant from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> engaging in unethical conduct in the course of performing Association duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> participating in the making or influencing the making of any Association decision, the outcome of which the Board member, officer, employee, agent, or consultant knows or had reason to know would have a reasonably foreseeable material financial effect, distinguishable from its effect on the public generally, on the person or a member of the immediate family of the person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> accepting any gift from any person or entity other than the Association that is given because of the position held by the person in the Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> making political contributions to any person or entity on behalf of the Association; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> lobbying or paying a person to lobby on behalf of the Association.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no Board member may receive any compensation from the Association or any other person or entity on account of Board membership.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses and per diem</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Board members may be reimbursed only by the Association for travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates consistent with rates authorized for employees of Federal agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from home or regular places of business in performance of services for the Association.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 324</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 20</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6755.</num>
<heading> Bylaws, standards, and disciplinary actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption and amendment of bylaws and standards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Association shall adopt procedures for the adoption of bylaws and standards that are similar to procedures under subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 (commonly known as the “Administrative Procedure Act”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Copy required to be filed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall submit to the President, through the Department of the Treasury, and the States (including State insurance regulators), and shall publish on the website of the Association, all proposed bylaws and standards of the Association, or any proposed amendment to the bylaws or standards of the Association, accompanied by a concise general statement of the basis and purpose of such proposal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any proposed bylaw or standard of the Association, and any proposed amendment to the bylaws or standards of the Association, shall take effect, after notice under paragraph (2) and opportunity for public comment, on such date as the Association may designate, unless suspended under <ref>section 6759(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to subject the Board or the Association to the requirements of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 (commonly known as the “Administrative Procedure Act”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disciplinary action by the Association</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specification of charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any proceeding to determine whether membership shall be denied, suspended, revoked, or not renewed, or to determine whether a member of the Association should be placed on probation (referred to in this section as a “disciplinary action”) or whether to assess fines or monetary penalties, the Association shall bring specific charges, notify the member of the charges, give the member an opportunity to defend against the charges, and keep a record.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supporting statement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A determination to take disciplinary action shall be supported by a statement setting forth—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any act or practice in which the member has been found to have been engaged;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the specific provision of this subchapter or standard of the Association that any such act or practice is deemed to violate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the sanction imposed and the reason for the sanction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility of private sector representatives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Board members appointed pursuant to <ref>section 6754(c)(3) of this title</ref> may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> participate in any disciplinary action or be counted toward establishing a quorum during a disciplinary action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have access to confidential information concerning any disciplinary action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 325</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 23</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6756.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to all the powers conferred upon a nonprofit corporation by the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act, the Association shall have the power to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish and collect such membership fees as the Association finds necessary to impose to cover the costs of its operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws, procedures, or standards governing the conduct of Association business and performance of its duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish procedures for providing notice and opportunity for comment pursuant to <ref>section 6755(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> enter into and perform such agreements as necessary to carry out the duties of the Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> hire employees, professionals, or specialists, and elect or appoint officers, and to fix their compensation, define their duties and give them appropriate authority to carry out the purposes of this subchapter, and determine their qualification;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> establish personnel policies of the Association and programs relating to, among other things, conflicts of interest, rates of compensation, where applicable, and qualifications of personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> borrow money; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> secure funding for such amounts as the Association determines to be necessary and appropriate to organize and begin operations of the Association, which shall be treated as loans to be repaid by the Association with interest at market rate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 326</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 24</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6757.</num>
<heading> Report by the Association</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the close of each fiscal year, the Association shall submit to the President, through the Department of the Treasury, and the States (including State insurance regulators), and shall publish on the website of the Association, a written report regarding the conduct of its business, and the exercise of the other rights and powers granted by this subchapter, during such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial statements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) with respect to any fiscal year shall include audited financial statements setting forth the financial position of the Association at the end of such fiscal year and the results of its operations (including the source and application of its funds) for such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 327</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 24</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6758.</num>
<heading> Liability of the Association and the Board members, officers, and employees of the Association</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Association shall not be deemed to be an insurer or insurance producer within the meaning of any State law, rule, regulation, or order regulating or taxing insurers, insurance producers, or other entities engaged in the business of insurance, including provisions imposing premium taxes, regulating insurer solvency or financial condition, establishing guaranty funds and levying assessments, or requiring claims settlement practices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of Board members, officers, and employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No Board member, officer, or employee of the Association shall be personally liable to any person for any action taken or omitted in good faith in any matter within the scope of their responsibilities in connection with the Association.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 328</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6759.</num>
<heading> Presidential oversight</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the President determines that the Association is acting in a manner contrary to the interests of the public or the purposes of this subchapter or has failed to perform its duties under this subchapter, the President may remove the entire existing Board for the remainder of the term to which the Board members were appointed and appoint, in accordance with <ref>section 6754 of this title</ref> and with the advice and consent of the Senate, in accordance with the procedures established under Senate Resolution 116 of the 112th Congress, new Board members to fill the vacancies on the Board for the remainder of the terms.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of Board member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may remove a Board member only for neglect of duty or malfeasance in office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of bylaws and standards and prohibition of actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Following notice to the Board, the President, or a person designated by the President for such purpose, may suspend the effectiveness of any bylaw or standard, or prohibit any action, of the Association that the President or the designee determines is contrary to the purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 329</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6760.</num>
<heading> Relationship to State law</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preemption of State laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">State laws, regulations, provisions, or other actions purporting to regulate insurance producers shall be preempted to the extent provided in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No State shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> impede the activities of, take any action against, or apply any provision of law or regulation arbitrarily or discriminatorily to, any insurance producer because that insurance producer or any affiliate plans to become, has applied to become, or is a member of the Association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> impose any requirement upon a member of the Association that it pay fees different from those required to be paid to that State were it not a member of the Association; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> impose any continuing education requirements on any nonresident insurance producer that is a member of the Association.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> States other than a home State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No State, other than the home State of a member of the Association, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> impose any licensing, personal or corporate qualifications, education, training, experience, residency, continuing education, or bonding requirement upon a member of the Association that is different from the criteria for membership in the Association or renewal of such membership;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> impose any requirement upon a member of the Association that it be licensed, registered, or otherwise qualified to do business or remain in good standing in the State, including any requirement that the insurance producer register as a foreign company with the secretary of state or equivalent State official;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> require that a member of the Association submit to a criminal history record check as a condition of doing business in the State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> impose any licensing, registration, or appointment requirements upon a member of the Association, or require a member of the Association to be authorized to operate as an insurance producer, in order to sell, solicit, or negotiate insurance for commercial property and casualty risks to an insured with risks located in more than one State, if the member is licensed or otherwise authorized to operate in the State where the insured maintains its principal place of business and the contract of insurance insures risks located in that State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation of State disciplinary authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a State from investigating and taking appropriate disciplinary action, including suspension or revocation of authority of an insurance producer to do business in a State, in accordance with State law and that is not inconsistent with the provisions of this section, against a member of the Association as a result of a complaint or for any alleged activity, regardless of whether the activity occurred before or after the insurance producer commenced doing business in the State pursuant to Association membership.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 330</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6761.</num>
<heading> Coordination with Financial Industry Regulatory Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Association shall coordinate with the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority in order to ease any administrative burdens that fall on members of the Association that are subject to regulation by the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority, consistent with the requirements of this subchapter and the Federal securities laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 331</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6762.</num>
<heading> Right of action</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person aggrieved by a decision or action of the Association may, after reasonably exhausting available avenues for resolution within the Association, commence a civil action in an appropriate United States district court, and obtain all appropriate relief.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Association interpretations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any action under subsection (a), the court shall give appropriate weight to the interpretation of the Association of its bylaws and standards and this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 332</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6763.</num>
<heading> Federal funding prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Association may not receive, accept, or borrow any amounts from the Federal Government to pay for, or reimburse,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002558">1</ref> the Association for, the costs of establishing or operating the Association.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 333</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 27</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6764.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Business entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “business entity” means a corporation, association, partnership, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or other legal entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depository institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “depository institution” has the meaning as in <ref>section 1813 of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Home State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “home State” means the State in which the insurance producer maintains its principal place of residence or business and is licensed to act as an insurance producer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insurance” means any product, other than title insurance or bail bonds, defined or regulated as insurance by the appropriate State insurance regulatory authority.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurance producer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insurance producer” means any insurance agent or broker, excess or surplus lines broker or agent, insurance consultant, limited insurance representative, and any other individual or entity that sells, solicits, or negotiates policies of insurance or offers advice, counsel, opinions or services related to insurance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insurer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “insurer” has the meaning as in <ref>section 313(e)(2)(B) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal place of business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “principal place of business” means the State in which an insurance producer maintains the headquarters of the insurance producer and, in the case of a business entity, where high-level officers of the entity direct, control, and coordinate the business activities of the business entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal place of residence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “principal place of residence” means the State in which an insurance producer resides for the greatest number of days during a calendar year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” includes any State, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, and Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State law</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “State law” includes all laws, decisions, rules, regulations, or other State action having the effect of law, of any State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Laws applicable in the District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A law of the United States applicable only to or within the District of Columbia shall be treated as a State law rather than a law of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 334</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–1, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-01-12">Jan. 12, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 27</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>RENTAL CAR AGENCY INSURANCE ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6781.</num>
<heading> Standard of regulation for motor vehicle rentals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection against retroactive application of regulatory and legal action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), during the 3-year period beginning on <date date="1999-11-12">November 12, 1999</date>, it shall be a presumption that no State law imposes any licensing, appointment, or education requirements on any person who solicits the purchase of or sells insurance connected with, and incidental to, the lease or rental of a motor vehicle.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preeminence of State insurance law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No provision of this section shall be construed as altering the validity, interpretation, construction, or effect of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any State statute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the prospective application of any court judgment interpreting or applying any State statute; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the prospective application of any final State regulation, order, bulletin, or other statutorily authorized interpretation or action,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">which, by its specific terms, expressly regulates or exempts from regulation any person who solicits the purchase of or sells insurance connected with, and incidental to, the short-term lease or rental of a motor vehicle.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the lease or rental of a motor vehicle for a total period of 90 consecutive days or less; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> insurance which is provided in connection with, and incidentally to, such lease or rental for a period of consecutive days not exceeding the lease or rental period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Motor vehicle defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “motor vehicle” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 13102 of title 49</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 341</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>