<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 99—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL CONSTRUCTION SAFETY TEAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7301.</num>
<heading> National Construction Safety Teams</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (in this chapter referred to as the “Director”) is authorized to establish National Construction Safety Teams (in this chapter referred to as a “Team”) for deployment after events causing the failure of a building or buildings that has resulted in substantial loss of life or that posed significant potential for substantial loss of life. To the maximum extent practicable, the Director shall establish and deploy a Team within 48 hours after such an event. The Director shall promptly publish in the Federal Register notice of the establishment of each Team.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of investigation; duties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The purpose of investigations by Teams is to improve the safety and structural integrity of buildings in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A Team shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish the likely technical cause or causes of the building failure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> evaluate the technical aspects of evacuation and emergency response procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommend, as necessary, specific improvements to building standards, codes, and practices based on the findings made pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> recommend any research and other appropriate actions needed to improve the structural safety of buildings, and improve evacuation and emergency response procedures, based on the findings of the investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 3 months after <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>, the Director, in consultation with the United States Fire Administration and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall develop procedures for the establishment and deployment of Teams. The Director shall update such procedures as appropriate. Such procedures shall include provisions—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> regarding conflicts of interest related to service on the Team;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> defining the circumstances under which the Director will establish and deploy a Team;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> prescribing the appropriate size of Teams;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> guiding the disclosure of information under <ref>section 7306 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> guiding the conduct of investigations under this chapter, including procedures for providing written notice of inspection authority under <ref>section 7303(a) of this title</ref> and for ensuring compliance with any other applicable law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> identifying and prescribing appropriate conditions for the provision by the Director of additional resources and services Teams may need;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> to ensure that investigations under this chapter do not impede and are coordinated with any search and rescue efforts being undertaken at the site of the building failure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> for regular briefings of the public on the status of the investigative proceedings and findings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> guiding the Teams in moving and preserving evidence as described in section 7303(a)(4), (b)(2), and (d)(4) of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> providing for coordination with Federal, State, and local entities that may sponsor research or investigations of building failures, including research conducted under the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 7701</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> regarding such other issues as the Director considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall publish promptly in the Federal Register final procedures, and subsequent updates thereof, developed under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 2</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–305, § 15</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7302.</num>
<heading> Composition of Teams</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Team shall be composed of individuals selected by the Director and led by an individual designated by the Director. Team members shall include at least 1 employee of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and shall include other experts who are not employees of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, who may include private sector experts, university experts, representatives of professional organizations with appropriate expertise, and appropriate Federal, State, or local officials. Team members who are not Federal employees shall be considered Federal Government contractors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 3</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1472</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7303.</num>
<heading> Authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entry and inspection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In investigating a building failure under this chapter, members of a Team, and any other person authorized by the Director to support a Team, on display of appropriate credentials provided by the Director and written notice of inspection authority, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter property where a building failure being investigated has occurred, or where building components, materials, and artifacts with respect to the building failure are located, and take action necessary, appropriate, and reasonable in light of the nature of the property to be inspected to carry out the duties of the Team under section 7301(b)(2)(A) and (B) of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during reasonable hours, inspect any record (including any design, construction, or maintenance record), process, or facility related to the investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inspect and test any building components, materials, and artifacts related to the building failure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> move such records, components, materials, and artifacts as provided by the procedures developed under <ref>section 7301(c)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Avoiding unnecessary interference and preserving evidence</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An inspection, test, or other action taken by a Team under this section shall be conducted in a way that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> does not interfere unnecessarily with services provided by the owner or operator of the building components, materials, or artifacts, property, records, process, or facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent feasible, preserves evidence related to the building failure, consistent with the ongoing needs of the investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With search and rescue efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Team shall not impede, and shall coordinate its investigation with, any search and rescue efforts being undertaken at the site of the building failure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With other research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Team shall coordinate its investigation, to the extent practicable, with qualified researchers who are conducting engineering or scientific (including social science) research relating to the building failure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memoranda of understanding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with each Federal agency that may conduct or sponsor a related investigation, providing for coordination of investigations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With State and local authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Team shall cooperate with State and local authorities carrying out any activities related to a Team’s investigation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil suits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Where practicable, a Team shall cooperate with civil litigants without compromising a Team’s investigation or the evidence preservation activities as described in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation priorities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2) or (3), a Team investigation shall have priority over any other investigation of any other Federal agency or any civil suit or civil action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Transportation Safety Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the National Transportation Safety Board is conducting an investigation related to an investigation of a Team, the National Transportation Safety Board investigation shall have priority over the Team investigation. Such priority shall not otherwise affect the authority of the Team to continue its investigation under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director, determines, and notifies the Director, that circumstances reasonably indicate that the building failure being investigated by a Team may have been caused by a criminal act, the Team shall relinquish investigative priority to the appropriate law enforcement agency. The relinquishment of investigative priority by the Team shall not otherwise affect the authority of the Team to continue its investigation under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation of evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a Federal law enforcement agency suspects and notifies the Director that a building failure being investigated by a Team under this chapter may have been caused by a criminal act, the Team, in consultation with the Federal law enforcement agency, shall take necessary actions to ensure that evidence of the criminal act is preserved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 4</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title II, § 10246(h)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7304.</num>
<heading> Briefings, hearings, witnesses, and subpoenas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director or his designee, on behalf of a Team, may conduct hearings, administer oaths, and require, by subpoena (pursuant to subsection (e)) and otherwise, necessary witnesses and evidence as necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director or his designee (who may be the leader or a member of a Team), on behalf of a Team, shall hold regular public briefings on the status of investigative proceedings and findings, including a final briefing after the report required by <ref>section 7307 of this title</ref> is issued.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public hearings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">During the course of an investigation by a Team, the National Institute of Standards and Technology may, if the Director considers it to be in the public interest, hold a public hearing for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> gathering testimony from witnesses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> informing the public on the progress of the investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Production of witnesses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A witness or evidence in an investigation under this chapter may be summoned or required to be produced from any place in the United States. A witness summoned under this subsection is entitled to the same fee and mileage the witness would have been paid in a court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of subpoenas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A subpoena shall be issued only under the signature of the Director but may be served by any person designated by the Director.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to obey subpoena</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a person disobeys a subpoena issued by the Director under this chapter, the Attorney General, acting on behalf of the Director, may bring a civil action in a district court of the United States to enforce the subpoena. An action under this subsection may be brought in the judicial district in which the person against whom the action is brought resides, is found, or does business. The court may punish a failure to obey an order of the court to comply with the subpoena as a contempt of court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 5</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7305.</num>
<heading> Additional powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to support Teams in carrying out this chapter, the Director may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> procure the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> request the use, when appropriate, of available services, equipment, personnel, and facilities of a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government on a reimbursable or other basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> confer with employees and request the use of services, records, and facilities of State and local governmental authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> accept voluntary and uncompensated services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> accept and use gifts of money and other property, to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> make contracts with nonprofit entities to carry out studies related to purpose, functions, and authorities of the Teams; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide nongovernmental members of the Team reasonable compensation for time spent carrying out activities under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 6</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7306.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a copy of a record, information, or investigation submitted or received by a Team shall be made available to the public on request and at reasonable cost.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) does not require the release of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information described by <ref>section 552(b) of title 5</ref> or protected from disclosure by any other law of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information described in subsection (a) by the National Institute of Standards and Technology or by a Team until the report required by <ref>section 7307 of this title</ref> is issued.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection of voluntary submission of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a Team, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and any agency receiving information from a Team or the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall not disclose voluntarily provided safety-related information if that information is not directly related to the building failure being investigated and the Director finds that the disclosure of the information would inhibit the voluntary provision of that type of information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public safety information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Team and the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall not publicly release any information it receives in the course of an investigation under this chapter if the Director finds that the disclosure of that information might jeopardize public safety.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 7</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7307.</num>
<heading> National Construction Safety Team report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after completing an investigation, a Team shall issue a public report which includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of the likely technical cause or causes of the building failure investigated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any technical recommendations for changes to or the establishment of evacuation and emergency response procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any recommended specific improvements to building standards, codes, and practices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommendations for research and other appropriate actions needed to help prevent future building failures.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 8</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7308.</num>
<heading> National Institute of Standards and Technology actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After the issuance of a public report under <ref>section 7307 of this title</ref>, the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall comprehensively review the report and, working with the United States Fire Administration and other appropriate Federal and non-Federal agencies and organizations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct, or enable or encourage the conducting of, appropriate research recommended by the Team; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> promote (consistent with existing procedures for the establishment of building standards, codes, and practices) the appropriate adoption by the Federal Government, and encourage the appropriate adoption by other agencies and organizations, of the recommendations of the Team with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> technical aspects of evacuation and emergency response procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specific improvements to building standards, codes, and practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other actions needed to help prevent future building failures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 9</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7309.</num>
<heading> National Institute of Standards and Technology annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than February 15 of each year, the Director shall transmit to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the investigations conducted by Teams during the prior fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary of recommendations made by the Teams in reports issued under <ref>section 7307 of this title</ref> during the prior fiscal year and a description of the extent to which those recommendations have been implemented; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the actions taken to improve building safety and structural integrity by the National Institute of Standards and Technology during the prior fiscal year in response to reports issued under <ref>section 7307 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 10</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7310.</num>
<heading> Advisory committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director, in consultation with the United States Fire Administration and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall establish an advisory committee to advise the Director on carrying out this chapter and to review the procedures developed under <ref>section 7301(c)(1) of this title</ref> and the reports issued under <ref>section 7307 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On January 1 of each year, the advisory committee shall transmit to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an evaluation of Team activities, along with recommendations to improve the operation and effectiveness of Teams; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of the implementation of the recommendations of Teams and of the advisory committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of advisory committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1013 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to the advisory committee established under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 11</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(77)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7311.</num>
<heading> Additional applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorities and restrictions applicable under this chapter to the Director and to Teams shall apply to the activities of the National Institute of Standards and Technology in response to the attacks of <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 12</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7312.</num>
<heading> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to confer any authority on the National Institute of Standards and Technology to require the adoption of building standards, codes, or practices.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 14</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1477</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7313.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Institute of Standards and Technology is authorized to use funds otherwise authorized by law to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–231, § 15</ref>, <date date="2002-10-01">Oct. 1, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1477</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>