<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 20—</num>
<heading>REGULATION OF INSURANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1011.</num>
<heading> Declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress hereby declares that the continued regulation and taxation by the several States of the business of insurance is in the public interest, and that silence on the part of the Congress shall not be construed to impose any barrier to the regulation or taxation of such business by the several States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 9, 1945, ch. 20, § 1</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 33</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1012.</num>
<heading> Regulation by State law; Federal law relating specifically to insurance; applicability of certain Federal laws after <date date="1948-06-30">June 30, 1948</date></heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State regulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The business of insurance, and every person engaged therein, shall be subject to the laws of the several States which relate to the regulation or taxation of such business.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal regulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No Act of Congress shall be construed to invalidate, impair, or supersede any law enacted by any State for the purpose of regulating the business of insurance, or which imposes a fee or tax upon such business, unless such Act specifically relates to the business of insurance: <i>Provided</i>, That after <date date="1948-06-30">June 30, 1948</date>, the Act of <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, as amended, known as the Sherman Act, and the Act of <date date="1914-10-15">October 15, 1914</date>, as amended, known as the Clayton Act, and the Act of <date date="1914-09-26">September 26, 1914</date>, known as the Federal Trade Commission Act, as amended [<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.], shall be applicable to the business of insurance to the extent that such business is not regulated by State Law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 9, 1945, ch. 20, § 2</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>July 25, 1947, ch. 326</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1013.</num>
<heading> Suspension until <date date="1948-06-30">June 30, 1948</date>, of application of certain Federal laws; Sherman Act applicable to agreements to, or acts of, boycott, coercion, or intimidation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Until <date date="1948-06-30">June 30, 1948</date>, the Act of <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, as amended, known as the Sherman Act, and the Act of <date date="1914-10-15">October 15, 1914</date>, as amended, known as the Clayton Act, and the Act of <date date="1914-09-26">September 26, 1914</date>, known as the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.], and the Act of <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, known as the Robinson-Patman Anti-Discrimination Act, shall not apply to the business of insurance or to acts in the conduct thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this chapter shall render the said Sherman Act inapplicable to any agreement to boycott, coerce, or intimidate, or act of boycott, coercion, or intimidation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this chapter shall modify, impair, or supersede the operation of any of the antitrust laws with respect to the business of health insurance (including the business of dental insurance and limited-scope dental benefits).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to making a contract, or engaging in a combination or conspiracy—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to collect, compile, or disseminate historical loss data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to determine a loss development factor applicable to historical loss data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to perform actuarial services if such contract, combination, or conspiracy does not involve a restraint of trade; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to develop or disseminate a standard insurance policy form (including a standard addendum to an insurance policy form and standard terminology in an insurance policy form) if such contract, combination, or conspiracy is not to adhere to such standard form or require adherence to such standard form.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “antitrust laws” has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of <ref>section 12 of this title</ref>, except that such term includes <ref>section 45 of this title</ref> to the extent that such section 45 applies to unfair methods of competition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the term “business of health insurance (including the business of dental insurance and limited-scope dental benefits)” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the business of life insurance (including annuities); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the business of property or casualty insurance, including but not limited to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any insurance or benefits defined as “excepted benefits” under paragraph (1), subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (2), or paragraph (3) of <ref>section 9832(c) of title 26</ref> whether offered separately or in combination with insurance or benefits described in paragraph (2)(A) of such section; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any other line of insurance that is classified as property or casualty insurance under State law;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “historical loss data” means information respecting claims paid, or reserves held for claims reported, by any person engaged in the business of insurance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “loss development factor” means an adjustment to be made to reserves held for losses incurred for claims reported by any person engaged in the business of insurance, for the purpose of bringing such reserves to an ultimate paid basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 9, 1945, ch. 20, § 3</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>July 25, 1947, ch. 326</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 448</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–327, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-13">Jan. 13, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 5097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1014.</num>
<heading> Effect on other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to affect in any manner the application to the business of insurance of the Act of <date date="1935-07-05">July 5, 1935</date>, as amended, known as the National Labor Relations Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], or the Act of <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, as amended, known as the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 [<ref>29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], or the Act of <date date="1920-06-05">June 5, 1920</date>, known as the Merchant Marine Act, 1920.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 9, 1945, ch. 20, § 4</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 34</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1015.</num>
<heading> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “State” includes the several States, Alaska, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 9, 1945, ch. 20, § 5</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 852, § 4</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>