<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 40—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1501.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Department; Secretary; seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be at the seat of government an executive department to be known as the Department of Commerce, and a Secretary of Commerce, who shall be the head thereof, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and whose term and tenure of office shall be like that of the heads of the other executive departments; and the provisions of title 4 of the Revised Statutes, including all amendments thereto, shall be applicable to said department. The said Secretary shall cause a seal of office to be made for the said department of such device as the President shall approve, and judicial notice shall be taken of the said seal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 1</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 825</ref>; <ref>Feb. 17, 1909, ch. 137</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref>35 Stat. 626</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 297, § 1</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 861</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1917, ch. 163, § 1</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 1111</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1925, ch. 549, § 4</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1502, 1503.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1503a.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Commerce for Economic Affairs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Commerce an Under Secretary of Commerce for Economic Affairs who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Under Secretary shall perform such duties as the Secretary of Commerce shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–195, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-06-16">June 16, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1503b.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere; duties; appointment; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Commerce an Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere who shall serve as the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration established by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1970 [5 U.S.C. App.] and perform such duties as the Secretary of Commerce shall prescribe. The Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate and shall be compensated at the rate now or hereafter provided for Level III of the Executive Schedule Pay Rates (<ref>5 U.S.C. 5314</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–659, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1504.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–195, § 1(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-06-16">June 16, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 115</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1505.</num>
<heading> Additional Assistant Secretary; duties, rank of Assistant Secretaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Commerce one additional Assistant Secretary of Commerce, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Secretary of Commerce may assign to his Assistant Secretaries such duties, including the direction of the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, as he shall prescribe, or may be required by law. The Assistant Secretaries of Commerce shall be without numerical distinction of rank.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 15, 1947, ch. 251</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1506.</num>
<heading> Additional Assistant Secretary; appointment; applicability of section 1505</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be on and after <date date="1954-07-02">July 2, 1954</date> in the Department of Commerce, in addition to the Assistant Secretaries now provided for by law, one additional Assistant Secretary of Commerce, who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall be subject in all respects to the provisions of <ref>section 1505 of this title</ref>, relating to Assistant Secretaries of Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 2, 1954, ch. 456</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref>68 Stat. 430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1507.</num>
<heading> Additional Assistant Secretary; appointment; compensation; duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Commerce, in addition to the Assistant Secretaries now provided by law, one additional Assistant Secretary of Commerce who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall receive compensation at the rate prescribed by law for Assistant Secretaries of Commerce, and shall perform such duties as the Secretary of Commerce shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–405</ref>, <date date="1962-02-16">Feb. 16, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1507a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(5)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-06">Aug. 6, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 154</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1507b.</num>
<heading> Assistant Secretary of Commerce; appointment; compensation; duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Commerce, in addition to the Assistant Secretaries provided by law as of <date date="1977-11-12">November 12, 1977</date>, one additional Assistant Secretary of Commerce who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Such Assistant Secretary shall perform such duties as the Secretary of Commerce shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–173, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-12">Nov. 12, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–195, § 1(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1982-06-16">June 16, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1507c.</num>
<heading> Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere; duties; appointment; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Commerce, in addition to the Assistant Secretaries of Commerce provided by law before <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, one additional Assistant Secretary of Commerce who shall have the title Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and shall serve as the Deputy Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration established by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1970 [5 U.S.C. App.] and perform such duties and functions as the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall prescribe. The Assistant Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate and shall be compensated at the rate now or hereafter provided for Level IV of the Executive Schedule Pay Rates (<ref>5 U.S.C. 5315</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–659, title IV, § 407(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1508.</num>
<heading> General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Commerce a General Counsel, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 18, 1904, ch. 716, § 1</ref>, <ref>33 Stat. 135</ref>; <ref>July 17, 1952, ch. 932, § 2</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>Aug. 20, 1954, ch. 776</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1509.</num>
<heading> Designation of officer to sign routine papers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may designate an officer of the Department to sign minor routine official papers and documents during the temporary absence of the Secretary, the Under Secretary, and the Assistant Secretaries of the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 21, 1945, ch. 129</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref>59 Stat. 188</ref>; <ref>July 15, 1947, ch. 251</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1510.</num>
<heading> Clerical assistants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall also be such clerical assistants as may from time to time be authorized by the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 2</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 826</ref>; <ref>July 16, 1952, ch. 878, § 2</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511.</num>
<heading> Bureaus in Department</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following named bureaus, administrations, services, offices, and programs of the public service, and all that pertains thereto, shall be under the jurisdiction and subject to the control of the Secretary of Commerce:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> United States Travel and Tourism Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> National Institute of Standards and Technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> United States Patent and Trademark Office <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002322">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Bureau of the Census; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> such other bureaus or other organizational units as the Secretary of Commerce may from time to time establish in accordance with law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552</ref>, §§ 4, 12, <ref>32 Stat. 826</ref>, 830; <ref>June 17, 1910, ch. 301, § 4</ref>, <ref>36 Stat. 537</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 3</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref>Jan. 5, 1923, ch. 23, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 1109</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1932, ch. 314</ref>, pt. II, title V, § 501, <ref>47 Stat. 415</ref>; <date date="1934-02-22">Feb. 22, 1934</date>, Ex. Ord. 6611; <ref>May 27, 1936, ch. 463, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1380</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, §§ 2(a), 4(e), 6, eff. <date date="1936-07-01">July 1, 1936</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref>53 Stat. 1432</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. IV, §§ 7, 8, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2422, <ref>54 Stat. 1235</ref>, 1236; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, §§ 101–104, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7875, <ref>60 Stat. 1097</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, title I, § 103(a), <ref>63 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, § 20</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 561</ref>; 1949 Reorg. Plan No. 7, § 1, eff. <date date="1949-08-19">Aug. 19, 1949</date>, 14 F.R. 5228, <ref>63 Stat. 1070</ref>; 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 21, §§ 101, 106, 201, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref>64 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–498, § 23</ref>, <date date="1974-10-29">Oct. 29, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1549</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 3</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–422, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-05">Oct. 5, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(6)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-06">Aug. 6, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–63, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-16">Oct. 16, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(b)(6)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–583; <ref>Pub. L. 106–503, title I, § 110(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–219, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1977-12-28">Dec. 28, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1613</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511b.</num>
<heading> United States fishery trade officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out export promotion and other fishery development responsibilities, the Secretary of Commerce (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall appoint not fewer than six officers who shall serve abroad to promote United States fishing interests. These officers shall be knowledgeable about the United States fishing industry, preferably with experience derived from the harvesting, processing, or marketing sectors of the industry or from the administration of fisheries programs. Such officers, who shall be employees of the Department of Commerce, shall have the designation of fishery trade officers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of State shall officially assign fishery trade officers to such diplomatic missions of the United States as the Secretary designates (three of which shall be those in Brussels, Belgium; Rome, Italy; and Tokyo, Japan) and shall obtain for them diplomatic privileges and immunities equivalent to those enjoyed by foreign service personnel of comparable rank and salary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of fishery trade officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The functions of fishery trade officers appointed under subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase the effectiveness of United States fishery export promotion efforts through such activities as the coordination of market development efforts and the provision of services and facilities for exporters of United States fishery products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to develop, maintain, and make available to interested persons listings of (A) trade, government, and other organizations that are concerned with, or have an interest in, international trade in United States fishery products, and (B) United States fishery products available for such trade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to prepare quarterly reports regarding (A) the supply, demand, and prices of each United States fishery product exported, or for which there may be export potential, to the foreign nation or area concerned, and (B) the trade barriers or incentives of such nation or area that affect imports of such products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to prepare weekly statements regarding the prices for each fishery product for which there may be United States export potential to the foreign nation or area concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to carry out such other functions as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State and the Secretary shall enter into cooperative arrangements concerning the provision of office space, equipment, facilities, clerical services, and such other administrative support as may be required for fishery trade officers and their families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–561, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511c.</num>
<heading> Estuarine Programs Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Administrator”) shall establish within the Administration an Estuarine Programs Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Estuarine Programs Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and implement a national estuarine strategy for the Administration that integrates the research, regulatory, and trusteeship responsibilities of the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate the estuarine activities of the various organizations within the Administration, including activities in estuarine research and assessment, fisheries research, coastal management, and habitat conservation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate the estuarine activities of the Administration with the activities of other Federal and State agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> provide technical assistance to the Administrator, to other Federal agencies, and to State and local government agencies in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assessing the condition of estuaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identifying estuaries of critical national or regional importance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identifying technical and management alternatives for the restoration and protection of estuarine resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> monitoring the implementation and effectiveness of estuarine management plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administration not to exceed $500,000 for fiscal year 1987, $530,000 for fiscal year 1988, $560,000 for fiscal year 1989, and $600,000 for fiscal year 1990 to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–659, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511d.</num>
<heading> Chesapeake Bay Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce shall establish, within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, an office to be known as the Chesapeake Bay Office (in this section referred to as the “Office”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Office shall be headed by a Director who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Chesapeake Executive Council. Any individual appointed as Director shall have knowledge and experience in research or resource management efforts in the Chesapeake Bay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director may appoint such additional personnel for the Office as the Director determines necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office, in consultation with the Chesapeake Executive Council, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> provide technical assistance to the Administrator, to other Federal departments and agencies, and to State and local government agencies in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assessing the processes that shape the Chesapeake Bay system and affect its living resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identifying technical and management alternatives for the restoration and protection of living resources and the habitats they depend upon; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> monitoring the implementation and effectiveness of management plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop and implement a strategy for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that integrates the science, research, monitoring, data collection, regulatory, and management responsibilities of the Secretary of Commerce in such a manner as to assist the cooperative, intergovernmental Chesapeake Bay Program to meet the commitments of the Chesapeake Bay Agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> coordinate the programs and activities of the various organizations within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Chesapeake Bay Regional Sea Grant Programs, and the Chesapeake Bay units of the National Estuarine Research Reserve System, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> programs and activities in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> coastal and estuarine research, monitoring, and assessment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> fisheries research and stock assessments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> data management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> remote sensing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> coastal management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> habitat conservation and restoration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> atmospheric deposition; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> programs and activities of the Cooperative Oxford Laboratory of the National Ocean Service with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> nonindigenous species;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> estuarine and marine species pathology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> human pathogens in estuarine and marine environments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> ecosystem health;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordinate the activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with the activities of the Environmental Protection Agency and other Federal, State, and local agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish an effective mechanism which shall ensure that projects have undergone appropriate peer review and provide other appropriate means to determine that projects have acceptable scientific and technical merit for the purpose of achieving maximum utilization of available funds and resources to benefit the Chesapeake Bay area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> remain cognizant of ongoing research, monitoring, and management projects and assist in the dissemination of the results and findings of those projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> submit a biennial report to the Congress and the Secretary of Commerce with respect to the activities of the Office and on the progress made in protecting and restoring the living resources and habitat of the Chesapeake Bay, which report shall include an action plan consisting of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of recommended research, monitoring, and data collection activities necessary to continue implementation of the strategy described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> proposals for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> continuing any new National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration activities in the Chesapeake Bay; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the integration of those activities with the activities of the partners in the Chesapeake Bay Program to meet the commitments of the Chesapeake 2000 agreement and subsequent agreements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chesapeake Bay fishery and habitat restoration small watershed grants program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Chesapeake Bay Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (in this section referred to as the “Director”), in cooperation with the Chesapeake Executive Council, shall carry out a community-based fishery and habitat restoration small grants and technical assistance program in the Chesapeake Bay watershed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall make grants under this subsection to pay the Federal share of the cost of projects that are carried out by entities eligible under paragraph (3) for the restoration of fisheries and habitats in the Chesapeake Bay.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal share under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed 75 percent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Projects for which grants may be made under this subsection include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the improvement of fish passageways;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the creation of natural or artificial reefs or substrata for habitats;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the restoration of wetland or sea grass;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the production of oysters for restoration projects; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the prevention, identification, and control of nonindigenous species.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The following entities are eligible to receive grants under this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The government of a political subdivision of a State in the Chesapeake Bay watershed, and the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An organization in the Chesapeake Bay watershed (such as an educational institution or a community organization)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is described in <ref>section 501(c) of title 26</ref> and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that will administer such grants in coordination with a government referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director may prescribe any additional requirements, including procedures, that the Director considers necessary to carry out the program under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chesapeake Executive Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, “Chesapeake Executive Council” means the representatives from the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, the Environmental Protection Agency, the District of Columbia, and the Chesapeake Bay Commission, who are signatories to the Chesapeake Bay Agreement, and any future signatories to that Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Commerce for the Chesapeake Bay Office $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2006.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–372, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 6</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3444</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1512.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties of Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the province and duty of said Department to foster, promote, and develop the foreign and domestic commerce, the mining, manufacturing, and fishery industries of the United States; and to this end it shall be vested with jurisdiction and control of the departments, bureaus, offices, and branches of the public service hereinafter specified, and with such other powers and duties as may be prescribed by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 3</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 826</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(7)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-06">Aug. 6, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1513.</num>
<heading> Duties and powers vested in Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All duties performed and all power and authority possessed or exercised by the head of any executive department in and over any bureau, office, officer, board, branch, or division of the public service transferred to the Department of Commerce, or any business arising therefrom or pertaining thereto, or in relation to the duties performed by and authority conferred by law upon such bureau, officer, office, board, branch, or division of the public service, whether of an appellate or revisory character or otherwise, shall be vested in and exercised by the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 10</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1513a.</num>
<heading> Cost estimates for National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration programs included in Department budget justification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning in fiscal year 2007 and for each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall include in the budget justification materials that the Secretary submits to Congress in support of the Department of Commerce budget (as submitted with the budget of the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>) an estimate for each National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration procurement, acquisition and construction program having a total multiyear program cost of more than $5,000,000 and an estimate of the budgetary requirements for each such program for each of the five subsequent fiscal years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–108, title II</ref>, <date date="2005-11-22">Nov. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2312</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1513b.</num>
<heading> Cost estimates for National Institute of Standards and Technology construction projects included in Department budget justification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning in fiscal year 2007 and for each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall include in the budget justification materials that the Secretary submits to Congress in support of the Department of Commerce budget (as submitted with the budget of the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>) an estimate for each National Institute of Standards and Technology construction project having a total multiyear program cost of more than $5,000,000 and simultaneously the budget justification materials shall include an estimate of the budgetary requirements for each such project for each of the five subsequent fiscal years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–108, title II</ref>, <date date="2005-11-22">Nov. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1514.</num>
<heading> Basic authority for performance of certain functions and activities of Department</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Appropriations are authorized for the following activities of the Department of Commerce:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> furnishing to employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies (including Army, Navy, and Air Force personnel where Army, Navy, or Air Force facilities or supplies are not available and upon request of the service concerned), and their dependents, in Alaska and other points outside the continental United States, free emergency medical services by contract or otherwise and free emergency medical supplies, where in the judgment of the Secretary furnishing of such supplies and services is necessary;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> when deemed necessary by the Secretary of Commerce, purchasing, transporting, storing, and distributing food and other subsistence supplies for resale to employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies (including Army, Navy, and Air Force personnel where Army, Navy, or Air Force facilities or supplies are not available and upon request of the service concerned), and their dependents, in Alaska and other points outside the continental United States at a reasonable value as determined by the Secretary of Commerce, the proceeds from such resales to be credited to the appropriation from which the expenditure was made;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> when deemed necessary by the Secretary of Commerce, the establishment, maintenance, and operation of messing facilities, by contract or otherwise, in Alaska and other points outside the continental United States where suitable family facilities are not available, such service to be furnished to employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies (including Army, Navy, and Air Force personnel where Army, Navy, or Air Force facilities are not available and upon request of the service concerned), and their dependents, in accordance with regulations established by the Secretary of Commerce, and at a reasonable value determined in accordance therewith, the proceeds from the furnishing of such services to be credited to the appropriation from which the expenditures are made;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> reimbursement, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, of officers and employees in or under the Department of Commerce, for food, clothing, medicines, and other supplies furnished by them in emergencies for the temporary relief of distressed persons in remote localities;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> providing motion-picture equipment and film for recreation of crews of vessels of the National Ocean Survey, for recreation of employees in remote localities where such facilities are not available, and for training purposes;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> erecting, altering, repairing, equipping, furnishing, and maintaining, by contract or otherwise, such living and working quarters and facilities as may be necessary to carry out its authorized work at remote localities not on foreign soil where such living and working accommodations are not otherwise available.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 26, 1949, ch. 733</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref>Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1076, § 1(11)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–608, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1515.</num>
<heading> Records, etc., of bureaus transferred to Department of Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The official records and papers on file in and pertaining exclusively to the business of any bureau, office, department, or branch of the public service transferred to the Department of Commerce, together with the furniture in use in such bureau, office, department, or branch of the public service, are transferred to the Department of Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4</ref> (part), <ref>32 Stat. 826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1516.</num>
<heading> Statistical information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall have control of the work of gathering and distributing statistical information naturally relating to the subjects confided to his department; and he shall have the power and authority to rearrange the statistical work of the bureaus and offices confided to the Department of Commerce, and to consolidate any of the statistical bureaus and offices above described. He shall also have authority to call upon other departments of the Government for statistical data and results obtained by them; and he may collate, arrange, and publish such statistical information so obtained in such manner as to him may seem wise.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4</ref> (part), <ref>32 Stat. 826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1516a.</num>
<heading> Statistics relating to social, health, and economic conditions of Americans of Spanish origin or descent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Commerce, the Department of Labor, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Department of Agriculture shall each collect, and publish regularly, statistics which indicate the social, health, and economic condition of Americans of Spanish origin or descent.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–311, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-06-16">June 16, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1517.</num>
<heading> Transfer of statistical or scientific work</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized, by order in writing, to transfer at any time the whole or any part of any office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service engaged in statistical or scientific work, from the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Defense, the Department of Justice, the United States Postal Service, or the Department of the Interior, to the Department of Commerce; and in every such case the duties and authority performed by and conferred by law upon such office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service, or the part thereof so transferred, shall be thereby transferred with such office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service, or the part thereof which is so transferred. All power and authority conferred by law, both supervisory and appellate, upon the department from which such transfer is made, or the Secretary thereof, in relation to the said office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service, or the part thereof so transferred, shall immediately, when such transfer is so ordered by the President, be fully conferred upon and vested in the Department of Commerce, or the Secretary thereof, as the case may be, as to the whole or part of such office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service so transferred.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 12</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 830</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 201(a), <ref>61 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref>Aug. 10, 1949, ch. 412, § 4</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 579</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, §§ 4(a), 6(<i>o</i>), <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 773</ref>, 783.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1518.</num>
<heading> Custody of buildings; officers transferred</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall have charge, in the buildings or premises occupied by or appropriated to the Department of Commerce, of the library, furniture, fixtures, rec­ords, and other property pertaining to it or acquired for use in its business; and he shall be allowed to expend for periodicals and the purposes of the library, and for the rental of appropriate quarters for the accommodation of the Department of Commerce within the District of Columbia, and for all other incidental expenses, such sums as Congress may provide from time to time. Where any office, bureau, or branch of the public service transferred to the Department of Commerce is occupying rented buildings or premises, it may still continue to do so until other suitable quarters are provided for its use. All officers, clerks, and employees employed on <date date="1903-02-14">February 14, 1903</date>, in or by any of the bureaus, offices, departments, or branches of the public service transferred to the Department of Commerce are each and all transferred to said department, except where otherwise provided by law. All laws prescribing the work and defining the duties of the several bureaus, offices, departments, or branches of the public service transferred to and made a part of the Department of Commerce shall, so far as the same are not in conflict with the provisions of this Act, remain in full force and effect until otherwise provided by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 9</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1519.</num>
<heading> Annual and special reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall annually, at the close of each fiscal year, make a report in writing to Congress, giving an account of all moneys received and disbursed by him and his Department, and describing the work done by the Department in fostering, promoting, and developing the foreign and domestic commerce, the mining, manufacturing, and fishery industries; of the United States, and making such recommendations as he shall deem necessary for the effective performance of the duties and purposes of the Department. He shall also from time to time make such special investigations and reports as he may be required to do by the President, or by either House of Congress, or which he himself may deem necessary and urgent.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 8</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(7)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-06">Aug. 6, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1519a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–449, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2443</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1520.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–412, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1970-09-25">Sept. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 864</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1521.</num>
<heading> Working capital fund; establishment; amount; uses; reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a working capital fund of $100,000, without fiscal year limitation, for the payment of salaries and other expenses necessary to the maintenance and operation of (1) central duplicating, photographic, drafting, and photostating services and (2) such other services as the Secretary, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, determines may be performed more advantageously as central services; said fund to be reimbursed from applicable funds of bureaus, offices, and agencies for which services are performed on the basis of rates which shall include estimated or actual charges for personal services, materials, equipment (including maintenance, repairs, and depreciation) and other expenses: <i>Provided</i>, That such central services shall, to the fullest extent practicable, be used to make unnecessary the maintenance of separate like services in the bureaus, offices, and agencies of the Department: <i>Provided further</i>, That a separate schedule of expenditures and reimbursements, and a statement of the current assets and liabilities of the working capital fund as of the close of the last completed fiscal year, shall be included in the annual Budget.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1944, ch. 294</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref>58 Stat. 415</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 7959, <ref>84 Stat. 2085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1521a.</num>
<heading> Department of Commerce Nonrecurring Expenses Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Department of Commerce Nonrecurring Expenses Fund” (the Fund): <i>Provided</i>, That unobligated balances of expired discretionary funds appropriated for this or any succeeding fiscal year from the General Fund of the Treasury to the Department of Commerce by this or any other Act may be transferred (not later than the end of the fifth fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such funds are available for the purposes for which appropriated) into the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available until expended, and in addition to such other funds as may be available for such purposes, for information and business technology system modernization and facilities infrastructure improvements necessary for the operation of the Department, subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts in the Fund may be obligated only after the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate are notified at least 15 days in advance of the planned use of funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In addition to amounts otherwise made available by this Act, there is appropriated $20,000,000, to remain available until <date date="2022-09-30">September 30, 2022</date>, to the Fund for necessary expenses for a business application system modernization.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–93, div. B, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1522.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of gifts and bequests for purposes of the Department; separate fund; disbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is hereby authorized to accept, hold, administer, and utilize gifts and bequests of property, both real and personal, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Department of Commerce. Gifts and bequests of money and the proceeds from sales of other property received as gifts or bequests shall be deposited in the Treasury in a separate fund and shall be disbursed upon order of the Secretary of Commerce. Property accepted pursuant to this provision, and the proceeds thereof, shall be used as nearly as possible in accordance with the terms of the gift or bequest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–611, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-10-02">Oct. 2, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1523.</num>
<heading> Tax status of gifts and bequests of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of Federal income, estate, and gift taxes, property accepted under <ref>section 1522 of this title</ref> shall be considered as a gift or bequest to or for the use of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–611, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-10-02">Oct. 2, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1524.</num>
<heading> Investment and reinvestments of moneys; credit and disbursement of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury may invest and reinvest in securities of the United States or in securities guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States any moneys contained in the fund authorized herein. Income accruing from such securities, and from any other property accepted pursuant to <ref>section 1522 of this title</ref>, shall be deposited to the credit of the fund authorized herein, and shall be disbursed upon order of the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–611, § 3</ref>, <date date="1964-10-02">Oct. 2, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1525.</num>
<heading> Special studies; special compilations, lists, bulletins, or reports; clearinghouse for technical information; transcripts or copies; cost payments for special work; joint projects: cost apportionment, waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized, upon the request of any person, firm, organization, or others, public or private, to make special studies on matters within the authority of the Department of Commerce; to prepare from its records special compilations, lists, bulletins, or reports; to perform the functions authorized by <ref>section 1152 of this title</ref>; and to furnish transcripts or copies of its studies, compilations, and other records; upon the payment of the actual or estimated cost of such special work.</p>
<p class="indent0">In the case of nonprofit organizations, research organizations, or public organizations or agencies, the Secretary may engage in joint projects, or perform services, on matters of mutual interest, the cost of which shall be apportioned equitably, as determined by the Secretary, who may, however, waive payment of any portion of such costs by others, when authorized to do so under regulations approved by the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–412, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-09-25">Sept. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 864</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 7959, <ref>84 Stat. 2085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1526.</num>
<heading> Receipts for work or services; deposit in special accounts; availability for payment of costs, repayment or advances to appropriations or funds, refunds, credits to working capital funds; appropriation limitation of annual expenditures from accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All payments for work or services performed or to be performed under this Act shall be deposited in a separate account or accounts which may be used to pay directly the costs of such work or services, to repay or make advances to appropriations or funds which do or will initially bear all or part of such costs, or to refund excess sums when necessary: <i>Provided</i>, That said receipts may be credited to a working capital fund otherwise established by law, and used under the law governing said funds, if the fund is available for use by the agency of the Department of Commerce which is responsible for performing the work or services for which payment is received. Acts appropriating funds to the Department of Commerce may include provisions limiting annual expenditure from said account or accounts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–412, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-09-25">Sept. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1527.</num>
<heading> Fees or charges for services or publications under existing law unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as to those laws expressly repealed herein, nothing in this Act shall alter, amend, modify, or repeal any existing law prescribing fees or charges or authorizing the prescribing of fees or charges for services performed or for any publication furnished by the Department of Commerce, or any of its several bureaus or offices.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–412, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-09-25">Sept. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 865</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1527a.</num>
<heading> Economics and Statistics Administration Revolving Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established the Economics and Statistics Administration Revolving Fund which shall be available without fiscal year limitation. For initial capitalization, there is appropriated $1,677,000 to the Fund: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to disseminate economic and statistical data products as authorized by sections 1525 to 1527 of this title and, notwithstanding <ref>section 4912 of this title</ref>, charge fees necessary to recover the full costs incurred in their production. Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, receipts received from these data dissemination activities shall be credited to this account as offsetting collections, to be available for carrying out these purposes without further appropriation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–317, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1744</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1528.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1529.</num>
<heading> Relinquishment of legislative jurisdiction over certain lands</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, the Secretary of Commerce, whenever the Secretary considers it desirable, may relinquish to a State, or to a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, all or part of the legislative jurisdiction of the United States over lands or interests under the Secretary’s control in that State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession. Relinquishment of legislative jurisdiction under this section may be accomplished—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by filing with the Governor (or, if none exists, with the chief executive officer) of the State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession concerned a notice of relinquishment to take effect upon acceptance of the notice; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as required by the laws of the State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–623, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1530.</num>
<heading> Awarding of contracts for performance of commercial activity by National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administration may not award any contract for the performance of any “commercial activity”, as defined by paragraph 6.a. of the Office of Management and Budget Circular Memorandum A–76, which is performed by Administration employees until at least 30 calendar days after the Administrator of the Administration has presented, in writing, to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, a full and complete description of such proposed contract, together with supporting documentation. Such documentation shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a comparison of the cost of such activity as performed by employees of the Administration and the cost of such activity as performed under the proposed contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a comparison of the services performed by employees of the Administration and the services to be performed under the proposed contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an assessment of the benefits to the Federal Government of proceeding with the proposed contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title VI, § 6083</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 5(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4582</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1531.</num>
<heading> Buying Power Maintenance accounts for International Trade Administration, Export Administration, and United States Travel and Tourism Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to maintain overseas program activity for the Department of Commerce provided for each fiscal year at the appropriated program levels, the Secretary may establish Buying Power Maintenance accounts for the International Trade Administration, the Export Administration, and the United States Travel and Tourism Administration. There are authorized to be appropriated for such accounts such sums as may be necessary to offset adverse fluctuations in foreign currency exchange rates, or unbudgeted overseas wage and price changes. To eliminate substantial gains to the approved levels of overseas operations, the Secretary shall transfer to a Buying Power Maintenance account such amounts determined to be excessive to the needs of the approved level of overseas operations because of fluctuations in foreign currency exchange rates or changes in unbudgeted overseas wages and prices, including unobligated balances associated with the overseas program. To offset adverse fluctuations in foreign currency exchange rates or unbudgeted overseas wage and price changes, the Secretary may transfer from a Buying Power Maintenance account such amounts determined to be necessary to maintain the approved level of overseas operations under an appropriation account. Funds transferred by the Secretary to or from a Buying Power Maintenance account to another account shall be merged with and be available for the same purpose, and for the same time period, as the funds in the account into which transferred. Any restriction contained in an appropriation Act or other provision of law limiting the amounts available for the Department of Commerce that may be obligated or expended shall be deemed to be adjusted to the extent necessary to offset the net effect of fluctuations in foreign currency exchange rates or unbudgeted overseas wage and price changes in order to maintain approved levels.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(a) [title I, § 108]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329</ref>, 1329–7.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1532.</num>
<heading> Telecommunications; electromagnetic radiation; research, analysis, dissemination of information; other functions of Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct research on all of the telecommunications sciences, including wave propagation and reception, the conditions which affect electromagnetic wave propagation and reception, electromagnetic noise and interference, radio system characteristics, operating techniques affecting the use of the electromagnetic spectrum, and methods for improving the use of the electromagnetic spectrum for telecommunications purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare and issue predictions of electromagnetic wave propagation conditions and warnings of disturbances in such conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> investigate conditions which affect the transmission of radio waves from their source to a receiver and the compilation and distribution of information on such transmission of radio waves as a basis for choice of frequencies to be used in radio operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conduct research and analysis in the general field of telecommunications sciences in support of assigned functions and in support of other Government agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> investigate nonionizing electromagnetic radiation and its uses, as well as methods and procedures for measuring and assessing electromagnetic environments, for the purpose of developing and coordinating policies and procedures affecting Federal Government use of the electromagnetic spectrum for telecommunications purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> compile, evaluate, publish, and otherwise disseminate general scientific and technical data resulting from the performance of the functions specified in this section or from other sources when such data are important to science, engineering, or industry, or to the general public, and are not available elsewhere; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> undertake such other activities similar to those specified in this subsection as the Secretary of Commerce determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5112(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1533.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title IV, § 407(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4004</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1534.</num>
<heading> Assessment of fees for access to environmental data</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis of assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary is authorized to assess fees, based on fair market value, for access to environmental data and information and products derived therefrom collected and/or archived by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible recipients; waiver of fees in cases of foreign governments and international organizations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide data, information, and products described in subsection (a) to Federal, State, and local government agencies, to universities, and to other nonprofit institutions at the cost of reproduction and transmission, if such data, information, and products are to be used for research and not for commercial purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall waive the assessment of fees under subsection (a) as necessary to continue to provide data, information, or products to foreign governments and international organizations on a basis of exchanging such data, information, and products or as otherwise provided by international agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall waive the assessment of fees authorized by subsection (a) as necessary to continue to provide weather warnings, watches, and similar products and services essential to the mission of the National Oceanic Atmospheric <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002324">1</ref> Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of fee schedules in Federal Register; initial schedule effective for three-year period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The initial schedule of any fees assessed under this section, and any subsequent amendment to such schedule, shall be published by the Secretary in the Federal Register at least 30 days before such fees will take effect. The initial schedule shall remain in effect without amendment for the three-year period beginning on the date that fees under the schedule take effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of assessments; progressive increments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any assessment of fees under this section by the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for archived data shall meet the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The initial schedule of fees established by the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for archived data shall remain in effect for the 3-year period beginning on the date that the fees under that schedule take effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> With respect to the first one-year period during which the initial fee schedule is in effect, fees shall be assessed at no more than one-third of the fair market value specified in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> With respect to the second one-year period during which the initial fee schedule is in effect, fees shall be assessed at not more than two-thirds of such fair market value.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> With respect to the third one-year period during which the initial fee schedule is in effect, and with respect to any period thereafter, fees shall be assessed at no more than the full amount of such fair market value.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data archive center operations; availability of fees for expenses of centers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Fees collected under this section by the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for archived data shall be available to the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for expenses incurred in the operation of its data archive centers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, not later than 90 days after <date date="1988-11-17">November 17, 1988</date>, submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report which sets forth—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any plan of the Secretary for assessing fees under this section by the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for archived data, including the methodology and bases by which the amount of such fees shall be determined, and the estimated revenues therefrom; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any plan of the Secretary for using revenues generated from such fees, as well as other resources, to improve the capability of the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service to collect, manage, process, archive, and disseminate the increasing amounts of data generated from satellites, radars, and other technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other assessment authorities unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary to assess fees under this section shall be in addition to, and shall not be construed to limit, the authority under any other law to assess fees relating to the environmental data activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including the authority of the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 1307 of title 44</ref>. Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to assess fees for nautical and aeronautical products of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in addition to those fees authorized under <ref>section 1307 of title 44</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–685, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title X, § 10201(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–392</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1535.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 6</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3444</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1536.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If it has been finally determined by a court or a Federal agency that any person intentionally affixed a label bearing a “Made in America” inscription, or an inscription with the same meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States, that person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract from the Department of Commerce, pursuant to the debarment, suspension, and ineligibility procedures in subpart 9.4 of chapter 1 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–245, title I, § 111(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 14</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1537.</num>
<heading> Needs assessment for data management, archival, and distribution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 12 months after <date date="1992-10-29">October 29, 1992</date>, and at least biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall complete an assessment of the adequacy of the environmental data and information systems of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. In conducting such an assessment, the Secretary shall take into consideration the need to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide adequate capacity to manage, archive, and disseminate environmental data and information collected and processed, or expected to be collected and processed, by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and other appropriate departments and agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish, develop, and maintain information bases, including necessary management systems, which will promote consistent, efficient, and compatible transfer and use of data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> develop effective interfaces among the environmental data and information systems of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and other appropriate departments and agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> develop and use nationally accepted formats and standards for data collected by various national and international sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> integrate and interpret data from different sources to produce information that can be used by decisionmakers in developing policies that effectively respond to national and global environmental concerns.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 12 months after <date date="1992-10-29">October 29, 1992</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall develop and submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a comprehensive plan, based on the assessment under paragraph (1), to modernize and improve the environmental data and information systems of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. The report shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> set forth modernization and improvement objectives for the 10-year period beginning with the year in which the plan is submitted, including facility requirements and critical new technological components that would be necessary to meet the objectives set forth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> propose specific agency programs and activities for implementing the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identify the data and information management, archival, and distribution responsibilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with respect to other Federal departments and agencies and international organizations, including the role of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with respect to large data systems like the Earth Observing System Data and Information System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide an implementation schedule and estimate funding levels necessary to achieve modernization and improvement objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title I, § 106(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1538.</num>
<heading> Notice of reprogramming</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall provide notice to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and to the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, not less than 15 days before reprogramming funds available for a program, project, or activity of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in an amount greater than the lesser of $250,000 or 5 percent of the total funding of such program, project, or activity if the reprogramming—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> augments an existing program, project, or activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reduces by 5 percent or more (A) the funding for an existing program, project, or activity or (B) the numbers of personnel therefor as approved by Congress; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> results from any general savings from a reduction in personnel which would result in a change in an existing program, project, or activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of reorganization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall provide notice to the Committees on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, Science, Space, and Technology, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Appropriations of the Senate not later than 15 days before any major reorganization of any program, project, or activity of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1539.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Processing of applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 12 months after <date date="1992-10-29">October 29, 1992</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall develop and, after notice and opportunity for public comment, promulgate regulations or guidelines to ensure that a completed application for a grant, contract, or other financial assistance under a nondiscretionary assistance program shall be processed and approved or disapproved within 75 days after submission of the application to the responsible program office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of applicant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 14 days after the date on which the Secretary of Commerce receives an application for a contract, grant, or other financial assistance provided under a nondiscretionary assistance program administered by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Secretary shall indicate in writing to the applicant whether or not the application is complete and, if not complete, shall specify the additional material that the applicant must provide to complete the application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a program for which the recipient of a grant, contract, or other financial assistance is specified by statute to be, or has customarily been, a State or an interstate fishery commission, such financial assistance may be provided by the Secretary to that recipient on a sole-source basis, notwithstanding any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Nondiscretionary assistance program” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “nondiscretionary assistance program” means any program for providing financial assistance—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under which the amount of funding for, and the intended recipient of, the financial assistance is specified by Congress; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the recipients of which have customarily been a State or an interstate fishery commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1540.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, may enter into cooperative agreements and other financial agreements with any nonprofit organization to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> aid and promote scientific and educational activities to foster public understanding of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or its programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> solicit private donations for the support of such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–567, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1541.</num>
<heading> Administrative Law Judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 559 of title 5</ref>, with respect to any marine resource conservation law or regulation administered by the Secretary of Commerce acting through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, all adjudicatory functions which are required by chapter 5 of title 5 to be performed by an Administrative Law Judge may be performed by another Federal agency on a reimbursable basis. Should another Federal agency require the detail of an Administrative Law Judge to perform any of these functions, it may request such temporary or occasional assistance from the Office of Personnel Management pursuant to <ref>section 3344 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–160, § 10</ref>, <date date="1998-03-06">Mar. 6, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–327, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1542.</num>
<heading> Establishment of the Ernest F. Hollings Scholarship Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall establish and administer the Ernest F. Hollings Scholarship Program. Under the program, the Administrator shall award scholarships in oceanic and atmospheric science, research, technology, and education to be known as Ernest F. Hollings Scholarships.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the Ernest F. Hollings Scholarships Program are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase undergraduate training in oceanic and atmospheric science, research, technology, and education and foster multidisciplinary training opportunities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to increase public understanding and support for stewardship of the ocean and atmosphere and improve environmental literacy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to recruit and prepare students for public service careers with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and other natural resource and science agencies at the Federal, State and Local levels of government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to recruit and prepare students for careers as teachers and educators in oceanic and atmospheric science and to improve scientific and environmental education in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Ernest F. Hollings Scholarship—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be used to support undergraduate studies in oceanic and atmospheric science, research, technology, and education that support the purposes of the programs and missions of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall recognize outstanding scholarship and ability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall promote participation by groups underrepresented in oceanic and atmospheric science and technology; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall be awarded competitively in accordance with guidelines issued by the Administrator and published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to be eligible to participate in the program, an individual must—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be enrolled or accepted for enrollment as a full-time student at an institution of higher education (as defined in <ref>section 1001(a) of title 20</ref>) in an academic field or discipline described in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be a United States citizen;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not have received a scholarship under this section for more than 4 academic years, unless the Administrator grants a waiver; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information, agreements, or assurances as the Administrator may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of each Ernest F. Hollings Scholarship shall be provided directly to a recipient selected by the Administrator upon receipt of certification that the recipient will adhere to a specific and detailed plan of study and research approved by an institution of higher education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the total amount appropriated for fiscal year 2005 and annually hereafter to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Administrator shall make available for the Ernest F. Hollings Scholarship program one-tenth of 1 percent of such appropriations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scholarship repayment requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall require an individual receiving a scholarship under this section to repay the full amount of the scholarship to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration if the Administrator determines that the individual, in obtaining or using the scholarship, engaged in fraudulent conduct or failed to comply with any term or condition of the scholarship. Such repayments shall be deposited in the NOAA Operations, Research, and Facilities Appropriations Account and treated as an offsetting collection and only be available for financing additional scholarships.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. B, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1543.</num>
<heading> Task force on job repatriation and manufacturing growth</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall maintain a task force on job repatriation and manufacturing growth and shall produce an annual report on related incentive strategies, implementation plans and program results.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. B, title I</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1544.</num>
<heading> Promotion of tourist travel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall encourage, promote, and develop travel within the United States, including any Commonwealth, territory, and possession thereof, through activities which are in the public interest and which do not compete with activities of any State, city, or private agency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1940, ch. 642, § 1</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–193, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-12-19">Dec. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–55, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-07-09">July 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1545.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with travel agencies; publication of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the purposes of sections 1544 to 1548 of this title, the Secretary is authorized to cooperate with public and private tourist, travel, and other agencies in the display of exhibits, and in the collection, publication, and dissemination of information with respect to places of interest, routes, transportation facilities, accommodations, and such other matters as he deems advisable and advantageous for the purpose of encouraging, promoting, or developing such travel. Nothing in said sections shall prohibit the preparation of graphic materials in foreign languages, designed to call attention to the attractions and places of interest in the United States and to encourage the use of American registered ships and planes. The existing facilities of the United States Government in foreign countries are authorized to assist in the distribution of this material. The Secretary may enter into contracts with private publishers for such printing and binding as he may deem advisable in carrying out the purposes of said sections. The Secretary is also authorized to make charges for any publications made available to the public pursuant to said sections; and any proceeds from the sale of publications produced by the expenditure of contributed funds shall continue to be available for printing and binding as aforesaid.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1940, ch. 642, § 2</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1546.</num>
<heading> United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board (referred to in this section as the “Board”), the members of which shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce for 2-year terms from companies and organizations in the travel and tourism industry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism shall serve as the Executive Director of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Secretariat</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Travel and Tourism Office of the International Trade Administration shall serve as the Executive Secretariat for the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board’s Charter shall specify that the Board will—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the advisory body to the Secretary of Commerce on matters relating to the travel and tourism industry in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise the Secretary of Commerce on government policies and programs that affect the United States travel and tourism industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> offer counsel on current and emerging issues;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide a forum for discussing and proposing solutions to problems related to the travel and tourism industry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide advice regarding the domestic travel and tourism industry as an economic engine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery strategies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall assist the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism in the development and implementation of the recovery strategies required under <ref>section 9803(e)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1940, ch. 642, § 3</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(10)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-06">Aug. 6, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–443, § 9</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1984-10-04">Oct. 4, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1547.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations; employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the performance of his functions and duties under the provisions of sections 1544 to 1548 of this title, the Secretary of Commerce is authorized—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To prescribe, amend, and repeal such rules and regulations as he may deem necessary, and to accept contributions for carrying out the purposes of said sections; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> To employ, subject to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, one special assistant and not to exceed five artists and illustrators.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1940, ch. 642, § 4</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–193, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-12-19">Dec. 19, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1548.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of sections 1544 to 1548 of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $2,500,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>; $625,000 for the transition period of <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, through <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>; $2,500,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, and $2,500,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1940, ch. 642, § 5</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–549</ref>, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–55, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-07-09">July 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>