<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 103—</num>
<heading>CONTROLLING THE ASSAULT OF NON-SOLICITED PORNOGRAPHY AND MARKETING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7701.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Electronic mail has become an extremely important and popular means of communication, relied on by millions of Americans on a daily basis for personal and commercial purposes. Its low cost and global reach make it extremely convenient and efficient, and offer unique opportunities for the development and growth of frictionless commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The convenience and efficiency of electronic mail are threatened by the extremely rapid growth in the volume of unsolicited commercial electronic mail. Unsolicited commercial electronic mail is currently estimated to account for over half of all electronic mail traffic, up from an estimated 7 percent in 2001, and the volume continues to rise. Most of these messages are fraudulent or deceptive in one or more respects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The receipt of unsolicited commercial electronic mail may result in costs to recipients who cannot refuse to accept such mail and who incur costs for the storage of such mail, or for the time spent accessing, reviewing, and discarding such mail, or for both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The receipt of a large number of unwanted messages also decreases the convenience of electronic mail and creates a risk that wanted electronic mail messages, both commercial and noncommercial, will be lost, overlooked, or discarded amidst the larger volume of unwanted messages, thus reducing the reliability and usefulness of electronic mail to the recipient.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Some commercial electronic mail contains material that many recipients may consider vulgar or pornographic in nature.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The growth in unsolicited commercial electronic mail imposes significant monetary costs on providers of Internet access services, businesses, and educational and nonprofit institutions that carry and receive such mail, as there is a finite volume of mail that such providers, businesses, and institutions can handle without further investment in infrastructure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Many senders of unsolicited commercial electronic mail purposefully disguise the source of such mail.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Many senders of unsolicited commercial electronic mail purposefully include misleading information in the messages’ subject lines in order to induce the recipients to view the messages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> While some senders of commercial electronic mail messages provide simple and reliable ways for recipients to reject (or “opt-out” of) receipt of commercial electronic mail from such senders in the future, other senders provide no such “opt-out” mechanism, or refuse to honor the requests of recipients not to receive electronic mail from such senders in the future, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Many senders of bulk unsolicited commercial electronic mail use computer programs to gather large numbers of electronic mail addresses on an automated basis from Internet websites or online services where users must post their addresses in order to make full use of the website or service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Many States have enacted legislation intended to regulate or reduce unsolicited commercial electronic mail, but these statutes impose different standards and requirements. As a result, they do not appear to have been successful in addressing the problems associated with unsolicited commercial electronic mail, in part because, since an electronic mail address does not specify a geographic location, it can be extremely difficult for law-abiding businesses to know with which of these disparate statutes they are required to comply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The problems associated with the rapid growth and abuse of unsolicited commercial electronic mail cannot be solved by Federal legislation alone. The development and adoption of technological approaches and the pursuit of cooperative efforts with other countries will be necessary as well.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional determination of public policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On the basis of the findings in subsection (a), the Congress determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there is a substantial government interest in regulation of commercial electronic mail on a nationwide basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> senders of commercial electronic mail should not mislead recipients as to the source or content of such mail; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recipients of commercial electronic mail have a right to decline to receive additional commercial electronic mail from the same source.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affirmative consent</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “affirmative consent”, when used with respect to a commercial electronic mail message, means that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the recipient expressly consented to receive the message, either in response to a clear and conspicuous request for such consent or at the recipient’s own initiative; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the message is from a party other than the party to which the recipient communicated such consent, the recipient was given clear and conspicuous notice at the time the consent was communicated that the recipient’s electronic mail address could be transferred to such other party for the purpose of initiating commercial electronic mail messages.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial electronic mail message</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “commercial electronic mail message” means any electronic mail message the primary purpose of which is the commercial advertisement or promotion of a commercial product or service (including content on an Internet website operated for a commercial purpose).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transactional or relationship messages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “commercial electronic mail message” does not include a transactional or relationship message.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations regarding primary purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2003-12-16">December 16, 2003</date>, the Commission shall issue regulations pursuant to <ref>section 7711 of this title</ref> defining the relevant criteria to facilitate the determination of the primary purpose of an electronic mail message.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reference to company or website</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The inclusion of a reference to a commercial entity or a link to the website of a commercial entity in an electronic mail message does not, by itself, cause such message to be treated as a commercial electronic mail message for purposes of this chapter if the contents or circumstances of the message indicate a primary purpose other than commercial advertisement or promotion of a commercial product or service.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the Federal Trade Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domain name</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “domain name” means any alphanumeric designation which is registered with or assigned by any domain name registrar, domain name registry, or other domain name registration authority as part of an electronic address on the Internet.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Electronic mail address</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “electronic mail address” means a destination, commonly expressed as a string of characters, consisting of a unique user name or mailbox (commonly referred to as the “local part”) and a reference to an Internet domain (commonly referred to as the “domain part”), whether or not displayed, to which an electronic mail message can be sent or delivered.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Electronic mail message</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “electronic mail message” means a message sent to a unique electronic mail address.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FTC Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “FTC Act” means the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Header information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “header information” means the source, destination, and routing information attached to an electronic mail message, including the originating domain name and originating electronic mail address, and any other information that appears in the line identifying, or purporting to identify, a person initiating the message.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “initiate”, when used with respect to a commercial electronic mail message, means to originate or transmit such message or to procure the origination or transmission of such message, but shall not include actions that constitute routine conveyance of such message. For purposes of this paragraph, more than one person may be considered to have initiated a message.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Internet</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Internet” has the meaning given that term in the Internet Tax Freedom Act (<ref>47 U.S.C. 151</ref> nt).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Internet access service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Internet access service” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 231(e)(4) of title 47</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “procure”, when used with respect to the initiation of a commercial electronic mail message, means intentionally to pay or provide other consideration to, or induce, another person to initiate such a message on one’s behalf.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protected computer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “protected computer” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1030(e)(2)(B) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recipient</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “recipient”, when used with respect to a commercial electronic mail message, means an authorized user of the electronic mail address to which the message was sent or delivered. If a recipient of a commercial electronic mail message has one or more electronic mail addresses in addition to the address to which the message was sent or delivered, the recipient shall be treated as a separate recipient with respect to each such address. If an electronic mail address is reassigned to a new user, the new user shall not be treated as a recipient of any commercial electronic mail message sent or delivered to that address before it was reassigned.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Routine conveyance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “routine conveyance” means the transmission, routing, relaying, handling, or storing, through an automatic technical process, of an electronic mail message for which another person has identified the recipients or provided the recipient addresses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sender</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “sender”, when used with respect to a commercial electronic mail message, means a person who initiates such a message and whose product, service, or Internet web site is advertised or promoted by the message.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate lines of business or divisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If an entity operates through separate lines of business or divisions and holds itself out to the recipient throughout the message as that particular line of business or division rather than as the entity of which such line of business or division is a part, then the line of business or the division shall be treated as the sender of such message for purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transactional or relationship message</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “transactional or relationship message” means an electronic mail message the primary purpose of which is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to facilitate, complete, or confirm a commercial transaction that the recipient has previously agreed to enter into with the sender;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide warranty information, product recall information, or safety or security information with respect to a commercial product or service used or purchased by the recipient;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> to provide—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> notification concerning a change in the terms or features of;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> notification of a change in the recipient’s standing or status with respect to; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> at regular periodic intervals, account balance information or other type of account statement with respect to,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> a subscription, membership, account, loan, or comparable ongoing commercial relationship involving the ongoing purchase or use by the recipient of products or services offered by the sender;</continuation>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to provide information directly related to an employment relationship or related benefit plan in which the recipient is currently involved, participating, or enrolled; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> to deliver goods or services, including product updates or upgrades, that the recipient is entitled to receive under the terms of a transaction that the recipient has previously agreed to enter into with the sender.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission by regulation pursuant to <ref>section 7711 of this title</ref> may modify the definition in subparagraph (A) to expand or contract the categories of messages that are treated as transactional or relationship messages for purposes of this chapter to the extent that such modification is necessary to accommodate changes in electronic mail technology or practices and accomplish the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7703.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against predatory and abusive commercial e-mail</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Sentencing Commission</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Directive</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Pursuant to its authority under <ref>section 994(p) of title 28</ref> and in accordance with this section, the United States Sentencing Commission shall review and, as appropriate, amend the sentencing guidelines and policy statements to provide appropriate penalties for violations of <ref>section 1037 of title 18</ref>, as added by this section, and other offenses that may be facilitated by the sending of large quantities of unsolicited electronic mail.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out this subsection, the Sentencing Commission shall consider providing sentencing enhancements for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> those convicted under <ref>section 1037 of title 18</ref> who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> obtained electronic mail addresses through improper means, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> harvesting electronic mail addresses of the users of a website, proprietary service, or other online public forum operated by another person, without the authorization of such person; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> randomly generating electronic mail addresses by computer; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> knew that the commercial electronic mail messages involved in the offense contained or advertised an Internet domain for which the registrant of the domain had provided false registration information; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> those convicted of other offenses, including offenses involving fraud, identity theft, obscenity, child pornography, and the sexual exploitation of children, if such offenses involved the sending of large quantities of electronic mail.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Spam has become the method of choice for those who distribute pornography, perpetrate fraudulent schemes, and introduce viruses, worms, and Trojan horses into personal and business computer systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Department of Justice should use all existing law enforcement tools to investigate and prosecute those who send bulk commercial e-mail to facilitate the commission of Federal crimes, including the tools contained in chapters 47 and 63 of title 18 (relating to fraud and false statements); chapter 71 of title 18 (relating to obscenity); chapter 110 of title 18 (relating to the sexual exploitation of children); and chapter 95 of title 18 (relating to racketeering), as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 4</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7704.</num>
<heading> Other protections for users of commercial electronic mail</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for transmission of messages</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of false or misleading transmission information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It is unlawful for any person to initiate the transmission, to a protected computer, of a commercial electronic mail message, or a transactional or relationship message, that contains, or is accompanied by, header information that is materially false or materially misleading. For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> header information that is technically accurate but includes an originating electronic mail address, domain name, or Internet Protocol address the access to which for purposes of initiating the message was obtained by means of false or fraudulent pretenses or representations shall be considered materially misleading;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a “from” line (the line identifying or purporting to identify a person initiating the message) that accurately identifies any person who initiated the message shall not be considered materially false or materially misleading; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> header information shall be considered materially misleading if it fails to identify accurately a protected computer used to initiate the message because the person initiating the message knowingly uses another protected computer to relay or retransmit the message for purposes of disguising its origin.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of deceptive subject headings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is unlawful for any person to initiate the transmission to a protected computer of a commercial electronic mail message if such person has actual knowledge, or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances, that a subject heading of the message would be likely to mislead a recipient, acting reasonably under the circumstances, about a material fact regarding the contents or subject matter of the message (consistent with the criteria used in enforcement of <ref>section 45 of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of return address or comparable mechanism in commercial electronic mail</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">It is unlawful for any person to initiate the transmission to a protected computer of a commercial electronic mail message that does not contain a functioning return electronic mail address or other Internet-based mechanism, clearly and conspicuously displayed, that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a recipient may use to submit, in a manner specified in the message, a reply electronic mail message or other form of Internet-based communication requesting not to receive future commercial electronic mail messages from that sender at the electronic mail address where the message was received; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> remains capable of receiving such messages or communications for no less than 30 days after the transmission of the original message.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> More detailed options possible</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The person initiating a commercial electronic mail message may comply with subparagraph (A)(i) by providing the recipient a list or menu from which the recipient may choose the specific types of commercial electronic mail messages the recipient wants to receive or does not want to receive from the sender, if the list or menu includes an option under which the recipient may choose not to receive any commercial electronic mail messages from the sender.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary inability to receive messages or process requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A return electronic mail address or other mechanism does not fail to satisfy the requirements of subparagraph (A) if it is unexpectedly and temporarily unable to receive messages or process requests due to a technical problem beyond the control of the sender if the problem is corrected within a reasonable time period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of transmission of commercial electronic mail after objection</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If a recipient makes a request using a mechanism provided pursuant to paragraph (3) not to receive some or any commercial electronic mail messages from such sender, then it is unlawful—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for the sender to initiate the transmission to the recipient, more than 10 business days after the receipt of such request, of a commercial electronic mail message that falls within the scope of the request;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for any person acting on behalf of the sender to initiate the transmission to the recipient, more than 10 business days after the receipt of such request, of a commercial electronic mail message with actual knowledge, or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances, that such message falls within the scope of the request;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> for any person acting on behalf of the sender to assist in initiating the transmission to the recipient, through the provision or selection of addresses to which the message will be sent, of a commercial electronic mail message with actual knowledge, or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances, that such message would violate clause (i) or (ii); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> for the sender, or any other person who knows that the recipient has made such a request, to sell, lease, exchange, or otherwise transfer or release the electronic mail address of the recipient (including through any transaction or other transfer involving mailing lists bearing the electronic mail address of the recipient) for any purpose other than compliance with this chapter or other provision of law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent affirmative consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A prohibition in subparagraph (A) does not apply if there is affirmative consent by the recipient subsequent to the request under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of identifier, opt-out, and physical address in commercial electronic mail</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> It is unlawful for any person to initiate the transmission of any commercial electronic mail message to a protected computer unless the message provides—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> clear and conspicuous identification that the message is an advertisement or solicitation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> clear and conspicuous notice of the opportunity under paragraph (3) to decline to receive further commercial electronic mail messages from the sender; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a valid physical postal address of the sender.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A)(i) does not apply to the transmission of a commercial electronic mail message if the recipient has given prior affirmative consent to receipt of the message.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Materially</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “materially”, when used with respect to false or misleading header information, includes the alteration or concealment of header information in a manner that would impair the ability of an Internet access service processing the message on behalf of a recipient, a person alleging a violation of this section, or a law enforcement agency to identify, locate, or respond to a person who initiated the electronic mail message or to investigate the alleged violation, or the ability of a recipient of the message to respond to a person who initiated the electronic message.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggravated violations relating to commercial electronic mail</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Address harvesting and dictionary attacks</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">It is unlawful for any person to initiate the transmission, to a protected computer, of a commercial electronic mail message that is unlawful under subsection (a), or to assist in the origination of such message through the provision or selection of addresses to which the message will be transmitted, if such person had actual knowledge, or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances, that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the electronic mail address of the recipient was obtained using an automated means from an Internet website or proprietary online service operated by another person, and such website or online service included, at the time the address was obtained, a notice stating that the operator of such website or online service will not give, sell, or otherwise transfer addresses maintained by such website or online service to any other party for the purposes of initiating, or enabling others to initiate, electronic mail messages; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the electronic mail address of the recipient was obtained using an automated means that generates possible electronic mail addresses by combining names, letters, or numbers into numerous permutations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclaimer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph creates an ownership or proprietary interest in such electronic mail addresses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Automated creation of multiple electronic mail accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is unlawful for any person to use scripts or other automated means to register for multiple electronic mail accounts or online user accounts from which to transmit to a protected computer, or enable another person to transmit to a protected computer, a commercial electronic mail message that is unlawful under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relay or retransmission through unauthorized access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is unlawful for any person knowingly to relay or retransmit a commercial electronic mail message that is unlawful under subsection (a) from a protected computer or computer network that such person has accessed without authorization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplementary rulemaking authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall by regulation, pursuant to <ref>section 7711 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> modify the 10-business-day period under subsection (a)(4)(A) or subsection (a)(4)(B), or both, if the Commission determines that a different period would be more reasonable after taking into account—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the purposes of subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the interests of recipients of commercial electronic mail; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the burdens imposed on senders of lawful commercial electronic mail; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specify additional activities or practices to which subsection (b) applies if the Commission determines that those activities or practices are contributing substantially to the proliferation of commercial electronic mail messages that are unlawful under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to place warning labels on commercial electronic mail containing sexually oriented material</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No person may initiate in or affecting interstate commerce the transmission, to a protected computer, of any commercial electronic mail message that includes sexually oriented material and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fail to include in subject heading for the electronic mail message the marks or notices prescribed by the Commission under this subsection; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> fail to provide that the matter in the message that is initially viewable to the recipient, when the message is opened by any recipient and absent any further actions by the recipient, includes only—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to the extent required or authorized pursuant to paragraph (2), any such marks or notices;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the information required to be included in the message pursuant to subsection (a)(5); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> instructions on how to access, or a mechanism to access, the sexually oriented material.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior affirmative consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) does not apply to the transmission of an electronic mail message if the recipient has given prior affirmative consent to receipt of the message.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prescription of marks and notices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2003-12-16">December 16, 2003</date>, the Commission in consultation with the Attorney General shall prescribe clearly identifiable marks or notices to be included in or associated with commercial electronic mail that contains sexually oriented material, in order to inform the recipient of that fact and to facilitate filtering of such electronic mail. The Commission shall publish in the Federal Register and provide notice to the public of the marks or notices prescribed under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “sexually oriented material” means any material that depicts sexually explicit conduct (as that term is defined in <ref>section 2256 of title 18</ref>), unless the depiction constitutes a small and insignificant part of the whole, the remainder of which is not primarily devoted to sexual matters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whoever knowingly violates paragraph (1) shall be fined under title 18, or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 5</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7705.</num>
<heading> Businesses knowingly promoted by electronic mail with false or misleading transmission information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is unlawful for a person to promote, or allow the promotion of, that person’s trade or business, or goods, products, property, or services sold, offered for sale, leased or offered for lease, or otherwise made available through that trade or business, in a commercial electronic mail message the transmission of which is in violation of <ref>section 7704(a)(1) of this title</ref> if that person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knows, or should have known in the ordinary course of that person’s trade or business, that the goods, products, property, or services sold, offered for sale, leased or offered for lease, or otherwise made available through that trade or business were being promoted in such a message;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> received or expected to receive an economic benefit from such promotion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> took no reasonable action—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to prevent the transmission; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to detect the transmission and report it to the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited enforcement against third parties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a person (hereinafter referred to as the “third party”) that provides goods, products, property, or services to another person that violates subsection (a) shall not be held liable for such violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Liability for a violation of subsection (a) shall be imputed to a third party that provides goods, products, property, or services to another person that violates subsection (a) if that third party—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> owns, or has a greater than 50 percent ownership or economic interest in, the trade or business of the person that violated subsection (a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has actual knowledge that goods, products, property, or services are promoted in a commercial electronic mail message the transmission of which is in violation of <ref>section 7704(a)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> receives, or expects to receive, an economic benefit from such promotion.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusive enforcement by FTC</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsections (f) and (g) of <ref>section 7706 of this title</ref> do not apply to violations of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 7706(f)(8) of this title</ref>, nothing in this section may be construed to limit or prevent any action that may be taken under this chapter with respect to any violation of any other section of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 6</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7706.</num>
<heading> Enforcement generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation is unfair or deceptive act or practice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), this chapter shall be enforced by the Commission as if the violation of this chapter were an unfair or deceptive act or practice proscribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement by certain other agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Compliance with this chapter shall be enforced—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> under section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1818</ref>), in the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> national banks, and Federal branches and Federal agencies of foreign banks, by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> member banks of the Federal Reserve System (other than national banks), branches and agencies of foreign banks (other than Federal branches, Federal agencies, and insured State branches of foreign banks), commercial lending companies owned or controlled by foreign banks, organizations operating under section 25 or 25A of the Federal Reserve Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 601</ref> and 611), and bank holding companies, by the Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> banks insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than members of the Federal Reserve System) and insured State branches of foreign banks, by the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> savings associations the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, by the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> under the Federal Credit Union Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.) by the Board of the National Credit Union Administration with respect to any Federally insured credit union;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.) by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to any broker or dealer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> under the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 80a–1</ref> et seq.) by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to investment companies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 80b–1</ref> et seq.) by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to investment advisers registered under that Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> under State insurance law in the case of any person engaged in providing insurance, by the applicable State insurance authority of the State in which the person is domiciled, subject to section 104 of the Gramm-Bliley-Leach Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 6701</ref>), except that in any State in which the State insurance authority elects not to exercise this power, the enforcement authority pursuant to this chapter shall be exercised by the Commission in accordance with subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> under part A of subtitle VII of title 49 by the Secretary of Transportation with respect to any air carrier or foreign air carrier subject to that part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> under the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.) (except as provided in section 406 of that Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 226</ref>, 227)), by the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to any activities subject to that Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> under the Farm Credit Act of 1971 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.) by the Farm Credit Administration with respect to any Federal land bank, Federal land bank association, Federal intermediate credit bank, or production credit association; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> under the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.) by the Federal Communications Commission with respect to any person subject to the provisions of that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exercise of certain powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of the exercise by any agency referred to in subsection (b) of its powers under any Act referred to in that subsection, a violation of this chapter is deemed to be a violation of a Federal Trade Commission trade regulation rule. In addition to its powers under any provision of law specifically referred to in subsection (b), each of the agencies referred to in that subsection may exercise, for the purpose of enforcing compliance with any requirement imposed under this chapter, any other authority conferred on it by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by the Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall prevent any person from violating this chapter in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.) were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter. Any entity that violates any provision of that subtitle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002577">1</ref> is subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, power, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made a part of that subtitle.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002577">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of cease-and-desist orders and injunctive relief without showing of knowledge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, in any proceeding or action pursuant to subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) of this section to enforce compliance, through an order to cease and desist or an injunction, with <ref>section 7704(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 7704(a)(2) of this title</ref>, clause (ii), (iii), or (iv) of <ref>section 7704(a)(4)(A) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 7704(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, or <ref>section 7704(b)(3) of this title</ref>, neither the Commission nor the Federal Communications Commission shall be required to allege or prove the state of mind required by such section or subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement by States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of that State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by any person who violates paragraph (1) or (2) of section 7704(a), who violates section 7704(d), or who engages in a pattern or practice that violates paragraph (3), (4), or (5) of section 7704(a), of this title, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in a district court of the United States of appropriate jurisdiction—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to enjoin further violation of <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> by the defendant; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to obtain damages on behalf of residents of the State, in an amount equal to the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the actual monetary loss suffered by such residents; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount determined under paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of injunctive relief without showing of knowledge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, in a civil action under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State shall not be required to allege or prove the state of mind required by <ref>section 7704(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 7704(a)(2) of this title</ref>, clause (ii), (iii), or (iv) of <ref>section 7704(a)(4)(A) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 7704(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, or <ref>section 7704(b)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory damages</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(ii), the amount determined under this paragraph is the amount calculated by multiplying the number of violations (with each separately addressed unlawful message received by or addressed to such residents treated as a separate violation) by up to $250.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For any violation of <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> (other than <ref>section 7704(a)(1) of this title</ref>), the amount determined under subparagraph (A) may not exceed $2,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggravated damages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The court may increase a damage award to an amount equal to not more than three times the amount otherwise available under this paragraph if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the court determines that the defendant committed the violation willfully and knowingly; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the defendant’s unlawful activity included one or more of the aggravating violations set forth in <ref>section 7704(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction of damages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In assessing damages under subparagraph (A), the court may consider whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the defendant has established and implemented, with due care, commercially reasonable practices and procedures designed to effectively prevent such violations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the violation occurred despite commercially reasonable efforts to maintain compliance the practices and procedures to which reference is made in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any successful action under paragraph (1), the court, in its discretion, may award the costs of the action and reasonable attorney fees to the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of Federal regulators</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The State shall serve prior written notice of any action under paragraph (1) upon the Federal Trade Commission or the appropriate Federal regulator determined under subsection (b) and provide the Commission or appropriate Federal regulator with a copy of its complaint, except in any case in which such prior notice is not feasible, in which case the State shall serve such notice immediately upon instituting such action. The Federal Trade Commission or appropriate Federal regulator shall have the right—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to intervene in the action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to remove the action to the appropriate United States district court; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to file petitions for appeal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of bringing any civil action under paragraph (1), nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prevent an attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of that State to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct investigations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> administer oaths or affirmations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Venue; service of process</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Venue</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any action brought under paragraph (1) may be brought in the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under <ref>section 1391 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service of process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In an action brought under paragraph (1), process may be served in any district in which the defendant—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is an inhabitant; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> maintains a physical place of business.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Commission, or other appropriate Federal agency under subsection (b), has instituted a civil action or an administrative action for violation of this chapter, no State attorney general, or official or agency of a State, may bring an action under this subsection during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission or the other agency for any violation of this chapter alleged in the complaint.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requisite scienter for certain civil actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in <ref>section 7704(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 7704(a)(2) of this title</ref>, clause (ii), (iii), or (iv) of <ref>section 7704(a)(4)(A) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 7704(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, or <ref>section 7704(b)(3) of this title</ref>, in a civil action brought by a State attorney general, or an official or agency of a State, to recover monetary damages for a violation of this chapter, the court shall not grant the relief sought unless the attorney general, official, or agency establishes that the defendant acted with actual knowledge, or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances, of the act or omission that constitutes the violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by provider of Internet access service</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action authorized</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A provider of Internet access service adversely affected by a violation of section 7704(a)(1), (b), or (d) of this title, or a pattern or practice that violates paragraph (2), (3), (4), or (5) of <ref>section 7704(a) of this title</ref>, may bring a civil action in any district court of the United States with jurisdiction over the defendant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to enjoin further violation by the defendant; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to recover damages in an amount equal to the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> actual monetary loss incurred by the provider of Internet access service as a result of such violation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount determined under paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special definition of “procure”</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any action brought under paragraph (1), this chapter shall be applied as if the definition of the term “procure” in <ref>section 7702(12) of this title</ref> contained, after “behalf” the words “with actual knowledge, or by consciously avoiding knowing, whether such person is engaging, or will engage, in a pattern or practice that violates this chapter”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory damages</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(ii), the amount determined under this paragraph is the amount calculated by multiplying the number of violations (with each separately addressed unlawful message that is transmitted or attempted to be transmitted over the facilities of the provider of Internet access service, or that is transmitted or attempted to be transmitted to an electronic mail address obtained from the provider of Internet access service in violation of <ref>section 7704(b)(1)(A)(i) of this title</ref>, treated as a separate violation) by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> up to $100, in the case of a violation of <ref>section 7704(a)(1) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> up to $25, in the case of any other violation of <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For any violation of <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> (other than <ref>section 7704(a)(1) of this title</ref>), the amount determined under subparagraph (A) may not exceed $1,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggravated damages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The court may increase a damage award to an amount equal to not more than three times the amount otherwise available under this paragraph if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the court determines that the defendant committed the violation willfully and knowingly; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the defendant’s unlawful activity included one or more of the aggravated violations set forth in <ref>section 7704(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction of damages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In assessing damages under subparagraph (A), the court may consider whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the defendant has established and implemented, with due care, commercially reasonable practices and procedures designed to effectively prevent such violations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the violation occurred despite commercially reasonable efforts to maintain compliance with the practices and procedures to which reference is made in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any action brought pursuant to paragraph (1), the court may, in its discretion, require an undertaking for the payment of the costs of such action, and assess reasonable costs, including reasonable attorneys’ fees, against any party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 7</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7707.</num>
<heading> Effect on other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to impair the enforcement of section 223 or 231 of title 47, chapter 71 (relating to obscenity) or 110 (relating to sexual exploitation of children) of title 18, or any other Federal criminal statute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect in any way the Commission’s authority to bring enforcement actions under FTC Act for materially false or deceptive representations or unfair practices in commercial electronic mail messages.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This chapter supersedes any statute, regulation, or rule of a State or political subdivision of a State that expressly regulates the use of electronic mail to send commercial messages, except to the extent that any such statute, regulation, or rule prohibits falsity or deception in any portion of a commercial electronic mail message or information attached thereto.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State law not specific to electronic mail</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This chapter shall not be construed to preempt the applicability of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State laws that are not specific to electronic mail, including State trespass, contract, or tort law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other State laws to the extent that those laws relate to acts of fraud or computer crime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on policies of providers of Internet access service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to have any effect on the lawfulness or unlawfulness, under any other provision of law, of the adoption, implementation, or enforcement by a provider of Internet access service of a policy of declining to transmit, route, relay, handle, or store certain types of electronic mail messages.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 8</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7708.</num>
<heading> Do-Not-E-Mail registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2003-12-16">December 16, 2003</date>, the Commission shall transmit to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Energy and Commerce a report that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sets forth a plan and timetable for establishing a nationwide marketing Do-Not-E-Mail registry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes an explanation of any practical, technical, security, privacy, enforceability, or other concerns that the Commission has regarding such a registry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> includes an explanation of how the registry would be applied with respect to children with e-mail accounts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to implement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may establish and implement the plan, but not earlier than 9 months after <date date="2003-12-16">December 16, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 9</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7709.</num>
<heading> Study of effects of commercial electronic mail</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 24 months after <date date="2003-12-16">December 16, 2003</date>, the Commission, in consultation with the Department of Justice and other appropriate agencies, shall submit a report to the Congress that provides a detailed analysis of the effectiveness and enforcement of the provisions of this chapter and the need (if any) for the Congress to modify such provisions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required analysis</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall include in the report required by subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of the extent to which technological and marketplace developments, including changes in the nature of the devices through which consumers access their electronic mail messages, may affect the practicality and effectiveness of the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> analysis and recommendations concerning how to address commercial electronic mail that originates in or is transmitted through or to facilities or computers in other nations, including initiatives or policy positions that the Federal Government could pursue through international negotiations, fora, organizations, or institutions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> analysis and recommendations concerning options for protecting consumers, including children, from the receipt and viewing of commercial electronic mail that is obscene or pornographic.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 10</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7710.</num>
<heading> Improving enforcement by providing rewards for information about violations; labeling</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall transmit to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Energy and Commerce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a report, within 9 months after <date date="2003-12-16">December 16, 2003</date>, that sets forth a system for rewarding those who supply information about violations of this chapter, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> procedures for the Commission to grant a reward of not less than 20 percent of the total civil penalty collected for a violation of this chapter to the first person that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identifies the person in violation of this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> supplies information that leads to the successful collection of a civil penalty by the Commission; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> procedures to minimize the burden of submitting a complaint to the Commission concerning violations of this chapter, including procedures to allow the electronic submission of complaints to the Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a report, within 18 months after <date date="2003-12-16">December 16, 2003</date>, that sets forth a plan for requiring commercial electronic mail to be identifiable from its subject line, by means of compliance with Internet Engineering Task Force Standards, the use of the characters “ADV” in the subject line, or other comparable identifier, or an explanation of any concerns the Commission has that cause the Commission to recommend against the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 11</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7711.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may issue regulations to implement the provisions of this Act (not including the amendments made by sections 4 and 12). Any such regulations shall be issued in accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) may not be construed to authorize the Commission to establish a requirement pursuant to <ref>section 7704(a)(5)(A) of this title</ref> to include any specific words, characters, marks, or labels in a commercial electronic mail message, or to include the identification required by <ref>section 7704(a)(5)(A) of this title</ref> in any particular part of such a mail message (such as the subject line or body).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 13</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7712.</num>
<heading> Application to wireless</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be interpreted to preclude or override the applicability of <ref>section 227 of title 47</ref> or the rules prescribed under <ref>section 6102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FCC rulemaking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Federal Communications Commission, in consultation with the Federal Trade Commission, shall promulgate rules within 270 days to protect consumers from unwanted mobile service commercial messages. The Federal Communications Commission, in promulgating the rules, shall, to the extent consistent with subsection (c)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide subscribers to commercial mobile services the ability to avoid receiving mobile service commercial messages unless the subscriber has provided express prior authorization to the sender, except as provided in paragraph (3);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> allow recipients of mobile service commercial messages to indicate electronically a desire not to receive future mobile service commercial messages from the sender;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> take into consideration, in determining whether to subject providers of commercial mobile services to paragraph (1), the relationship that exists between providers of such services and their subscribers, but if the Commission determines that such providers should not be subject to paragraph (1), the rules shall require such providers, in addition to complying with the other provisions of this chapter, to allow subscribers to indicate a desire not to receive future mobile service commercial messages from the provider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the time of subscribing to such service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any billing mechanism; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> determine how a sender of mobile service commercial messages may comply with the provisions of this chapter, considering the unique technical aspects, including the functional and character limitations, of devices that receive such messages.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other factors considered</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Communications Commission shall consider the ability of a sender of a commercial electronic mail message to reasonably determine that the message is a mobile service commercial message.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mobile service commercial message defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “mobile service commercial message” means a commercial electronic mail message that is transmitted directly to a wireless device that is utilized by a subscriber of commercial mobile service (as such term is defined in <ref>section 332(d) of title 47</ref>) in connection with such service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 14</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7713.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this chapter and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–187, § 15</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>