<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 77—</num>
<heading>STEEL AND ALUMINUM ENERGY CONSERVATION AND TECHNOLOGY COMPETITIVENESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5101.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintaining viable domestic steel, aluminum, copper, and other metals industries is vital to the national security and economic well being of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the promotion of technology competitiveness and energy conservation in the American steel and aluminum industries by the Federal Government through a program of joint research and development will help maintain viable domestic steel and aluminum industries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increase the energy efficiency and enhance the competitiveness of American steel, aluminum, and copper industries by providing Federal incentives for the establishment of public-private sector research and development partnerships to undertake scientific research and development to develop advanced technologies utilizing the expertise of the steel, aluminum, copper, and other metals industries, Government-owned laboratories of the Department of Energy and the National Institute of Standards and Technology, universities, State development agencies, and others; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> continue steel research and development initiative efforts begun under title II of the Interior and Related Agencies portion of the joint resolution entitled “Joint Resolution making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1986, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1985-12-19">December 19, 1985</date> (<ref>Public Law 99–190</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “domestic company” means a company which is substantially involved in the United States domestic production, processing, or use of steel, aluminum, copper, or other metals and has a substantial percentage of its operations located within the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the terms “management plan” and “plan” mean the Steel Initiative Management Plan issued on <date date="1987-04-01">April 1, 1987</date>, by the Department of Energy, which establishes the management framework for the steel research and development initiative, and updates to that plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “research plan” means the Steel Initiative Research Plan issued in April 1988 by the Department of Energy, and updates to that plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5103.</num>
<heading> Establishment of scientific research and development program to develop competitive manufacturing technologies and increase energy efficiency in steel and aluminum industries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, pursuant to the authority provided under provisions of the Federal Nonnuclear Research and Development Act of 1974 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5901</ref>, et seq.), shall reestablish an industrial energy conservation and competitive technology program to conduct scientific research and development of steel and aluminum technologies to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Such program shall provide the financial and technical assistance and other incentives which, in the judgment of the Secretary, are necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 6 months after <date date="1988-11-17">November 17, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall publish an update of the management plan to expand the steel research and development initiative to include aluminum and to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The Secretary, from time to time, may further update the management plan. The management plan shall be subject to the following conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For newly initiated research and development proposals submitted under the revised management plan, the non-Federal financial share shall equal at least 30 percent of the total cost of any project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Existing facilities, equipment, supplies, and other property may be included in the non-Federal share under this section only when they are directly relevant to the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The knowledge resulting from research and development activities conducted under this chapter shall be developed for the benefit of the domestic companies who provide financial resources to the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary, for a period of up to 5 years after the development of information that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> results from research and development activities conducted under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would be a trade secret or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential, as described in <ref>section 5104(a) of this title</ref>, if the information had been obtained from a domestic company,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">may provide appropriate protections against the dissemination of such information, including exemption from subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The plan shall assure basic research support, for the research carried out under the research plan, from independent laboratories, universities, and nonprofit organizations, by coordinating activities under the research plan with the basic research efforts of the Department of Energy, such as the Energy Conversion and Utilization Technologies Program and the Materials Processing and Sensor and Controls programs within the Office of Industrial Technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 6 months after <date date="1988-11-17">November 17, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall publish an update of the research plan. In reviewing research and development activities for possible inclusion in the research plan, the Secretary shall consider the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Steel projects</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The direct production of liquid steel from domestic materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The production of near-net shape forms from liquid, powder, or solid steel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The development of universal grades of steel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The application of automatic processing technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The removal of residual elements from steel scrap.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The treatment and storage of waste materials and other byproducts from steel production and processing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The development of super-plastic steel processing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The development of advanced sheet and bar steels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The development of technologies and equipment related to the production of steel that enhance the protection of the environment and the safety and health of workers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Other steel technologies which, in the judgment of the Secretary, further the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The development of technologies which reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aluminum and other projects</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The production of aluminum.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The application of automatic processing technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The treatment and storage of waste materials and other byproducts from aluminum production and processing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The manufacture of aluminum mill products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Aluminum recycling technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The development of technologies and equipment related to the production of aluminum that enhance the protection of the environment and the safety and health of workers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Aluminum, copper, and other metals technologies which, in the judgment of the Secretary, further the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Industry participation and review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall arrange for participation and review by representatives of each affected industry and by labor in the updating of the management and research plans and in the evaluation of the progress of research and development activities for their industry conducted under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4074</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XXI, § 2106(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3070</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VI, § 602(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5104.</num>
<heading> Protection of proprietary rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proprietary rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential, under the meaning of <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> which is obtained from a domestic company shall be disclosed in the conduct of the management plan or research plan, or as a result of activities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Patent rights vested in United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All patent rights from inventions developed under the management plan or the research plan implemented pursuant to this chapter shall be vested in accordance with <ref>section 5908 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4075</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5105.</num>
<heading> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate the research and development conducted under this chapter with other research and development being conducted by the Department of Energy and other Federal agencies in order to increase efficiency and avoid duplication of effort.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4076</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5106.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VI, § 602(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 853</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5107.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare and submit annually to the President and the Congress at the close of each fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2008, a complete report of the research and development activities carried out under this chapter during the fiscal year involved, including the actual and anticipated obligation of funds, for such activities, together with such recommendations as the Secretary may consider appropriate for further legislative, administrative, and other actions, including actions by the American steel, aluminum, copper, and other metals industries, which should be taken in order to achieve the purposes of this chapter. The report submitted at the close of fiscal year 1991 shall also contain a complete summary of activities under the management plan and the research plan from the first year of their operation, along with an analysis of the extent to which they have succeeded in accomplishing the purposes of this chapter. The reports submitted at the close of fiscal years 1993, 1995, and 1997 shall also contain a complete summary of activities under the management plan and the research plan from the first year of their operation, along with an analysis of the extent to which they have succeeded in accomplishing the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 8</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4076</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XXI, § 2106(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3070</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VI, § 602(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5108.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this chapter $12,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2012.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 9</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4076</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XXI, § 2106(a)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3070</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5109.</num>
<heading> Relation of existing program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Proposals received by the Department of Energy before <date date="1988-11-17">November 17, 1988</date>, may be carried out without regard to changes in the management plan and research plan required by this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 10</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4076</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5110.</num>
<heading> Drug-free workplace</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States receiving funds authorized to be appropriated under this chapter for fiscal year 1989, fiscal year 1990, fiscal year 1991, fiscal year 1992, fiscal year 1993, fiscal year 1994, fiscal year 1995, fiscal year 1996, and fiscal year 1997, or under any other Act authorizing appropriations for fiscal year 1989, fiscal year 1990, fiscal year 1991, fiscal year 1992, fiscal year 1993, fiscal year 1994, fiscal year 1995, fiscal year 1996, and fiscal year 1997, shall obligate or spend any such funds, unless such department, agency, or instrumentality has in place, and will continue to administer in good faith, a written policy designed to ensure that all of its work places are free from the illegal use, possession, or distribution of controlled substances (as defined in the Controlled Substances Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.]) by the officers and employees of such department, agency, or instrumentality.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No funds so authorized to be appropriated to any such department, agency, or instrumentality shall be available for payment in connection with any grant, contract, or other agreement, unless the recipient of such grant, contract, or party to such agreement, as the case may be, has in place and will continue to administer in good faith a written policy, adopted by such recipient, contractor, or party’s board of directors or other governing authority, satisfactory to the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality making such payment, designed to ensure that all of the workplace of such recipient, contractor, or party are free from the illegal use, possession, or distribution of controlled substances (as defined in the Controlled Substances Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.]) by the officers and employees of such recipient, contractor, or party.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–680, § 11</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4077</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XXI, § 2106(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3070</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>