<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 56A—</num>
<heading>GLOBAL CHANGE RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2921.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Committee” means the Committee on Earth and Environmental Sciences established under <ref>section 2932 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Council” means the Federal Coordinating Council on Science, Engineering, and Technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “global change” means changes in the global environment (including alterations in climate, land productivity, oceans or other water resources, atmospheric chemistry, and ecological systems) that may alter the capacity of the Earth to sustain life;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “global change research” means study, monitoring, assessment, prediction, and information management activities to describe and understand—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the interactive physical, chemical, and biological processes that regulate the total Earth system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the unique environment that the Earth provides for life;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> changes that are occurring in the Earth system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the manner in which such system, environment, and changes are influenced by human actions;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “Plan” means the National Global Change Research Plan developed under <ref>section 2934 of this title</ref>, or any revision thereof; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “Program” means the United States Global Change Research Program established under <ref>section 2933 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES GLOBAL CHANGE RESEARCH PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2931.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Industrial, agricultural, and other human activities, coupled with an expanding world population, are contributing to processes of global change that may significantly alter the Earth habitat within a few human generations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such human-induced changes, in conjunction with natural fluctuations, may lead to significant global warming and thus alter world climate patterns and increase global sea levels. Over the next century, these consequences could adversely affect world agricultural and marine production, coastal habitability, biological diversity, human health, and global economic and social well-being.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The release of chlorofluorocarbons and other stratospheric ozone-depleting substances is rapidly reducing the ability of the atmosphere to screen out harmful ultraviolet radiation, which could adversely affect human health and ecological systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Development of effective policies to abate, mitigate, and cope with global change will rely on greatly improved scientific understanding of global environmental processes and on our ability to distinguish human-induced from natural global change.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> New developments in interdisciplinary Earth sciences, global observing systems, and computing technology make possible significant advances in the scientific understanding and prediction of these global changes and their effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Although significant Federal global change research efforts are underway, an effective Federal research program will require efficient interagency coordination, and coordination with the research activities of State, private, and international entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to provide for development and coordination of a comprehensive and integrated United States research program which will assist the Nation and the world to understand, assess, predict, and respond to human-induced and natural processes of global change.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2932.</num>
<heading> Committee on Earth and Environmental Sciences</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, through the Council, shall establish a Committee on Earth and Environmental Sciences. The Committee shall carry out Council functions under <ref>section 6651 of title 42</ref> relating to global change research, for the purpose of increasing the overall effectiveness and productivity of Federal global change research efforts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee shall consist of at least one representative from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the National Science Foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of the Department of Commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Environmental Protection Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Department of Energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Department of State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Department of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Department of Transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the Office of Management and Budget;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the Council on Environmental Quality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences of the National Institutes of Health; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> such other agencies and departments of the United States as the President or the Chairman of the Council considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such representatives shall be high ranking officials of their agency or department, wherever possible the head of the portion of that agency or department that is most revelant <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002471">1</ref> to the purpose of the subchapter described in <ref>section 2931(b) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman of the Council, in consultation with the Committee, biennially shall select one of the Committee members to serve as Chairperson. The Chairperson shall be knowledgeable and experienced with regard to the administration of scientific research programs, and shall be a representative of an agency that contributes substantially, in terms of scientific research capability and budget, to the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An Executive Secretary shall be appointed by the Chairperson of the Committee, with the approval of the Committee. The Executive Secretary shall be a permanent employee of one of the agencies or departments represented on the Committee, and shall remain in the employ of such agency or department. The Chairman of the Council shall have the authority to make personnel decisions regarding any employees detailed to the Council for purposes of working on business of the Committee pursuant to <ref>section 6651 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions relative to global change</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council, through the Committee, shall be responsible for planning and coordinating the Program. In carrying out this responsibility, the Committee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the forum for developing the Plan and for overseeing its implementation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improve cooperation among Federal agencies and departments with respect to global change research activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide budgetary advice as specified in <ref>section 2935 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> work with academic, State, industry, and other groups conducting global change research, to provide for periodic public and peer review of the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> cooperate with the Secretary of State in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing representation at international meetings and conferences on global change research in which the United States participates; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinating the Federal activities of the United States with programs of other nations and with international global change research activities such as the International Geosphere-Biosphere Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> consult with actual and potential users of the results of the Program to ensure that such results are useful in developing national and international policy responses to global change; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> report at least annually to the President and the Congress, through the Chairman of the Council, on Federal global change research priorities, policies, and programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2933.</num>
<heading> United States Global Change Research Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish an interagency United States Global Change Research Program to improve understanding of global change. The Program shall be implemented by the Plan developed under <ref>section 2934 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2934.</num>
<heading> National Global Change Research Plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman of the Council, through the Committee, shall develop a National Global Change Research Plan for implementation of the Program. The Plan shall contain recommendations for national global change research. The Chairman of the Council shall submit the Plan to the Congress within one year after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, and a revised Plan shall be submitted at least once every three years thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of Plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Plan shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish, for the 10-year period beginning in the year the Plan is submitted, the goals and priorities for Federal global change research which most effectively advance scientific understanding of global change and provide usable information on which to base policy decisions relating to global change;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describe specific activities, including research activities, data collection and data analysis requirements, predictive modeling, participation in international research efforts, and information management, required to achieve such goals and priorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify and address, as appropriate, relevant programs and activities of the Federal agencies and departments represented on the Committee that contribute to the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> set forth the role of each Federal agency and department in implementing the Plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consider and utilize, as appropriate, reports and studies conducted by Federal agencies and departments, the National Research Council, or other entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> make recommendations for the coordination of the global change research activities of the United States with such activities of other nations and international organizations, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the extent and nature of necessary international cooperation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the development by the Committee, in consultation when appropriate with the National Space Council, of proposals for cooperation on major capital projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> bilateral and multilateral proposals for improving worldwide access to scientific data and information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> methods for improving participation in international global change research by developing nations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> estimate, to the extent practicable, Federal funding for global change research activities to be conducted under the Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Plan shall provide for, but not be limited to, the following research elements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Global measurements, establishing worldwide observations necessary to understand the physical, chemical, and biological processes responsible for changes in the Earth system on all relevant spatial and time scales.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Documentation of global change, including the development of mechanisms for recording changes that will actually occur in the Earth system over the coming decades.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Studies of earlier changes in the Earth system, using evidence from the geological and fossil record.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Predictions, using quantitative models of the Earth system to identify and simulate global environmental processes and trends, and the regional implications of such processes and trends.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Focused research initiatives to understand the nature of and interaction among physical, chemical, biological, and social processes related to global change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Plan shall provide recommendations for collaboration within the Federal Government and among nations to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish, develop, and maintain information bases, including necessary management systems which will promote consistent, efficient, and compatible transfer and use of data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> create globally accessible formats for data collected by various international sources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> combine and interpret data from various sources to produce information readily usable by policymakers attempting to formulate effective strategies for preventing, mitigating, and adapting to the effects of global change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Research Council evaluation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chairman of the Council shall enter into an agreement with the National Research Council under which the National Research Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluate the scientific content of the Plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide information and advice obtained from United States and international sources, and recommended priorities for future global change research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing the Plan, the Committee shall consult with academic, State, industry, and environmental groups and representatives. Not later than 90 days before the Chairman of the Council submits the Plan, or any revision thereof, to the Congress, a summary of the proposed Plan shall be published in the Federal Register for a public comment period of not less than 60 days.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3099</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2935.</num>
<heading> Budget coordination</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committee guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee shall each year provide general guidance to each Federal agency or department participating in the Program with respect to the preparation of requests for appropriations for activities related to the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of reports with agency appropriations requests</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Working in conjunction with the Committee, each Federal agency or department involved in global change research shall include with its annual request for appropriations submitted to the President under <ref>section 1108 of title 31</ref> a report which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identifies each element of the proposed global change research activities of the agency or department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specifies whether each element (i) contributes directly to the Program or (ii) contributes indirectly but in important ways to the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> states the portion of its request for appropriations allocated to each element of the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each agency or department that submits a report under paragraph (1) shall submit such report simultaneously to the Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration in President’s budget</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President shall, in a timely fashion, provide the Committee with an opportunity to review and comment on the budget estimate of each agency and department involved in global change research in the context of the Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President shall identify in each annual budget submitted to the Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> those items in each agency’s or department’s annual budget which are elements of the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2936.</num>
<heading> Scientific assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On a periodic basis (not less frequently than every 4 years), the Council, through the Committee, shall prepare and submit to the President and the Congress an assessment which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> integrates, evaluates, and interprets the findings of the Program and discusses the scientific uncertainties associated with such findings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> analyzes the effects of global change on the natural environment, agriculture, energy production and use, land and water resources, transportation, human health and welfare, human social systems, and biological diversity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> analyzes current trends in global change, both human-inducted <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002472">1</ref> and natural, and projects major trends for the subsequent 25 to 100 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2937.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2938.</num>
<heading> Relation to other authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Climate Program research activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, the Chairman of the Council, and the Secretary of Commerce shall ensure that relevant research activities of the National Climate Program, established by the National Climate Program Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2901</ref> et seq.), are considered in developing national global change research efforts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of research findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President, the Chairman of the Council, and the heads of the agencies and departments represented on the Committee, shall ensure that the research findings of the Committee, and of Federal agencies and departments, are available to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Environmental Protection Agency for use in the formulation of a coordinated national policy on global climate change pursuant to section 1103 of the Global Climate Protection Act of 1987 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2901</ref> note); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all Federal agencies and departments for use in the formulation of coordinated national policies for responding to human-induced and natural processes of global change pursuant to other statutory responsibilities and obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on Federal response actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed, interpreted, or applied to preclude or delay the planning or implementation of any Federal action designed, in whole or in part, to address the threats of stratospheric ozone depletion or global climate change.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION IN GLOBAL CHANGE RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2951.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Pooling of international resources and scientific capabilities will be essential to a successful international global change program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> While international scientific planning is already underway, there is currently no comprehensive intergovernmental mechanism for planning, coordinating, or implementing research to understand global change and to mitigate possible adverse effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An international global change research program will be important in building future consensus on methods for reducing global environmental degradation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The United States, as a world leader in environmental and Earth sciences, should help provide leadership in developing and implementing an international global change research program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote international, intergovernmental cooperation on global change research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> involve scientists and policymakers from developing nations in such cooperative global change research programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote international efforts to provide technical and other assistance to developing nations which will facilitate improvements in their domestic standard of living while minimizing damage to the global or regional environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2952.</num>
<heading> International discussions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Global change research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President should direct the Secretary of State, in cooperation with the Committee, to initiate discussions with other nations leading toward international protocols and other agreements to coordinate global change research activities. Such discussions should include the following issues:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Allocation of costs in global change research programs, especially with respect to major capital projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Coordination of global change research plans with those developed by international organizations such as the International Council on Scientific Unions, the World Meteorological Organization, and the United Nations Environment Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Establishment of global change research centers and training programs for scientists, especially those from developing nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Development of innovative methods for management of international global change research, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use of new or existing intergovernmental organizations for the coordination or funding of global change research; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> creation of a limited foundation for global change research.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The prompt establishment of international projects to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> create globally accessible formats for data collected by various international sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> combine and interpret data from various sources to produce information readily usable by policymakers attempting to formulate effective strategies for preventing, mitigating, and adapting to possible adverse effects of global change.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Establishment of international offices to disseminate information useful in identifying, preventing, mitigating, or adapting to the possible effects of global change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President should direct the Secretary of State (in cooperation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, the United States Trade Representative, and other appropriate members of the Committee) to initiate discussions with other nations leading toward an international research protocol for cooperation on the development of energy technologies which have minimally adverse effects on the environment. Such discussions should include, but not be limited to, the following issues:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Creation of an international cooperative program to fund research related to energy efficiency, solar and other renewable energy sources, and passively safe and diversion-resistant nuclear reactors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Creation of an international cooperative program to develop low cost energy technologies which are appropriate to the environmental, economic, and social needs of developing nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Exchange of information concerning environmentally safe energy technologies and practices, including those described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2953.</num>
<heading> Global Change Research Information Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not more than 180 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the President shall, in consultation with the Committee and all relevant Federal agencies, establish an Office of Global Change Research Information. The purpose of the Office shall be to disseminate to foreign governments, businesses, and institutions, as well as the citizens of foreign countries, scientific research information available in the United States which would be useful in preventing, mitigating, or adapting to the effects of global change. Such information shall include, but need not be limited to, results of scientific research and development on technologies useful for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reducing energy consumption through conservation and energy efficiency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promoting the use of solar and renewable energy sources which reduce the amount of greenhouse gases released into the atmosphere;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> developing replacements for chlorofluorocarbons, halons, and other ozone-depleting substances which exhibit a significantly reduced potential for depleting stratospheric ozone;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> promoting the conservation of forest resources which help reduce the amount of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> assisting developing countries in ecological pest management practices and in the proper use of agricultural, and industrial chemicals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> promoting recycling and source reduction of pollutants in order to reduce the volume of waste which must be disposed of, thus decreasing energy use and greenhouse gas emissions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>GROWTH DECISION AID</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2961.</num>
<heading> Study and decision aid</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study of consequences of community growth and development; decision aid to assist State and local authorities in managing development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall conduct a study of the implications and potential consequences of growth and development on urban, suburban, and rural communities. Based upon the findings of the study, the Secretary shall produce a decision aid to assist State and local authorities in planning and managing urban, suburban, and rural growth and development while preserving community character.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with appropriate Federal departments and agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall consult with other appropriate Federal departments and agencies as necessary in carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Congress a report containing the decision aid produced under subsection (a) no later than <date date="1992-01-30">January 30, 1992</date>. The Secretary shall notify appropriate State and local authorities that such decision aid is available on request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–606, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3104</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>