<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 26—</num>
<heading>HOUSEHOLD REFRIGERATORS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1211.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against transportation of refrigerators without safety devices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to introduce or deliver for introduction into interstate commerce any household refrigerator manufactured on or after the date this section takes effect unless it is equipped with a device, enabling the door thereof to be opened from the inside, which conforms with standards prescribed pursuant to <ref>section 1213 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1956, ch. 890, § 1</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1212.</num>
<heading> Violations; misdemeanor; penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who violates <ref>section 1211 of this title</ref> shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall, upon conviction thereof, be subject to imprisonment for not more than one year, or a fine of not more than $1,000, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1956, ch. 890, § 2</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1213.</num>
<heading> Publication of safety standards in Federal Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Consumer Product Safety Commission shall prescribe and publish in the Federal Register commercial standards for devices which, when used in or on household refrigerators, will enable the doors thereof to be opened easily from the inside; and the standards first established under this section shall be so prescribed and published not later than one year after <date date="1956-08-02">August 2, 1956</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1956, ch. 890, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–573, § 30(c)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1231</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1214.</num>
<heading> “Interstate commerce” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “interstate commerce” includes commerce between one State, Territory, possession, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and another State, Territory, possession, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1956, ch. 890, § 4</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>