<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 122—</num>
<heading>TRAVEL AND TOURISM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9801.</num>
<heading> Defined term</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this title,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002665">1</ref> the term “COVID–19 public health emergency”—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> means the public health emergency first declared on <date date="2020-01-31">January 31, 2020</date>, by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under <ref>section 247d of title 42</ref> with respect to COVID–19; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes any renewal of such declaration pursuant to such <ref>section 247d of title 42</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title VI, § 600</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9802.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subtitle are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support the travel and tourism industry, which produces economic impacts that are vital to our national economy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to establish national goals for international visitors to the United States, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> recommendations for achieving such goals and timelines for implementing such recommendations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordination between Federal and State agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the resources needed by each Government agency to achieve such goals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of international visitors and the value of national travel exports.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9803.</num>
<heading> Responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visitation goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism (referred to in this section as the “Assistant Secretary”) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> after consultation with the travel and tourism industry, work with the Travel Promotion Committee and the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board to establish an annual goal, consistent with the goals of the travel and tourism strategy developed pursuant to <ref>section 9804(1) of this title</ref>, for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of international visitors to the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the value of travel and tourism commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop recommendations for achieving the annual goals established pursuant to paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that travel and tourism policy is developed in consultation with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Tourism Policy Council;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Homeland Security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Corporation for Travel Promotion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> travel and tourism industry representatives, including public and private destination marketing organizations, travel and tourism suppliers, gig economy representatives, and labor representatives from these industries;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish short, medium, and long-term timelines for implementing the recommendations developed pursuant to paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> conduct Federal agency needs assessments, in consultation with the Office of Management and Budget and other relevant Federal agencies, to identify the resources, statutory or regulatory changes, and private sector engagement needed to achieve the annual visitation goals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> provide assessments and recommendations to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the public through a publicly accessible website.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic travel and tourism</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary, to the extent feasible, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluate, on an ongoing basis, domestic policy options for supporting competitiveness with respect to the strengths, weaknesses, and growth of the domestic travel industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop recommendations and goals to support and enhance domestic tourism, separated by business and leisure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> engage public and private stakeholders to support domestic tourism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Workforce</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with the Secretary of Labor to develop strategies and best practices for improving the timeliness and reliability of travel and tourism workforce data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> work with the Secretary of Labor and the Bureau of Economic Analysis to improve travel and tourism industry data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide recommendations for policy enhancements and efficiencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide policy recommendations regarding the gig economy as it relates to travel and tourism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Facilitation of international business travel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary, in coordination with relevant Federal agencies, shall strive to increase and facilitate international business travel to the United States and ensure competitiveness by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> facilitating large meetings, incentives, conferences, and exhibitions in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> emphasizing rural and other destinations in the United States that are rich in cultural heritage or ecological tourism, among other uniquely American destinations, as locations for hosting international meetings, incentives, conferences, and exhibitions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitating sports and recreation events and activities in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery strategies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after amounts are appropriated to the Department of Commerce to accomplish the purposes of this section, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the entities referred to in subsection (a)(3), shall develop recovery strategies for the travel and tourism industry in response to the economic impacts of the COVID–19 pandemic and in anticipation of other unpredictable catastrophic events that would significantly affect the travel and tourism industry, such as hurricanes, floods, tsunamis, tornadoes, wildfires, terrorist attacks, and pandemics.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-benefit analysis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In developing the recovery strategies under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary shall conduct cost-benefit analyses that take into account the health and economic effects of public health mitigation measures on the travel and tourism industry.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistant Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Assistant Secretary, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall produce an annual forecasting report on the travel and tourism industry, which shall include current and anticipated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> domestic employment needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> international inbound volume and spending, taking into account the lasting effects of the COVID–19 public health emergency and the impact of the recovery strategy implemented pursuant to subsection (e)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> domestic volume and spending, including Federal and State public land travel and tourism data.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bureau of Economic Analysis</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director of the Bureau of Economic Analysis, subject to the availability of appropriations and to the extent feasible, should make quarterly updates to the Travel and Tourism Satellite Accounts, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State-level travel and tourism spending data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> travel and tourism workforce data for full-time and part-time employment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Federal and State public lands outdoor recreational activity and tourism spending data.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Travel and Tourism Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director of the National Travel and Tourism Office—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in partnership with the Bureau of Economic Analysis and other relevant Federal agencies, shall provide a monthly report on international arrival and spending data to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Travel and Tourism Advisory Board; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the public through a publicly accessible website; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall include questions in the Survey of International Air Travelers regarding wait-times, visits to public lands, and State data, to the extent applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9804.</num>
<heading> Travel and tourism strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board, the Tourism Policy Council, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall develop and submit to Congress a 10-year travel and tourism strategy, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the establishment of goals with respect to the number of annual international visitors to the United States and the annual amount of travel and tourism commerce in the United States during such 10-year period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the resources needed to achieve the goals established pursuant to paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recommendations for statutory or regulatory changes that would be necessary to achieve such goals.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9805.</num>
<heading> Data on domestic travel and tourism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall collect and make public aggregate data on domestic travel and tourism trends.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. BB, title VI, § 608</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>