<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32—</num>
<heading>TELECASTING OF PROFESSIONAL SPORTS CONTESTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1291.</num>
<heading> Exemption from antitrust laws of agreements covering the telecasting of sports contests and the combining of professional football leagues</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The antitrust laws, as defined in <ref>section 1 of the Act of October 15, 1914</ref>, as amended (<ref>38 Stat. 730</ref>) [<ref>15 U.S.C. 12</ref>], or in the Federal Trade Commission Act, as amended (<ref>38 Stat. 717</ref>) [<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.], shall not apply to any joint agreement by or among persons engaging in or conducting the organized professional team sports of football, baseball, basketball, or hockey, by which any league of clubs participating in professional football, baseball, basketball, or hockey contests sells or otherwise transfers all or any part of the rights of such league’s member clubs in the sponsored telecasting of the games of football, baseball, basketball, or hockey, as the case may be, engaged in or conducted by such clubs. In addition, such laws shall not apply to a joint agreement by which the member clubs of two or more professional football leagues, which are exempt from income tax under section 501(c)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref>26 U.S.C. 501(c)(6)</ref>], combine their operations in expanded single league so exempt from income tax, if such agreement increases rather than decreases the number of professional football clubs so operating, and the provisions of which are directly relevant thereto.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–331, § 1</ref>, <date date="1961-09-30">Sept. 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–800, § 6(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-08">Nov. 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1515</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1292.</num>
<heading> Area telecasting restriction limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1291 of this title</ref> shall not apply to any joint agreement described in the first sentence in such section which prohibits any person to whom such rights are sold or transferred from televising any games within any area, except within the home territory of a member club of the league on a day when such club is playing a game at home.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–331, § 2</ref>, <date date="1961-09-30">Sept. 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–800, § 6(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-08">Nov. 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1515</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1293.</num>
<heading> Intercollegiate and interscholastic football contest limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The first sentence of <ref>section 1291 of this title</ref> shall not apply to any joint agreement described in such section which permits the telecasting of all or a substantial part of any professional football game on any Friday after six o’clock postmeridian or on any Saturday during the period beginning on the second Friday in September and ending on the second Saturday in December in any year from any telecasting station located within seventy-five miles of the game site of any intercollegiate or interscholastic football contest scheduled to be played on such a date if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such intercollegiate football contest is between institutions of higher learning both of which confer degrees upon students following completion of sufficient credit hours to equal a four-year course, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an interscholastic football contest, such contest is between secondary schools, both of which are accredited or certified under the laws of the State or States in which they are situated and offer courses continuing through the twelfth grade of the standard school curriculum, or the equivalent, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such intercollegiate or interscholastic football contest and such game site were announced through publication in a newspaper of general circulation prior to August 1 of such year as being regularly scheduled for such day and place.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–331, § 3</ref>, <date date="1961-09-30">Sept. 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–800, § 6(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-08">Nov. 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1515</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1294.</num>
<heading> Antitrust laws unaffected as regards to other activities of professional sports contests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be deemed to change, determine, or otherwise affect the applicability or nonapplicability of the antitrust laws to any act, contract, agreement, rule, course of conduct, or other activity by, between, or among persons engaging in, conducting, or participating in the organized professional team sports of football, baseball, basketball, or hockey, except the agreements to which <ref>section 1291 of this title</ref> shall apply.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–331, § 4</ref>, <date date="1961-09-30">Sept. 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1295.</num>
<heading> “Persons” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter, “persons” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or unincorporated association or any combination or association thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–331, § 5</ref>, <date date="1961-09-30">Sept. 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>