<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 85—</num>
<heading>ARMORED CAR INDUSTRY RECIPROCITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5901.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the distribution of goods and services to consumers in the United States requires the free flow of currency, bullion, securities, supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits, and other items of unusual value in interstate commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the armored car industry transports and protects such items in interstate commerce, including daily transportation of currency and supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits valued at more than $1,000,000,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> armored car crew members are often subject to armed attack by individuals attempting to steal such items;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to protect themselves and the items they transport, such crew members are armed with weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> various States require both weapons training and a criminal record background check before licensing a crew member to carry a weapon; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> there is a need for each State to reciprocally accept weapons licenses of other States for armored car crew members to assure the free and safe transport of valuable items in interstate commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–55, § 2</ref>, <date date="1993-07-28">July 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 276</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E)</ref>, (2)(L), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1096</ref>, 1097; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E), (2)(L), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1858.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5902.</num>
<heading> State reciprocity of weapons licenses issued to armored car company crew members</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If an armored car crew member employed by an armored car company—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has in effect a license issued by the appropriate State agency (in the State in which such member is primarily employed by such company) to carry a weapon while acting in the services of such company in that State, and such State agency meets the minimum requirements under subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has met all other applicable requirements to act as an armored car crew member in the State in which such member is primarily employed by such company,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then such crew member shall be entitled to lawfully carry any weapon to which such license relates and function as an armored car crew member in any State while such member is acting in the service of such company.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum State requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State agency meets the minimum State requirements of this subsection if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in issuing an initial weapons license to an armored car crew member described in subsection (a), the agency determines to its satisfaction that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the crew member has received classroom and range training in weapons safety and marksmanship during the current year from a qualified instructor for each weapon that the crew member will be licensed to carry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the receipt or possession of a weapon by the crew member would not violate Federal law, determined on the basis of a criminal record background check conducted during the current year;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in issuing a renewal of a weapons license to an armored car crew member described in subsection (a), the agency determines to its satisfaction that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the crew member has received continuing training in weapons safety and marksmanship from a qualified instructor for each weapon that the crew member is licensed to carry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the receipt or possession of a weapon by the crew member would not violate Federal law, as determined by the agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in issuing a weapons license under paragraph (1) or paragraph (2), as the case may be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency issues such license for a period not to exceed 2 years; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the agency issues such license for a period not to exceed 5 years in the case of a State that enacted a State law before <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>, that provides for the issuance of an initial weapons license or a renewal of a weapons license, as the case may be, for a period not to exceed 5 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–55, § 3</ref>, <date date="1993-07-28">July 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 276</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–287, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5903.</num>
<heading> Relation to other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall supersede any provision of State law (or the law of any political subdivision of a State) that is inconsistent with this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–55, § 4</ref>, <date date="1993-07-28">July 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5904.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “armored car crew member” means an individual who provides protection for goods transported by an armored car company.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “armored car company” means a company—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to regulation under subchapter I of chapter 135 of title 49; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002539">1</ref> registered under chapter 139 of such title, in order to engage in the business of transporting and protecting currency, bullion, securities, precious metals, supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits, and other articles of unusual value in interstate commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “State” means any State of the United States or the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–55, § 5</ref>, <date date="1993-07-28">July 28, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 277</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 336</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E)</ref>, (2)(L), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1096</ref>, 1097; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E), (2)(L), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1858.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>