<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 39—</num>
<heading>FAIR PACKAGING AND LABELING PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1451.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Informed consumers are essential to the fair and efficient functioning of a free market economy. Packages and their labels should enable consumers to obtain accurate information as to the quantity of the contents and should facilitate value comparisons. Therefore, it is hereby declared to be the policy of the Congress to assist consumers and manufacturers in reaching these goals in the marketing of consumer goods.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1452.</num>
<heading> Unfair and deceptive packaging and labeling; scope of prohibition</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonconforming labels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person engaged in the packaging or labeling of any consumer commodity (as defined in this chapter) for distribution in commerce, or for any person (other than a common carrier for hire, a contract carrier for hire, or a freight forwarder for hire) engaged in the distribution in commerce of any packaged or labeled consumer commodity, to distribute or to cause to be distributed in commerce any such commodity if such commodity is contained in a package, or if there is affixed to that commodity a label, which does not conform to the provisions of this chapter and of regulations promulgated under the authority of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The prohibition contained in subsection (a) shall not apply to persons engaged in business as wholesale or retail distributors of consumer commodities except to the extent that such persons (1) are engaged in the packaging or labeling of such commodities, or (2) prescribe or specify by any means the manner in which such commodities are packaged or labeled.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1453.</num>
<heading> Requirements of labeling; placement, form, and contents of statement of quantity; supplemental statement of quantity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of label</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No person subject to the prohibition contained in <ref>section 1452 of this title</ref> shall distribute or cause to be distributed in commerce any packaged consumer commodity unless in conformity with regulations which shall be established by the promulgating authority pursuant to <ref>section 1455 of this title</ref> which shall provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The commodity shall bear a label specifying the identity of the commodity and the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The net quantity of contents (in terms of weight or mass, measure, or numerical count) shall be separately and accurately stated in a uniform location upon the principal display panel of that label, using the most appropriate units of both the customary inch/pound system of measure, as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, and, except as provided in paragraph (3)(A)(ii) or paragraph (6) of this subsection, the SI metric system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The separate label statement of net quantity of contents appearing upon or affixed to any package—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if on a package labeled in terms of weight, shall be expressed in pounds, with any remainder in terms of ounces or common or decimal fractions of the pound; or in the case of liquid measure, in the largest whole unit (quarts, quarts and pints, or pints, as appropriate) with any remainder in terms of fluid ounces or common or decimal fractions of the pint or quart;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if on a random package, may be expressed in terms of pounds and decimal fractions of the pound carried out to not more than three decimal places and is not required to, but may, include a statement in terms of the SI metric system carried out to not more than three decimal places;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if on a package labeled in terms of linear measure, shall be expressed in terms of the largest whole unit (yards, yards and feet, or feet, as appropriate) with any remainder in terms of inches or common or decimal fractions of the foot or yard;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> if on a package labeled in terms of measure of area, shall be expressed in terms of the largest whole square unit (square yards, square yards and square feet, or square feet, as appropriate) with any remainder in terms of square inches or common or decimal fractions of the square foot or square yard;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall appear in conspicuous and easily legible type in distinct contrast (by topography, layout, color, embossing, or molding) with other matter on the package;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall contain letters or numerals in a type size which shall be (i) established in relationship to the area of the principal display panel of the package, and (ii) uniform for all packages of substantially the same size; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> shall be so placed that the lines of printed matter included in that statement are generally parallel to the base on which the package rests as it is designed to be displayed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The label of any package of a consumer commodity which bears a representation as to the number of servings of such commodity contained in such package shall bear a statement of the net quantity (in terms of weight or mass, measure, or numerical count) of each such serving.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For purposes of paragraph (3)(A)(ii) of this subsection the term “random package” means a package which is one of a lot, shipment, or delivery of packages of the same consumer commodity with varying weights or masses, that is, packages with no fixed weight or mass pattern.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The requirement of paragraph (2) that the statement of net quantity of contents include a statement in terms of the SI metric system shall not apply to foods that are packaged at the retail store level.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplemental statements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person subject to the prohibition contained in <ref>section 1452 of this title</ref> shall distribute or cause to be distributed in commerce any packaged consumer commodity if any qualifying words or phrases appear in conjunction with the separate statement of the net quantity of contents required by subsection (a), but nothing in this subsection or in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) shall prohibit supplemental statements, at other places on the package, describing in nondeceptive terms the net quantity of contents: <i>Provided</i>, That such supplemental statements of net quantity of contents shall not include any term qualifying a unit of weight or mass, measure, or count that tends to exaggerate the amount of the commodity contained in the package.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–245, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 13</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–329</ref>, §§ 1, 3, <date date="1992-08-03">Aug. 3, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 847</ref>, 848.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1454.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgating authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority to promulgate regulations under this chapter is vested in (A) the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to hereinafter as the “Secretary”) with respect to any consumer commodity which is a food, drug, device, or cosmetic, as each such term is defined by <ref>section 321 of title 21</ref>; and (B) the Federal Trade Commission (referred to hereinafter as the “Commission”) with respect to any other consumer commodity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption of commodities from regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the promulgating authority specified in this section finds that, because of the nature, form, or quantity of a particular consumer commodity, or for other good and sufficient reasons, full compliance with all the requirements otherwise applicable under <ref>section 1453 of this title</ref> is impracticable or is not necessary for the adequate protection of consumers, the Secretary or the Commission (whichever the case may be) shall promulgate regulations exempting such commodity from those requirements to the extent and under such conditions as the promulgating authority determines to be consistent with <ref>section 1451 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of additional regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the promulgating authority determines that regulations containing prohibitions or requirements other than those prescribed by <ref>section 1453 of this title</ref> are necessary to prevent the deception of consumers or to facilitate value comparisons as to any consumer commodity, such authority shall promulgate with respect to that commodity regulations effective to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish and define standards for characterization of the size of a package enclosing any consumer commodity, which may be used to supplement the label statement of net quantity of contents of packages containing such commodity, but this paragraph shall not be construed as authorizing any limitation on the size, shape, weight or mass, dimensions, or number of packages which may be used to enclose any commodity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regulate the placement upon any package containing any commodity, or upon any label affixed to such commodity, of any printed matter stating or representing by implication that such commodity is offered for retail sale at a price lower than the ordinary and customary retail sale price or that a retail sale price advantage is accorded to purchasers thereof by reason of the size of that package or the quantity of its contents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> require that the label on each package of a consumer commodity (other than one which is a food within the meaning of <ref>section 321(f) of title 21</ref>) bear (A) the common or usual name of such consumer commodity, if any, and (B) in case such consumer commodity consists of two or more ingredients, the common or usual name of each such ingredient listed in order of decreasing predominance, but nothing in this paragraph shall be deemed to require that any trade secret be divulged; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> prevent the nonfunctional-slack-fill of packages containing consumer commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (4) of this subsection, a package shall be deemed to be nonfunctionally slack-filled if it is filled to substantially less than its capacity for reasons other than (A) protection of the contents of such package or (B) the requirements of machines used for enclosing the contents in such package.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development by manufacturers, packers, and distributors of voluntary product standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary of Commerce determines that there is undue proliferation of the weights or masses, measures, or quantities in which any consumer commodity or reasonably comparable consumer commodities are being distributed in packages for sale at retail and such undue proliferation impairs the reasonable ability of consumers to make value comparisons with respect to such consumer commodity or commodities, he shall request manufacturers, packers, and distributors of the commodity or commodities to participate in the development of a voluntary product standard for such commodity or commodities under the procedures for the development of voluntary products standards established by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 272 of this title</ref>. Such procedures shall provide adequate manufacturer, packer, distributor, and consumer representation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report and recommendations to Congress upon industry failure to develop or abide by voluntary product standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If (1) after one year after the date on which the Secretary of Commerce first makes the request of manufacturers, packers, and distributors to participate in the development of a voluntary product standard as provided in subsection (d) of this section, he determines that such a standard will not be published pursuant to the provisions of such subsection (d), or (2) if such a standard is published and the Secretary of Commerce determines that it has not been observed, he shall promptly report such determination to the Congress with a statement of the efforts that have been made under the voluntary standards program and his recommendation as to whether Congress should enact legislation providing regulatory authority to deal with the situation in question.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–245, title I, § 107(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 13</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–329</ref>, §§ 1(1), (2), 3, <date date="1992-08-03">Aug. 3, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 847</ref>, 848.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1455.</num>
<heading> Procedure for promulgation of regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings by Secretary of Health and Human Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations promulgated by the Secretary under section 1453 or 1454 of this title shall be promulgated, and shall be subject to judicial review, pursuant to the provisions of subsections (e), (f), and (g) of <ref>section 371 of title 21</ref>. Hearings authorized or required for the promulgation of any such regulations by the Secretary shall be conducted by the Secretary or by such officer or employees of the Department of Health and Human Services as he may designate for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review; hearings by Federal Trade Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations promulgated by the Commission under section 1453 or 1454 of this title shall be promulgated, and shall be subject to judicial review, by proceedings taken in conformity with the provisions of subsections (e), (f), and (g) of <ref>section 371 of title 21</ref> in the same manner, and with the same effect, as if such proceedings were taken by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. Hearings authorized or required for the promulgation of any such regulations by the Commission shall be conducted by the Commission or by such officer or employee of the Commission as the Commission may designate for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other departments and agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying into effect the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary and the Commission are authorized to cooperate with any department or agency of the United States, with any State, Commonwealth, or possession of the United States, and with any department, agency, or political subdivision of any such State, Commonwealth, or possession.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Returnable or reusable glass containers for beverages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No regulation adopted under this chapter shall preclude the continued use of returnable or reusable glass containers for beverages in inventory or with the trade as of the effective date of this Act, nor shall any regulation under this chapter preclude the orderly disposal of packages in inventory or with the trade as of the effective date of such regulation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 6</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1299</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1456.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Misbranded consumer commodities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any consumer commodity which is a food, drug, device, or cosmetic, as each such term is defined by section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 321</ref>), and which is introduced or delivered for introduction into commerce in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, or the regulations issued pursuant to this chapter, shall be deemed to be misbranded within the meaning of chapter III of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 331</ref> et seq.], but the provisions of section 303 of that Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 333</ref>) shall have no application to any violation of <ref>section 1452 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unfair or deceptive acts or practices in commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, or the regulations issued pursuant to this chapter, with respect to any consumer commodity which is not a food, drug, device, or cosmetic, shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act or practice in commerce in violation of <ref>section 45(a) of this title</ref> and shall be subject to enforcement under <ref>section 45(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any imports into the United States of any consumer commodity covered by this chapter, the provisions of sections 1453 and 1454 of this title shall be enforced by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to section 801(a) and (b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 381</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 7</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1457.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1458.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with State authorities; transmittal of regulations to States; noninterference with existing programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A copy of each regulation promulgated under this chapter shall be transmitted promptly to the Secretary of Commerce, who shall (1) transmit copies thereof to all appropriate State officers and agencies, and (2) furnish to such State officers and agencies information and assistance to promote to the greatest practicable extent uniformity in State and Federal regulation of the labeling of consumer commodities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to impair or otherwise interfere with any program carried into effect by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under other provisions of law in cooperation with State governments or agencies, instrumentalities, or political subdivisions thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 9</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1459.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The term “consumer commodity”, except as otherwise specifically provided by this subsection, means any food, drug, device, or cosmetic (as those terms are defined by the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.]), and any other article, product, or commodity of any kind or class which is customarily produced or distributed for sale through retail sales agencies or instrumentalities for consumption by individuals, or use by individuals for purposes of personal care or in the performance of services ordinarily rendered within the household, and which usually is consumed or expended in the course of such consumption or use. Such term does not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any meat or meat product, poultry or poultry product, or tobacco or tobacco product;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any commodity subject to packaging or labeling requirements imposed by the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 136</ref> et seq.], or the provisions of the eighth paragraph under the heading “Bureau of Animal Industry” of the Act of <date date="1913-03-04">March 4, 1913</date> (<ref>37 Stat. 832–833</ref>; <ref>21 U.S.C. 151–157</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002320">1</ref> commonly known as the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any drug subject to the provisions of section 503(b)(1) or 506 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 353(b)(1)</ref> and 356);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any beverage subject to or complying with packaging or labeling requirements imposed under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (<ref>27 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any commodity subject to the provisions of the Federal Seed Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1551–161</ref>0).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The term “package” means any container or wrapping in which any consumer commodity is enclosed for use in the delivery or display of that consumer commodity to retail purchasers, but does not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shipping containers or wrappings used solely for the transportation of any consumer commodity in bulk or in quantity to manufacturers, packers, or processors, or to wholesale or retail distributors thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shipping containers or outer wrappings used by retailers to ship or deliver any commodity to retail customers if such containers and wrappings bear no printed matter pertaining to any particular commodity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> containers subject to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1912-08-03">August 3, 1912</date> (<ref>37 Stat. 250</ref>, as amended; <ref>15 U.S.C. 231–233</ref>), or the Act of <date date="1915-03-04">March 4, 1915</date> (<ref>38 Stat. 1186</ref>, as amended; <ref>15 U.S.C. 234–236</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The term “label” means any written, printed, or graphic matter affixed to any consumer commodity or affixed to or appearing upon a package containing any consumer commodity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The term “person” includes any firm, corporation, or association.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The term “commerce” means (1) commerce between any State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States, and any place outside thereof, and (2) commerce within the District of Columbia or within any territory or possession of the United States not organized with a legislative body, but shall not include exports to foreign countries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The term “principal display panel” means that part of a label that is most likely to be displayed, presented, shown, or examined under normal and customary conditions of display for retail sale.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 10</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–628, § 2</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1460.</num>
<heading> Savings provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to repeal, invalidate, or supersede—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] or any statute defined therein as an antitrust Act;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref>21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> the Federal Hazardous Substances Labeling Act [<ref>15 U.S.C. 1261</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 11</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1461.</num>
<heading> Effect upon State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is hereby declared that it is the express intent of Congress to supersede any and all laws of the States or political subdivisions thereof insofar as they may now or hereafter provide for the labeling of the net quantity of contents of the package of any consumer commodity covered by this chapter which are less stringent than or require information different from the requirements of <ref>section 1453 of this title</ref> or regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–755, § 12</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>