<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9A—</num>
<heading>WEATHER MODIFICATION ACTIVITIES OR ATTEMPTS; REPORTING REQUIREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 330.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “person” means any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, joint stock company, any State or local government or any agency thereof, or any other organization, whether commercial or nonprofit, who is performing weather modification activities, except where acting solely as an employee, agent, or independent contractor of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “weather modification” means any activity performed with the intention of producing artificial changes in the composition, behavior, or dynamics of the atmosphere.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “United States” includes the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or insular possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–205, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 735</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 330a.</num>
<heading> Report requirement; form; information; time of submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person may engage, or attempt to engage, in any weather modification activity in the United States unless he submits to the Secretary such reports with respect thereto, in such form and containing such information, as the Secretary may by rule prescribe. The Secretary may require that such reports be submitted to him before, during, and after any such activity or attempt.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–205, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 330b.</num>
<heading> Duties of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records, maintenance; summaries, publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain a record of weather modification activities, including attempts, which take place in the United States and shall publish summaries thereof from time to time as he determines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability of reports, documents, and other information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All reports, documents, and other information received by the Secretary under the provisions of this chapter shall be made available to the public to the fullest practicable extent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure of confidential information; prohibition; exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Secretary shall not disclose any information referred to in <ref>section 1905 of title 18</ref> and is otherwise unavailable to the public, except that such information shall be disclosed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to other Federal Government departments, agencies, and officials for official use upon request;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any judicial proceeding under court order formulated to preserve the confidentiality of such information without impairing the proceeding; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to the public if necessary to protect their health and safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–205, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 330c.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information; reports and records; inspection; availability of data from any Federal agency as limitation of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may obtain from any person whose activities relate to weather modification by rule, subpena, or otherwise such information in the form of testimony, books, records, or other writings, may require the keeping and furnishing of such reports and records, and may make such inspection of the books, records, and other writings and premises and property of any person as may be deemed necessary or appropriate by him to carry out the provisions of this chapter, but this authority shall not be exercised to obtain any information with respect to which adequate and authoritative data are available from any Federal agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliance; application of Attorney General; jurisdiction; orders; contempts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpena served upon any person pursuant to this section, the district court of the United States for any district in which such person is found or resides or transacts business, upon application by the Attorney General, shall have jurisdiction to issue an order requiring such person to appear and give testimony or to appear and produce documents, or both; and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–205, § 4</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 330d.</num>
<heading> Violation; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who knowingly and willfully violates <ref>section 330a of this title</ref>, or any rule issued thereunder, shall upon conviction thereof be fined not more than $10,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–205, § 5</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 330e.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $150,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, $200,000 each for the fiscal years 1973 through 1980, $100,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, $100,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, $100,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>, $100,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>, to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–205, § 6</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–436</ref>, <date date="1974-10-05">Oct. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–490, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-13">Oct. 13, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–547, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-12-18">Dec. 18, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3217</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title VI, § 6081</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>