<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 113—</num>
<heading>FINANCE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>EQUIPMENT TRUSTS AND SECURITY INTERESTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11301.</num>
<heading> Equipment trusts: recordation; evidence of indebtedness</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A mortgage (other than a mortgage under chapter 313 of title 46), lease, equipment trust agreement, conditional sales agreement, or other instrument evidencing the mortgage, lease, conditional sale, or bailment of or security interest in vessels, railroad cars, locomotives, or other rolling stock, or accessories used on such railroad cars, locomotives, or other rolling stock (including superstructures and racks), intended for a use related to interstate commerce shall be filed with the Board in order to perfect the security interest that is the subject of such instrument. An assignment of a right or interest under one of those instruments and an amendment to that instrument or assignment including a release, discharge, or satisfaction of any part of it shall also be filed with the Board. The instrument, assignment, or amendment must be in writing, executed by the parties to it, and acknowledged or verified under Board regulations. When filed under this section, that document is notice to, and enforceable against, all persons. A document filed under this section does not have to be filed, deposited, registered, or recorded under another law of the United States, a State (or its political subdivisions), or territory or possession of the United States, related to filing, deposit, registration, or recordation of those documents. This section does not change chapter 313 of title 46.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Board shall maintain a system for recording each document filed under subsection (a) of this section and mark each of them with a consecutive number and the date and hour of their recordation. The Board shall maintain and keep open for public inspection an index of documents filed under that subsection. That index shall include the name and address of the principal debtors, trustees, guarantors, and other parties to those documents and may include other facts that will assist in determining the rights of the parties to those transactions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Board may to the greatest extent practicable perform its functions under this section through contracts with private sector entities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> A mortgage, lease, equipment trust agreement, conditional sales agreement, or other instrument evidencing the mortgage, lease, conditional sale, or bailment of or security interest in vessels, railroad cars, locomotives, or other rolling stock, or accessories used on such railroad cars, locomotives, or other rolling stock (including superstructures and racks), or any assignment thereof, which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is duly constituted under the laws of a country other than the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> relates to property that bears the reporting marks and identification numbers of any person domiciled in or corporation organized under the laws of such country,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be recognized with the same effect as having been filed under this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Interests with respect to which documents are filed or recognized under this section are deemed perfected in all jurisdictions, and shall be governed by applicable State or foreign law in all matters not specifically governed by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Board shall collect, maintain, and keep open for public inspection a railway equipment register consistent with the manner and format maintained by the Interstate Commerce Commission as of <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 837</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(25)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COMBINATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11321.</num>
<heading> Scope of authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The authority of the Board under this subchapter is exclusive. A rail carrier or corporation participating in or resulting from a transaction approved by or exempted by the Board under this subchapter may carry out the transaction, own and operate property, and exercise control or franchises acquired through the transaction without the approval of a State authority. A rail carrier, corporation, or person participating in that approved or exempted transaction is exempt from the antitrust laws and from all other law, including State and municipal law, as necessary to let that rail carrier, corporation, or person carry out the transaction, hold, maintain, and operate property, and exercise control or franchises acquired through the transaction. However, if a purchase and sale, a lease, or a corporate consolidation or merger is involved in the transaction, the carrier or corporation may carry out the transaction only with the assent of a majority, or the number required under applicable State law, of the votes of the holders of the capital stock of that corporation entitled to vote. The vote must occur at a regular meeting, or special meeting called for that purpose, of those stockholders and the notice of the meeting must indicate its purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A power granted under this subchapter to a carrier or corporation is in addition to and changes its powers under its corporate charter and under State law. Action under this subchapter does not establish or provide for establishing a corporation under the laws of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11322.</num>
<heading> Limitation on pooling and division of transportation or earnings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part may not agree or combine with another of those rail carriers to pool or divide traffic or services or any part of their earnings without the approval of the Board under this section or <ref>section 11123 of this title</ref>. The Board may approve and authorize the agreement or combination if the rail carriers involved assent to the pooling or division and the Board finds that a pooling or division of traffic, services, or earnings—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> will be in the interest of better service to the public or of economy of operation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> will not unreasonably restrain competition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Board may impose conditions governing the pooling or division and may approve and authorize payment of a reasonable consideration between the rail carriers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Board may begin a proceeding under this section on its own initiative or on application.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11323.</num>
<heading> Consolidation, merger, and acquisition of control</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The following transactions involving rail carriers providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part may be carried out only with the approval and authorization of the Board:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Consolidation or merger of the properties or franchises of at least 2 rail carriers into one corporation for the ownership, management, and operation of the previously separately owned properties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A purchase, lease, or contract to operate property of another rail carrier by any number of rail carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Acquisition of control of a rail carrier by any number of rail carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Acquisition of control of at least 2 rail carriers by a person that is not a rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Acquisition of control of a rail carrier by a person that is not a rail carrier but that controls any number of rail carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Acquisition by a rail carrier of trackage rights over, or joint ownership in or joint use of, a railroad line (and terminals incidental to it) owned or operated by another rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A person may carry out a transaction referred to in subsection (a) of this section or participate in achieving the control or management, including the power to exercise control or management, in a common interest of more than one of those rail carriers, regardless of how that result is reached, only with the approval and authorization of the Board under this subchapter. In addition to other transactions, each of the following transactions are considered achievements of control or management:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A transaction by a rail carrier that has the effect of putting that rail carrier and person affiliated with it, taken together, in control of another rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A transaction by a person affiliated with a rail carrier that has the effect of putting that rail carrier and persons affiliated with it, taken together, in control of another rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A transaction by at least 2 persons acting together (one of whom is a rail carrier or is affiliated with a rail carrier) that has the effect of putting those persons and rail carriers and persons affiliated with any of them, or with any of those affiliated rail carriers, taken together, in control of another rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A person is affiliated with a rail carrier under this subchapter if, because of the relationship between that person and a rail carrier, it is reasonable to believe that the affairs of another rail carrier, control of which may be acquired by that person, will be managed in the interest of the other rail carrier.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11324.</num>
<heading> Consolidation, merger, and acquisition of control: conditions of approval</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Board may begin a proceeding to approve and authorize a transaction referred to in <ref>section 11323 of this title</ref> on application of the person seeking that authority. When an application is filed with the Board, the Board shall notify the chief executive officer of each State in which property of the rail carriers involved in the proposed transaction is located and shall notify those rail carriers. The Board shall hold a public hearing unless the Board determines that a public hearing is not necessary in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In a proceeding under this section which involves the merger or control of at least two Class I railroads, as defined by the Board, the Board shall consider at least—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the effect of the proposed transaction on the adequacy of transportation to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the effect on the public interest of including, or failing to include, other rail carriers in the area involved in the proposed transaction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the total fixed charges that result from the proposed transaction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the interest of rail carrier employees affected by the proposed transaction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> whether the proposed transaction would have an adverse effect on competition among rail carriers in the affected region or in the national rail system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Board shall approve and authorize a transaction under this section when it finds the transaction is consistent with the public interest. The Board may impose conditions governing the transaction, including the divestiture of parallel tracks or requiring the granting of trackage rights and access to other facilities. Any trackage rights and related conditions imposed to alleviate anticompetitive effects of the transaction shall provide for operating terms and compensation levels to ensure that such effects are alleviated. When the transaction contemplates a guaranty or assumption of payment of dividends or of fixed charges or will result in an increase of total fixed charges, the Board may approve and authorize the transaction only if it finds that the guaranty, assumption, or increase is consistent with the public interest. The Board may require inclusion of other rail carriers located in the area involved in the transaction if they apply for inclusion and the Board finds their inclusion to be consistent with the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In a proceeding under this section which does not involve the merger or control of at least two Class I railroads, as defined by the Board, the Board shall approve such an application unless it finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as a result of the transaction, there is likely to be substantial lessening of competition, creation of a monopoly, or restraint of trade in freight surface transportation in any region of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the anticompetitive effects of the transaction outweigh the public interest in meeting significant transportation needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In making such findings, the Board shall, with respect to any application that is part of a plan or proposal developed under section 333(a)–(d) of this title, accord substantial weight to any recommendations of the Attorney General.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> No transaction described in section 11326(b) may have the effect of avoiding a collective bargaining agreement or shifting work from a rail carrier with a collective bargaining agreement to a rail carrier without a collective bargaining agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To the extent provided in this subsection, a proceeding under this subchapter relating to a transaction involving at least one Class I rail carrier shall not be considered an adjudication required by statute to be determined on the record after opportunity for an agency hearing, for the purposes of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Ex parte communications, as defined in <ref>section 551(14) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, shall be permitted in proceedings described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, subject to the requirements of paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any member or employee of the Board who makes or receives a written ex parte communication concerning the merits of a proceeding described in paragraph (1) shall promptly place the communication in the public docket of the proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any member or employee of the Board who makes or receives an oral ex parte communication concerning the merits of a proceeding described in paragraph (1) shall promptly place a written summary of the oral communication in the public docket of the proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the Board or any of its members or employees to engage in any ex parte communication with any person. Nothing in this subsection or any other law shall be construed to limit the authority of the members or employees of the Board, in their discretion, to note in the docket or otherwise publicly the occurrence and substance of an ex parte communication.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11325.</num>
<heading> Consolidation, merger, and acquisition of control: procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Board shall publish notice of the application under section 11324 in the Federal Register by the end of the 30th day after the application is filed with the Board. However, if the application is incomplete, the Board shall reject it by the end of that period. The order of rejection is a final action of the Board. The published notice shall indicate whether the application involves—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the merger or control of at least two Class I railroads, as defined by the Board, to be decided within the time limits specified in subsection (b) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transactions of regional or national transportation significance, to be decided within the time limits specified in subsection (c) of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other transaction covered by this section, to be decided within the time limits specified in subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If the application involves the merger or control of two or more Class I railroads, as defined by the Board, the following conditions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Written comments about an application may be filed with the Board within 45 days after notice of the application is published under subsection (a) of this section. Copies of such comments shall be served on the Attorney General and the Secretary of Transportation, who may decide to intervene as a party to the proceeding. That decision must be made by the 15th day after the date of receipt of the written comments, and if the decision is to intervene, preliminary comments about the application must be sent to the Board by the end of the 15th day after the date of receipt of the written comments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board shall require that applications inconsistent with an application, notice of which was published under subsection (a) of this section, and applications for inclusion in the transaction, be filed with it by the 90th day after publication of notice under that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Board must conclude evidentiary proceedings by the end of 1 year after the date of publication of notice under subsection (a) of this section. The Board must issue a final decision by the 90th day after the date on which it concludes the evidentiary proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> If the application involves a transaction other than the merger or control of at least two Class I railroads, as defined by the Board, which the Board has determined to be of regional or national transportation significance, the following conditions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Written comments about an application, including comments of the Attorney General and the Secretary of Transportation, may be filed with the Board within 30 days after notice of the application is published under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board shall require that applications inconsistent with an application, notice of which was published under subsection (a) of this section, and applications for inclusion in the transaction, be filed with it by the 60th day after publication of notice under that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Board must conclude any evidentiary proceedings by the 180th day after the date of publication of notice under subsection (a) of this section. The Board must issue a final decision by the 90th day after the date on which it concludes the evidentiary proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> For all applications under this section other than those specified in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the following conditions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Written comments about an application, including comments of the Attorney General and the Secretary of Transportation, may be filed with the Board within 30 days after notice of the application is published under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board must conclude any evidentiary proceedings by the 105th day after the date of publication of notice under subsection (a) of this section. The Board must issue a final decision by the 45th day after the date on which it concludes the evidentiary proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11326.</num>
<heading> Employee protective arrangements in transactions involving rail carriers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, when approval is sought for a transaction under sections 11324 and 11325 of this title, the Board shall require the rail carrier to provide a fair arrangement at least as protective of the interests of employees who are affected by the transaction as the terms imposed under section 5(2)(f) of the Interstate Commerce Act before <date date="1976-02-05">February 5, 1976</date>, and the terms established under section 24706(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002048">1</ref> of this title. Notwithstanding this part, the arrangement may be made by the rail carrier and the authorized representative of its employees. The arrangement and the order approving the transaction must require that the employees of the affected rail carrier will not be in a worse position related to their employment as a result of the transaction during the 4 years following the effective date of the final action of the Board (or if an employee was employed for a lesser period of time by the rail carrier before the action became effective, for that lesser period).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When approval is sought under sections 11324 and 11325 for a transaction involving one Class II and one or more Class III rail carriers, there shall be an arrangement as required under subsection (a) of this section, except that such arrangement shall be limited to one year of severance pay, which shall not exceed the amount of earnings from the railroad employment of that employee during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the application for approval of such transaction is filed with the Board. The amount of such severance pay shall be reduced by the amount of earnings from railroad employment of that employee with the acquiring carrier during the 12-month period immediately following the effective date of the transaction. The parties may agree to terms other than as provided in this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When approval is sought under sections 11324 and 11325 for a transaction involving only Class III rail carriers, this section shall not apply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11327.</num>
<heading> Supplemental orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When cause exists, the Board may make appropriate orders supplemental to an order made in a proceeding under sections 11322 through 11326 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11328.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on officers and directors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A person may hold the position of officer or director of more than one rail carrier only when authorized by the Board. The Board may authorize a person to hold the position of officer or director of more than one of those carriers when public or private interests will not be adversely affected.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to an individual holding the position of officer or director only of Class III rail carriers.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>