<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 153—</num>
<heading>JURISDICTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 15301.</num>
<heading> General pipeline jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board has jurisdiction over transportation by pipeline, or by pipeline and railroad or water, when transporting a commodity other than water, gas, or oil. Jurisdiction under this subsection applies only to transportation in the United States between a place in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a State and a place in another State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia and another place in the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a State and a place in a territory or possession of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a territory or possession of the United States and a place in another such territory or possession;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a territory or possession of the United States and another place in the same territory or possession;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the United States and another place in the United States through a foreign country; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the United States and a place in a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Jurisdiction Over Intrastate Transportation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board does not have jurisdiction under subsection (a) over the transportation of property, or the receipt, delivery, storage, or handling of property, entirely in a State (other than the District of Columbia) and not transported between a place in the United States and a place in a foreign country except as otherwise provided in this part.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of States Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This part does not affect the power of a State, in exercising its police power, to require reasonable intrastate transportation by carriers providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this chapter unless the State requirement is inconsistent with an order of the Board issued under this part or is prohibited under this part.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15302.</num>
<heading> Authority to exempt pipeline carrier transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>—</heading>
<chapeau>In a matter related to a pipeline carrier providing transportation subject to jurisdiction under this chapter, the Board shall exempt a person, class of persons, or a transaction or service when the Board finds that the application, in whole or in part, of a provision of this part—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not necessary to carry out the transportation policy of section 15101; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> either (A) the transaction or service is of limited scope, or (B) the application, in whole or in part, of the provision is not needed to protect shippers from the abuse of market power.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initiation of Proceeding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may, where appropriate, begin a proceeding under this section on its own initiative or an interested party.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Period of Exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may specify the period of time during which an exemption granted under this section is effective.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may revoke an exemption, to the extent it specifies, when it finds that application, in whole or in part, of a provision of this part to the person, class, or transportation is necessary to carry out the transportation policy of section 15101.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>