<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 131—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 13101.</num>
<heading> Transportation policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To ensure the development, coordination, and preservation of a transportation system that meets the transportation needs of the United States, including the United States Postal Service and national defense, it is the policy of the United States Government to oversee the modes of transportation and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in overseeing those modes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to recognize and preserve the inherent advantage of each mode of transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to promote safe, adequate, economical, and efficient transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to encourage sound economic conditions in transportation, including sound economic conditions among carriers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to encourage the establishment and maintenance of reasonable rates for transportation, without unreasonable discrimination or unfair or destructive competitive practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to cooperate with each State and the officials of each State on transportation matters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to encourage fair wages and working conditions in the transportation industry;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in overseeing transportation by motor carrier, to promote competitive and efficient transportation services in order to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encourage fair competition, and reasonable rates for transportation by motor carriers of property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote efficiency in the motor carrier transportation system and to require fair and expeditious decisions when required;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> meet the needs of shippers, receivers, passengers, and consumers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> allow a variety of quality and price options to meet changing market demands and the diverse requirements of the shipping and traveling public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> allow the most productive use of equipment and energy resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> enable efficient and well-managed carriers to earn adequate profits, attract capital, and maintain fair wages and working conditions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> provide and maintain service to small communities and small shippers and intrastate bus services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> provide and maintain commuter bus operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> improve and maintain a sound, safe, and competitive privately owned motor carrier system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> promote greater participation by minorities in the motor carrier system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> promote intermodal transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in overseeing transportation by motor carrier of passengers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to cooperate with the States on transportation matters for the purpose of encouraging the States to exercise intrastate regulatory jurisdiction in accordance with the objectives of this part;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide Federal procedures which ensure that intrastate regulation is exercised in accordance with this part; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to ensure that Federal reform initiatives enacted by section 31138 and the Bus Regulatory Reform Act of 1982 are not nullified by State regulatory actions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in overseeing transportation by water carrier, to encourage and promote service and price competition in the noncontiguous domestic trade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration To Carry Out Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This part shall be administered and enforced to carry out the policy of this section and to promote the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Board” means the Surface Transportation Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Broker</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “broker” means a person, other than a motor carrier or an employee or agent of a motor carrier, that as a principal or agent sells, offers for sale, negotiates for, or holds itself out by solicitation, advertisement, or otherwise as selling, providing, or arranging for, transportation by motor carrier for compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “carrier” means a motor carrier, a water carrier, and a freight forwarder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract carriage</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “contract carriage” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for transportation provided before <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, service provided pursuant to a permit issued under section 10923, as in effect on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for transportation provided after <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, service provided under an agreement entered into under section 14101(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Control</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “control”, when referring to a relationship between persons, includes actual control, legal control, and the power to exercise control, through or by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> common directors, officers, stockholders, a voting trust, or a holding or investment company, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other means.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign motor carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “foreign motor carrier” means a person (including a motor carrier of property but excluding a motor private carrier)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is domiciled in a contiguous foreign country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that is owned or controlled by persons of a contiguous foreign country; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a person that is not a motor carrier of property, that provides interstate transportation of property by motor vehicle under an agreement or contract entered into with a motor carrier of property (other than a motor private carrier or a motor carrier of property described in subparagraph (A)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign motor private carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “foreign motor private carrier” means a person (including a motor private carrier but excluding a motor carrier of property)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is domiciled in a contiguous foreign country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that is owned or controlled by persons of a contiguous foreign country; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a person that is not a motor private carrier, that provides interstate transportation of property by motor vehicle under an agreement or contract entered into with a person (other than a motor carrier of property or a motor private carrier described in subparagraph (A)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Freight forwarder</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “freight forwarder” means a person holding itself out to the general public (other than as a pipeline, rail, motor, or water carrier) to provide transportation of property for compensation and in the ordinary course of its business—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assembles and consolidates, or provides for assembling and consolidating, shipments and performs or provides for break-bulk and distribution operations of the shipments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assumes responsibility for the transportation from the place of receipt to the place of destination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> uses for any part of the transportation a carrier subject to jurisdiction under this subtitle.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The term does not include a person using transportation of an air carrier subject to part A of subtitle VII.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Highway</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “highway” means a road, highway, street, and way in a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Household goods</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “household goods”, as used in connection with transportation, means personal effects and property used or to be used in a dwelling, when a part of the equipment or supply of such dwelling, and similar property if the transportation of such effects or property is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> arranged and paid for by the householder, except such term does not include property moving from a factory or store, other than property that the householder has purchased with the intent to use in his or her dwelling and is transported at the request of, and the transportation charges are paid to the carrier by, the householder; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> arranged and paid for by another party.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Household goods freight forwarder</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “household goods freight forwarder” means a freight forwarder of one or more of the following items: household goods, unaccompanied baggage, or used automobiles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Household goods motor carrier.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “household goods motor carrier” means a motor carrier that, in the ordinary course of its business of providing transportation of household goods, offers some or all of the following additional services:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Binding and nonbinding estimates.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Inventorying.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Protective packing and unpacking of individual items at personal residences.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Loading and unloading at personal residences.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term includes any person that is considered to be a household goods motor carrier under regulations, determinations, and decisions of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration that are in effect on the date of enactment of the Household Goods Mover Oversight Enforcement and Reform Act of 2005.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limited service exclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term does not include a motor carrier when the motor carrier provides transportation of household goods in containers or trailers that are entirely loaded and unloaded by an individual (other than an employee or agent of the motor carrier).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individual shipper</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “individual shipper” means any person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is the shipper, consignor, or consignee of a household goods shipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is identified as the shipper, consignor, or consignee on the face of the bill of lading;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> owns the goods being transported; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> pays his or her own tariff transportation charges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motor carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “motor carrier” means a person providing motor vehicle transportation for compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motor private carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “motor private carrier” means a person, other than a motor carrier, transporting property by motor vehicle when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transportation is as provided in <ref>section 13501 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the person is the owner, lessee, or bailee of the property being transported; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the property is being transported for sale, lease, rent, or bailment or to further a commercial enterprise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motor vehicle</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “motor vehicle” means a vehicle, machine, tractor, trailer, or semitrailer propelled or drawn by mechanical power and used on a highway in transportation, or a combination determined by the Secretary, but does not include a vehicle, locomotive, or car operated only on a rail, or a trolley bus operated by electric power from a fixed overhead wire, and providing local passenger transportation similar to street-railway service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Noncontiguous domestic trade</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “noncontiguous domestic trade” means transportation subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 involving traffic originating in or destined to Alaska, Hawaii, or a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Person</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “person”, in addition to its meaning under <ref>section 1 of title 1</ref>, includes a trustee, receiver, assignee, or personal representative of a person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pre-arranged ground transportation service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “pre-arranged ground transportation service” means transportation for a passenger (or a group of passengers) that is arranged in advance (or is operated on a regular route or between specified points) and is provided in a motor vehicle with a seating capacity not exceeding 15 passengers (including the driver).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” means the 50 States of the United States and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Taxicab service</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “taxicab service” means passenger transportation in a motor vehicle having a capacity of not more than 8 passengers (including the driver), not operated on a regular route or between specified places, and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is licensed as a taxicab by a State or a local jurisdiction; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is offered by a person that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provides local transportation for a fare determined (except with respect to transportation to or from airports) primarily on the basis of the distance traveled; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not primarily provide transportation to or from airports.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “transportation” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a motor vehicle, vessel, warehouse, wharf, pier, dock, yard, property, facility, instrumentality, or equipment of any kind related to the movement of passengers or property, or both, regardless of ownership or an agreement concerning use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> services related to that movement, including arranging for, receipt, delivery, elevation, transfer in transit, refrigeration, icing, ventilation, storage, handling, packing, unpacking, and interchange of passengers and property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “United States” means the States of the United States and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vessel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “vessel” means a watercraft or other artificial contrivance that is used, is capable of being used, or is intended to be used, as a means of transportation by water.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Water carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “water carrier” means a person providing water transportation for compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Over-the-road bus</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “over-the-road bus” means a bus characterized by an elevated passenger deck located over a baggage compartment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 854</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(27)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3390</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–159, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–298, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2343</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title IV</ref>, §§ 4142(a), 4202(b), <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1747</ref>, 1751; <ref>Pub. L. 110–244, title III, § 305(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-06">June 6, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–291, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13103.</num>
<heading> Remedies as cumulative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this part, the remedies provided under this part are in addition to remedies existing under another law or common law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 856</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>