<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 137—</num>
<heading>RATES AND THROUGH ROUTES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 13701.</num>
<heading> Requirements for reasonable rates, classifications, through routes, rules, and practices for certain transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reasonableness.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain household goods transportation; joint rates involving water transportation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A rate, classification, rule, or practice related to transportation or service provided by a carrier subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 for transportation or service involving—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a movement of household goods,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a rate for a movement by or with a water carrier in noncontiguous domestic trade, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> rates, rules, and classifications made collectively by motor carriers under agreements approved pursuant to section 13703,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">must be reasonable.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Through routes and divisions of joint rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Through routes and divisions of joint rates for such transportation or service must be reasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prescription by Board for Violations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Board finds it necessary to stop or prevent a violation of subsection (a), the Board shall prescribe the rate, classification, rule, practice, through route, or division of joint rates to be applied for such transportation or service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing of Complaint</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A complaint that a rate, classification, rule, or practice in noncontiguous domestic trade violates subsection (a) may be filed with the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Zone of Reasonableness.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, a rate or division of a motor carrier for service in noncontiguous domestic trade or water carrier for port-to-port service in that trade is reasonable if the aggregate of increases and decreases in any such rate or division is not more than 7.5 percent above, or more than 10 percent below, the rate or division in effect 1 year before the effective date of the proposed rate or division.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adjustments to the zone</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The percentage specified in paragraph (1) shall be increased or decreased, as the case may be, by the percentage change in the Producers Price Index, as published by the Department of Labor, that has occurred during the most recent 1-year period before the date the rate or division in question first took effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determinations after complaint</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall determine whether any rate or division of a carrier or service in noncontiguous domestic trade which is not within the range described in paragraph (1) is reasonable if a complaint is filed under subsection (c) or section 13702(b)(6).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reparations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon a finding of violation of subsection (a), the Board shall award reparations to the complaining shipper or shippers in an amount equal to all sums assessed and collected that exceed the determined reasonable rate, division, rate structure, or tariff. Upon complaint from any governmental agency or authority and upon a finding or violation of subsection (a), the Board shall make such orders as are just and shall require the carrier to return, to the extent practicable, to shippers all amounts plus interest, which the Board finds to have been assessed and collected in violation of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 867</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13702.</num>
<heading> Tariff requirement for certain transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except when providing transportation for charitable purposes without charge, a carrier subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 may provide transportation or service that is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in noncontiguous domestic trade, except with regard to bulk cargo, forest products, recycled metal scrap, waste paper, and paper waste; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for movement of household goods;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">only if the rate for such transportation or service is contained in a tariff that is in effect under this section. The carrier may not charge or receive a different compensation for the transportation or service than the rate specified in the tariff, whether by returning a part of that rate to a person, giving a person a privilege, allowing the use of a facility that affects the value of that transportation or service, or another device. A rate contained in a tariff shall be stated in money of the United States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tariff Requirements for Noncontiguous Domestic Trade.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A carrier providing transportation or service described in subsection (a)(1) shall publish and file with the Board tariffs containing the rates established for such transportation or service. The carriers shall keep such tariffs available for public inspection. The Board shall prescribe the form and manner of publishing, filing, and keeping tariffs available for public inspection under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board may prescribe any specific information and charges to be identified in a tariff, but at a minimum tariffs must identify plainly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the carriers that are parties to it;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the places between which property will be transported;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> terminal charges if a carrier provides transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under subchapter III of chapter 135;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> privileges given and facilities allowed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any rules that change, affect, or determine any part of the published rate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inland divisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A carrier providing transportation or service described in subsection (a)(1) under a joint rate for a through movement shall not be required to state separately or otherwise reveal in tariff filings the inland divisions of that through rate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time-volume rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Rates in tariffs filed under this subsection may vary with the volume of cargo offered over a specified period of time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Changes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board may permit carriers to change rates, classifications, rules, and practices without filing complete tariffs under this subsection that cover matter that is not being changed when the Board finds that action to be consistent with the public interest. Those carriers may either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> publish new tariffs that incorporate changes, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> plainly indicate the proposed changes in the tariffs then in effect and make the tariffs as changed available for public inspection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Complaints</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A complaint that a rate or related rule or practice maintained in a tariff under this subsection violates section 13701(a) may be submitted to the Board for resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tariff Requirements for Household Goods Carriers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A carrier providing transportation described in subsection (a)(2) shall maintain rates and related rules and practices in a published tariff. The tariff must be available for inspection by the Board and be made available for inspection by shippers upon reasonable request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A carrier that maintains a tariff under this subsection may not enforce the provisions of the tariff unless the carrier has given notice that the tariff is available for inspection in its bill of lading or by other actual notice to individuals whose shipments are subject to the tariff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A carrier that maintains a tariff under this subsection is bound by the tariff except as otherwise provided in this part. A tariff that does not comply with this subsection may not be enforced against any individual shipper.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incorporation by reference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A carrier may incorporate by reference the rates, terms, and other conditions of a tariff in agreements covering the transportation of household goods.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Complaints</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A complaint that a rate or related rule or practice maintained in a tariff under this subsection violates section 13701(a) may be submitted to the Board for resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Invalidation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may invalidate a tariff prepared by a carrier or carriers under this section if that tariff violates this section or a regulation of the Board carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13703.</num>
<heading> Certain collective activities; exemption from antitrust laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to enter</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A motor carrier providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 may enter into an agreement with one or more such carriers to establish—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> through routes and joint rates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> rates for the transportation of household goods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> classifications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> mileage guides;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> rules;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> divisions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> rate adjustments of general application based on industry average carrier costs (so long as there is no discussion of individual markets or particular single-line rates); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> procedures for joint consideration, initiation, or establishment of matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (G).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of agreement to board; approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement entered into under paragraph (1) may be submitted by any carrier or carriers that are parties to such agreement to the Board for approval and may be approved by the Board only if it finds that such agreement is in the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may require compliance with reasonable conditions consistent with this part to assure that the agreement furthers the transportation policy set forth in section 13101.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Independently established rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any carrier which is a party to an agreement under paragraph (1) is not, and may not be, precluded from independently establishing its own rates, classification, and mileages or from adopting and using a noncollectively made classification or mileage guide.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Investigations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reasonableness</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may suspend and investigate the reasonableness of any rate, rule, classification, or rate adjustment of general application made pursuant to an agreement under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions not in the public interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may investigate any action taken pursuant to an agreement approved under this section. If the Board finds that the action is not in the public interest, the Board may take such measures as may be necessary to protect the public interest with regard to the action, including issuing an order directing the parties to cease and desist or modify the action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Board approves the agreement or renews approval of the agreement, it may be made and carried out under its terms and under the conditions required by the Board, and the antitrust laws, as defined in the first section of the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 12</ref>), do not apply to parties and other persons with respect to making or carrying out the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may require an organization established or continued under an agreement approved under this section to maintain records and submit reports. The Board, or its delegate, may inspect a record maintained under this section, or monitor any organization’s compliance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Review.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board may review an agreement approved under this section, on its own initiative or on request, and shall change the conditions of approval or terminate it when necessary to protect the public interest. Action of the Board under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> approving an agreement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> denying, ending, or changing approval,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> prescribing the conditions on which approval is granted, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> changing those conditions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">has effect only as related to application of the antitrust laws referred to in subsection (a).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic review of approvals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to this section, in the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph and in each 5-year period thereafter, the Board shall initiate a proceeding to review any agreement approved pursuant to this section. Any such agreement shall be continued unless the Board determines otherwise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Existing Agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements existing as of <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date></inline>.—</heading>
<content>Agreements approved under former section 10706(b) and in effect on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, shall be treated for purposes of this section as approved by the Board under this section beginning on <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cases pending as of date of the enactment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in section 227 (other than subsection (b)) of the Motor Carrier Safety Improvement Act of 1999, including the amendments made by such section, shall be construed to affect any case brought under this section that is pending before the Board as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Statutory Construction.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Undercharge claims</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall serve as a basis for any undercharge claim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation of shipper</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this title, the ICC Termination Act of 1995, or any amendments or repeals made by such Act shall be construed as creating any obligation for a shipper based solely on a classification that was on file with the Interstate Commerce Commission or elsewhere on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Industry Standard Guides.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Routes, rates, classifications, mileage guides, and rules established under agreements approved under this section shall be published and made available for public inspection upon request.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation of carriers</inline>.—</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A motor carrier of property whose routes, rates, classifications, mileage guides, rules, or packaging are determined or governed by publications established under agreements approved under this section must participate in the determining or governing publication for such provisions to apply.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Power of attorney</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The motor carrier of property shall issue a power of attorney to the publishing agent and, upon its acceptance, the agent shall issue a written certification to the motor carrier affirming its participation in the governing publication, and the certification shall be made available for public inspection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mileage limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No carrier subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I or III of chapter 135 may enforce collection of its mileage rates unless such carrier—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a participant in a publication of mileages formulated under an agreement approved under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> uses a publication of mileage (other than a publication described in subparagraph (A)) that can be examined by any interested person upon reasonable request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single Line Rate Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “single line rate” means a rate, charge, or allowance proposed by a single motor carrier that is applicable only over its line and for which the transportation can be provided by that carrier.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 869</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(28)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(9)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2204</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–159, title II, § 227</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. I, title III, § 354</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13704.</num>
<heading> Household goods rates—estimates; guarantees of service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a motor carrier providing transportation of household goods subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135 may establish a rate for the transportation of household goods which is based on the carrier’s written, binding estimate of charges for providing such transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonpreferential; nonpredatory</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any rate established under this subsection must be available on a nonpreferential basis to shippers and must not result in charges to shippers which are predatory.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Rates for Guaranteed Service.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a motor carrier providing transportation of household goods subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135 may establish rates for the transportation of household goods which guarantee that the carrier will pick up and deliver such household goods at the times specified in the contract for such services and provide a penalty or per diem payment in the event the carrier fails to pick up or deliver such household goods at the specified time. The charges, if any, for such guarantee and penalty provision may vary to reflect one or more options available to meet a particular shipper’s needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary to require nonguaranteed service rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before a carrier may establish a rate for any service under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary may require such carrier to have in effect and keep in effect, during any period such rate is in effect under paragraph (1), a rate for such service which does not guarantee the pick up and delivery of household goods at the times specified in the contract for such services and which does not provide a penalty or per diem payment in the event the carrier fails to pick up or deliver household goods at the specified time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13705.</num>
<heading> Requirements for through routes among motor carriers of passengers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment; Reasonableness</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A motor carrier providing transportation of passengers subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135 shall establish through routes with other carriers of the same type and shall establish individual and joint rates applicable to them. Such through route must be reasonable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prescribed by Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Board finds it necessary to enforce the requirements of this section, the Board may prescribe through routes and the conditions under which those routes must be operated for motor carriers providing transportation of passengers subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13706.</num>
<heading> Liability for payment of rates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Liability of Consignee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Liability for payment of rates for transportation for a shipment of property by a shipper or consignor to a consignee other than the shipper or consignor, is determined under this section when the transportation is provided by motor carrier under this part. When the shipper or consignor instructs the carrier transporting the property to deliver it to a consignee that is an agent only, not having beneficial title to the property, the consignee is liable for rates billed at the time of delivery for which the consignee is otherwise liable, but not for additional rates that may be found to be due after delivery if the consignee gives written notice to the delivering carrier before delivery of the property—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> of the agency and absence of beneficial title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of the name and address of the beneficial owner of the property if it is reconsigned or diverted to a place other than the place specified in the original bill of lading.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Liability of Beneficial Owner</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the consignee is liable only for rates billed at the time of delivery under subsection (a), the shipper or consignor, or, if the property is reconsigned or diverted, the beneficial owner is liable for those additional rates regardless of the bill of the lading or contract under which the property was transported. The beneficial owner is liable for all rates when the property is reconsigned or diverted by an agent but is refused or abandoned at its ultimate destination if the agent gave the carrier in the reconsignment or diversion order a notice of agency and the name and address of the beneficial owner. A consignee giving the carrier erroneous information about the identity of the beneficial owner of the property is liable for the additional rates.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13707.</num>
<heading> Payment of rates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Possession Upon Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), a carrier providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under this part shall give up possession at the destination of the property transported by it only when payment for the transportation or service is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations of the Secretary governing the payment for transportation and service and preventing discrimination, those carriers may give up possession at destination of property transported by them before payment for the transportation or service. The regulations of the Secretary may provide for weekly or monthly payment for transportation provided by motor carriers and for periodic payment for transportation provided by water carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extensions of credit to governmental entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Such a carrier (including a motor carrier being used by a household goods freight forwarder) may extend credit for transporting property for the United States Government, a State, a territory or possession of the United States, or a political subdivision of any of them.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Shipments of household goods.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A carrier providing transportation of a shipment of household goods shall give up possession of the household goods being transported at the destination upon payment of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 100 percent of the charges contained in a binding estimate provided by the carrier;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not more than 110 percent of the charges contained in a nonbinding estimate provided by the carrier; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of a partial delivery of the shipment, the prorated percentage of the charges calculated in accordance with subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Calculation of prorated charges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii), the prorated percentage of the charges shall be the percentage of the total charges due to the carrier as described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) that is equal to the percentage of the weight of that portion of the shipment delivered to the total weight of the shipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Post-contract services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) does not apply to additional services requested by a shipper after the contract of service is executed that were not included in the estimate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Impracticable operations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) does not apply to impracticable operations, as defined by the applicable carrier tariff, except that the charges collected at delivery for such operations shall not exceed 15 percent of all other charges due at delivery. Any remaining charges due shall be paid within 30 days after the carrier presents its freight bill.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 873</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title IV, § 4203</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1752</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13708.</num>
<heading> Billing and collecting practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A motor carrier subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135 shall disclose, when a document is presented or electronically transmitted for payment to the person responsible directly to the motor carrier for payment or agent of such responsible person, the actual rates, charges, or allowances for any transportation service and shall also disclose, at such time, whether and to whom any allowance or reduction in charges is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">False or Misleading Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may cause a motor carrier to present false or misleading information on a document about the actual rate, charge, or allowance to any party to the transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowances for Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the actual rate, charge, or allowance is dependent upon the performance of a service by a party to the transportation arrangement, such as tendering a volume of freight over a stated period of time, the motor carrier shall indicate in any document presented for payment to the person responsible directly to the motor carrier that a reduction, allowance, or other adjustment may apply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 873</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13709.</num>
<heading> Procedures for resolving claims involving unfiled, negotiated transportation rates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transportation Provided at Rates Other Than Legal Tariff Rates.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When a claim is made by a motor carrier of property (other than a household goods carrier) providing transportation subject to jurisdiction under subchapter II of chapter 105 (as in effect on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>) or subchapter I of chapter 135, by a freight forwarder (other than a household goods freight forwarder), or by a party representing such a carrier or freight forwarder regarding the collection of rates or charges for such transportation in addition to those originally billed and collected by the carrier or freight forwarder for such transportation, the person against whom the claim is made may elect to satisfy the claim under the provisions of subsection (b), (c), or (d), upon showing that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the carrier or freight forwarder is no longer transporting property or is transporting property for the purpose of avoiding the application of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to the claim—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the person was offered a transportation rate by the carrier or freight forwarder other than that legally on file at the time with the Board or with the Interstate Commerce Commission, as required, for the transportation service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the person tendered freight to the carrier or freight forwarder in reasonable reliance upon the offered transportation rate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the carrier or freight forwarder did not properly or timely file with the Board or with the Interstate Commerce Commission, as required, a tariff providing for such transportation rate or failed to enter into an agreement for contract carriage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> such transportation rate was billed and collected by the carrier or freight forwarder; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the carrier or freight forwarder demands additional payment of a higher rate filed in a tariff.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If there is a dispute as to the showing under paragraph (1)(A), such dispute shall be resolved by the court in which the claim is brought. If there is a dispute as to the showing under paragraph (1)(B), such dispute shall be resolved by the Board. Pending the resolution of any such dispute, the person shall not have to pay any additional compensation to the carrier or freight forwarder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of satisfaction of claims</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Satisfaction of the claim under subsection (b), (c), or (d) shall be binding on the parties, and the parties shall not be subject to chapter 119 of this title, as such chapter was in effect on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, or chapter 149.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claims Involving Shipments Weighing</inline> 10,000 <inline class="small-caps">Pounds or Less</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person from whom the additional legally applicable and effective tariff rate or charges are sought may elect to satisfy the claim if the shipments each weighed 10,000 pounds or less, by payment of 20 percent of the difference between the carrier’s applicable and effective tariff rate and the rate originally billed and paid. In the event that a dispute arises as to the rate that was legally applicable to the shipment, such dispute shall be resolved by the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claims Involving Shipments Weighing More Than</inline> 10,000 <inline class="small-caps">Pounds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person from whom the additional legally applicable and effective tariff rate or charges are sought may elect to satisfy the claim if the shipments each weighed more than 10,000 pounds, by payment of 15 percent of the difference between the carrier’s applicable and effective tariff rate and the rate originally billed and paid. In the event that a dispute arises as to the rate that was legally applicable to the shipment, such dispute shall be resolved by the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claims Involving Public Warehousemen</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c), a person from whom the additional legally applicable and effective tariff rate or charges are sought may elect to satisfy the claim by payment of 5 percent of the difference between the carrier’s applicable and effective tariff rate and the rate originally billed and paid if such person is a public warehouseman. In the event that a dispute arises as to the rate that was legally applicable to the shipment, such dispute shall be resolved by the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effects of Election</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When a person from whom additional legally applicable freight rates or charges are sought does not elect to use the provisions of subsection (b), (c) or (d), the person may pursue all rights and remedies existing under this part or, for transportation provided before <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, all rights and remedies that existed under this title on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stay of Additional Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When a person proceeds under this section to challenge the reasonableness of the legally applicable freight rate or charges being claimed by a carrier or freight forwarder in addition to those already billed and collected, the person shall not have to pay any additional compensation to the carrier or freight forwarder until the Board has made a determination as to the reasonableness of the challenged rate as applied to the freight of the person against whom the claim is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification of Election.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person must notify the carrier or freight forwarder as to its election to proceed under subsection (b), (c), or (d). Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), such election may be made at any time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demands for payment initially made after <date date="1993-12-03">december 3, 1993</date></inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the carrier or freight forwarder or party representing such carrier or freight forwarder initially demands the payment of additional freight charges after <date date="1993-12-03">December 3, 1993</date>, and notifies the person from whom additional freight charges are sought of the provisions of subsections (a) through (f) at the time of the making of such initial demand, the election must be made not later than the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 60th day following the filing of an answer to a suit for the collection of such additional legally applicable freight rate or charges, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><date date="1994-03-05">March 5, 1994</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pending suits for collection made before <date date="1993-12-04">december 4, 1993</date></inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the carrier or freight forwarder or party representing such carrier or freight forwarder has filed, before <date date="1993-12-04">December 4, 1993</date>, a suit for the collection of additional freight charges and notifies the person from whom additional freight charges are sought of the provisions of subsections (a) through (f), the election must be made not later than the 90th day following the date on which such notification is received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demands for payment made before <date date="1993-12-04">december 4, 1993</date></inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the carrier or freight forwarder or party representing such carrier or freight forwarder has demanded the payment of additional freight charges, and has not filed a suit for the collection of such additional freight charges, before <date date="1993-12-04">December 4, 1993</date>, and notifies the person from whom additional freight charges are sought of the provisions of subsections (a) through (f), the election must be made not later than the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 60th day following the filing of an answer to a suit for the collection of such additional legally applicable freight rate or charges, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><date date="1994-03-05">March 5, 1994</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Claims Involving Small-Business Concerns, Charitable Organizations, and Re­cyclable Materials.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsections (b), (c), and (d), a person from whom the additional legally applicable and effective tariff rate or charges are sought shall not be liable for the difference between the carrier’s applicable and effective tariff rate and the rate originally billed and paid—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if such person qualifies as a small-business concern under the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if such person is an organization which is described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if the cargo involved in the claim is recyclable materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recyclable materials defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “recyclable materials” means waste products for recycling or reuse in the furtherance of recognized pollution control programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 874</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(29)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13710.</num>
<heading> Additional billing and collecting practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Miscellaneous Provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information relating to basis of rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A motor carrier of property (other than a motor carrier providing transportation in noncontiguous domestic trade) shall provide to the shipper, on request of the shipper, a written or electronic copy of the rate, classification, rules, and practices, upon which any rate applicable to its shipment or agreed to between the shipper and carrier is based.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reasonableness of rates; collecting additional charges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the applicability or reasonableness of the rates and related provisions billed by a motor carrier is challenged by the person paying the freight charges, the Board shall determine whether such rates and provisions are reasonable under section 13701 or applicable based on the record before it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Billing disputes.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initiated by motor carriers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In those cases where a motor carrier (other than a motor carrier providing transportation of household goods or in noncontiguous domestic trade) seeks to collect charges in addition to those billed and collected which are contested by the payor, the carrier may request that the Board determine whether any additional charges over those billed and collected must be paid. A carrier must issue any bill for charges in addition to those originally billed within 180 days of the receipt of the original bill in order to have the right to collect such charges.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initiated by shippers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a shipper seeks to contest the charges originally billed or additional charges subsequently billed, the shipper may request that the Board determine whether the charges billed must be paid. A shipper must contest the original bill or subsequent bill within 180 days of receipt of the bill in order to have the right to contest such charges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voiding of certain tariffs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any tariff on file with the Interstate Commerce Commission on <date date="1994-08-26">August 26, 1994</date>, and not required to be filed after that date is null and void beginning on that date. Any tariff on file with the Interstate Commerce Commission on <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, and not required to be filed after that date is null and void beginning on that date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resolution of Disputes Over Status of Common Carrier or Contract Carrier</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a motor carrier (other than a motor carrier providing transportation of household goods) that was subject to jurisdiction under subchapter II of chapter 105, as in effect on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, and that had authority to provide transportation as both a motor common carrier and a motor contract carrier and a dispute arises as to whether certain transportation that was provided prior to <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, was provided in its common carrier or contract carrier capacity and the parties are not able to resolve the dispute consensually, the Board shall resolve the dispute.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 876</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(30)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13711.</num>
<heading> Alternative procedure for resolving undercharge disputes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It shall be an unreasonable practice for a motor carrier of property (other than a household goods carrier) providing transportation subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135 or, before <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, to have provided transportation that was subject to jurisdiction under subchapter II of chapter 105, as in effect on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, a freight forwarder (other than a household goods freight forwarder), or a party representing such a carrier or freight forwarder to attempt to charge or to charge for a transportation service the difference between (1) the applicable rate that was lawfully in effect pursuant to a tariff that was filed in accordance with this chapter or, with respect to transportation provided before <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, in accordance with chapter 107, as in effect on the date the transportation was provided, by the carrier or freight forwarder applicable to such transportation service, and (2) the negotiated rate for such transportation service if the carrier or freight forwarder is no longer transporting property between places described in section 13501(1) or is transporting property between places described in section 13501(1) for the purpose of avoiding application of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction of Board.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall have jurisdiction to make a determination of whether or not attempting to charge or the charging of a rate by a motor carrier or freight forwarder or party representing a motor carrier or freight forwarder is an unreasonable practice under subsection (a). If the Board determines that attempting to charge or the charging of the rate is an unreasonable practice under subsection (a), the carrier, freight forwarder, or party may not collect the difference described in subsection (a) between the applicable rate and the negotiated rate for the transportation service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors to consider</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In making a determination under paragraph (1), the Board shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether the person was offered a transportation rate by the carrier or freight forwarder or party other than that legally on file with the Interstate Commerce Commission or the Board, as required, at the time of the movement for the transportation service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the person tendered freight to the carrier or freight forwarder in reasonable reliance upon the offered transportation rate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether the carrier or freight forwarder did not properly or timely file with the Interstate Commerce Commission or the Board, as required, a tariff providing for such transportation rate or failed to enter into an agreement for contract carriage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether the transportation rate was billed and collected by the carrier or freight forwarder; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> whether the carrier or freight forwarder or party demands additional payment of a higher rate filed in a tariff.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stay of Additional Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When a person proceeds under this section to challenge the reasonableness of the practice of a motor carrier, freight forwarder, or party described in subsection (a) to attempt to charge or to charge the difference described in subsection (a) between the applicable rate and the negotiated rate for the transportation service in addition to those charges already billed and collected for the transportation service, the person shall not have to pay any additional compensation to the carrier, freight forwarder, or party until the Board has made a determination as to the reasonableness of the practice as applied to the freight of the person against whom the claim is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) is an exception to the requirements of section 13702 and, for transportation provided before <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, to the requirements of sections 10761(a) and 10762, as in effect on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, as such sections relate to a filed tariff rate and other general tariff requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability of Negotiated Rate Dispute Resolution Procedure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a person elects to seek enforcement of subsection (a) with respect to a rate for a transportation or service, section 13709 shall not apply to such rate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “negotiated rate” means a rate, charge, classification, or rule agreed upon by a motor carrier or freight forwarder and a shipper through negotiations pursuant to which no tariff was lawfully and timely filed and for which there is written evidence of such agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability to Pending Cases</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall apply to all cases and proceedings pending on <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 877</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(31)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13712.</num>
<heading> Government traffic</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A carrier providing transportation or service for the United States Government may transport property or individuals for the United States Government without charge or at a rate reduced from the applicable commercial rate. Section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41 does not apply when transportation for the United States Government can be obtained from a carrier lawfully operating in the area where the transportation would be provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 879</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5</ref>(<i>o</i>)(5), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13713.</num>
<heading> Food and grocery transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain Compensation Prohibited</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, it shall not be unlawful for a seller of food and grocery products using a uniform zone delivered pricing system to compensate a customer who picks up purchased food and grocery products at the shipping point of the seller if such compensation is available to all customers of the seller on a nondiscriminatory basis and does not exceed the actual cost to the seller of delivery to such customer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the sense of the Congress that any savings accruing to a customer by reason of compensation permitted by subsection (a) of this section should be passed on to the ultimate consumer.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 879</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>