<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 157—</num>
<heading>OPERATIONS OF CARRIERS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER A—</num>
<heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 15701.</num>
<heading> Providing transportation and service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service on Reasonable Request</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A pipeline carrier providing transportation or service under this part shall provide the transportation or service on reasonable request.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rates and Other Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A pipeline carrier shall also provide to any person, on request, the carrier’s rates and other service terms. The response by a pipeline carrier to a request for the carrier’s rates and other service terms shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in writing and forwarded to the requesting person promptly after receipt of the request; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promptly made available in electronic form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Rate Increases and Changes to Service Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A pipeline carrier may not increase any common carrier rates or change any common carrier service terms unless 20 days have expired after written or electronic notice is provided to any person who, within the previous 12 months—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has requested such rates or terms under subsection (b); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has made arrangements with the carrier for a shipment that would be subject to such increased rates or changed terms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A pipeline carrier shall provide transportation or service in accordance with the rates and service terms, and any changes thereto, as published or otherwise made available under subsection (b) or (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall, by regulation, establish rules to implement this section. The regulations shall provide for immediate disclosure and dissemination of rates and service terms, including classifications, rules, and practices, and their effective dates. The regulations may modify the 20-day period specified in subsection (c). Final regulations shall be adopted by the Board not later than 180 days after <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 925</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(44)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER B—</num>
<heading>OPERATIONS OF CARRIERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 15721.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Carrier, lessor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms “carrier” and “lessor” include a receiver or trustee of a pipeline carrier and lessor, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lessor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “lessor” means a person owning a pipeline that is leased to and operated by a carrier providing transportation under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Association</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “association” means an organization maintained by or in the interest of a group of pipeline carriers that performs a service, or engages in activities, related to transportation under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15722.</num>
<heading> Records: form; inspection; preservation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may prescribe the form of records required to be prepared or compiled under this subchapter by pipeline carriers and lessors, including records related to movement of traffic and receipts and expenditures of money.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board, or an employee designated by the Board, may on demand and display of proper credentials—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> inspect and examine the lands, buildings, and equipment of a pipeline carrier or lessor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> inspect and copy any record of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a pipeline carrier, lessor, or association; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a person controlling, controlled by, or under common control with a pipeline carrier if the Board considers inspection relevant to that person’s relation to, or transaction with, that carrier.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation Period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may prescribe the time period during which operating, accounting, and financial records must be preserved by pipeline carriers and lessors.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 926</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15723.</num>
<heading> Reports by carriers, lessors, and associations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing of Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board may require pipeline carriers, lessors, and associations, or classes of them as the Board may prescribe, to file annual, periodic, and special reports with the Board containing answers to questions asked by it.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Under Oath</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any report under this section shall be made under oath.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 926</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>