<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 413—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN AIR TRANSPORTATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 41301.</num>
<heading> Requirement for a permit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A foreign air carrier may provide foreign air transportation only if the foreign air carrier holds a permit issued under this chapter authorizing the foreign air transportation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41302.</num>
<heading> Permits of foreign air carriers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation may issue a permit to a person (except a citizen of the United States) authorizing the person to provide foreign air transportation as a foreign air carrier if the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the person is fit, willing, and able to provide the foreign air transportation to be authorized by the permit and to comply with this part and regulations of the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the person is qualified, and has been designated by the government of its country, to provide the foreign air transportation under an agreement with the United States Government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the foreign air transportation to be provided under the permit will be in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41303.</num>
<heading> Transfers of permits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A permit issued under <ref>section 41302 of this title</ref> may be transferred only when the Secretary of Transportation approves the transfer because the transfer is in the public interest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41304.</num>
<heading> Effective periods and amendments, modifications, suspensions, and revocations of permits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may prescribe the period during which a permit issued under <ref>section 41302 of this title</ref> is in effect. After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary may amend, modify, suspend, or revoke the permit if the Secretary finds that action to be in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Suspensions and Restrictions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Without a hearing, but subject to the approval of the President, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> may suspend summarily the permits of foreign air carriers of a foreign country, or amend, modify, or limit the operations of the foreign air carriers under the permits, when the Secretary finds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the action is in the public interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the government, an aeronautical authority, or a foreign air carrier of the foreign country, over the objection of the United States Government, has—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> limited or denied the operating rights of an air carrier; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> engaged in unfair, discriminatory, or restrictive practices that have a substantial adverse competitive impact on an air carrier related to air transportation to, from, through, or over the territory of the foreign country; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to make this subsection effective, may restrict operations between the United States and the foreign country by a foreign air carrier of a third country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Illegal Importation of Controlled Substances</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in consultation with appropriate departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Government, shall reexamine immediately the fitness of a foreign air carrier that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> violates the laws and regulations of the United States related to the illegal importation of a controlled substance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not adopt available measures to prevent the illegal importation of a controlled substance into the United States on its aircraft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when appropriate, shall amend, modify, suspend, or revoke the permit of the carrier issued under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An interested person may file a response with the Secretary opposing or supporting the amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of a permit under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41305.</num>
<heading> Applications for permits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form, Contents, Notice, Response, and Actions on Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A person must apply in writing to the Secretary of Transportation to be issued a permit under <ref>section 41302 of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to require that the application be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> verified;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in a certain form and contain certain information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> served on interested persons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> accompanied by proof of service on those persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When an application is filed, the Secretary shall post a notice of the application in the office of the Secretary and give notice of the application to other persons as required by regulations of the Secretary. An interested person may file a response with the Secretary opposing or supporting the issuance of the permit. The Secretary shall act on an application as expeditiously as possible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may impose terms for providing foreign air transportation under the permit that the Secretary finds may be required in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41306.</num>
<heading> Simplified procedure to apply for, amend, modify, and suspend permits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations that simplify the procedure for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acting on an application for a permit to provide foreign air transportation under <ref>section 41302 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> amending, modifying, or suspending any part of that permit under section 41304(a) or (b) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Opportunity To Respond</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Regulations under this section shall provide for notice and an opportunity for each interested person to file appropriate written evidence and argument. An oral evidentiary hearing is not required to be provided under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41307.</num>
<heading> Presidential review of actions about foreign air transportation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall submit to the President for review each decision of the Secretary to issue, deny, amend, modify, suspend, revoke, or transfer a certificate issued under <ref>section 41102 of this title</ref> authorizing an air carrier, or a permit issued under <ref>section 41302 of this title</ref> authorizing a foreign air carrier, to provide foreign air transportation. The President may disapprove the decision of the Secretary only if the reason for disapproval is based on foreign relations or national defense considerations that are under the jurisdiction of the President. The President may not disapprove a decision of the Secretary if the reason is economic or related to carrier selection. A decision of the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is void if the President disapproves the decision and publishes the reasons (to the extent allowed by national security) for disapproval not later than 60 days after it is submitted to the President; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> takes effect as a decision of the Secretary if the President does not disapprove the decision not later than 60 days after the decision is submitted to the President; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> when effective, may be reviewed judicially under <ref>section 46110 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41308.</num>
<heading> Exemption from the antitrust laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, “antitrust laws” has the same meaning given that term in the first section of the Clayton Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 12</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Secretary of Transportation decides it is required by the public interest, the Secretary, as part of an order under section 41309 or 42111 of this title, may exempt a person affected by the order from the antitrust laws to the extent necessary to allow the person to proceed with the transaction specifically approved by the order and with any transaction necessarily contemplated by the order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an order under <ref>section 41309 of this title</ref> approving an agreement, request, modification, or cancellation, the Secretary, on the basis of the findings required under section 41309(b)(1), shall exempt a person affected by the order from the antitrust laws to the extent necessary to allow the person to proceed with the transaction specifically approved by the order and with any transaction necessarily contemplated by the order.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41309.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements and requests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An air carrier or foreign air carrier may file with the Secretary of Transportation a true copy of or, if oral, a true and complete memorandum of, an agreement (except an agreement related to interstate air transportation), or a request for authority to discuss cooperative arrangements (except arrangements related to interstate air transportation), and any modification or cancellation of an agreement, between the air carrier or foreign air carrier and another air carrier, a foreign carrier, or another carrier.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall approve an agreement, request, modification, or cancellation referred to in subsection (a) of this section when the Secretary finds it is not adverse to the public interest and is not in violation of this part. However, the Secretary shall disapprove—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> or, after periodic review, end approval of, an agreement, request, modification, or cancellation, that substantially reduces or eliminates competition unless the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agreement, request, modification, or cancellation is necessary to meet a serious transportation need or to achieve important public benefits (including international comity and foreign policy considerations); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the transportation need cannot be met or those benefits cannot be achieved by reasonably available alternatives that are materially less anticompetitive; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an agreement that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is between an air carrier not directly operating aircraft in foreign air transportation and a carrier subject to subtitle IV of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> governs the compensation the carrier may receive for the transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Opportunity To Respond or for Hearing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When an agreement, request, modification, or cancellation is filed, the Secretary of Transportation shall give the Attorney General and the Secretary of State written notice of, and an opportunity to submit written comments about, the filing. On the initiative of the Secretary of Transportation or on request of the Attorney General or Secretary of State, the Secretary of Transportation may conduct a hearing to decide whether an agreement, request, modification, or cancellation is consistent with this part whether or not it was approved previously.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In a proceeding before the Secretary of Transportation applying standards under subsection (b)(1) of this section, a party opposing an agreement, request, modification, or cancellation has the burden of proving that it substantially reduces or eliminates competition and that less anticompetitive alternatives are available. The party defending the agreement, request, modification, or cancellation has the burden of proving the transportation need or public benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation shall include the findings required by subsection (b)(1) of this section in an order of the Secretary approving or disapproving an agreement, request, modification, or cancellation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1129</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 308</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(71)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41310.</num>
<heading> Discriminatory practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An air carrier or foreign air carrier may not subject a person, place, port, or type of traffic in foreign air transportation to unreasonable discrimination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review and Negotiation of Discriminatory Foreign Charges</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation shall survey charges imposed on an air carrier by the government of a foreign country or another foreign entity for the use of airport property or airway property in foreign air transportation. If the Secretary of Transportation decides that a charge is discriminatory, the Secretary promptly shall report the decision to the Secretary of State. The Secretaries of State and Transportation promptly shall begin negotiations with the appropriate government to end the discrimination. If the discrimination is not ended in a reasonable time through negotiation, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a compensating charge equal to the discriminatory charge. With the approval of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury shall impose the compensating charge on a foreign air carrier of that country as a condition to accepting the general declaration of the aircraft of the foreign air carrier when it lands or takes off.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall maintain an account to credit money collected under paragraph (1) of this subsection. An air carrier shall be paid from the account an amount certified by the Secretary of Transportation to compensate the air carrier for the discriminatory charge paid to the government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions Against Discriminatory Activity</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Transportation may take actions the Secretary considers are in the public interest to eliminate an activity of a government of a foreign country or another foreign entity, including a foreign air carrier, when the Secretary, on the initiative of the Secretary or on complaint, decides that the activity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an unjustifiable or unreasonable discriminatory, predatory, or anticompetitive practice against an air carrier; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> imposes an unjustifiable or unreasonable restriction on access of an air carrier to a foreign market.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation may deny, amend, modify, suspend, revoke, or transfer under paragraph (1) of this subsection a foreign air carrier permit or tariff under section 41302, 41303, 41304(a), 41504(c), 41507, or 41509 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing of, and Acting on, Complaints</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An air carrier, computer reservations system firm, or a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government may file a complaint under subsection (c) or (g) of this section with the Secretary of Transportation. The Secretary shall approve, deny, or dismiss the complaint, set the complaint for a hearing or investigation, or begin another proceeding proposing remedial action not later than 60 days after receiving the complaint. The Secretary may extend the period for acting for additional periods totaling not more than 30 days if the Secretary decides that with additional time it is likely that a complaint can be resolved satisfactorily through negotiations with the government of the foreign country or foreign entity. The Secretary must act not later than 90 days after receiving the complaint. However, the Secretary may extend this 90-day period for not more than an additional 90 days if, on the last day of the initial 90-day period, the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> negotiations with the government have progressed to a point that a satisfactory resolution of the complaint appears imminent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an air carrier or computer reservations system firm has not been subjected to economic injury by the government or entity as a result of filing the complaint; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the public interest requires additional time before the Secretary acts on the complaint.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out paragraph (1) of this subsection and subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> solicit the views of the Secretaries of Commerce and State and the United States Trade Representative;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> give an affected air carrier or foreign air carrier reasonable notice and an opportunity to submit written evidence and arguments within the time limits of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> submit to the President under section 41307 or 41509(f) of this title actions proposed by the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretaries of State, the Treasury, and Transportation and the heads of other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Government shall keep under review, to the extent of each of their jurisdictions, each form of discrimination or unfair competitive practice to which an air carrier is subject when providing foreign air transportation or a computer reservations system firm is subject when providing services with respect to airline service. Each Secretary and head shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take appropriate action to eliminate any discrimination or unfair competitive practice found to exist; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> request Congress to enact legislation when the authority to eliminate the discrimination or unfair practice is inadequate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation shall report to Congress annually on each action taken under paragraph (1) of this subsection and on the continuing program to eliminate discrimination and unfair competitive practices. The Secretaries of State and the Treasury each shall give the Secretary of Transportation information necessary to prepare the report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after acting on a complaint under this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on action taken under this section on the complaint.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions Against Discriminatory Activity by Foreign CRS Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation may take such actions as the Secretary considers are in the public interest to eliminate an activity of a foreign air carrier that owns or markets a computer reservations system, or of a computer reservations system firm whose principal offices are located outside the United States, when the Secretary, on the initiative of the Secretary or on complaint, decides that the activity, with respect to airline service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is an unjustifiable or unreasonable discriminatory, predatory, or anticompetitive practice against a computer reservations system firm whose principal offices are located inside the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> imposes an unjustifiable or unreasonable restriction on access of such a computer reservations system to a foreign market.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1130</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title VII, § 741</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41311.</num>
<heading> Gambling restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An air carrier or foreign air carrier may not install, transport, or operate, or permit the use of, any gambling device on board an aircraft in foreign air transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “gambling device” means any machine or mechanical device (including gambling applications on electronic interactive video systems installed on board aircraft for passenger use)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which when operated may deliver, as the result of the application of an element of chance, any money or property; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by the operation of which a person may become entitled to receive, as the result of the application of an element of chance, any money or property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–305, title II, § 205(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1583</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41312.</num>
<heading> Ending or suspending foreign air transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An air carrier holding a certificate issued under <ref>section 41102 of this title</ref> to provide foreign air transportation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may end or suspend the transportation to a place under the certificate only when the carrier gives at least 90 days notice of its intention to end or suspend the transportation to the Secretary of Transportation, any community affected by that decision, and the State authority of the State in which a community is located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if it is the only air carrier holding a certificate to provide non-stop or single-plane foreign air transportation between 2 places, may end or suspend the transportation between those places only when the carrier gives at least 60 days notice of its intention to end or suspend the transportation to the Secretary and each community directly affected by that decision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Temporary Suspension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may authorize the temporary suspension of foreign air transportation under subsection (a) of this section when the Secretary finds the suspension is in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(51)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4384</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(72)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41313.</num>
<heading> Plans to address needs of families of passengers involved in foreign air carrier accidents</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aircraft accident</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “aircraft accident” means any aviation disaster, regardless of its cause or suspected cause, that occurs within the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Passenger</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “passenger” has the meaning given such term by section 1136.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of Plans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A foreign air carrier providing foreign air transportation under this chapter shall transmit to the Secretary of Transportation and the Chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board a plan for addressing the needs of the families of passengers involved in an aircraft accident that involves an aircraft under the control of the foreign air carrier and results in any loss of life.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of Plans</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the extent permitted by foreign law which was in effect on the date of the enactment of this section, a plan submitted by a foreign air carrier under subsection (b) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Telephone number</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A plan for publicizing a reliable, toll-free telephone number and staff to take calls to such number from families of passengers involved in an aircraft accident that involves an aircraft under the control of the foreign air carrier and results in any loss of life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of families</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A process for notifying, in person to the extent practicable, the families of passengers involved in an aircraft accident that involves an aircraft under the control of the foreign air carrier and results in any loss of life before providing any public notice of the names of such passengers. Such notice shall be provided by using the services of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the organization designated for the accident under section 1136(a)(2); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other suitably trained individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice provided as soon as possible</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the notice required by paragraph (2) shall be provided as soon as practicable after the foreign air carrier has verified the identity of a passenger on the foreign aircraft, whether or not the names of all of the passengers have been verified.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">List of passengers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An assurance that the foreign air carrier shall provide, immediately upon request, and update a list (based on the best available information at the time of the request) of the names of the passengers aboard the aircraft (whether or not such names have been verified), to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the director of family support services designated for the accident under section 1136(a)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the organization designated for the accident under section 1136(a)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation regarding disposition of remains and effects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the family of each passenger will be consulted about the disposition of any remains and personal effects of the passenger that are within the control of the foreign air carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Return of possessions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that, if requested by the family of a passenger, any possession (regardless of its condition) of that passenger that is within the control of the foreign air carrier will be returned to the family unless the possession is needed for the accident investigation or a criminal investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unclaimed possessions retained</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that any unclaimed possession of a passenger within the control of the foreign air carrier will be retained by the foreign air carrier for not less than 18 months after the date of the accident.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Monuments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the family of each passenger will be consulted about construction by the foreign air carrier of any monument to the passengers built in the United States, including any inscription on the monument.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equal treatment of passengers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the treatment of the families of nonrevenue passengers (and any other victim of the accident, including any victim on the ground) will be the same as the treatment of the families of revenue passengers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service and assistance to families of passengers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the foreign air carrier will work with any organization designated under section 1136(a)(2) on an ongoing basis to ensure that families of passengers receive an appropriate level of services and assistance following an accident.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation to service organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the foreign air carrier will provide reasonable compensation to any organization designated under section 1136(a)(2) for services and assistance provided by the organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel and care expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the foreign air carrier will assist the family of any passenger in traveling to the location of the accident and provide for the physical care of the family while the family is staying at such location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resources for plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the foreign air carrier will commit sufficient resources to carry out the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Substitute measures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a foreign air carrier does not wish to comply with paragraph (10), (11), or (12), a description of proposed adequate substitute measures for the requirements of each paragraph with which the foreign air carrier does not wish to comply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training of employees and agents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that the foreign air carrier will provide adequate training to the employees and agents of the carrier to meet the needs of survivors and family members following an accident.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation on carrier response not covered by plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that, in the event that the foreign air carrier volunteers assistance to United States citizens within the United States with respect to an aircraft accident outside the United States involving any loss of life, the foreign air carrier shall consult with the Board and the Department of State on the provision of the assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice concerning liability for manmade structures.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that, in the case of an accident that results in any damage to a manmade structure or other property on the ground that is not government-owned, the foreign air carrier will promptly provide notice, in writing, to the extent practicable, directly to the owner of the structure or other property about liability for any property damage and means for obtaining compensation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum contents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At a minimum, the written notice shall advise an owner (i) to contact the insurer of the property as the authoritative source for information about coverage and compensation; (ii) to not rely on unofficial information offered by foreign air carrier representatives about compensation by the foreign air carrier for accident-site property damage; and (iii) to obtain photographic or other detailed evidence of property damage as soon as possible after the accident, consistent with restrictions on access to the accident site.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Simultaneous electronic transmission of ntsb hearing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assurance that, in the case of an accident in which the National Transportation Safety Board conducts a public hearing or comparable proceeding at a location greater than 80 miles from the accident site, the foreign air carrier will ensure that the proceeding is made available simultaneously by electronic means at a location open to the public at both the origin city and destination city of the foreign air carrier’s flight if that city is located in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permit and Exemption Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall not approve an application for a permit under section 41302 unless the applicant has included as part of the application or request for exemption a plan that meets the requirements of subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A foreign air carrier shall not be liable for damages in any action brought in a Federal or State court arising out of the performance of the foreign air carrier in preparing or providing a passenger list pursuant to a plan submitted by the foreign air carrier under subsection (c), unless the liability was caused by conduct of the foreign air carrier which was grossly negligent or which constituted intentional misconduct.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–148, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-12-16">Dec. 16, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2681</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>–(c)(1), <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 130</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title VIII, § 809(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2589</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title V, § 539(d)</ref>, div. C, § 1109(b), <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3370</ref>, 3434; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title XI, § 1101(i)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1413</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>