<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 55—</num>
<heading>INTERMODAL TRANSPORTATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5501.</num>
<heading> National Intermodal Transportation System policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the policy of the United States Government to develop a National Intermodal Transportation System that is economically efficient and environmentally sound, provides the foundation for the United States to compete in the global economy, and will move individuals and property in an energy efficient way.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">System Characteristics</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System shall consist of all forms of transportation in a unified, interconnected manner, including the transportation systems of the future, to reduce energy consumption and air pollution while promoting economic development and supporting the United States’ preeminent position in international commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System shall include a National Highway System consisting of the Dwight D. Eisenhower System of Interstate and Defense Highways and those principal arterial roads that are essential for interstate and regional commerce and travel, national defense, intermodal transfer facilities, and international commerce and border crossings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System shall include significant improvements in public transportation necessary to achieve national goals for improved air quality, energy conservation, international competitiveness, and mobility for elderly individuals, individuals with disabilities, and economically disadvantaged individuals in urban and rural areas of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System shall provide improved access to ports and airports, the Nation’s link to commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System shall give special emphasis to the contributions of the transportation sectors to increased productivity growth. Social benefits must be considered with particular attention to the external benefits of reduced air pollution, reduced traffic congestion, and other aspects of the quality of life in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System must be operated and maintained with insistent attention to the concepts of innovation, competition, energy efficiency, productivity, growth, and accountability. Practices that resulted in the lengthy and overly costly construction of the Dwight D. Eisenhower System of Interstate and Defense Highways must be confronted and stopped.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System shall be adapted to “intelligent vehicles”, “magnetic levitation systems”, and other new technologies, wherever feasible and economical, with benefit cost estimates given special emphasis on safety considerations and techniques for cost allocation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> When appropriate, the National Intermodal Transportation System will be financed, as regards Government apportionments and reimbursements, by the Highway Trust Fund. Financial assistance will be provided to State and local governments and their instrumentalities to help carry out national goals related to mobility for elderly individuals, individuals with disabilities, and economically disadvantaged individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The National Intermodal Transportation System must be the centerpiece of a national investment commitment to create the new wealth of the United States for the 21st century.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution and Posting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall distribute copies of the policy in subsections (a) and (b) of this section to each employee of the Department of Transportation and ensure that the policy is posted in all offices of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 5502.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title V, § 25021(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 878</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 5503.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title VI, § 6015(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1571</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5504.</num>
<heading> Model intermodal transportation plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall make grants to States to develop model State intermodal transportation plans that are consistent with the policy set forth in <ref>section 302(e) of this title</ref>. The model plans shall include systems for collecting data related to intermodal transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall award grants to States under this section that represent a variety of geographic regions and transportation needs, patterns, and modes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plan Submission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a condition to a State receiving a grant under this section, the Secretary shall require that the State provide assurances that the State will submit to the Secretary a State intermodal transportation plan not later than 18 months after the date of receipt of the grant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall reserve, from amounts deducted under <ref>section 104(a) of title 23</ref>, $3,000,000 to make grants under this section. The total amount that a State may receive in grants under this section may not be more than $500,000.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 850</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5505.</num>
<heading> University transportation centers program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">University Transportation Centers Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and operation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Research and Technology (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”), shall make grants under this section to eligible nonprofit institutions of higher education to establish and operate university transportation centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Role of centers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The role of each university transportation center referred to in paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to advance transportation expertise and technology in the varied disciplines that comprise the field of transportation through education, research, and technology transfer activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide for a critical multimodal transportation knowledge base outside of the Department of Transportation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to address critical workforce needs and educate the next generation of transportation leaders with respect to the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) of section 6503(c)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Competitive Selection Process.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To receive a grant under this section, a consortium of nonprofit institutions of higher education shall submit to the Secretary an application that is in such form and contains such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Restriction.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A lead institution of a consortium of nonprofit institutions of higher education, as applicable, may only receive 1 grant per fiscal year as a lead institution under this section, except as provided in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for consortium members that are not lead institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a nonprofit institution of higher education that is a member of a consortium of nonprofit institutions of higher education but not the lead institution of such consortium.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall solicit grant applications for national transportation centers, regional transportation centers, and Tier 1 university transportation centers with identical advertisement schedules and deadlines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">General selection criteria.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided by this section, the Secretary shall award grants under this section in nonexclusive candidate topic areas established by the Secretary that address the research priorities described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) of section 6503(c)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, in consultation with the heads of the modal administrations of the Department of Transportation, as appropriate, shall select each recipient of a grant under this section through a competitive process based on the assessment of the Secretary relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the demonstrated ability of the recipient to address each specific topic area described in the research and strategic plans of the recipient;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the demonstrated research, technology transfer, and education resources available to the recipient to carry out this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the ability of the recipient to provide leadership in solving immediate and long-range national and regional transportation problems;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the ability of the recipient to carry out research, education, and technology transfer activities that are multimodal and multidisciplinary in scope;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> the demonstrated commitment of the recipient to carry out transportation workforce development programs through—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> degree-granting programs or programs that provide other industry-recognized credentials; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> outreach activities to attract new entrants into the transportation field, including women and underrepresented populations;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the demonstrated ability of the recipient to disseminate results and spur the implementation of transportation research and education programs through national or statewide continuing education programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the demonstrated commitment of the recipient to the use of peer review principles and other research best practices in the selection, management, and dissemination of research projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> the strategic plan submitted by the recipient describing the proposed research to be carried out by the recipient and the performance metrics to be used in assessing the performance of the recipient in meeting the stated research, technology transfer, education, and outreach goals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> the ability of the recipient to implement the proposed program in a cost-efficient manner, such as through cost sharing and overall reduced overhead, facilities, and administrative costs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transparency.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall provide to each applicant, upon request, any materials, including copies of reviews (with any information that would identify a reviewer redacted), used in the evaluation process of the proposal of the applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall make available to the public on a website of the Department of Transportation a report describing the overall review process under paragraph (4) that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> specific criteria of evaluation used in the review;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> descriptions of the review process; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> explanations of the selected awards.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Outside stakeholders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, consult external stakeholders, including the Transportation Research Board of the National Research Council of the National Academies, to evaluate and competitively review all proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grants.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall select grant recipients under subsection (b) and make grant amounts available to the selected recipients.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">National transportation centers.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall provide grants to 5 consortia that the Secretary determines best meet the criteria described in subsection (b)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Restrictions.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each fiscal year, a grant made available under this paragraph shall be not greater than $4,000,000 and not less than $2,000,000 per recipient.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Focused research</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A consortium receiving a grant under this paragraph shall focus research on 1 of the transportation issue areas specified in section 6503(c).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Matching requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a condition of receiving a grant under this paragraph, a grant recipient shall match 100 percent of the amounts made available under the grant.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sources</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The matching amounts referred to in clause (i) may include amounts made available to the recipient under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>section 504(b) of title 23</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 505 of title 23</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regional university transportation centers.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Location of regional centers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>One regional university transportation center shall be located in each of the 10 Federal regions that comprise the Standard Federal Regions established by the Office of Management and Budget in the document entitled “Standard Federal Regions” and dated April 1974 (circular A–105).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In conducting a competition under subsection (b), the Secretary shall provide grants to 10 consortia on the basis of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the criteria described in subsection (b)(4);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the location of the lead center within the Federal region to be served; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> whether the consortium of institutions demonstrates that the consortium has a well-established, nationally recognized program in transportation research and education, as evidenced by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> recent expenditures by the institution in highway or public transportation research;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a historical track record of awarding graduate degrees in professional fields closely related to highways and public transportation; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> an experienced faculty who specialize in professional fields closely related to highways and public transportation.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restrictions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each fiscal year, a grant made available under this paragraph shall be not greater than $3,000,000 and not less than $1,500,000 per recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Matching requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a condition of receiving a grant under this paragraph, a grant recipient shall match 100 percent of the amounts made available under the grant.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sources</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The matching amounts referred to in clause (i) may include amounts made available to the recipient under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>section 504(b) of title 23</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 505 of title 23</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Focused research.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A regional university transportation center receiving a grant under this paragraph shall carry out research focusing on 1 or more of the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) of section 6503(c)(1).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Focused objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall make a grant to 1 of the 10 regional university transportation centers established under this paragraph for the purpose of furthering the objectives described in subsection (a)(2) in the field of comprehensive transportation safety, congestion, connected vehicles, connected infrastructure, and autonomous vehicles, including the cybersecurity implications of technologies relating to connected vehicles, connected infrastructure, and autonomous vehicles.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tier 1 university transportation centers.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall provide grants of not greater than $2,000,000 and not less than $1,000,000 to not more than 20 recipients to carry out this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Matching requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a condition of receiving a grant under this paragraph, a grant recipient shall match 50 percent of the amounts made available under the grant.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sources</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The matching amounts referred to in clause (i) may include amounts made available to the recipient under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>section 504(b) of title 23</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 505 of title 23</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Focused research</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In awarding grants under this section, consideration shall be given to minority institutions, as defined by section 365 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1067k</ref>), or consortia that include such institutions that have demonstrated an ability in transportation-related research.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Program Coordination.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate the research, education, and technology transfer activities carried out by grant recipients under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> disseminate the results of that research through the establishment and operation of a publicly accessible online information clearinghouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review and evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not less frequently than biennially, and consistent with the plan developed under section 6503, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review and evaluate the programs carried out under this section by grant recipients; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make available to the public on a website of the Department of Transportation a report describing that review and evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program evaluation and oversight</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, the Secretary shall expend not more than 1 and a half percent of the amounts made available to the Secretary to carry out this section for any coordination, evaluation, and oversight activities of the Secretary under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Availability of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts made available to the Secretary to carry out this section shall remain available for obligation by the Secretary for a period of 3 years after the last day of the fiscal year for which the amounts are authorized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Collection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any survey, questionnaire, or interview that the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out reporting requirements relating to any program assessment or evaluation activity under this section, including customer satisfaction assessments, shall not be subject to chapter 35 of title 44.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title V, § 5110(a)</ref>, (d), <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title IX, § 9011(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 863</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title V, § 5401(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. E, title II, § 52009(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 882</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title VI, § 6016</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title V, § 25017</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 873</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5506.</num>
<heading> Advanced transportation research initiative</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Eligible Entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a State agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a local government agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1002</ref>)), including a university transportation center established under section 5505;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a nonprofit organization, including a nonprofit research organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a private sector organization working in collaboration with an entity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish an advanced transportation research pilot program under which the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall establish a process for eligible entities to submit to the Secretary unsolicited research proposals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may enter into arrangements with 1 or more eligible entities to fund research proposed under paragraph (1), in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Research</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may enter into an arrangement with an eligible entity under this section to fund research that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> addresses—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a research need identified by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Administrator of a modal administration of the Department of Transportation; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an issue that the Secretary determines to be important; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> is not duplicative of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any other Federal research project; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any project for which funding is provided by another Federal agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project Review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review each research proposal submitted under the pilot program established under subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> if funding is denied for the research proposal—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> provide to the eligible entity that submitted the proposal a written notice of the denial that, as applicable—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> explains why the research proposal was not selected, including whether the research proposal fails to cover an area of need; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> recommends that the research proposal be submitted to another research program; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if the Secretary recommends that the research proposal be submitted to another research program under clause (i)(II), provide guidance and direction to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the eligible entity; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the proposed research program office; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if the research proposal is selected for funding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide to the eligible entity that submitted the proposal a written notice of the selection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> seek to enter into an arrangement with the eligible entity to provide funding for the proposed research.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Coordination.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the activities carried out under subsection (c) are coordinated with, and do not duplicate the efforts of, programs of the Department of Transportation and other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intraagency coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall coordinate the research carried out under this section with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the research, education, and technology transfer activities carried out by grant recipients under section 5505; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities of other relevant programs of the Department of Transportation, including all modal administrations of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interagency collaboration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall coordinate, as appropriate, regarding fundamental research with the potential for application in the transportation sector with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Director of the National Science Foundation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Energy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Homeland Security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review, Evaluation, and Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not less frequently than biennially, in accordance with the plan developed under section 6503, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review and evaluate the pilot program established under subsection (b), including the research carried out under that pilot program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make public on a website of the Department of Transportation a report describing the review and evaluation under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal Share.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal share of the cost of an activity carried out under this section shall not exceed 80 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-federal share</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All costs directly incurred by the non-Federal partners (including personnel, travel, facility, and hardware development costs) shall be credited toward the non-Federal share of the cost of an activity carried out under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Certain Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of any amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary may use not more than 1.5 percent for coordination, evaluation, and oversight activities under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title V, § 25013(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 867</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5507.</num>
<heading> Transportation workforce outreach program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish and administer a transportation workforce outreach program, under which the Secretary shall carry out a series of public service announcement campaigns during each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of the campaigns carried out under the program under this section shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase awareness of career opportunities in the transportation sector, including aviation pilots, safety inspectors, mechanics and technicians, air traffic controllers, flight attendants, truck and bus drivers, engineers, transit workers, railroad workers, and other transportation professionals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to target awareness of professional opportunities in the transportation sector to diverse segments of the population, including with respect to race, sex, ethnicity, ability (including physical and mental ability), veteran status, and socioeconomic status.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advertising</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use, or authorize the use of, amounts made available to carry out the program under this section for the development, production, and use of broadcast, digital, and print media advertising and outreach in carrying out a campaign under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use to carry out this section any amounts otherwise made available to the Secretary, not to exceed $5,000,000, for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title V, § 25020(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 877</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>TERMINALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5561.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, “civic and cultural activities” includes libraries, musical and dramatic presentations, art exhibits, adult education programs, public meeting places, and other facilities for carrying on an activity any part of which is supported under a law of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5562.</num>
<heading> Assistance projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements To Provide Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall provide financial, technical, and advisory assistance under this chapter to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote, on a feasibility demonstration basis, the conversion of at least 3 rail passenger terminals into intermodal transportation terminals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> preserve rail passenger terminals that reasonably are likely to be converted or maintained pending preparation of plans for their reuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> acquire and use space in suitable buildings of historic or architectural significance but only if use of the space is feasible and prudent when compared to available alternatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage State and local governments, local and regional transportation authorities, common carriers, philanthropic organizations, and other responsible persons to develop plans to convert rail passenger terminals into intermodal transportation terminals and civic and cultural activity centers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter does not affect the eligibility of any rail passenger terminal for preservation or reuse assistance under another program or law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquiring Space</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may acquire space under subsection (a)(3) of this section only after consulting with the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation and the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5563.</num>
<heading> Conversion of certain rail passenger terminals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Provide Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation may provide financial assistance to convert a rail passenger terminal to an intermodal transportation terminal under <ref>section 5562(a)(1) of this title</ref> only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the terminal can be converted to accommodate other modes of transportation the Secretary of Transportation decides are appropriate, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> motorbus transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mass transit (rail or rubber tire); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> airline ticket offices and passenger terminals providing direct transportation to area airports;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terminal is listed on the National Register of Historic Places maintained by the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the architectural integrity of the terminal will be preserved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent practicable, the use of the terminal facilities for transportation may be combined with use of those facilities for other civic and cultural activities, especially when another activity is recommended by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> consultants retained under subsection (b) of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the terminal and the conversion project meet other criteria prescribed by the Secretary of Transportation after consultation with the Council and Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Architectural Integrity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation must employ consultants on whether the architectural integrity of the rail passenger terminal will be preserved under subsection (a)(3) of this section. The Secretary may decide that the architectural integrity will be preserved only if the consultants concur. The Council and Chairman shall recommend consultants to be employed by the Secretary. The consultants also may make recommendations referred to in subsection (a)(4) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Government’s Share of Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may not make a grant under this section for more than 80 percent of the total cost of converting a rail passenger terminal into an intermodal transportation terminal.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5564.</num>
<heading> Interim preservation of certain rail passenger terminals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Grant Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of Transportation may make a grant of financial assistance to a responsible person (including a governmental authority) to preserve a rail passenger terminal under <ref>section 5562(a)(2) of this title</ref>. To receive assistance under this section, the person must be qualified, prepared, committed, and authorized by law to maintain (and prevent the demolition, dismantling, or further deterioration of) the terminal until plans for its reuse are prepared.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation may make a grant of financial assistance under this section only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary decides the rail passenger terminal has a reasonable likelihood of being converted to, or conditioned for reuse as, an intermodal transportation terminal, a civic or cultural activities center, or both; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> planning activity directed toward conversion or reuse has begun and is proceeding in a competent way.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximizing Preservation of Terminals</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts appropriated to carry out this section and <ref>section 5562(a)(2) of this title</ref> shall be expended in the way most likely to maximize the preservation of rail passenger terminals that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reasonably capable of conversion to intermodal transportation terminals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> listed in the National Register of Historic Places maintained by the Secretary of the Interior; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommended (on the basis of architectural integrity and quality) by the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation or the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation may not make a grant under this section for more than 80 percent of the total cost of maintaining the terminal for an interim period of not more than 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5565.</num>
<heading> Encouraging the development of plans for converting certain rail passenger terminals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Grant Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation may make a grant of financial assistance to a qualified person (including a governmental authority) to encourage the development of plans for converting a rail passenger terminal under <ref>section 5562(a)(4) of this title</ref>. To receive assistance under this section, the person must—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be prepared to develop practicable plans that meet zoning, land use, and other requirements of the applicable State and local jurisdictions in which the terminal is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> incorporate into the designs and plans proposed for converting the terminal, features that reasonably appear likely to attract private investors willing to carry out the planned conversion and its subsequent maintenance and operation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> complete the designs and plans for the conversion within the period of time prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making a grant under this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall give preferential consideration to an applicant whose completed designs and plans will be carried out within 3 years after their completion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximizing Conversion and Continued Public Use</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts appropriated to carry out this section and <ref>section 5562(a)(4) of this title</ref> shall be expended in the way most likely to maximize the conversion and continued public use of rail passenger terminals that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> listed in the National Register of Historic Places maintained by the Secretary of the Interior; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommended (on the basis of architectural integrity and quality) by the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation or the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation may not make a grant under this section for more than 80 percent of the total cost of the project for which the financial assistance is provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 853</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(15)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5566.</num>
<heading> Records and audits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Record Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each recipient of financial assistance under this chapter shall keep records required by the Secretary of Transportation. The records shall disclose—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount, and disposition by the recipient, of the proceeds of the assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the total cost of the project for which the assistance was given or used;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount of that part of the cost of the project supplied by other sources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other records that will make an effective audit easier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audits and Inspections</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For 3 years after a project is completed, the Secretary and the Comptroller General may audit and inspect records of a recipient that the Secretary or Comptroller General decides may be related or pertinent to the financial assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5567.</num>
<heading> Preference for preserving buildings of historic or architectural significance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amtrak shall give preference to the use of rail passenger terminal facilities that will preserve buildings of historic or architectural significance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 854</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5568.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following amounts may be appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not more than $15,000,000 to carry out section 5562(a)(1) and (3) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not more than $2,500,000 to carry out <ref>section 5562(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not more than $2,500,000 to carry out <ref>section 5562(a)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated to carry out this chapter remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 854</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>