<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 227—</num>
<heading>STATE RAIL PLANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 22701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter: <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002079">1</ref></chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Private benefit.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “private benefit”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> means a benefit accrued to a person or private entity, other than Amtrak, that directly improves the economic and competitive condition of that person or entity through improved assets, cost reductions, service improvements, or any other means as defined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be determined on a project-by-project basis, based upon an agreement between the parties.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may seek the advice of the States and rail carriers in further defining this term.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Public benefit.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “public benefit”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> means a benefit accrued to the public, including Amtrak, in the form of enhanced mobility of people or goods, environmental protection or enhancement, congestion mitigation, enhanced trade and economic development, improved air quality or land use, more efficient energy use, enhanced public safety or security, reduction of public expenditures due to improved transportation efficiency or infrastructure preservation, and any other positive community effects as defined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be determined on a project-by-project basis, based upon an agreement between the parties.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may seek the advice of the States and rail carriers in further defining this term.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” means any of the 50 States and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State rail transportation authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State rail transportation authority” means the State agency or official responsible under the direction of the Governor of the State or a State law for preparation, maintenance, coordination, and administration of the State rail plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22702.</num>
<heading> Authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each State may prepare and maintain a State rail plan in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall establish the minimum requirements for the preparation and periodic revision of a State rail plan, including that a State shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish or designate a State rail transportation authority to prepare, maintain, coordinate, and administer the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish or designate a State rail plan approval authority to approve the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> submit the State’s approved plan to the Secretary of Transportation for review; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> revise and resubmit a State-approved plan no less frequently than once every 4 years for acceptance by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4948</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title XI, § 11315(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1674</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22703.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of a State rail plan are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To set forth State policy involving freight and passenger rail transportation, including commuter rail operations, in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To establish the period covered by the State rail plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To present priorities and strategies to enhance rail service in the State that benefits the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To serve as the basis for Federal and State rail investments within the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State rail plan shall be coordinated with other State transportation planning goals and programs, including the plan required under <ref>section 135 of title 23</ref>, and set forth rail transportation’s role within the State transportation system.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22704.</num>
<heading> Transparency; coordination; review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preparation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State shall provide adequate and reasonable notice and opportunity for comment and other input to the public, rail carriers, commuter and transit authorities operating in, or affected by rail operations within the State, units of local government, and other interested parties in the preparation and review of its State rail plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intergovernmental Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State shall review the freight and passenger rail service activities and initiatives by regional planning agencies, regional transportation authorities, and municipalities within the State, or in the region in which the State is located, while preparing the plan, and shall include any recommendations made by such agencies, authorities, and municipalities as deemed appropriate by the State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22705.</num>
<heading> Content</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each State rail plan shall, at a minimum, contain the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An inventory of the existing overall rail transportation system and rail services and facilities within the State and an analysis of the role of rail transportation within the State’s surface transportation system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A review of all rail lines within the State, including proposed high-speed rail corridors and significant rail line segments not currently in service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A statement of the State’s passenger rail service objectives, including minimum service levels, for rail transportation routes in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A general analysis of rail’s transportation, economic, and environmental impacts in the State, including congestion mitigation, trade and economic development, air quality, land-use, energy-use, and community impacts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A long-range rail investment program for current and future freight and passenger infrastructure in the State that meets the requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A statement of public financing issues for rail projects and service in the State, including a list of current and prospective public capital and operating funding resources, public subsidies, State taxation, and other financial policies relating to rail infrastructure development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> An identification of rail infrastructure issues within the State that reflects consultation with all relevant stakeholders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A review of major passenger and freight intermodal rail connections and facilities within the State, including seaports, and prioritized options to maximize service integration and efficiency between rail and other modes of transportation within the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> A review of publicly funded projects within the State to improve rail transportation safety and security, including all major projects funded under <ref>section 130 of title 23</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> A performance evaluation of passenger rail services operating in the State, including possible improvements in those services, and a description of strategies to achieve those improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> A compilation of studies and reports on high-speed rail corridor development within the State not included in a previous plan under this subchapter,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">1</ref> and a plan for funding any recommended development of such corridors in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Long-Range Service and Investment Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program content</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A long-range rail investment program included in a State rail plan under subsection (a)(5) shall, at a minimum, include the following matters:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A list of any rail capital projects expected to be undertaken or supported in whole or in part by the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A detailed funding plan for those projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project list content</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The list of rail capital projects shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the anticipated public and private benefits of each such project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a statement of the correlation between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> public funding contributions for the projects; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the public benefits.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations for project list</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In preparing the list of freight and intercity passenger rail capital projects, a State rail transportation authority should take into consideration the following matters:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Contributions made by non-Federal and non-State sources through user fees, matching funds, or other private capital involvement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Rail capacity and congestion effects.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Effects on highway, aviation, and maritime capacity, congestion, or safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Regional balance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Environmental impact.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Economic and employment impacts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Projected ridership and other service measures for passenger rail projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4949</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title XI, § 11315(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1674</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 22706.</num>
<heading> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe procedures for States to submit State rail plans for review under this title, including standardized format and data requirements. State rail plans completed before the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 that substantially meet the requirements of this chapter, as determined by the Secretary, shall be deemed by the Secretary to have met the requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>