<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 451—</num>
<heading>ALCOHOL AND CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES TESTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 45101.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, “controlled substance” means any substance under section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<ref>21 U.S.C. 802</ref>) specified by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45102.</num>
<heading> Alcohol and controlled substances testing programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program for Employees of Air Carriers and Foreign Air Carriers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the interest of aviation safety, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall prescribe regulations that establish a program requiring air carriers and foreign air carriers to conduct preemployment, reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing of airmen, crew members, airport security screening personnel, and other air carrier employees responsible for safety-sensitive functions (as decided by the Administrator) for the use of a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation; and to conduct reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing of airmen, crew members, airport security screening personnel, and other air carrier employees responsible for safety-sensitive functions (as decided by the Administrator) for the use of alcohol in violation of law or a United States Government regulation. The regulations shall permit air carriers and foreign air carriers to conduct preemployment testing of airmen, crew members, airport security screening personnel, and other air carrier employees responsible for safety-sensitive functions (as decided by the Administrator) for the use of alcohol.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When the Administrator considers it appropriate in the interest of safety, the Administrator may prescribe regulations for conducting periodic recurring testing of airmen, crewmembers, airport security screening personnel, and other air carrier employees responsible for safety-sensitive functions for the use of alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a Government regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program for Employees of the Federal Aviation Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Administrator shall establish a program of preemployment, reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing for the use of a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation for employees of the Administration whose duties include responsibility for safety-sensitive functions and shall establish a program of reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing for the use of alcohol in violation of law or a United States Government regulation for such employees. The Administrator may establish a program of preemployment testing for the use of alcohol for such employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When the Administrator considers it appropriate in the interest of safety, the Administrator may prescribe regulations for conducting periodic recurring testing of employees of the Administration responsible for safety-sensitive functions for use of alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a Government regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sanctions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In prescribing regulations under the programs required by this section, the Administrator shall require, as the Administrator considers appropriate, the suspension or revocation of any certificate issued to an individual referred to in this section, or the disqualification or dismissal of the individual, under this chapter when a test conducted and confirmed under this chapter indicates the individual has used alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a Government regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 342(d)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 139(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45103.</num>
<heading> Prohibited service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Alcohol or a Controlled Substance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual may not use alcohol or a controlled substance after <date date="1991-10-28">October 28, 1991</date>, in violation of law or a United States Government regulation and serve as an airman, crewmember, airport security screening employee, air carrier employee responsible for safety-sensitive functions (as decided by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration), or employee of the Administration with responsibility for safety-sensitive functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rehabilitation Required To Resume Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, an individual found to have used alcohol or a controlled substance after <date date="1991-10-28">October 28, 1991</date>, in violation of law or a Government regulation may serve as an airman, crewmember, airport security screening employee, air carrier employee responsible for safety-sensitive functions (as decided by the Administrator), or employee of the Administration with responsibility for safety-sensitive functions only if the individual completes a rehabilitation program described in <ref>section 45105 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance of Prior Duties Prohibited</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual who served as an airman, crewmember, airport security screening employee, air carrier employee responsible for safety-sensitive functions (as decided by the Administrator), or employee of the Administration with responsibility for safety-sensitive functions and who was found by the Administrator to have used alcohol or a controlled substance after <date date="1991-10-28">October 28, 1991</date>, in violation of law or a Government regulation may not carry out the duties related to air transportation that the individual carried out before the finding of the Administrator if the individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> used the alcohol or controlled substance when on duty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> began or completed a rehabilitation program described in <ref>section 45105 of this title</ref> before using the alcohol or controlled substance; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> refuses to begin or complete a rehabilitation program described in <ref>section 45105 of this title</ref> after a finding by the Administrator under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 139(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45104.</num>
<heading> Testing and laboratory requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out <ref>section 45102 of this title</ref>, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall develop requirements that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote, to the maximum extent practicable, individual privacy in the collection of specimens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for laboratories and testing procedures for controlled substances, incorporate the Department of Health and Human Services scientific and technical guidelines dated <date date="1988-04-11">April 11, 1988</date>, and any amendments to those guidelines, including mandatory guidelines establishing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> comprehensive standards for every aspect of laboratory controlled substances testing and laboratory procedures to be applied in carrying out this chapter, including standards requiring the use of the best available technology to ensure the complete reliability and accuracy of controlled substances tests and strict procedures governing the chain of custody of specimens collected for controlled substances testing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the minimum list of controlled substances for which individuals may be tested; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> appropriate standards and procedures for periodic review of laboratories and criteria for certification and revocation of certification of laboratories to perform controlled substances testing in carrying out this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> require that a laboratory involved in controlled substances testing under this chapter have the capability and facility, at the laboratory, of performing screening and confirmation tests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide that all tests indicating the use of alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation be confirmed by a scientifically recognized method of testing capable of providing quantitative information about alcohol or a controlled substance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide that each specimen be subdivided, secured, and labeled in the presence of the tested individual and that a part of the specimen be retained in a secure manner to prevent the possibility of tampering, so that if the individual’s confirmation test results are positive the individual has an opportunity to have the retained part tested by a 2d confirmation test done independently at another certified laboratory if the individual requests the 2d confirmation test not later than 3 days after being advised of the results of the first confirmation test;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> ensure appropriate safeguards for testing to detect and quantify alcohol in breath and body fluid samples, including urine and blood, through the development of regulations that may be necessary and in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide for the confidentiality of test results and medical information (except information about alcohol or a controlled substance) of employees, except that this clause does not prevent the use of test results for the orderly imposition of appropriate sanctions under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> ensure that employees are selected for tests by nondiscriminatory and impartial methods, so that no employee is harassed by being treated differently from other employees in similar circumstances.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45105.</num>
<heading> Rehabilitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program for Employees of Air Carriers and Foreign Air Carriers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall prescribe regulations establishing requirements for rehabilitation programs that at least provide for the identification and opportunity for treatment of employees of air carriers and foreign air carriers referred to in <ref>section 45102(a)(1) of this title</ref> who need assistance in resolving problems with the use of alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation. Each air carrier and foreign air carrier is encouraged to make such a program available to all its employees in addition to the employees referred to in section 45102(a)(1). The Administrator shall decide on the circumstances under which employees shall be required to participate in a program. This subsection does not prevent an air carrier or foreign air carrier from establishing a program under this subsection in cooperation with another air carrier or foreign air carrier.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program for Employees of the Federal Aviation Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish and maintain a rehabilitation program that at least provides for the identification and opportunity for treatment of employees of the Administration whose duties include responsibility for safety-sensitive functions who need assistance in resolving problems with the use of alcohol or a controlled substance.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(58)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4385</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45106.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other laws, regulations, standards, and orders</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on State and Local Government Laws, Regulations, Standards, or Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State or local government may not prescribe, issue, or continue in effect a law, regulation, standard, or order that is inconsistent with regulations prescribed under this chapter. However, a regulation prescribed under this chapter does not preempt a State criminal law that imposes sanctions for reckless conduct leading to loss of life, injury, or damage to property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">International Obligations and Foreign Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In prescribing regulations under this chapter, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall establish only requirements applicable to foreign air carriers that are consistent with international obligations of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall consider applicable laws and regulations of foreign countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretaries of State and Transportation jointly shall request the governments of foreign countries that are members of the International Civil Aviation Organization to strengthen and enforce existing standards to prohibit crewmembers in international civil aviation from using alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Regulations Allowed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not prevent the Administrator from continuing in effect, amending, or further supplementing a regulation prescribed before <date date="1991-10-28">October 28, 1991</date>, governing the use of alcohol or a controlled substance by airmen, crewmembers, airport security screening employees, air carrier employees responsible for safety-sensitive functions (as decided by the Administrator), or employees of the Administration with responsibility for safety-sensitive functions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 139(3)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45107.</num>
<heading> Transportation Security Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Functions Relating to Testing Programs With Respect to Airport Security Screening Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under this chapter with respect to programs relating to testing of airport security screening personnel are transferred to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration. Notwithstanding section 45102(a), the regulations prescribed under section 45102(a) shall require testing of such personnel by their employers instead of by air carriers and foreign air carriers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Chapter With Respect to Employees of Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of this chapter that apply with respect to employees of the Federal Aviation Administration whose duties include responsibility for safety-sensitive functions shall apply with respect to employees of the Transportation Security Administration whose duties include responsibility for security-sensitive functions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 139(4)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 640</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, title I, § 1991(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3642</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>