<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 603—</num>
<heading>USER FEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 60301.</num>
<heading> User fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Schedule of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe a schedule of fees for all natural gas and hazardous liquids transported by pipelines subject to chapter 601 of this title. The fees shall be based on usage (in reasonable relationship to volume-miles, miles, revenues, or a combination of volume-miles, miles, and revenues) of the pipelines. The Secretary shall consider the allocation of resources of the Department of Transportation when establishing the schedule.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Imposition and Time of Collection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee shall be imposed on each person operating a gas pipeline transmission facility, a liquefied natural gas pipeline facility, or a hazardous liquid pipeline facility to which chapter 601 of this title applies. The fee shall be collected before the end of the fiscal year to which it applies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Means of Collection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe procedures to collect fees under this section. The Secretary may use a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government or of a State or local government to collect the fee and may reimburse the department, agency, or instrumentality a reasonable amount for its services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A fee collected under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> related to a gas pipeline facility may be used only for an activity related to gas under chapter 601 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> related to a hazardous liquid pipeline facility may be used only for an activity related to hazardous liquid under chapter 601 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be used only to the extent provided in advance in an appropriation law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Fees prescribed under subsection (a) of this section shall be sufficient to pay for the costs of activities described in subsection (d) of this section. However, the total amount collected for a fiscal year may not be more than 105 percent of the total amount of the appropriations made for the fiscal year for activities to be financed by the fees.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1328</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60302.</num>
<heading> User fees for underground natural gas storage facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee shall be imposed on an entity operating an underground natural gas storage facility subject to section 60141. Any such fee imposed shall be collected before the end of the fiscal year to which it applies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Means of Collection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe procedures to collect fees under this section. The Secretary may use a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government or of a State or local government to collect the fee and may reimburse the department, agency, or instrumentality a reasonable amount for its services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Fees.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Account</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established an Underground Natural Gas Storage Facility Safety Account in the Pipeline Safety Fund established in the Treasury of the United States under section 60301.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of fees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A fee collected under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be deposited in the Underground Natural Gas Storage Facility Safety Account; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the fee is related to an underground natural gas storage facility subject to section 60141, the amount of the fee may be used only for an activity related to underground natural gas storage facility safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No fee may be collected under this section, except to the extent that the expenditure of such fee to pay the costs of an activity related to underground natural gas storage facility safety for which such fee is imposed is provided in advance in an appropriations Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–183, § 12(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-06-22">June 22, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60303.</num>
<heading> Fees for compliance reviews of liquefied natural gas facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Imposition of Fee.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall impose on a person who files with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission an application for a liquefied natural gas facility that has design and construction costs totaling not less than $2,500,000,000 a fee for the necessary expenses of a review, if any, that the Secretary conducts, in connection with that application, to determine compliance with subpart B of part 193 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relation to other review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not impose fees under paragraph (1) and section 60117(<i>o</i>) or 60301(b) for the same compliance review described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Means of Collection.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe procedures to collect fees under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of government entities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government or of a State or local government to collect fees under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reimburse that department, agency, or instrumentality a reasonable amount for the services provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Account</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established an account, to be known as the “Liquefied Natural Gas Siting Account”, in the Pipeline Safety Fund established in the Treasury of the United States under section 60301.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. R, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>