<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 105—</num>
<heading>JURISDICTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10501.</num>
<heading> General jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to this chapter, the Board has jurisdiction over transportation by rail carrier that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> only by railroad; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by railroad and water, when the transportation is under common control, management, or arrangement for a continuous carriage or shipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Jurisdiction under paragraph (1) applies only to transportation in the United States between a place in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State and a place in the same or another State as part of the interstate rail network;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a State and a place in a territory or possession of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a territory or possession of the United States and a place in another such territory or possession;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a territory or possession of the United States and another place in the same territory or possession;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the United States and another place in the United States through a foreign country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the United States and a place in a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The jurisdiction of the Board over—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> transportation by rail carriers, and the remedies provided in this part with respect to rates, classifications, rules (including car service, interchange, and other operating rules), practices, routes, services, and facilities of such carriers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the construction, acquisition, operation, abandonment, or discontinuance of spur, industrial, team, switching, or side tracks, or facilities, even if the tracks are located, or intended to be located, entirely in one State,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is exclusive. Except as otherwise provided in this part, the remedies provided under this part with respect to regulation of rail transportation are exclusive and preempt the remedies provided under Federal or State law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the term “local governmental authority”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has the same meaning given that term by <ref>section 5302 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> includes a person or entity that contracts with the local governmental authority to provide transportation services; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “public transportation” means transportation services described in <ref>section 5302 of this title</ref> that are provided by rail.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Board does not have jurisdiction under this part over—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> public transportation provided by a local government authority; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a solid waste rail transfer facility as defined in <ref>section 10908 of this title</ref>, except as provided under sections 10908 and 10909 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, a local governmental authority, described in paragraph (2), is subject to applicable laws of the United States related to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> safety;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the representation of employees for collective bargaining; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> employment, retirement, annuity, and unemployment systems or other provisions related to dealings between employees and employers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Board has jurisdiction under sections 11102 and 11103 of this title over transportation provided by a local governmental authority only if the Board finds that such governmental authority meets all of the standards and requirements for being a rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Interstate Commerce Commission that were in effect immediately before <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>. The enactment of the ICC Termination Act of 1995 shall neither expand nor contract coverage of employees and employers by the Railway Labor Act, the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974, the Railroad Retirement Tax Act, and the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 807</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(21)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3390</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. A, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title III, § 3030(g)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10502.</num>
<heading> Authority to exempt rail carrier transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In a matter related to a rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part, the Board, to the maximum extent consistent with this part, shall exempt a person, class of persons, or a transaction or service whenever the Board finds that the application in whole or in part of a provision of this part—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not necessary to carry out the transportation policy of <ref>section 10101 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transaction or service is of limited scope; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the application in whole or in part of the provision is not needed to protect shippers from the abuse of market power.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Board may, where appropriate, begin a proceeding under this section on its own initiative or on application by the Secretary of Transportation or an interested party. The Board shall, within 90 days after receipt of any such application, determine whether to begin an appropriate proceeding. If the Board decides not to begin a class exemption proceeding, the reasons for the decision shall be published in the Federal Register. Any proceeding begun as a result of an application under this subsection shall be completed within 9 months after it is begun.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Board may specify the period of time during which an exemption granted under this section is effective.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Board may revoke an exemption, to the extent it specifies, when it finds that application in whole or in part of a provision of this part to the person, class, or transportation is necessary to carry out the transportation policy of <ref>section 10101 of this title</ref>. The Board shall, within 90 days after receipt of a request for revocation under this subsection, determine whether to begin an appropriate proceeding. If the Board decides not to begin a proceeding to revoke a class exemption, the reasons for the decision shall be published in the Federal Register. Any proceeding begun as a result of a request under this subsection shall be completed within 9 months after it is begun.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> No exemption order issued pursuant to this section shall operate to relieve any rail carrier from an obligation to provide contractual terms for liability and claims which are consistent with the provisions of <ref>section 11706 of this title</ref>. Nothing in this subsection or <ref>section 11706 of this title</ref> shall prevent rail carriers from offering alternative terms nor give the Board the authority to require any specific level of rates or services based upon the provisions of <ref>section 11706 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Board may exercise its authority under this section to exempt transportation that is provided by a rail carrier as part of a continuous intermodal movement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Board may not exercise its authority under this section to relieve a rail carrier of its obligation to protect the interests of employees as required by this part.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>