<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 702—</num>
<heading>MULTIMODAL FREIGHT TRANSPORTATION PLANNING AND INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70201.</num>
<heading> State freight advisory committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall encourage each State to establish a freight advisory committee consisting of a representative cross-section of public and private sector freight stakeholders, including representatives of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ports, if applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> freight railroads, if applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shippers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carriers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> freight-related associations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> third-party logistics providers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the freight industry workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the transportation department of the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> metropolitan planning organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> local governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the environmental protection department of the State, if applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the air resources board of the State, if applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> economic development agencies of the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> not-for-profit organizations or community organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each member of a freight advisory committee established under subsection (a) shall have qualifications sufficient to serve on a freight advisory committee, including, as applicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> general business and financial experience;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> experience or qualifications in the areas of freight transportation and logistics;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> experience in transportation planning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> experience representing employees of the freight industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> experience representing a State, local government, or metropolitan planning organization; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> experience representing the views of a community group or not-for-profit organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Role of Committee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A freight advisory committee of a State described in subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> advise the State on freight-related priorities, issues, projects, and funding needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> serve as a forum for discussion for State transportation decisions affecting freight mobility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> communicate and coordinate regional priorities with other organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> promote the sharing of information between the private and public sectors on freight issues; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> participate in the development of the freight plan of the State described in section 70202, including by providing advice regarding the development of the freight investment plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title VIII, § 8001(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title I, § 21107</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 662</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70202.</num>
<heading> State freight plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each State that receives funding under <ref>section 167 of title 23</ref> shall develop a freight plan that provides a comprehensive plan for the immediate and long-range planning activities and investments of the State with respect to freight.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plan Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A State freight plan described in subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an identification of significant freight system trends, needs, and issues with respect to the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the freight policies, strategies, and performance measures that will guide the freight-related transportation investment decisions of the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> when applicable, a listing of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> multimodal critical rural freight facilities and corridors designated within the State under <ref>section 70103 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> critical rural and urban freight corridors designated within the State under <ref>section 167 of title 23</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a description of how the plan will improve the ability of the State to meet the national multimodal freight policy goals described in <ref>section 70101(b) of this title</ref> and the national highway freight program goals described in <ref>section 167 of title 23</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of how innovative technologies and operational strategies, including freight intelligent transportation systems, that improve the safety and efficiency of freight movement, were considered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> in the case of roadways on which travel by heavy vehicles (including mining, agricultural, energy cargo or equipment, and timber vehicles) is projected to substantially deteriorate the condition of the roadways, a description of improvements that may be required to reduce or impede the deterioration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> an inventory of facilities with freight mobility issues, such as bottlenecks, within the State, and for those facilities that are State owned or operated, a description of the strategies the State is employing to address the freight mobility issues;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> consideration of any significant congestion or delay caused by freight movements and any strategies to mitigate that congestion or delay;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> a freight investment plan that, subject to subsection (c)(2), includes a list of priority projects and describes how funds made available to carry out <ref>section 167 of title 23</ref> would be invested and matched;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the most recent commercial motor vehicle parking facilities assessment conducted by the State under subsection (f);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the most recent supply chain cargo flows in the State, expressed by mode of transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> an inventory of commercial ports in the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> if applicable, consideration of the findings or recommendations made by any multi-State freight compact to which the State is a party under section 70204;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the impacts of e-commerce on freight infrastructure in the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> considerations of military freight;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<chapeau> strategies and goals to decrease—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the severity of impacts of extreme weather and natural disasters on freight mobility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the impacts of freight movement on local air pollution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the impacts of freight movement on flooding and stormwater runoff; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the impacts of freight movement on wildlife habitat loss; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> consultation with the State freight advisory committee, if applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Long-Range Plan.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incorporation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State freight plan described in subsection (a) may be developed separately from or incorporated into the statewide strategic long-range transportation plan required by <ref>section 135 of title 23</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fiscal constraint</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The freight investment plan component of a freight plan shall include a project, or an identified phase of a project, only if funding for completion of the project can reasonably be anticipated to be available for the project within the time period identified in the freight investment plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Planning Period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State freight plan described in subsection (a) shall address a 8-year forecast period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Updates.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State shall update a State freight plan described in subsection (a) not less frequently than once every 4 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Freight investment plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State may update a freight investment plan described in subsection (b)(9) more frequently than is required under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial Motor Vehicle Parking Facilities Assessments</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As part of the development or updating, as applicable, of a State freight plan under this section, each State that receives funding under <ref>section 167 of title 23</ref>, in consultation with relevant State motor carrier safety personnel, shall conduct an assessment of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the capability of the State, together with the private sector in the State, to provide adequate parking facilities and rest facilities for commercial motor vehicles engaged in interstate transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the volume of commercial motor vehicle traffic in the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whether there exist any areas within the State with a shortage of adequate commercial motor vehicle parking facilities, including an analysis (economic or otherwise, as the State determines to be appropriate) of the underlying causes of such a shortage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each State freight plan under this section shall include a requirement that the State, in carrying out activities under the State freight plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhance reliability or redundancy of freight transportation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> incorporate the ability to rapidly restore access and reliability with respect to freight transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Approval.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall approve a State freight plan described in subsection (a) if the plan achieves compliance with the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Savings provision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection establishes new procedural requirements for the approval of a State freight plan described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title VIII, § 8001(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title I, § 21104(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 658</ref>, 659.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70203.</num>
<heading> Transportation investment data and planning tools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> begin development of new tools and improvement of existing tools to support an outcome-oriented, performance-based approach to evaluate proposed freight-related and other transportation projects, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> methodologies for systematic analysis of benefits and costs on a national or regional basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> tools for ensuring that the evaluation of freight-related and other transportation projects could consider safety, economic competitiveness, urban and rural access, environmental sustainability, and system condition in the project selection process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> improved methods for data collection and trend analysis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> encouragement of public-private collaboration to carry out data sharing activities while maintaining the confidentiality of all proprietary data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other tools to assist in effective transportation planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identify transportation-related model data elements to support a broad range of evaluation methods and techniques to assist in making transportation investment decisions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at a minimum, in consultation with other relevant Federal agencies, consider any improvements to existing freight flow data collection efforts that could reduce identified freight data gaps and deficiencies and help improve forecasts of freight transportation demand.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult with Federal, State, and other stakeholders to develop, improve, and implement the tools and collect the data described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title VIII, § 8001(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70204.</num>
<heading> Multi-State freight corridor planning</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consent to Multi-State Freight Mobility Compacts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Congress recognizes the right of States, cities, regional planning organizations, federally recognized Indian Tribes, and local public authorities (including public port authorities) that are regionally linked with an interest in a specific nationally or regionally significant multi-State freight corridor to enter into multi-State compacts to promote the improved mobility of goods, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identifying projects along the corridor that benefit multiple States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assembling rights-of-way; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> performing capital improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A multi-State freight compact established by entities under subsection (a) may provide that, in order to carry out the compact, the relevant States or other entities may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> accept contributions from a unit of State or local government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use any Federal or State funds made available for freight mobility infrastructure planning or construction, including applying for grants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> subject to such terms and conditions as the States consider to be advisable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> borrow money on a short-term basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> issue—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> notes for borrowing under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> bonds; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> obtain financing by other means permitted under applicable Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Advisory Committees.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A multi-State freight compact under this section may establish a multi-State freight corridor advisory committee, which shall include representatives of State departments of transportation and other public and private sector entities with an interest in freight mobility, such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> freight railroads;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shippers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> carriers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> freight-related associations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> third-party logistics providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the freight industry workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> environmental organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> community organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> units of local government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An advisory committee established under paragraph (1) may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> advise the parties to the applicable multi-State freight compact with respect to freight-related priorities, issues, projects, and funding needs that impact multi-State—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> freight mobility; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> supply chains;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve as a forum for States, Indian Tribes, and other public entities to discuss decisions affecting freight mobility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> communicate and coordinate multi-State freight priorities with other organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promote the sharing of information between the private and public sectors with respect to freight issues; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> provide information for consideration in the development of State freight plans under section 70202.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grants.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide grants to multi-State freight compacts, or States seeking to form a multi-State freight compact, that seek to improve a route or corridor that is a part of the National Multimodal Freight Network established under section 70103.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">New compacts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To incentivize the establishment of multi-State freight compacts, the Secretary may award a grant for operations costs in an amount of not more than $2,000,000 to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a multi-State freight compact established under subsection (a) during the 2-year period beginning on the date of establishment of the multi-State freight compact; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> States seeking to form a multi-State freight compact described in that subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligibility.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">New multi-state freight compacts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A multi-State freight compact shall be eligible for a grant under this paragraph only during the initial 2 years of operation of the compact.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">States seeking to form a compact</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>States seeking to form a multi-State freight compact shall be eligible for a grant under this paragraph during—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the 2-year period beginning on the date on which an application for a grant under this paragraph with respect to the proposed compact is submitted to the Secretary; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if the compact is formed before the date on which a grant under this paragraph is awarded in accordance with subclause (I), the initial 2 years of operation of the compact.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible to receive a grant under this paragraph, a multi-State freight compact or the applicable States seeking to form a multi-State freight compact shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide a non-Federal match equal to not less than 25 percent of the operating costs of the multi-State freight compact; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> commit to establishing a multi-State freight corridor advisory committee under subsection (c)(1) during the initial 2-year period of operation of the compact.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Existing compacts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may award a grant to multi-State freight compacts that are not eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (2) for operations costs in an amount of not more than $1,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible to receive a grant under this paragraph, a multi-State freight compact shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide a non-Federal match of not less than 50 percent of the operating costs of the compact; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> demonstrate that the compact has established a multi-State freight corridor advisory committee under subsection (c)(1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $5,000,000 for each fiscal year to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title I, § 21106(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 659</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70205.</num>
<heading> National multimodal cooperative freight research program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish and support a national cooperative freight transportation research program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administration by National Academy of Sciences.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to support and carry out administrative and management activities under the program established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advisory committee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To assist the National Academy of Sciences in carrying out this subsection, the National Academy shall establish an advisory committee, the members of which represent a cross-section of multimodal freight stakeholders, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Department of Transportation and other relevant Federal departments and agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> State (including the District of Columbia) departments of transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> units of local government, including public port authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> nonprofit entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> institutions of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> labor organizations representing employees in freight industries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> private sector entities representing various transportation modes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">National research agenda.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The advisory committee established under subsection (b)(2), in consultation with interested parties, shall recommend a national research agenda for the program in accordance with subsection (d), which shall include a multiyear strategic plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action by interested parties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A), an interested party may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> submit to the advisory committee research proposals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> participate in merit reviews of research proposals and peer reviews of research products; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> receive research results.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Research contracts and grants.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The National Academy of Sciences may award research contracts and grants under the program established under subsection (a) through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> open competition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> merit review, conducted on a regular basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Evaluation.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Peer review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract or grant for research under subparagraph (A) may allow peer review of the research results.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programmatic evaluations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Academy of Sciences may conduct periodic programmatic evaluations on a regular basis of a contract or grant for research under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dissemination of findings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The National Academy of Sciences shall disseminate the findings of any research conducted under this paragraph to relevant researchers, practitioners, and decisionmakers through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conferences and seminars;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> field demonstrations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> workshops;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> training programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> presentations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> testimony to government officials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> publicly accessible websites;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> publications for the general public; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> other appropriate means.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of establishment of the program under subsection (a), and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall make available on a public website a report that describes the ongoing research and findings under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Areas for Research</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The national research agenda under subsection (c)(1) shall consider research in the following areas:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Improving the efficiency and resiliency of freight movement, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improving the connections between rural areas and domestic and foreign markets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maximizing infrastructure utility, including improving urban curb-use efficiency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> quantifying the national impact of blocked railroad crossings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> improved techniques for estimating and quantifying public benefits derived from freight transportation projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> low-cost methods to reduce congestion at bottlenecks.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Adapting to future trends in freight, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> considering the impacts of e-commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> automation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> zero-emissions transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Workforce considerations in freight, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> diversifying the freight transportation industry workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> creating and transitioning a workforce capable of designing, deploying, and operating emerging technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal Share.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal share of the cost of an activity carried out under this section shall be up to 100 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of non-federal funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to using funds made available to carry out this section, the National Academy of Sciences may seek and accept additional funding from public and private entities capable of accepting funding from the Department of Transportation, States, units of local government, nonprofit entities, and the private sector.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $3,750,000 for each fiscal year to carry out the program established under subsection (a), to remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program established under subsection (a) shall terminate 5 years after the date of enactment of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title I, § 21204(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70206.</num>
<heading> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subtitle provides additional authority to regulate or direct private activity on freight networks designated under this subtitle.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title VIII, § 8001(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1612</ref>, § 70204; renumbered § 70206, <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title I, § 21106(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 659</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>