<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 475—</num>
<heading>NOISE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>NOISE ABATEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 47501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “airport” means a public-use airport as defined in <ref>section 47102 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “airport operator” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for an airport serving air carriers that have certificates from the Secretary of Transportation, any person holding an airport operating certificate issued under <ref>section 44706 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for any other airport, the person operating the airport.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47502.</num>
<heading> Noise measurement and exposure systems and identifying land use compatible with noise exposure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and United States Government, State, and interstate agencies that the Secretary of Transportation considers appropriate, the Secretary shall by regulation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> establish a single system of measuring noise that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has a highly reliable relationship between projected noise exposure and surveyed reactions of individuals to noise; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is applied uniformly in measuring noise at airports and the surrounding area;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a single system for determining the exposure of individuals to noise resulting from airport operations, including noise intensity, duration, frequency, and time of occurrence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify land uses normally compatible with various exposures of individuals to noise.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47503.</num>
<heading> Noise exposure maps</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission and Preparation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An airport operator may submit to the Secretary of Transportation a noise exposure map showing the noncompatible uses in each area of the map on the date the map is submitted, a description of estimated aircraft operations during a forecast period that is at least 5 years in the future and how those operations will affect the map. The map shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be prepared in consultation with public agencies and planning authorities in the area surrounding the airport; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> comply with regulations prescribed under <ref>section 47502 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Revised Maps.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An airport operator that submits a noise exposure map under subsection (a) shall submit a revised map to the Secretary if, in an area surrounding an airport, a change in the operation of the airport would establish a substantial new noncompatible use, or would significantly reduce noise over existing noncompatible uses, that is not reflected in either the existing conditions map or forecast map currently on file with the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A submission under paragraph (1) shall be required only if the relevant change in the operation of the airport occurs during—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the forecast period of the applicable noise exposure map submitted by an airport operator under subsection (a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the implementation period of the airport operator’s noise compatibility program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2542</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title I, § 174</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47504.</num>
<heading> Noise compatibility programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submissions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An airport operator that submitted a noise exposure map and related information under <ref>section 47503(a) of this title</ref> may submit a noise compatibility program to the Secretary of Transportation after—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consulting with public agencies and planning authorities in the area surrounding the airport, United States Government officials having local responsibility for the airport, and air carriers using the airport; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> notice and an opportunity for a public hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A program submitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall state the measures the operator has taken or proposes to take to reduce existing noncompatible uses and prevent introducing additional noncompatible uses in the area covered by the map. The measures may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing a preferential runway system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> restricting the use of the airport by a type or class of aircraft because of the noise characteristics of the aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> constructing barriers and acoustical shielding and soundproofing public buildings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> using flight procedures to control the operation of aircraft to reduce exposure of individuals to noise in the area surrounding the airport; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> acquiring land, air rights, easements, development rights, and other interests to ensure that the property will be used in ways compatible with airport operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approvals</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall approve or disapprove a program submitted under subsection (a) of this section (except as the program is related to flight procedures referred to in subsection (a)(2)(D) of this section) not later than 180 days after receiving it. The Secretary shall approve the program (except as the program is related to flight procedures referred to in subsection (a)(2)(D)) if the program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not place an unreasonable burden on interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is reasonably consistent with achieving the goal of reducing noncompatible uses and preventing the introduction of additional noncompatible uses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provides for necessary revisions because of a revised map submitted under <ref>section 47503(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A program (except as the program is related to flight procedures referred to in subsection (a)(2)(D) of this section) is deemed to be approved if the Secretary does not act within the 180-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall submit any part of a program related to flight procedures referred to in subsection (a)(2)(D) of this section to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration. The Administrator shall approve or disapprove that part of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall not approve in fiscal years 2004 through 2007 a program submitted under subsection (a) if the program requires the expenditure of funds made available under section 48103 for mitigation of aircraft noise less than 65 DNL.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may incur obligations to make grants from amounts available under <ref>section 48103 of this title</ref> to carry out a project under a part of a noise compatibility program approved under subsection (b) of this section. A grant may be made to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an airport operator submitting the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a unit of local government in the area surrounding the airport, if the Secretary decides the unit is able to carry out the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Soundproofing and acquisition of certain residential buildings and properties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may incur obligations to make grants from amounts made available under <ref>section 48103 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for projects to soundproof residential buildings—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if the airport operator received approval for a grant for a project to soundproof residential buildings pursuant to section 301(d)(4)(B) of the Airport and Airway Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1987;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the airport operator submits updated noise exposure contours, as required by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the Secretary determines that the proposed projects are compatible with the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to an airport operator and unit of local government referred to in paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B) of this subsection to soundproof residential buildings located on residential properties, and to acquire residential properties, at which noise levels are not compatible with normal operations of an airport—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if the airport operator amended an existing local aircraft noise regulation during calendar year 1993 to increase the maximum permitted noise levels for scheduled air carrier aircraft as a direct result of implementation of revised aircraft noise departure procedures mandated for aircraft safety purposes by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration for standardized application at airports served by scheduled air carriers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the airport operator submits updated noise exposure contours, as required by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the Secretary determines that the proposed projects are compatible with the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to an airport operator and unit of local government referred to in paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B) of this subsection to carry out any part of a program developed before <date date="1980-02-18">February 18, 1980</date>, or before implementing regulations were prescribed, if the Secretary decides the program is substantially consistent with reducing existing noncompatible uses and preventing the introduction of additional noncompatible uses and the purposes of this chapter will be furthered by promptly carrying out the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to an airport operator and unit of local government referred to in paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B) of this subsection to soundproof a building in the noise impact area surrounding the airport that is used primarily for educational or medical purposes and that the Secretary decides is adversely affected by airport noise;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to an airport operator of a congested airport (as defined in section 47175) and a unit of local government referred to in paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection to carry out a project to mitigate noise in the area surrounding the airport if the project is included as a commitment in a record of decision of the Federal Aviation Administration for an airport capacity enhancement project (as defined in section 47175) even if that airport has not met the requirements of part 150 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> to an airport operator of a congested airport (as defined in section 47175) and a unit of local government referred to in paragraph (1)(B) to carry out a project to mitigate noise, if the project—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> consists of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> replacement windows, doors, and the installation of through-the-wall air conditioning units; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a contribution of the equivalent costs to be used for reconstruction if reconstruction is the preferred local solution;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is located at a school near the airport; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is included in a memorandum of agreement entered into before <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, even if the airport has not met the requirements of part 150 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and only if the financial limitations of the memorandum are applied.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An airport operator may agree to make a grant made under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection available to a public agency in the area surrounding the airport if the Secretary decides the agency is able to carry out the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Government’s share of a project for which a grant is made under this subsection is the greater of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 80 percent of the cost of the project; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Government’s share that would apply if the amounts available for the project were made available under subchapter I of chapter 471 of this title for a project at the airport.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of subchapter I of chapter 471 of this title related to grants apply to a grant made under this chapter, except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 47109(a) and (b) of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any provision that the Secretary decides is inconsistent with, or unnecessary to carry out, this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aircraft noise primarily caused by military aircraft</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may make a grant under this subsection for a project even if the purpose of the project is to mitigate the effect of noise primarily caused by military aircraft at an airport.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Government Relief From Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Government is not liable for damages from aviation noise because of action taken under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grants for Assessment of Flight Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with subsection (c)(1), the Secretary may make a grant to an airport operator to assist in completing environmental review and assessment activities for proposals to implement flight procedures at such airport that have been approved as part of an airport noise compatibility program under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional staff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may accept funds from an airport operator, including funds provided to the operator under paragraph (1), to hire additional staff or obtain the services of consultants in order to facilitate the timely processing, review, and completion of environmental activities associated with proposals to implement flight procedures at such airport that have been approved as part of an airport noise compatibility program under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receipts credited as offsetting collections</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, any funds accepted under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be credited as offsetting collections to the account that finances the activities and services for which the funds are accepted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be available for expenditure only to pay the costs of activities and services for which the funds are accepted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Fair Market Value of Residential Properties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In approving a project to acquire residential real property using financial assistance made available under this section or chapter 471, the Secretary shall ensure that the appraisal of the property to be acquired disregards any decrease or increase in the fair market value of the real property caused by the project for which the property is to be acquired, or by the likelihood that the property would be acquired for the project, other than that due to physical deterioration within the reasonable control of the owner.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–305, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1580</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(71)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title I, § 154</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title I, § 189</ref>, title III, § 306, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2519</ref>, 2539; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title V</ref>, §§ 504, 505, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1044</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47505.</num>
<heading> Airport noise compatibility planning grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation may make a grant to a sponsor of an airport to develop, for planning purposes, information necessary to prepare and submit—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a noise exposure map and related information under <ref>section 47503 of this title</ref>, including the cost of obtaining the information; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a noise compatibility program under <ref>section 47504 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Amounts and Government’s Share of Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant under subsection (a) of this section may be made from amounts available under <ref>section 48103 of this title</ref>. The United States Government’s share of the grant is the percent for which a project for airport development at an airport would be eligible under section 47109(a) and (b) of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47506.</num>
<heading> Limitations on recovering damages for noise</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person acquiring an interest in property after <date date="1980-02-18">February 18, 1980</date>, in an area surrounding an airport for which a noise exposure map has been submitted under <ref>section 47503 of this title</ref> and having actual or constructive knowledge of the existence of the map may recover damages for noise attributable to the airport only if, in addition to any other elements for recovery of damages, the person shows that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> after acquiring the interest, there was a significant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> change in the type or frequency of aircraft operations at the airport;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> change in the airport layout;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> change in flight patterns; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> increase in nighttime operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the damages resulted from the change or increase.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Constructive Knowledge</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Constructive knowledge of the existence of a map under subsection (a) of this section shall be imputed, at a minimum, to a person if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> before the person acquired the interest, notice of the existence of the map was published at least 3 times in a newspaper of general circulation in the county in which the property is located; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the person is given a copy of the map when acquiring the interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47507.</num>
<heading> Nonadmissibility of noise exposure map and related information as evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No part of a noise exposure map or related information described in <ref>section 47503 of this title</ref> that is submitted to, or prepared by, the Secretary of Transportation and no part of a list of land uses the Secretary identifies as normally compatible with various exposures of individuals to noise may be admitted into evidence or used for any other purpose in a civil action asking for relief for noise resulting from the operation of an airport.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47508.</num>
<heading> Noise standards for air carriers and foreign air carriers providing foreign air transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall require each air carrier and foreign air carrier providing foreign air transportation to comply with noise standards—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary prescribed for new subsonic aircraft in regulations of the Secretary in effect on <date date="1977-01-01">January 1, 1977</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of the International Civil Aviation Organization that are substantially compatible with standards of the Secretary for new subsonic aircraft in regulations of the Secretary at parts 36 and 91 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, prescribed between <date date="1977-01-02">January 2, 1977</date>, and <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance at Phased Rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall require each air carrier and foreign air carrier providing foreign air transportation to comply with the noise standards at a phased rate similar to the rate for aircraft registered in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nondiscrimination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement for air carriers providing foreign air transportation may not be more stringent than the requirement for foreign air carriers.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47509.</num>
<heading> Research program on quiet aircraft technology for propeller and rotor driven aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall conduct a study to identify technologies for noise reduction of propeller driven aircraft and rotorcraft.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Goal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The goal of the study conducted under subsection (a) is to determine the status of research and development now underway in the area of quiet technology for propeller driven aircraft and rotorcraft, including technology that is cost beneficial, and to determine whether a research program to supplement existing research activities is necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In conducting the study required under subsection (a), the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall encourage the participation of the Department of Defense, the Department of the Interior, the airtour industry, the aviation industry, academia and other appropriate groups.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less than 280 days after <date date="1994-08-23">August 23, 1994</date>, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall transmit to Congress a report on the results of the study required under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research and Development Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration determine that additional research and development is necessary and would substantially contribute to the development of quiet aircraft technology, then the agencies shall conduct an appropriate research program in consultation with the entities listed in subsection (c) to develop safe, effective, and economical noise reduction technology (including technology that can be applied to existing propeller driven aircraft and rotorcraft) that would result in aircraft that operate at substantially reduced levels of noise to reduce the impact of such aircraft and rotorcraft on the resources of national parks and other areas.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–305, title III, § 308(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1593</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(86)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47510.</num>
<heading> Tradeoff allowance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding another law or a regulation prescribed or order issued under that law, the tradeoff provisions contained in appendix C of part 36 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, apply in deciding whether an aircraft complies with subpart I of part 91 of title 14.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(72)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47511.</num>
<heading> CLEEN engine and airframe technology partnership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall enter into a cost-sharing cooperative agreement, using a competitive process, with institutions, entities, or consortiums to carry out a program for the development, maturation, and testing of certifiable CLEEN aircraft, engine technologies, and jet fuels for civil airplanes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">CLEEN Engine and Airframe Technology Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “CLEEN aircraft and engine technology” means continuous lower energy, emissions, and noise aircraft and engine technology.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish the performance objectives for the program in terms of the specific objectives to reduce fuel burn, emissions and noise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the program, the Administrator may provide that not less than 2 of the cooperative agreements entered into under this section involve the participation of an entity that is a small business concern (as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>)), provided that the submitted technology proposal of the entity meets, at a minimum, FAA Acquisition Management System requirements and requisite technology readiness levels for entry into the agreement, as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title VII, § 743(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3413</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title X, § 1008</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL AVIATION NOISE POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 47521.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> aviation noise management is crucial to the continued increase in airport capacity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> community noise concerns have led to uncoordinated and inconsistent restrictions on aviation that could impede the national air transportation system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a noise policy must be carried out at the national level;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> local interest in aviation noise management shall be considered in determining the national interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> community concerns can be alleviated through the use of new technology aircraft and the use of revenues, including those available from passenger facility charges, for noise management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> revenues controlled by the United States Government can help resolve noise problems and carry with them a responsibility to the national airport system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> revenues derived from a passenger facility charge may be applied to noise management and increased airport capacity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a precondition to the establishment and collection of a passenger facility charge is the prescribing by the Secretary of Transportation of a regulation establishing procedures for reviewing airport noise and access restrictions on operations of stage 2 and stage 3 aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title I, § 111(c)(2)(A)(vi)</ref>, (B), <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47522.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “air carrier”, “air transportation”, and “United States” have the same meanings given those terms in <ref>section 40102(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “stage 3 noise levels” means the stage 3 noise levels in part 36 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, in effect on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47523.</num>
<heading> National aviation noise policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="1991-07-01">July 1, 1991</date>, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish by regulation a national aviation noise policy that considers this subchapter, including the phaseout and nonaddition of stage 2 aircraft as provided in this subchapter and dates for carrying out that policy and reporting requirements consistent with this subchapter and law existing as of <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detailed Economic Analysis</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The policy shall be based on a detailed economic analysis of the impact of the phaseout date for stage 2 aircraft on competition in the airline industry, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the ability of air carriers to achieve capacity growth consistent with the projected rate of growth for the airline industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the impact of competition in the airline and air cargo industries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the impact on nonhub and small community air service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the impact on new entry into the airline industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47524.</num>
<heading> Airport noise and access restriction review program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The national aviation noise policy established under <ref>section 47523 of this title</ref> shall provide for establishing by regulation a national program for reviewing airport noise and access restrictions on the operation of stage 2 and stage 3 aircraft. The program shall provide for adequate public notice and opportunity for comment on the restrictions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stage</inline> 2 <inline class="small-caps">Aircraft</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, an airport noise or access restriction may include a restriction on the operation of stage 2 aircraft proposed after <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, only if the airport operator publishes the proposed restriction and prepares and makes available for public comment at least 180 days before the effective date of the proposed restriction—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of the anticipated or actual costs and benefits of the existing or proposed restriction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of alternative restrictions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the alternative measures considered that do not involve aircraft restrictions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a comparison of the costs and benefits of the alternative measures to the costs and benefits of the proposed restriction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stage</inline> 3 <inline class="small-caps">Aircraft</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, an airport noise or access restriction on the operation of stage 3 aircraft not in effect on <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, may become effective only if the restriction has been agreed to by the airport proprietor and all aircraft operators or has been submitted to and approved by the Secretary of Transportation after an airport or aircraft operator’s request for approval as provided by the program established under this section. Restrictions to which this paragraph applies include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a restriction on noise levels generated on either a single event or cumulative basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a restriction on the total number of stage 3 aircraft operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a noise budget or noise allocation program that would include stage 3 aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a restriction on hours of operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other restriction on stage 3 aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 180 days after the Secretary receives an airport or aircraft operator’s request for approval of an airport noise or access restriction on the operation of a stage 3 aircraft, the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the restriction. The Secretary may approve the restriction only if the Secretary finds on the basis of substantial evidence that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the restriction is reasonable, nonarbitrary, and nondiscriminatory;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the restriction does not create an unreasonable burden on interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the restriction is not inconsistent with maintaining the safe and efficient use of the navigable airspace;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the restriction does not conflict with a law or regulation of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an adequate opportunity has been provided for public comment on the restriction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the restriction does not create an unreasonable burden on the national aviation system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection do not apply if the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, before <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, has formed a working group (outside the process established by part 150 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations) with a local airport operator to examine the noise impact of air traffic control procedure changes at the airport. However, if an agreement on noise reductions at that airport is made between the airport proprietor and one or more air carriers or foreign air carriers that constitute a majority of the carrier use of the airport, this paragraph applies only to a local action to enforce the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may reevaluate an airport noise or access restriction previously agreed to or approved under this subsection on request of an aircraft operator able to demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Secretary that there has been a change in the noise environment of the affected airport that justifies a reevaluation. The Secretary shall establish by regulation procedures for conducting a reevaluation. A reevaluation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be based on the criteria in paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may be conducted only after 2 years after a decision under paragraph (2) of this subsection has been made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsections (b) and (c) of this section do not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a local action to enforce a negotiated or executed airport noise or access agreement between the airport operator and the aircraft operators in effect on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a local action to enforce a negotiated or executed airport noise or access restriction agreed to by the airport operator and the aircraft operators before <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an intergovernmental agreement including an airport noise or access restriction in effect on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a subsequent amendment to an airport noise or access agreement or restriction in effect on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, that does not reduce or limit aircraft operations or affect aircraft safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an airport noise or access restriction adopted by an airport operator not later than <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, and stayed as of <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, by a court order or as a result of litigation, if any part of the restriction is subsequently allowed by a court to take effect; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a new restriction imposed by an airport operator to replace any part of a restriction described in subclause (A) of this clause that is disallowed by a court, if the new restriction would not prohibit aircraft operations in effect on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a local action that represents the adoption of the final part of a program of a staged airport noise or access restriction if the initial part of the program was adopted during 1988 and was in effect on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Beginning on the 91st day after the Secretary prescribes a regulation under subsection (a) of this section, a sponsor of a facility operating under an airport noise or access restriction on the operation of stage 3 aircraft that first became effective after <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, is eligible for a grant under <ref>section 47104 of this title</ref> and is eligible to impose a passenger facility charge under <ref>section 40117 of this title</ref> only if the restriction has been—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> agreed to by the airport proprietor and aircraft operators;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> approved by the Secretary as required by subsection (c)(1) of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> rescinded.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title I, § 111(c)(2)(A)(vii)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47525.</num>
<heading> Decision about airport noise and access restrictions on certain stage 2 aircraft</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall conduct a study and decide on the application of section 47524(a)–(d) of this title to airport noise and access restrictions on the operation of stage 2 aircraft with a maximum weight of not more than 75,000 pounds. In making the decision, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> noise levels produced by those aircraft relative to other aircraft;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the benefits to general aviation and the need for efficiency in the national air transportation system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the differences in the nature of operations at airports and the areas immediately surrounding the airports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> international standards and agreements on aircraft noise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> other factors the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47526.</num>
<heading> Limitations for noncomplying airport noise and access restrictions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Unless the Secretary of Transportation is satisfied that an airport is not imposing an airport noise or access restriction not in compliance with this subchapter, the airport may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receive money under subchapter I of chapter 471 of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> impose a passenger facility charge under <ref>section 40117 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title I, § 111(c)(2)(A)(viii)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47527.</num>
<heading> Liability of the United States Government for noise damages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a proposed airport noise or access restriction is disapproved under this subchapter, the United States Government shall assume liability for noise damages only to the extent that a taking has occurred as a direct result of the disapproval. The United States Court of Federal Claims has exclusive jurisdiction of a civil action under this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47528.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on operating certain aircraft not complying with stage 3 noise levels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b) or (f) of this section and <ref>section 47530 of this title</ref>, a person may operate after <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, a civil subsonic turbojet (for which an airworthiness certificate other than an experimental certificate has been issued by the Administrator) with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds to or from an airport in the United States only if the Secretary of Transportation finds that the aircraft complies with the stage 3 noise levels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waivers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If, not later than <date date="1999-07-01">July 1, 1999</date>, at least 85 percent of the aircraft used by an air carrier or foreign air carrier to provide air transportation comply with the stage 3 noise levels, the carrier may apply for a waiver of subsection (a) of this section for the remaining aircraft used by the carrier to provide air transportation. The application must be filed with the Secretary not later than <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, or, in the case of a foreign air carrier, the 15th day following the date of the enactment of the Wendell H. Ford Aviation Investment and Reform Act for the 21st Century and must include a plan with firm orders for making all aircraft used by the carrier to provide air transportation comply with the noise levels not later than <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may grant a waiver under this subsection if the Secretary finds it would be in the public interest. In making the finding, the Secretary shall consider the effect of granting the waiver on competition in the air carrier industry and on small community air service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A waiver granted under this subsection may not permit the operation of stage 2 aircraft in the United States after <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Schedule for Phased-In Compliance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall establish by regulation a schedule for phased-in compliance with subsection (a) of this section. The phase-in period shall begin on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, and end before <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>. The regulations shall establish interim compliance dates. The schedule for phased-in compliance shall be based on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed economic analysis of the impact of the phaseout date for stage 2 aircraft on competition in the airline industry, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ability of air carriers to achieve capacity growth consistent with the projected rate of growth for the airline industry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the impact of competition in the airline and air cargo industries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the impact on nonhub and small community air service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the impact on new entry into the airline industry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an analysis of the impact of aircraft noise on individuals residing near airports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Beginning with calendar year 1992—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each air carrier shall submit to the Secretary an annual report on the progress the carrier is making toward complying with the requirements of this section and regulations prescribed under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report on the progress being made toward that compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hawaiian Operations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In this subsection, “turnaround service” means a flight between places only in Hawaii.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An air carrier or foreign air carrier may not operate in Hawaii, or between a place in Hawaii and a place outside the 48 contiguous States, a greater number of stage 2 aircraft with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds than it operated in Hawaii, or between a place in Hawaii and a place outside the 48 contiguous States, on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An air carrier that provided turnaround service in Hawaii on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, using stage 2 aircraft with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds may include in the number of aircraft authorized under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph all stage 2 aircraft with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds that were owned or leased by that carrier on that date, whether or not the aircraft were operated by the carrier on that date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An air carrier may provide turnaround service in Hawaii using stage 2 aircraft with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds only if the carrier provided the service on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> An air carrier operating stage 2 aircraft under this subsection may transport stage 2 aircraft to or from the 48 contiguous States on a nonrevenue basis in order—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to perform maintenance (including major alterations) or preventative maintenance on aircraft operated, or to be operated, within the limitations of paragraph (2)(B); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct operations within the limitations of paragraph (2)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Aircraft Modification, Disposal, Scheduled Heavy Maintenance, or Leasing.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall permit a person to operate after <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, a stage 2 aircraft in nonrevenue service through the airspace of the United States or to or from an airport in the contiguous 48 States in order to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sell, lease, or use the aircraft outside the contiguous 48 States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> scrap the aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> obtain modifications to the aircraft to meet stage 3 noise levels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> perform scheduled heavy maintenance or significant modifications on the aircraft at a maintenance facility located in the contiguous 48 States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> deliver the aircraft to an operator leasing the aircraft from the owner or return the aircraft to the lessor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> prepare or park or store the aircraft in anticipation of any of the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> divert the aircraft to an alternative airport in the contiguous 48 States on account of weather, mechanical, fuel, air traffic control, or other safety reasons while conducting a flight in order to perform any of the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (F).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedure To Be Published</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish and publish a procedure to implement paragraph (1) through the use of categorical waivers, ferry permits, or other means.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutory Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed as interfering with, nullifying, or otherwise affecting determinations made by the Federal Aviation Administration, or to be made by the Administration with respect to applications under part 161 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, that were pending on <date date="1999-11-01">November 1, 1999</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(5) [title II, § 231(a), (b)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–300, 1501A–301; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title VII, § 721(a)</ref>–(c)(1), (d), <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 164</ref>, 165.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47529.</num>
<heading> Nonaddition rule</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and <ref>section 47530 of this title</ref>, a person may operate a civil subsonic turbojet aircraft with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds that is imported into the United States after <date date="1990-11-04">November 4, 1990</date>, only if the aircraft—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> complies with the stage 3 noise levels; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was purchased by the person importing the aircraft into the United States under a legally binding contract made before <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may provide an exemption from subsection (a) of this section to permit a person to obtain modifications to an aircraft to meet the stage 3 noise levels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aircraft Deemed Not Imported</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, an aircraft is deemed not to have been imported into the United States if the aircraft—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> was owned on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a corporation, trust, or partnership organized under the laws of the United States or a State (including the District of Columbia);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual who is a citizen of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an entity that is owned or controlled by a corporation, trust, partnership, or individual described in subclause (A) or (B) of this clause; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enters the United States not later than 6 months after the expiration of a lease agreement (including any extension) between an owner described in clause (1) of this subsection and a foreign carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47530.</num>
<heading> Nonapplication of sections 47528(a)–(d) and 47529 to aircraft outside the 48 contiguous States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 47528(a)–(d) and 47529 of this title do not apply to aircraft used only to provide air transportation outside the 48 contiguous States. A civil subsonic turbojet aircraft with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds that is imported into a noncontiguous State or a territory or possession of the United States after <date date="1990-11-04">November 4, 1990</date>, may be used to provide air transportation in the 48 contiguous States only if the aircraft complies with the stage 3 noise levels.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47531.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person violating section 47528, 47529, 47530, or 47534 of this title or a regulation prescribed under any of those sections is subject to the same civil penalties and procedures under chapter 463 of this title as a person violating section 44701(a) or (b) or any of sections 44702–44716 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(73)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title V, § 506(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47532.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An action taken by the Secretary of Transportation under any of sections 47528–47531 or 47534 of this title is subject to judicial review as provided under <ref>section 46110 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(74)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title V, § 506(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47533.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other laws</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided by <ref>section 47524 of this title</ref>, this subchapter does not affect—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> law in effect on <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, on airport noise or access restrictions by local authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any proposed airport noise or access restriction at a general aviation airport if the airport proprietor has formally initiated a regulatory or legislative process before <date date="1990-10-02">October 2, 1990</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the authority of the Secretary of Transportation to seek and obtain legal remedies the Secretary considers appropriate, including injunctive relief.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47534.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on operating certain aircraft weighing 75,000 pounds or less not complying with stage 3 noise levels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided by this section, after <date date="2015-12-31">December 31, 2015</date>, a person may not operate a civil subsonic jet airplane with a maximum weight of 75,000 pounds or less, and for which an airworthiness certificate (other than an experimental certificate) has been issued, to or from an airport in the United States unless the Secretary of Transportation finds that the aircraft complies with stage 3 noise levels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aircraft Operations Outside 48 Contiguous States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) shall not apply to aircraft operated only outside the 48 contiguous States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Temporary Operations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may allow temporary operation of an aircraft otherwise prohibited from operation under subsection (a) to or from an airport in the contiguous United States by granting a special flight authorization for one or more of the following circumstances:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To sell, lease, or use the aircraft outside the 48 contiguous States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To scrap the aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To obtain modifications to the aircraft to meet stage 3 noise levels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To perform scheduled heavy maintenance or significant modifications on the aircraft at a maintenance facility located in the contiguous 48 States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To deliver the aircraft to an operator leasing the aircraft from the owner or return the aircraft to the lessor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To prepare, park, or store the aircraft in anticipation of any of the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To provide transport of persons and goods in the relief of an emergency situation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To divert the aircraft to an alternative airport in the 48 contiguous States on account of weather, mechanical, fuel, air traffic control, or other safety reasons while conducting a flight in order to perform any of the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (7).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary for the implementation of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Statutory Construction.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">AIP grant assurances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Noncompliance with subsection (a) shall not be construed as a violation of section 47107 or any regulations prescribed thereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pending applications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed as interfering with, nullifying, or otherwise affecting determinations made by the Federal Aviation Administration, or to be made by the Administration, with respect to applications under part 161 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, that were pending on the date of enactment of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>