<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 445—</num>
<heading>FACILITIES, PERSONNEL, AND RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 44501.</num>
<heading> Plans and policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Long Range Plans and Policy Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall make long range plans and policy for the orderly development and use of the navigable airspace, and the orderly development of air navigation facilities and services, that will best meet the needs of, and serve the interests of, civil aeronautics and the national defense, except for needs of the armed forces that are peculiar to air warfare and primarily of military concern.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Airway Capital Investment Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall review, revise, and publish a national airways system plan, known as the Airway Capital Investment Plan, before the beginning of each fiscal year. The plan shall set forth—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for a 10-year period, the research, engineering, procurement, and development programs and the facilities, services, and equipment that the Administrator considers necessary for a system of airways, air traffic services, and navigation aids that will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meet the forecasted needs of civil aeronautics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meet the requirements that the Secretary of Defense establishes for the support of the national defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide the highest degree of safety in air commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for the first and second years of the plan, detailed annual estimates of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number, type, location, and cost of acquiring, operating, and maintaining required facilities and services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of research, engineering, procurement, and development required to improve safety, system capacity, and efficiency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> personnel levels required for the activities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for the third, fourth, and fifth years of the plan, estimates of the total cost of each major program for the 3-year period, and additional major research programs, acquisition of systems, services, and facilities, and changes in personnel levels that may be required to meet long range objectives and that may have significant impact on future funding requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> a 10-year investment plan that considers long range objectives that the Administrator considers necessary to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that safety is given the highest priority in providing for a safe and efficient airway system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meet the current and projected growth of the aerospace industry and the requirements of interstate commerce, the United States Postal Service, and the national defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a list of capital projects that are part of the Next Generation Air Transportation System and funded by amounts appropriated under section 48101(a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Aviation Research Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall prepare and publish annually a national aviation research plan and submit the plan to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives. The plan shall be submitted not later than the date that is 30 days after the date of submission of the President’s budget to Congress. If such report cannot be prepared and submitted by the date that is 30 days after the date of submission of the President’s budget to Congress, the Administrator shall submit, before such date, a letter to the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002150">1</ref> Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives stating the reason for delayed submission, impacts of the delay, and actions taken to address circumstances that led to the delay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The plan shall describe, for a 5-year period, the research, engineering, and development that the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration considers necessary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to ensure the continued capacity, safety, and efficiency of aviation in the United States, considering emerging technologies and forecasted needs of civil aeronautics; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide the highest degree of safety in air travel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The plan shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide estimates by year of the schedule, cost, and work force levels for each active and planned major research and development project under sections 44504, 44505, 44507, 44509, 44511–44513, and 44912 of this title, including activities carried out under cooperative agreements with other Federal departments and agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> specify the goals and the priorities for allocation of resources among the major categories of research and development activities, including the rationale for the priorities identified;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> identify the allocation of resources among long-term research, near-term research, and development activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> identify the individual research and development projects in each funding category that are described in the annual budget request;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> highlight the research and development activities that address specific recommendations of the research advisory committee established under <ref>section 44508 of this title</ref>, and document the recommendations of the committee that are not accepted, specifying the reasons for nonacceptance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> highlight the research and development technology transfer activities that promote technology sharing among government, industry, and academia through the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Subject to section 44912(d)(2) and regulations prescribed under such section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall submit to the committees named in paragraph (1) of this subsection an annual report on the accomplishments of the research completed during the prior fiscal year, including a description of the dissemination to the private sector of research results and a description of any new technologies developed. The report shall be submitted with the plan required under paragraph (1) and be organized to allow comparison with the plan in effect for the prior fiscal year. The report shall be prepared in accordance with requirements of <ref>section 1116 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1173</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–264, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(74)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 195</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title VI, § 618(a)</ref>, title X, § 1004(a), title XI, § 1101(j), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1230</ref>, 1386, 1413.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44502.</num>
<heading> General facilities and personnel authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acquire, establish, improve, operate, and maintain air navigation facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide facilities and personnel to regulate and protect air traffic.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The cost of site preparation work associated with acquiring, establishing, or improving an air navigation facility under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection shall be charged to amounts available for that purpose appropriated under <ref>section 48101(a) of this title</ref>. The Secretary of Transportation may make an agreement with an airport owner or sponsor (as defined in <ref>section 47102 of this title</ref>) so that the owner or sponsor will provide the work and be paid or reimbursed by the Secretary from the appropriated amounts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation may authorize a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government to carry out any duty or power under this subsection with the consent of the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Purchase of instrument landing system.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall purchase precision approach instrument landing system equipment for installation at airports on an expedited basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No less than $30,000,000 of the amounts appropriated under section 48101(a) for each of fiscal years 2000 through 2002 shall be used for the purpose of carrying out this paragraph, including acquisition under new or existing contracts, site preparation work, installation, and related expenditures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Improvements on leased properties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may make improvements to real property leased for no or nominal consideration for an air navigation facility, regardless of whether the cost of making the improvements exceeds the cost of leasing the real property, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the improvements primarily benefit the Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the improvements are essential for accomplishment of the mission of the Federal Aviation Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the interest of the United States Government in the improvements is protected.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification of Necessity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except for Government money expended under this part or for a military purpose, Government money may be expended to acquire, establish, construct, operate, repair, alter, or maintain an air navigation facility only if the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration certifies in writing that the facility is reasonably necessary for use in air commerce or for the national defense. An interested person may apply for a certificate for a facility to be acquired, established, constructed, operated, repaired, altered, or maintained by or for the person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ensuring Conformity With Plans and Policies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To ensure conformity with plans and policies for, and allocation of, airspace by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under <ref>section 40103(b)(1) of this title</ref>, a military airport, military landing area, or missile or rocket site may be acquired, established, or constructed, or a runway may be altered substantially, only if the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration is given reasonable prior notice so that the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may advise the appropriate committees of Congress and interested departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Government on the effect of the acquisition, establishment, construction, or alteration on the use of airspace by aircraft. A disagreement between the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Secretary of Defense or the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration may be appealed to the President for a final decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To ensure conformity, an airport or landing area not involving the expenditure of Government money may be established or constructed, or a runway may be altered substantially, only if the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration is given reasonable prior notice so that the Administrator may provide advice on the effects of the establishment, construction, or alteration on the use of airspace by aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Use and Emergency Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government having jurisdiction over an air navigation facility owned or operated by the Government may provide, under regulations the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality prescribes, for public use of the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The head of a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government having jurisdiction over an airport or emergency landing field owned or operated by the Government may provide, under regulations the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality prescribes, for assistance, and the sale of fuel, oil, equipment, and supplies, to an aircraft, but only when necessary, because of an emergency, to allow the aircraft to continue to the nearest airport operated by private enterprise. The head of the department, agency, or instrumentality shall provide for the assistance and sale at the prevailing local fair market value as determined by the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality. An amount that the head decides is equal to the cost of the assistance provided and the fuel, oil, equipment, and supplies sold shall be credited to the appropriation from which the cost was paid. The balance shall be credited to miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfers of Air Traffic Systems.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (4), an airport in a non-contiguous State may transfer, without consideration, to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, an eligible air traffic system or equipment that conforms to performance specifications of the Administrator if a Government airport aid program, airport development aid program, or airport improvement project grant was used to assist in purchasing the system or equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall accept the eligible air traffic system or equipment and operate and maintain it under criteria of the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “eligible air traffic system or equipment” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an instrument landing system consisting of a glide slope and localizer (if the Administrator has determined that a satellite navigation system cannot provide a suitable approach to an airport);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Automated Weather Observing System weather observation system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a Remote Communication Air/Ground and Remote Communication Outlet communications facility; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a Medium Intensity Approach Lighting System with Runway Alignment Indicator Lights.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement under paragraph (1) that an eligible air traffic system or equipment be purchased in part using a Government airport aid program, airport development aid program, or airport improvement project grant shall not apply if the air traffic system or equipment is installed at an airport that is categorized as a basic or local general aviation airport under the most recently published national plan of integrated airport systems under section 47103.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Airport Space.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may not require an airport owner or sponsor (as defined in section 47102) to provide to the Federal Aviation Administration without cost any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Building construction, maintenance, utilities, or expenses for services relating to air traffic control, air navigation, or weather reporting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Space in a facility owned by the airport owner or sponsor for services relating to air traffic control, air navigation, or weather reporting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any agreement the Secretary may have or make with an airport owner or sponsor for the airport owner or sponsor to provide any of the items described in paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B) at below-market rates; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any grant assurance that requires an airport owner or sponsor to provide land to the Administration without cost for an air traffic control facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–305, title I, § 120(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(54)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(75)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title I, § 153</ref>, title VII, § 712, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 87</ref>, 160; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title I, § 147</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title VII, § 728(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44503.</num>
<heading> Reducing nonessential expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall attempt to reduce the capital, operating, maintenance, and administrative costs of the national airport and airway system to the maximum extent practicable consistent with the highest degree of aviation safety. At least annually, the Secretary shall consult with and consider the recommendations of users of the system on ways to reduce nonessential expenditures of the United States Government for aviation. The Secretary shall give particular attention to a recommendation that may reduce, with no adverse effect on safety, future personnel requirements and costs to the Government required to be recovered from user charges.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44504.</num>
<heading> Improved aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, and appliances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Developmental Work and Service Testing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may conduct or supervise developmental work and service testing to improve aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, and appliances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall conduct or supervise research—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to develop technologies and analyze information to predict the effects of aircraft design, maintenance, testing, wear, and fatigue on the life of aircraft, including nonstructural aircraft systems, and air safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to develop methods of analyzing and improving aircraft maintenance technology and practices, including nondestructive evaluation of aircraft structures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to assess the fire and smoke resistance of aircraft material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to develop improved fire and smoke resistant material for aircraft interiors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to develop and improve fire and smoke containment systems for inflight aircraft fires;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to develop advanced aircraft fuels with low flammability and technologies that will contain aircraft fuels to minimize post-crash fire hazards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to develop technologies and methods to assess the risk of and prevent defects, failures, and malfunctions of products, parts, processes, and articles manufactured for use in aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, and appliances that could result in a catastrophic failure of an aircraft; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> in conjunction with other Federal agencies, as appropriate, to develop technologies and methods to assess the risk of and prevent defects, failures, and malfunctions of products, parts, and processes for use in all classes of unmanned aircraft systems that could result in a catastrophic failure of the unmanned aircraft that would endanger other aircraft in the national airspace system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Buy Items Offering Special Advantages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this section, the Administrator, by negotiation or otherwise, may buy or exchange experimental aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, and appliances that the Administrator decides may offer special advantages to aeronautics.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1176</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 196</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title IX, § 903(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 138</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44505.</num>
<heading> Systems, procedures, facilities, services, and devices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop, alter, test, and evaluate systems, procedures, facilities, services, and devices, and define their performance characteristics, to meet the needs for safe and efficient navigation and traffic control of civil and military aviation, except for needs of the armed forces that are peculiar to air warfare and primarily of military concern; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> select systems, procedures, facilities, services, and devices that will best serve those needs and promote maximum coordination of air traffic control and air defense systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Administrator may make contracts to carry out this subsection without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> When a substantial question exists under paragraph (1) of this subsection about whether a matter is of primary concern to the armed forces, the Administrator shall decide whether the Administrator or the Secretary of the appropriate military department has responsibility. The Administrator shall be given technical information related to each research and development project of the armed forces that potentially applies to, or potentially conflicts with, the common system to ensure that potential application to the common system is considered properly and that potential conflicts with the system are eliminated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research on Human Factors and Simulation Models</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall conduct or supervise research—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to develop a better understanding of the relationship between human factors and aviation accidents and between human factors and air safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to enhance air traffic controller, mechanic, and flight crew performance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to develop a human-factor analysis of the hazards associated with new technologies to be used by air traffic controllers, mechanics, and flight crews;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to identify innovative and effective corrective measures for human errors that adversely affect air safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> to develop or procure dynamic simulation models and tools of the air traffic control system and airport design and operating procedures that will provide analytical technology—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to predict airport and air traffic control safety and capacity problems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to evaluate planned research projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to test proposed revisions in airport and air traffic control operations programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to develop a better understanding of the relationship between human factors and unmanned aircraft system safety; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to develop or procure dynamic simulation models and tools for integrating all classes of unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system without any degradation of existing levels of safety for all national airspace system users.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research on Developing and Maintaining a Safe and Efficient System</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall conduct or supervise research on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> airspace and airport planning and design;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> airport capacity enhancement techniques;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> human performance in the air transportation environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> aviation safety and security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the supply of trained air transportation personnel, including pilots and mechanics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> other aviation issues related to developing and maintaining a safe and efficient air transportation system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Research on Design for Certification.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, the Administrator shall conduct research on methods and procedures to improve both confidence in and the timeliness of certification of new technologies for their introduction into the national airspace system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, the Administrator shall develop a plan for the research under paragraph (1) that contains objectives, proposed tasks, milestones, and a 5-year budgetary profile.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall enter into an arrangement with the National Research Council to conduct an independent review of the plan developed under paragraph (2) and shall provide the results of that review to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may enter into cooperative agreements on a cost-shared basis with Federal and non-Federal entities that the Administrator may select in order to conduct, encourage, and promote aviation research, engineering, and development, including the development of prototypes and demonstration models.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–305, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title IX</ref>, §§ 903(b), 905, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 138</ref>, 139; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title VI, § 618(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1231</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44506.</num>
<heading> Air traffic controllers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research on Effect of Automation on Performance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To develop the means necessary to establish appropriate selection criteria and training methodologies for the next generation of air traffic controllers, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall conduct research to study the effect of automation on the performance of the next generation of air traffic controllers and the air traffic control system. The research shall include investigating—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> methods for improving and accelerating future air traffic controller training through the application of advanced training techniques, including the use of simulation technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the role of automation in the air traffic control system and its physical and psychological effects on air traffic controllers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the attributes and aptitudes needed to function well in a highly automated air traffic control system and the development of appropriate testing methods for identifying individuals with those attributes and aptitudes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> innovative methods for training potential air traffic controllers to enhance the benefits of automation and maximize the effectiveness of the air traffic control system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> new technologies and procedures for exploiting automated communication systems, including Mode S Transponders, to improve information transfers between air traffic controllers and aircraft pilots.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research on Human Factor Aspects of Automation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrators of the Federal Aviation Administration and National Aeronautics and Space Administration may make an agreement for the use of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s unique human factor facilities and expertise in conducting research activities to study the human factor aspects of the highly automated environment for the next generation of air traffic controllers. The research activities shall include investigating—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> human perceptual capabilities and the effect of computer-aided decision making on the workload and performance of air traffic controllers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information management techniques for advanced air traffic control display systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> air traffic controller workload and performance measures, including the development of predictive models.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collegiate Training Initiative</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may maintain the Collegiate Training Initiative program by making new agreements and continuing existing agreements with institutions of higher education (as defined by the Administrator) under which the institutions prepare students for the position of air traffic controller with the Department of Transportation (as defined in <ref>section 2109 of title 5</ref>). The Administrator may establish standards for the entry of institutions into the program and for their continued participation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may appoint an individual who has successfully completed a course of training in a program described in paragraph (1) of this subsection to the position of air traffic controller noncompetitively in the excepted service (as defined in <ref>section 2103 of title 5</ref>). An individual appointed under this paragraph serves at the pleasure of the Administrator, subject to <ref>section 7511 of title 5</ref>. However, an appointment under this paragraph may be converted from one in the excepted service to a career conditional or career appointment in the competitive civil service (as defined in <ref>section 2102 of title 5</ref>) when the individual achieves full performance level air traffic controller status, as decided by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The authority under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph to make appointments in the excepted service expires on <date date="1997-10-06">October 6, 1997</date>, except that the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may extend the authority for one or more successive one-year periods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Air Traffic Control Specialist Qualification Training.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of air traffic control specialists</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator is authorized to appoint a qualified air traffic control specialist candidate for placement in an airport traffic control facility if the candidate has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> received a control tower operator certification (referred to in this subsection as a “CTO” certificate); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> satisfied all other applicable qualification requirements for an air traffic control specialist position, including successful completion of orientation training at the Federal Aviation Administration Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation and benefits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual appointed under paragraph (1) shall receive the same compensation and benefits, and be treated in the same manner as, any other individual appointed as a developmental air traffic controller.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report that evaluates the effectiveness of the air traffic control specialist qualification training provided pursuant to this section, including the graduation rates of candidates who received a CTO certificate and are working in airport traffic control facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Administrator determines that air traffic control specialists appointed pursuant to this subsection are more successful in carrying out the duties of an air traffic controller than air traffic control specialists hired from the general public without any such certification, the Administrator shall increase, to the maximum extent practicable, the number of appointments of candidates who possess such certification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for travel expenses associated with certifications.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Administrator may accept reimbursement from an educational entity that provides training to an air traffic control specialist candidate to cover reasonable travel expenses of the Administrator associated with issuing certifications to such candidates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of reimbursements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, any reimbursement authorized to be collected under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be credited as offsetting collections to the account that finances the activities and services for which the reimbursement is accepted;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> be available for expenditure only to pay the costs of activities and services for which the reimbursement is accepted, including all costs associated with collecting such reimbursement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> remain available until expended.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staffing Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall submit annually to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the staffing standards used to determine the number of fully certified air traffic controllers needed to operate the air traffic control system of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for each air traffic control facility operated by the Federal Aviation Administration—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the current certified professional controller staffing levels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the operational staffing targets for certified professional controllers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the anticipated certified professional controller attrition for each of the next 3 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of certified professional controller trainees;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a 3-year projection of the number of controllers needed to be employed to operate the system to meet the standards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a detailed plan for employing the controllers, including projected budget requests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Hiring of Certain Air Traffic Control Specialists.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consideration of applicants.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ensuring selection of most qualified applicants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In appointing individuals to the position of air traffic controller, the Administrator shall give preferential consideration to qualified individuals maintaining 52 consecutive weeks of air traffic control experience involving the full-time active separation of air traffic after receipt of an air traffic certification or air traffic control facility rating within 5 years of application while serving at—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a Federal Aviation Administration air traffic control facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a civilian or military air traffic control facility of the Department of Defense (including a facility of the National Guard); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a tower operating under contract with the Federal Aviation Administration under section 47124.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consideration of additional applicants.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After giving preferential consideration to applicants under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall consider additional applicants for the position of air traffic controller by giving further preferential consideration, within each qualification category based upon pre-employment testing results (including application of veterans’ preference as required under section 40122(g)(2)(B)), to pool 1 applicants described in clause (ii) before pool 2 applicants described in clause (iii).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pool 1</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Pool 1 applicants are individuals who—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> have successfully completed air traffic controller training and graduated from an institution participating in the Collegiate Training Initiative program maintained under subsection (c)(1) and who have received from the institution—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> an appropriate recommendation; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> an endorsement certifying that the individual would have met the requirements in effect as of <date date="2013-12-31">December 31, 2013</date>, for an appropriate recommendation;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> are eligible for a veterans recruitment appointment pursuant to <ref>section 4214 of title 38</ref> and provide a Certificate of Release or Discharge from Active Duty within 120 days of the announcement closing;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> are eligible veterans (as defined in <ref>section 4211 of title 38</ref>) maintaining aviation experience obtained in the course of the individual’s military experience; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> are preference eligible veterans (as defined in <ref>section 2108 of title 5</ref>).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pool 2</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Pool 2 applicants are individuals who apply under a vacancy announcement recruiting from all United States citizens.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special rule.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), after giving preferential consideration to applicants under subparagraph (A) and if, after consulting with the labor organization recognized as the exclusive representative of air traffic controllers under <ref>section 7111 of title 5</ref>, the Administrator determines there are unique circumstances affecting a covered facility that warrant a vacancy announcement with a limited area of consideration, the Administrator may consider applicants for the position of air traffic controller who apply under a vacancy announcement recruiting from the local commuting area for that covered facility.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Biographical assessments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall not use any biographical assessment with respect to an applicant under this subparagraph who would otherwise qualify as a Pool 1 applicant under subparagraph (B)(ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered facility defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subparagraph the term “covered facility” means a radar facility with at least 1,000,000 operations annually that is located in a metropolitan statistical area (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget) with a population estimate by the Bureau of the Census of more than 15,000,000 (as of <date date="2016-07-01">July 1, 2016</date>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of biographical assessments.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Biographical assessments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall not use any biographical assessment when hiring under paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reconsideration of applicants disqualified on basis of biographical assessments.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an individual described in paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (1)(B)(ii), who applied for the position of air traffic controller with the Administration in response to Vacancy Announcement FAA–AMC–14–ALLSRCE–33537 (issued on <date date="2014-02-10">February 10, 2014</date>), was disqualified from the position as the result of a biographical assessment, the Administrator shall provide the applicant an opportunity to reapply for the position as soon as practicable under the revised hiring practices.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of age restriction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall waive any maximum age restriction for the position of air traffic controller with the Administration that would otherwise disqualify an individual from the position if the individual—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is reapplying for the position pursuant to clause (i) on or before <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> met the maximum age requirement on the date of the individual’s previous application for the position during the interim hiring process.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum entry age for experienced controllers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3307 of title 5</ref>, except for individuals covered by the program described in paragraph (4), the maximum limit of age for an original appointment to a position as an air traffic controller shall be 35 years of age for those maintaining 52 weeks of air traffic control experience involving the full-time active separation of air traffic after receipt of an air traffic certification or air traffic control facility rating in a civilian or military air traffic control facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retired military controllers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator may establish a program to provide an original appointment to a position as an air traffic controller for individuals who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are on terminal leave pending retirement from active duty military service or have retired from active duty military service within 5 years of applying for the appointment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have held either an air traffic certification or air traffic control facility rating according to Administration standards within 5 years of applying for the appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–190, title II, § 2106(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. M, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI</ref>, §§ 1132, 1133, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1615</ref>, 1616; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title IV</ref>, §§ 433, 437(e)(2), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1174</ref>, 1178.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44507.</num>
<heading> Regions and centers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Civil Aeromedical Institute established by <ref>section 106(j) of this title</ref> may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> conduct civil aeromedical research, including research related to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the protection and survival of aircraft occupants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> medical accident investigation and airman medical certification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> toxicology and the effects of drugs on human performance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the impact of disease and disability on human performance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> vision and its relationship to human performance and equipment design;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> human factors of flight crews, air traffic controllers, mechanics, inspectors, airway facility technicians, and other individuals involved in operating and maintaining aircraft and air traffic control equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> agency work force optimization, including training, equipment design, reduction of errors, and identification of candidate tasks for automation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make comments to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration on human factors aspects of proposed air safety regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make comments to the Administrator on human factors aspects of proposed training programs, equipment requirements, standards, and procedures for aviation personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> advise, assist, and represent the Federal Aviation Administration in the human factors aspects of joint projects between the Administration and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government, industry, and governments of foreign countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide medical consultation services to the Administrator about medical certification of airmen.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1179</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title V, § 524(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title II, § 206(h)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1046</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44508.</num>
<heading> Research advisory committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There is a research advisory committee in the Federal Aviation Administration. The committee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide advice and recommendations to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and Congress about needs, objectives, plans, approaches, content, and accomplishments of all aviation research and development activities and programs carried out, including those under sections 44504, 44505, 44507, 44511–44513, and 44912 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assist in ensuring that the research is coordinated with similar research being conducted outside the Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> review the operations of the regional centers of air transportation excellence established under <ref>section 44513 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> annually review the allocation made by the Administrator of the amounts authorized by <ref>section 48102(a) of this title</ref> among the major categories of research and development activities carried out by the Administration and provide advice and recommendations to the Administrator on whether such allocation is appropriate to meet the needs and objectives identified under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Administrator may establish subordinate committees to provide advice on specific areas of research conducted under sections 44504, 44505, 44507, 44511–44513, and 44912 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members, Chairman, Pay, and Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The committee is composed of not more than 30 members appointed by the Administrator from among individuals who are not employees of the Administration and who are specially qualified to serve on the committee because of their education, training, or experience. In appointing members of the committee, the Administrator shall ensure that the regional centers of air transportation excellence, universities, corporations, associations, consumers, and other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government are represented.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Administrator shall designate the chairman of the committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member of the committee serves without pay. However, the Administrator may allow a member, when attending meetings of the committee or a subordinate committee, expenses as authorized under <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support Staff, Information, and Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall provide support staff for the committee. On request of the committee, the Administrator shall provide information, administrative services, and supplies that the Administrator considers necessary for the committee to carry out its duties and powers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 1013 of title 5</ref> does not apply to the committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use and Limitation of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than .1 percent of the amounts made available to conduct research under sections 44504, 44505, 44507, 44511–44513, and 44912 of this title may be used by the Administrator to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A limitation on amounts available for obligation by or for the committee does not apply to amounts made available to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Written Reply.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 60 days after receiving any recommendation from the research advisory committee, the Administrator shall provide a written reply to the research advisory committee that, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> clearly states whether the Administrator accepts or rejects the recommendation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> explains the rationale for the Administrator’s decision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sets forth the timeframe in which the Administrator will implement the recommendation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> describes the steps the Administrator will take to implement the recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transparency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The written reply to the research advisory committee, when transmitted to the research advisory committee, shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> made publicly available on the research advisory committee website; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transmitted to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National aviation research plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The national aviation research plan required under section 44501(c) shall include a summary of all research advisory committee recommendations and a description of the status of their implementation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1180</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–264, title XI, § 1104</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title VII, § 712</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3410</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(313)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title XI, § 1101</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1414</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44509.</num>
<heading> Demonstration projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation may carry out under this chapter demonstration projects that the Secretary considers necessary for research and development activities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44510.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1148</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44511.</num>
<heading> Aviation research grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make grants to institutions of higher education and nonprofit research organizations to conduct aviation research in areas the Administrator considers necessary for the long-term growth of civil aviation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An institution of higher education or nonprofit research organization interested in receiving a grant under this section may submit an application to the Administrator. The application must be in the form and contain the information the Administrator requires.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation, Review, and Evaluation Process</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall establish a solicitation, review, and evaluation process that ensures—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> providing grants under this section for proposals having adequate merit and relevancy to the mission of the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a fair geographical distribution of grants under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the inclusion of historically black institutions of higher education and other minority nonprofit research organizations for grant consideration under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each person receiving a grant under this section shall maintain records that the Administrator requires as being necessary to facilitate an effective audit and evaluation of the use of money provided under the grant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Airport Cooperative Research Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall maintain an airport cooperative research program to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify problems that are shared by airport operating agencies and can be solved through applied research but that are not being adequately addressed by existing Federal research programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fund research to address those problems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Governance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall appoint an independent governing board for the research program established under this subsection. The governing board shall be appointed from candidates nominated by national associations representing public airport operating agencies, airport executives, State aviation officials, and the scheduled airlines, and shall include representatives of appropriate Federal agencies. <ref>Section 1013 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to the governing board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to provide staff support to the governing board established under paragraph (2) and to carry out projects proposed by the governing board that the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2012-09-30">September 30, 2012</date>, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress a report on the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1181</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(74)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title VII, § 712</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(314)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4340</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44512.</num>
<heading> Catastrophic failure prevention research grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make grants to institutions of higher education and nonprofit research organizations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to conduct aviation research related to the development of technologies and methods to assess the risk of, and prevent, defects, failures, and malfunctions of products, parts, processes, and articles manufactured for use in aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, and appliances that could result in a catastrophic failure of an aircraft; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to establish centers of excellence for continuing the research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation, Application, Review, and Evaluation Process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish a solicitation, application, review, and evaluation process that ensures providing grants under this section for proposals having adequate merit and relevancy to the research described in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1182</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44513.</num>
<heading> Regional centers of air transportation excellence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make grants to institutions of higher education to establish and operate regional centers of air transportation excellence. The locations shall be distributed in a geographically fair way.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The responsibilities of each center established under this section shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> conducting research on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> airspace and airport planning and design;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> airport capacity enhancement techniques;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> human performance in the air transportation environment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> aviation safety and security;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the supply of trained air transportation personnel, including pilots and mechanics; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> other aviation issues related to developing and maintaining a safe and efficient air transportation system; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> interpreting, publishing, and disseminating the results of the research.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In conducting research described in paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, each center may make contracts with nonprofit research organizations and other appropriate persons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An institution of higher education interested in receiving a grant under this section may submit an application to the Administrator. The application must be in the form and contain the information that the Administrator requires by regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall select recipients of grants under this section on the basis of the following criteria:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the extent to which the needs of the State in which the applicant is located are representative of the needs of the region for improved air transportation services and facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the demonstrated research and extension resources available to the applicant to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the ability of the applicant to provide leadership in making national and regional contributions to the solution of both long-range and immediate air transportation problems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent to which the applicant has an established air transportation program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the demonstrated ability of the applicant to disseminate results of air transportation research and educational programs through a statewide or regionwide continuing education program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the projects the applicant proposes to carry out under the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenditure Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be made under this section in a fiscal year only if the recipient makes an agreement with the Administrator that the Administrator requires to ensure that the recipient will maintain its total expenditures from all other sources for establishing and operating the center and related research activities at a level at least equal to the average level of those expenditures in the 2 fiscal years of the recipient occurring immediately before <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Government’s Share of Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Government’s share of establishing and operating a center and all related research activities that grant recipients carry out shall not exceed 50 percent of the costs, except that the Administrator may increase such share to a maximum of 75 percent of the costs for a fiscal year if the Administrator determines that a center would be unable to carry out the authorized activities described in this section without additional funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocating Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall allocate amounts made available to carry out this section in a geographically fair way.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall transmit annually to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate at the time of the President’s budget request a report that lists—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the research projects that have been initiated by each center in the preceding year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of funding for each research project and the funding source;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the institutions participating in each research project and their shares of the overall funding for each research project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the level of cost-sharing for each research project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title IX, § 907</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44514.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 337</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1093</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44515.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1148</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44516.</num>
<heading> Human factors program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Human Factors Training.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Air traffic controllers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> address the problems and concerns raised by the National Research Council in its report “The Future of Air Traffic Control” on air traffic control automation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> respond to the recommendations made by the National Research Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pilots and flight crews</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall work with representatives of the aviation industry and appropriate aviation programs associated with universities to develop specific training curricula to address critical safety problems, including problems of pilots—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in recovering from loss of control of an aircraft, including handling unusual attitudes and mechanical malfunctions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in deviating from standard operating procedures, including inappropriate responses to emergencies and hazardous weather;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in awareness of altitude and location relative to terrain to prevent controlled flight into terrain; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in landing and approaches, including nonprecision approaches and go-around procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Test Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish a test program in cooperation with air carriers to use model Jeppesen approach plates or other similar tools to improve precision-like landing approaches for aircraft.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall transmit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the status of the Administration’s efforts to encourage the adoption and implementation of advanced qualification programs for air carriers under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advanced Qualification Program Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “advanced qualification program” means an alternative method for qualifying, training, certifying, and ensuring the competency of flight crews and other commercial aviation operations personnel subject to the training and evaluation requirements of parts 121 and 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title VII, § 713(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44517.</num>
<heading> Program to permit cost sharing of air traffic modernization projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the requirements of this section, the Secretary may carry out a program under which the Secretary may make grants to project sponsors for not more than 10 eligible projects per fiscal year for the purpose of improving aviation safety and enhancing mobility of the Nation’s air transportation system by encouraging non-Federal investment in critical air traffic control equipment and software.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Share</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal share of the cost of an eligible project carried out under the program shall not exceed 33 percent. The non-Federal share of the cost of an eligible project shall be provided from non-Federal sources, including revenues collected pursuant to section 40117.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Grant Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No eligible project may receive more than $5,000,000 in Federal funds under the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall use amounts appropriated under section 48101(a) to carry out the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible project</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “eligible project” means a project to purchase equipment or software relating to the Nation’s air traffic control system that is certified or approved by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and that promotes safety, efficiency, or mobility. Such projects may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> airport-specific air traffic facilities and equipment, including local area augmentation systems, instrument landing systems, weather and wind shear detection equipment, and lighting improvements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> automation tools to effect improvements in airport capacity, including passive final approach spacing tools and traffic management advisory equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> equipment and software that enhance airspace control procedures or assist in en route surveillance, including oceanic and offshore flight tracking.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project sponsor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “project sponsor” means any major user of the national airspace system, as determined by the Secretary, including a public-use airport or a joint venture between a public-use airport and one or more air carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers of Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and upon agreement by the Administrator, a project sponsor may transfer, without consideration, to the Federal Aviation Administration, facilities, equipment, or automation tools, the purchase of which was assisted by a grant made under this section, if such facilities, equipment or tools meet Federal Aviation Administration operation and maintenance criteria.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall issue advisory guidelines on the implementation of the program. The guidelines shall not be subject to administrative rulemaking requirements under subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title I, § 183(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44518.</num>
<heading> Advanced Materials Center of Excellence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continued operations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> continue operation of the Advanced Materials Center of Excellence (referred to in this section as the “Center”); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make a determination on whether to award a grant to the Center not later than 90 days after the date on which the grants officer of the Federal Aviation Administration recommends a proposal for award of such grant to the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Center shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> focus on applied research and training on the safe use of composites and advanced materials, and related manufacturing practices, in airframe structures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct research and development into aircraft structure crash worthiness and passenger safety, as well as address safe and accessible air travel of individuals with a disability (as defined in section 382.3 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation)), including materials required to facilitate safe wheelchair restraint systems on commercial aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Center shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote and facilitate collaboration among member universities, academia, the Administration, the commercial aircraft industry, including manufacturers, commercial air carriers, and suppliers, and other appropriate stakeholders for the purposes under subsection (a) and the activities described in paragraphs (2) through (4);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> carry out research and development activities to advance technology, improve engineering practices, and facilitate continuing education in relevant areas of study, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> all structural materials, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> metallic and non-metallic based additive materials, ceramic materials, carbon fiber polymers, and thermoplastic composites;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the long-term material and structural behavior of such materials; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> evaluating the resiliency and long-term durability of advanced materials in high temperature conditions and in engines for applications in advanced aircraft; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> structural technologies, such as additive manufacturing, to be used in applications within the commercial aircraft industry, including traditional fixed-wing aircraft, rotorcraft, and emerging aircraft types such as advanced air mobility aircraft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct research activities for the purpose of improving the safety and certification of aviation structures, materials, and additively manufactured aviation products and components; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conducting <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002151">1</ref> research activities to advance the safe movement of all passengers, including individuals with a disability (as defined in section 382.3 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation)), and individuals using personal wheelchairs in flight, that takes into account the modeling, engineering, testing, operating, and training issues significant to all passengers and relevant stakeholders.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Out of amounts appropriated under section 48102(a), the Administrator may expend not more than $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2023 to carry out this section. Amounts appropriated under the preceding sentence for each fiscal year shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title VII, § 762(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3428</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title X, § 1005</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44519.</num>
<heading> Certification personnel continuing education and training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop a program for regular recurrent training of engineers, inspectors, and other subject-matter experts employed in the Aircraft Certification Service of the Administration in accordance with the training strategy developed pursuant to section 231 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<ref>Public Law 115–254</ref>; <ref>132 Stat. 3256</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, implement measures, including assignments in multiple divisions of the Aircraft Certification Service, to ensure that such engineers and other subject-matter experts in the Aircraft Certification Service have access to diverse professional opportunities that expand their knowledge and skills;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop a program to provide continuing education and training to Administration personnel who hold positions involving aircraft certification and flight standards, including human factors specialists, engineers, flight test pilots, inspectors, and, as determined appropriate by the Administrator, industry personnel who may be responsible for compliance activities including designees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> in consultation with outside experts, develop—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an education and training curriculum on current and new aircraft technologies, human factors, project management, and the roles and responsibilities associated with oversight of designees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommended practices for compliance with Administration regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that actions taken pursuant to subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> permit engineers, inspectors, and other subject matter experts to continue developing knowledge of, and expertise in, new and emerging technologies in systems design, flight controls, principles of aviation safety, system oversight, and certification project management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> minimize the likelihood of an individual developing an inappropriate bias toward a designer or manufacturer of aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, or appliances;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> are consistent with any applicable collective bargaining agreements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> account for gaps in knowledge and skills (as identified by the Administrator in consultation with the exclusive bargaining representatives certified under <ref>section 7111 of title 5</ref>, United States Code) between Administration employees and private-sector employees for each group of Administration employees covered under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2028 to carry out this section. Amounts appropriated under the preceding sentence for any fiscal year shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 112(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2331</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 306(d)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1072</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44520.</num>
<heading> Center of Excellence for Alternative Jet Fuels and Environment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall continue operation of the Center of Excellence for Alternative Jet Fuels and Environment (in this section referred to as the “Center”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Center shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> focus on research to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assist in the development, qualification, and certification of the use of aviation fuel from alternative and renewable sources (such as biomass, next-generation feedstocks, alcohols, organic acids, hydrogen, bioderived chemicals and gaseous carbon) for commercial aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assist in informing the safe use of alternative aviation fuels in commercial aircraft that also apply electrified aircraft propulsion systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> reduce community exposure to civilian aircraft noise and pollutant emissions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> inform decision making to support United States leadership on international aviation environmental issues, including the development of domestic and international standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> improve and expand the scientific understanding of civil aviation noise and pollutant emissions and their impacts, as well as support the development of improved modeling approaches and tools;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> examine the use of novel technologies and other forms of innovation to reduce noise, emissions, and fuel burn in commercial aircraft; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> support collaboration with other Federal agencies, industry stakeholders, research institutions, and other relevant entities to accelerate the research, development, testing, evaluation, and demonstration programs and facilitate United States sustainability and competitiveness in aviation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall carry out the work of the Center through the use of grants or other measures, as determined appropriate by the Administrator pursuant to section 44513, including through interagency agreements and coordination with other Federal agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Participation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation of educational and research institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the responsibilities described in subsection (b), the Center shall include, as appropriate, participation by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> institutions of higher education and research institutions that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have existing facilities for research, development, and testing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> leverage private sector partnerships;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other Federal agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> consortia with experience across the alternative fuels supply chain, including with research, feedstock development and production, small-scale development, testing, and technology evaluation related to the creation, processing, production, and transportation of alternative aviation fuel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> consortia with experience in innovative technologies to reduce noise, emissions, and fuel burn in commercial aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of nasa facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Center shall, in consultation with the Administrator of NASA, consider using, on a reimbursable basis, the existing and available capacity in aeronautics research facilities at the Langley Research Center, the NASA John H. Glenn Center at the Neil A. Armstrong Test Facility, and other appropriate facilities of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title X, § 1017(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>