<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 501—</num>
<heading>BUY-AMERICAN PREFERENCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50101.</num>
<heading> Buying goods produced in the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may obligate an amount that may be appropriated to carry out section 106(k), 44502(a)(2), or 44509, subchapter I of chapter 471, or chapter 481 (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110) of this title for a project only if steel and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may waive subsection (a) of this section if the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> applying subsection (a) would be inconsistent with the public interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the steel and goods produced in the United States are not produced in a sufficient and reasonably available amount or are not of a satisfactory quality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> when procuring a facility or equipment under section 44502(a)(2) or 44509, subchapter I of chapter 471, or chapter 481 (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110) of this title—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the cost of components and subcomponents produced in the United States is more than 60 percent of the cost of all components of the facility or equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> final assembly of the facility or equipment has occurred in the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> including domestic material will increase the cost of the overall project by more than 25 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Labor Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, labor costs involved in final assembly are not included in calculating the cost of components.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Certain Rolling Stock Procurements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Financial assistance made available under the provisions described in subsection (a) shall not be used in awarding a contract or subcontract to an entity on or after the date of enactment of this subsection for the procurement of rolling stock for use in an airport-related project if the manufacturer of the rolling stock—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is incorporated in or has manufacturing facilities in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is owned or controlled by, is a subsidiary of, or is otherwise related legally or financially to a corporation based in a country that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is identified as a nonmarket economy country (as defined in section 771(18) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1677(18)</ref>)) as of the date of enactment of this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> was identified by the United States Trade Representative in the most recent report required by section 182 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2242</ref>) as a foreign country included on the priority watch list defined in subsection (g)(3) of that section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is subject to monitoring by the Trade Representative under section 306 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2416</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “otherwise related legally or financially” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a minority relationship or investment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> relationship with or investment in a subsidiary, joint venture, or other entity based in a country described in paragraph (1)(B) that does not export rolling stock or components of rolling stock for use in the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Corporation based in people’s republic of china</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A)(i), for purposes of paragraph (1), the term “otherwise related legally or financially” includes a minority relationship or investment if the relationship or investment involves a corporation based in the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">International agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection shall be applied in a manner consistent with the obligations of the United States under international agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Waiver.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may waive the limitation described in paragraph (1) using the criteria described in subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 10 days after issuing a waiver under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1298</ref>, § 49101; renumbered § 50101 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(88)(D)</ref>, (89), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title VII, § 768(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50102.</num>
<heading> Restricting contract awards because of discrimination against United States goods or services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person or enterprise domiciled or operating under the laws of a foreign country may not make a contract or subcontract under section 106(k), 44502(a)(2), or 44509, subchapter I of chapter 471, or chapter 481 (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110) of this title or subtitle B of title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (<ref>Public Law 101–508</ref>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–353</ref>) if the government of that country unfairly maintains, in government procurement, a significant and persistent pattern of discrimination against United States goods or services that results in identifiable harm to United States businesses, that the President identifies under section 305(g)(1)(A) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2515(g)(1)(A)</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1298</ref>, § 49102; renumbered § 50102 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(88)(D)</ref>, (89), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title VII, § 768(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50103.</num>
<heading> Contract preference for domestic firms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “domestic firm” means a business entity incorporated, and conducting business, in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “foreign firm” means a business entity not described in clause (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make, with a domestic firm, a contract related to a grant made under section 44511, 44512, or 44513 of this title that, under competitive procedures, would be made with a foreign firm, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Administrator decides, and the Secretary of Commerce and the United States Trade Representative concur, that the public interest requires making the contract with the domestic firm, considering United States international obligations and trade relations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the difference between the bids submitted by the foreign firm and the domestic firm is not more than 6 percent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the final product of the domestic firm will be assembled completely in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> at least 51 percent of the final product of the domestic firm will be produced in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (b) of this section does not apply if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> compelling national security considerations require that subsection (b) of this section not apply; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Trade Representative decides that making the contract would violate the multilateral trade agreements (as defined in <ref>section 3501(4) of title 19</ref>) or an international agreement to which the United States is a party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to Certain Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies only to a contract related to a grant made under section 44511, 44512, or 44513 of this title for which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an amount is authorized by section 48102(a), (b), or (d) of this title to be made available for the fiscal years ending <date date="1991-09-30">September 30, 1991</date>, and <date date="1992-09-30">September 30, 1992</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a solicitation for bid is issued after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall submit a report to Congress on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contracts to which this section applies that are made with foreign firms in the fiscal years ending <date date="1991-09-30">September 30, 1991</date>, and <date date="1992-09-30">September 30, 1992</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of contracts that meet the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, but that the Trade Representative decides would violate the multilateral trade agreements (as defined in <ref>section 3501(4) of title 19</ref>) or an international agreement to which the United States is a party; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of contracts made under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1298</ref>, § 49103; renumbered § 50103, <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(88)(D)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1002(i)</ref>, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50104.</num>
<heading> Restriction on airport projects using products or services of foreign countries denying fair market opportunities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition and Rules for Construing Section</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “project” has the same meaning given that term in <ref>section 47102 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> each foreign instrumentality and each territory and possession of a foreign country administered separately for customs purposes is a separate foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an article substantially produced or manufactured in a foreign country is a product of the country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a service provided by a person that is a national of a foreign country or that is controlled by a national of a foreign country is a service of the country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Use of Available Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An amount made available under subchapter I of chapter 471 of this title may not be used for a project that uses a product or service of a foreign country during any period the country is on the list maintained by the United States Trade Representative under subsection (d)(1) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply when the Secretary of Transportation decides that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> applying paragraph (1) to the product, service, or project is not in the public interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a product or service of the same class or type and of satisfactory quality is not produced or offered in the United States, or in a foreign country not listed under subsection (d)(1) of this section, in a sufficient and reasonably available amount; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the project cost will increase by more than 20 percent if the product or service is excluded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decisions on Denial of Fair Market Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after a report is submitted to Congress under section 181(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2241(b)</ref>), the Trade Representative, for a construction project of more than $500,000 for which the government of a foreign country supplies any part of the amount, shall decide whether the foreign country denies fair market opportunities for products and suppliers of the United States in procurement or for United States bidders. In making the decision, the Trade Representative shall consider information obtained in preparing the report and other information the Trade Representative considers relevant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">List of Countries Denying Fair Market Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Trade Representative shall maintain a list of each foreign country the Trade Representative finds under subsection (c) of this section is denying fair market opportunities. The country shall remain on the list until the Trade Representative decides the country provides fair market opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Trade Representative shall publish in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> annually the list required under paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any modification of the list made before the next list is published.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1299</ref>, § 49104; renumbered § 50104 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(88)(D)</ref>, (89), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title VII, § 768(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50105.</num>
<heading> Fraudulent use of “Made in America” label</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary of Transportation decides that a person intentionally affixed a “Made in America” label to goods sold in or shipped to the United States that are not made in the United States, the Secretary shall declare the person ineligible, for not less than 3 nor more than 5 years, to receive a contract or grant from the United States Government related to a contract made under section 106(k), 44502(a)(2), or 44509, subchapter I of chapter 471, or chapter 481 (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110) of this title or subtitle B of title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (<ref>Public Law 101–508</ref>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–353</ref>). The Secretary may bring a civil action to enforce this section in any district court of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1300</ref>, § 49105; renumbered § 50105 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(88)(D)</ref>, (89), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title VII, § 768(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>