<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 111—</num>
<heading>OPERATIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11101.</num>
<heading> Common carrier transportation, service, and rates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A rail carrier providing transportation or service subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part shall provide the transportation or service on reasonable request. A rail carrier shall not be found to have violated this section because it fulfills its reasonable commitments under contracts authorized under <ref>section 10709 of this title</ref> before responding to reasonable requests for service. Commitments which deprive a carrier of its ability to respond to reasonable requests for common carrier service are not reasonable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A rail carrier shall also provide to any person, on request, the carrier’s rates and other service terms. The response by a rail carrier to a request for the carrier’s rates and other service terms shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in writing and forwarded to the requesting person promptly after receipt of the request; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promptly made available in electronic form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A rail carrier may not increase any common carrier rates or change any common carrier service terms unless 20 days have expired after written or electronic notice is provided to any person who, within the previous 12 months—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has requested such rates or terms under subsection (b); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has made arrangements with the carrier for a shipment that would be subject to such increased rates or changed terms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> With respect to transportation of agricultural products, in addition to the requirements of subsections (a), (b), and (c), a rail carrier shall publish, make available, and retain for public inspection its common carrier rates, schedules of rates, and other service terms, and any proposed and actual changes to such rates and service terms. For purposes of this subsection, agricultural products shall include grain as defined in section 3 of the United States Grain Standards Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 75</ref>) and all products thereof, and fertilizer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A rail carrier shall provide transportation or service in accordance with the rates and service terms, and any changes thereto, as published or otherwise made available under subsection (b), (c), or (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Board shall, by regulation, establish rules to implement this section. The regulations shall provide for immediate disclosure and dissemination of rates and service terms, including classifications, rules, and practices, and their effective dates. Final regulations shall be adopted by the Board not later than 180 days after <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 830</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(25)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11102.</num>
<heading> Use of terminal facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Board may require terminal facilities, including main-line tracks for a reasonable distance outside of a terminal, owned by a rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part, to be used by another rail carrier if the Board finds that use to be practicable and in the public interest without substantially impairing the ability of the rail carrier owning the facilities or entitled to use the facilities to handle its own business. The rail carriers are responsible for establishing the conditions and compensation for use of the facilities. However, if the rail carriers cannot agree, the Board may establish conditions and compensation for use of the facilities under the principle controlling compensation in condemnation proceedings. The compensation shall be paid or adequately secured before a rail carrier may begin to use the facilities of another rail carrier under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A rail carrier whose terminal facilities are required to be used by another rail carrier under this section is entitled to recover damages from the other rail carrier for injuries sustained as the result of compliance with the requirement or for compensation for the use, or both as appropriate, in a civil action, if it is not satisfied with the conditions for use of the facilities or if the amount of the compensation is not paid promptly.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Board may require rail carriers to enter into reciprocal switching agreements, where it finds such agreements to be practicable and in the public interest, or where such agreements are necessary to provide competitive rail service. The rail carriers entering into such an agreement shall establish the conditions and compensation applicable to such agreement, but, if the rail carriers cannot agree upon such conditions and compensation within a reasonable period of time, the Board may establish such conditions and compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board may require reciprocal switching agreements entered into by rail carriers pursuant to this subsection to contain provisions for the protection of the interests of employees affected thereby.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Board shall complete any proceeding under subsection (a) or (b) within 180 days after the filing of the request for relief.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11103.</num>
<heading> Switch connections and tracks</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> On application of the owner of a lateral branch line of railroad, or of a shipper tendering interstate traffic for transportation, a rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part shall construct, maintain, and operate, on reasonable conditions, a switch connection to connect that branch line or private side track with its railroad and shall furnish cars to move that traffic to the best of its ability without discrimination in favor of or against the shipper when the connection—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is reasonably practicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> can be made safely; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> will furnish sufficient business to justify its construction and maintenance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If a rail carrier fails to install and operate a switch connection after application is made under subsection (a) of this section, the owner of the lateral branch line of railroad or the shipper may file a complaint with the Board under <ref>section 11701 of this title</ref>. The Board shall investigate the complaint and decide the safety, practicability, justification, and compensation to be paid for the connection. The Board may direct the rail carrier to comply with subsection (a) of this section only after a full hearing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CAR SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11121.</num>
<heading> Criteria</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part shall furnish safe and adequate car service and establish, observe, and enforce reasonable rules and practices on car service. The Board may require a rail carrier to provide facilities and equipment that are reasonably necessary to furnish safe and adequate car service if the Board decides that the rail carrier has materially failed to furnish that service. The Board may begin a proceeding under this paragraph when an interested person files an application with it. The Board may act only after a hearing on the record and an affirmative finding, based on the evidence presented, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing the facilities or equipment will not materially and adversely affect the ability of the rail carrier to provide safe and adequate transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount spent for the facilities or equipment, including a return equal to the rail carrier’s current cost of capital, will be recovered; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> providing the facilities or equipment will not impair the ability of the rail carrier to attract adequate capital.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board may require a rail carrier to file its car service rules with the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Board may designate and appoint agents and agencies to make and carry out its directions related to car service and matters under sections 11123 and 11124(a)(1) of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Board shall consult, as it considers necessary, with the National Grain Car Council on matters within the charter of that body.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11122.</num>
<heading> Compensation and practice</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The regulations of the Board on car service shall encourage the purchase, acquisition, and efficient use of freight cars. The regulations may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the compensation to be paid for the use of a locomotive, freight car, or other vehicle;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the other terms of any arrangement for the use by a rail carrier of a locomotive, freight car, or other vehicle not owned by the rail carrier using the locomotive, freight car, or other vehicle, whether or not owned by another carrier, shipper, or third person; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sanctions for nonobservance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The rate of compensation to be paid for each type of freight car shall be determined by the expense of owning and maintaining that type of freight car, including a fair return on its cost giving consideration to current costs of capital, repairs, materials, parts, and labor. In determining the rate of compensation, the Board shall consider the transportation use of each type of freight car, the national level of ownership of each type of freight car, and other factors that affect the adequacy of the national freight car supply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11123.</num>
<heading> Situations requiring immediate action to serve the public</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> When the Board determines that shortage of equipment, congestion of traffic, unauthorized cessation of operations, failure of existing commuter rail passenger transportation operations caused by a cessation of service by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, or other failure of traffic movement exists which creates an emergency situation of such magnitude as to have substantial adverse effects on shippers, or on rail service in a region of the United States, or that a rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part cannot transport the traffic offered to it in a manner that properly serves the public, the Board may, to promote commerce and service to the public, for a period not to exceed 30 days—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> direct the handling, routing, and movement of the traffic of a rail carrier and its distribution over its own or other railroad lines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require joint or common use of railroad facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prescribe temporary through routes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> give directions for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preference or priority in transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> embargoes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> movement of traffic under permits; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in the case of a failure of existing freight or commuter rail passenger transportation operations caused by a cessation of service by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, direct the continuation of the operations and dispatching, maintenance, and other necessary infrastructure functions related to the operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except with respect to proceedings under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board may act under this section on its own initiative or on application without regard to subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Rail carriers may establish between themselves the terms of compensation for operations, and use of facilities and equipment, required under this section. When rail carriers do not agree on the terms of compensation under this section, the Board may establish the terms for them. The Board may act under subsection (a) before conducting a proceeding under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), when a rail carrier is directed under this section to operate the lines of another rail carrier due to that carrier’s cessation of operations, compensation for the directed operations shall derive only from revenues generated by the directed operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a failure of existing freight or commuter rail passenger transportation operations caused by a cessation of service by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, the Board shall provide funding to fully reimburse the directed service provider for its costs associated with the activities directed under subsection (a), including the payment of increased insurance premiums. The Board shall order complete indemnification against any and all claims associated with the provision of service to which the directed rail carrier may be exposed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Board may extend any action taken under subsection (a) of this section beyond 30 days if the Board finds that a transportation emergency described in subsection (a) continues to exist. Action by the Board under subsection (a) of this section may not remain in effect for more than 240 days beyond the initial 30-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Board may not take action under this section that would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cause a rail carrier to operate in violation of this part; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> impair substantially the ability of a rail carrier to serve its own customers adequately, or to fulfill its common carrier obligations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A rail carrier directed by the Board to take action under this section is not responsible, as a result of that action, for debts of any other rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a failure of existing freight or commuter rail passenger transportation operations caused by cessation of service by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, the Board may not direct a rail carrier to undertake activities under subsection (a) to continue such operations unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Board first affirmatively finds that the rail carrier is operationally capable of conducting the directed service in a safe and efficient manner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the funding for such directed service required by subparagraph (B) of subsection (b)(3) is provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In carrying out this section, the Board shall require, to the maximum extent practicable, the use of employees who would normally have performed work in connection with the traffic subject to the action of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the National Railroad Passenger Corporation and any entity providing commuter rail passenger transportation shall be considered rail carriers subject to the Board’s jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “commuter rail passenger transportation” has the meaning given that term in section 24102(4).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002047">1</ref></content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 833</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. F, title I, § 150(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11124.</num>
<heading> War emergencies; embargoes imposed by carriers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When the President, during time of war or threatened war, notifies the Board that it is essential to the defense and security of the United States to give preference or priority to the movement of certain traffic, the Board shall direct that preference or priority be given to that traffic.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When the President, during time of war or threatened war, demands that preference and precedence be given to the transportation of troops and material of war over all other traffic, all rail carriers providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part shall adopt every means within their control to facilitate and expedite the military traffic.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An embargo imposed by any such rail carrier does not apply to shipments consigned to agents of the United States Government for its use. The rail carrier shall deliver those shipments as promptly as possible.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>REPORTS AND RECORDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11141.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “rail carrier” and “lessor” include a receiver or trustee of a rail carrier and lessor, respectively;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “lessor” means a person owning a railroad that is leased to and operated by a carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “association” means an organization maintained by or in the interest of a group of rail carriers providing transportation or service subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part that performs a service, or engages in activities, related to transportation under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11142.</num>
<heading> Uniform accounting system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board may prescribe a uniform accounting system for classes of rail carriers providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part. To the maximum extent practicable, the Board shall conform such system to generally accepted accounting principles, and shall administer this subchapter in accordance with such principles.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11143.</num>
<heading> Depreciation charges</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board shall, for a class of rail carriers providing transportation subject to its jurisdiction under this part, prescribe, and change when necessary, those classes of property for which depreciation charges may be included under operating expenses and a rate of depreciation that may be charged to a class of property. The Board may classify those rail carriers for purposes of this section. A rail carrier for whom depreciation charges and rates of depreciation are in effect under this section for any class of property may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> charge to operating expenses a depreciation charge on a class of property other than that prescribed by the Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> charge another rate of depreciation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include other depreciation charges in operating expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11144.</num>
<heading> Records: form; inspection; preservation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Board may prescribe the form of records required to be prepared or compiled under this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by rail carriers and lessors, including records related to movement of traffic and receipts and expenditures of money; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by persons furnishing cars to or for a rail carrier providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part to the extent related to those cars or that service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Board, or an employee designated by the Board, may on demand and display of proper credentials—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> inspect and examine the lands, buildings, and equipment of a rail carrier or lessor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> inspect and copy any record of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a rail carrier, lessor, or association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a person controlling, controlled by, or under common control with a rail carrier if the Board considers inspection relevant to that person’s relation to, or transaction with, that rail carrier; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a person furnishing cars to or for a rail carrier if the Board prescribed the form of that record.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Board may prescribe the time period during which operating, accounting, and financial records must be preserved by rail carriers, lessors, and persons furnishing cars.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11145.</num>
<heading> Reports by rail carriers, lessors, and associations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Board may require—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> rail carriers, lessors, and associations, or classes of them as the Board may prescribe, to file annual, periodic, and special reports with the Board containing answers to questions asked by it; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a person furnishing cars to a rail carrier to file reports with the Board containing answers to questions about those cars.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An annual report shall contain an account, in as much detail as the Board may require, of the affairs of the rail carrier, lessor, or association for the 12-month period ending on December 31 of each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An annual report shall be filed with the Board by the end of the third month after the end of the year for which the report is made unless the Board extends the filing date or changes the period covered by the report. The annual report and, if the Board requires, any other report made under this section, shall be made under oath.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>RAILROAD COST ACCOUNTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11161.</num>
<heading> Implementation of cost accounting principles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall periodically review its cost accounting rules and shall make such changes in those rules as are required to achieve the regulatory purposes of this part. The Board shall insure that the rules promulgated under this section are the most efficient and least burdensome means by which the required information may be developed for regulatory purposes. To the maximum extent practicable, the Board shall conform such rules to generally accepted accounting principles.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11162.</num>
<heading> Rail carrier cost accounting system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each rail carrier shall have and maintain a cost accounting system that is in compliance with the rules promulgated by the Board under <ref>section 11161 of this title</ref>. A rail carrier may, after notifying the Board, make modifications in such system unless, within 60 days after the date of notification, the Board finds such modifications to be inconsistent with the rules promulgated by the Board under <ref>section 11161 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of determining whether the cost accounting system of a rail carrier is in compliance with the rules promulgated by the Board, the Board shall have the right to examine and make copies of any documents, papers, or records of such rail carrier relating to compliance with such rules. Such documents, papers, and records (and any copies thereof) shall not be subject to the mandatory disclosure requirements of <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11163.</num>
<heading> Cost availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As required by the rules of the Board governing discovery in Board proceedings, rail carriers shall make relevant cost data available to shippers, States, ports, communities, and other interested parties that are a party to a Board proceeding in which such data are required.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11164.</num>
<heading> Accounting and cost reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To obtain expense and revenue information for regulatory purposes, the Board may promulgate reasonable rules for rail carriers providing transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part, prescribing expense and revenue accounting and reporting requirements consistent with generally accepted accounting principles uniformly applied to such carriers. Such requirements shall be cost effective and compatible with and not duplicative of the managerial and responsibility accounting requirements of those carriers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>