<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 463—</num>
<heading>PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 46301.</num>
<heading> Civil penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A person is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $75,000 (or $1,100 if the person is an individual or small business concern) for violating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> chapter 401 (except sections 40103(a) and (d), 40105, 40116, and 40117), chapter 411, chapter 413 (except sections 41307 and 41310(b)–(f)), chapter 415 (except sections 41502, 41505, and 41507–41509), chapter 417 (except sections 41703, 41704, 41710, 41713, and 41714), chapter 419, subchapter II or III of chapter 421, chapter 423, chapter 441 (except section 44109), section 44502(b) or (c), chapter 447 (except sections 44717 and 44719–44723), chapter 448, chapter 449 (except sections 44902, 44903(d), 44904, 44907(a)–(d)(1)(A) and (d)(1)(C)–(f), and 44908), chapter 451, section 47107(a)(22) (including any assurance made under such section), section 47107(b) (including any assurance made under such section), or <ref>section 47133 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a regulation prescribed or order issued under any provision to which clause (A) of this paragraph applies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any term of a certificate or permit issued under section 41102, 41103, or 41302 of this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a regulation of the United States Postal Service under this part.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A separate violation occurs under this subsection for each day the violation (other than a violation of section 41719) continues or, if applicable, for each flight involving the violation (other than a violation of section 41719).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty for diversion of aviation revenues</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of a civil penalty assessed under this section for a violation of <ref>section 47107(b) of this title</ref> (or any assurance made under such section) or <ref>section 47133 of this title</ref> may be increased above the otherwise applicable maximum amount under this section to an amount not to exceed 3 times the amount of revenues that are used in violation of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aviation security violations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the maximum civil penalty for violating chapter 449 shall be $10,000; except that the maximum civil penalty shall be $25,000 in the case of a person operating an aircraft for the transportation of passengers or property for compensation (except an individual serving as an airman).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Penalties applicable to individuals and small business concerns.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An individual (except an airman serving as an airman) or small business concern is liable to the Government for a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for violating—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> chapter 401 (except sections 40103(a) and (d), 40105, 40106(b), 40116, and 40117), section 44502 (b) or (c), chapter 447 (except sections 44717–44723), chapter 448, chapter 449 (except sections 44902, 44903(d), 44904, and 44907–44909), chapter 451, or <ref>section 46314(a) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a regulation prescribed or order issued under any provision to which clause (i) applies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A civil penalty of not more than $10,000 may be imposed for each violation under paragraph (1) committed by an individual or small business concern related to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the transportation of hazardous material;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the registration or recordation under chapter 441 of an aircraft not used to provide air transportation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a violation of section 44718(d), relating to the limitation on construction or establishment of landfills;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a violation of section 44725, relating to the safe disposal of life-limited aircraft parts; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a violation of section 40127 or section 41705, relating to discrimination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the maximum civil penalty for a violation of section 41719 committed by an individual or small business concern shall be $5,000 instead of $1,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the maximum civil penalty for a violation of section 41712 (including a regulation prescribed or order issued under such section) or any other regulation prescribed by the Secretary of Transportation by an individual or small business concern that is intended to afford consumer protection to commercial air transportation passengers shall be $2,500 for each violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure to collect airport security badges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), any employer (other than a governmental entity or airport operator) who employs an employee to whom an airport security badge or other identifier used to obtain access to a secure area of an airport is issued before, on, or after the date of enactment of this paragraph and who does not collect or make reasonable efforts to collect such badge from the employee on the date that the employment of the employee is terminated and does not notify the operator of the airport of such termination within 24 hours of the date of such termination shall be liable to the Government for a civil penalty not to exceed $10,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties relating to harm to passengers with disabilities</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty for bodily harm or damage to wheelchair or other mobility aid</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of a civil penalty assessed under this section for a violation of section 41705 that involves damage to a passenger’s wheelchair or other mobility aid or injury to a passenger with a disability may be increased above the otherwise applicable maximum amount under this section for a violation of section 41705 to an amount not to exceed 3 times the maximum penalty otherwise allowed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Each act constitutes separate offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), a separate violation of section 41705 occurs for each act of discrimination prohibited by that section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure to Continue Offering Aviation Fuel</inline> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002174">1</ref>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the maximum civil penalty for a violation of section 47107(a)(22) (including any assurance made under such section) committed by a person, including if the person is an individual or a small business concern, shall be $5,000 for each day that the person is in violation of that section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Smoke Alarm Device Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A passenger may not tamper with, disable, or destroy a smoke alarm device located in a lavatory on an aircraft providing air transportation or intrastate air transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An individual violating this subsection is liable to the Government for a civil penalty of not more than $2,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedural Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Transportation may impose a civil penalty for the following violations only after notice and an opportunity for a hearing:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a violation of subsection (b) of this section or chapter 411, chapter 413 (except sections 41307 and 41310(b)–(f)), chapter 415 (except sections 41502, 41505, and 41507–41509), chapter 417 (except sections 41703, 41704, 41710, 41713, and 41714), chapter 419, subchapter II of chapter 421, chapter 423, or <ref>section 44909 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a violation of a regulation prescribed or order issued under any provision to which clause (A) of this paragraph applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a violation of any term of a certificate or permit issued under section 41102, 41103, or 41302 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a violation under subsection (a)(1) of this section related to the transportation of hazardous material.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall give written notice of the finding of a violation and the civil penalty under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Imposition of Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “flight engineer” means an individual who holds a flight engineer certificate issued under part 63 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “mechanic” means an individual who holds a mechanic certificate issued under part 65 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> “pilot” means an individual who holds a pilot certificate issued under part 61 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> “repairman” means an individual who holds a repairman certificate issued under part 65 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may impose a civil penalty for a violation of chapter 401 (except sections 40103(a) and (d), 40105, 40106(b), 40116, and 40117), section 42121, chapter 441 (except section 44109), section 44502(b) or (c), chapter 447 (except sections 44717 and 44719–44723), chapter 448, chapter 451, section 46301(b), section 46302 (for a violation relating to section 46504), section 46318, section 46319, section 46320, or section 47107(b) (as further defined by the Secretary of Transportation under section 47107(k) and including any assurance made under section 47107(b)) of this title or a regulation prescribed or order issued under any of those provisions. The Secretary of Homeland Security may impose a civil penalty for a violation of chapter 449 (except sections 44902, 44903(d), 44907(a)–(d)(1)(A), 44907(d)(1)(C)–(f), 44908, and 44909), section 46302 (except for a violation relating to section 46504), or <ref>section 46303 of this title</ref> or a regulation prescribed or order issued under any of those provisions. The Secretary of Homeland Security or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall give written notice of the finding of a violation and the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In a civil action to collect a civil penalty imposed by the Secretary of Homeland Security or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under this subsection, the issues of liability and the amount of the penalty may not be reexamined.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, the district courts of the United States have exclusive jurisdiction of a civil action involving a penalty the Secretary of Homeland Security or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration initiates if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the amount in controversy is more than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $400,000 if the violation was committed by any person other than an individual or small business concern before the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $50,000 if the violation was committed by an individual or small business concern before the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> $1,200,000 if the violation was committed by a person other than an individual or small business concern on or after the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> $100,000 if the violation was committed by an individual on or after the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the action is in rem or another action in rem based on the same violation has been brought;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the action involves an aircraft subject to a lien that has been seized by the Government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> another action has been brought for an injunction based on the same violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may issue an order imposing a penalty under this subsection against an individual acting as a pilot, flight engineer, mechanic, or repairman only after advising the individual of the charges or any reason the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration relied on for the proposed penalty and providing the individual an opportunity to answer the charges and be heard about why the order shall not be issued.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An individual acting as a pilot, flight engineer, mechanic, or repairman may appeal an order imposing a penalty under this subsection to the National Transportation Safety Board. After notice and an opportunity for a hearing on the record, the Board shall affirm, modify, or reverse the order. The Board may modify a civil penalty imposed to a suspension or revocation of a certificate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> When conducting a hearing under this paragraph, the Board is not bound by findings of fact of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration but is bound by all validly adopted interpretations of laws and regulations the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration carries out and of written agency policy guidance available to the public related to sanctions to be imposed under this section unless the Board finds an interpretation is arbitrary, capricious, or otherwise not according to law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> When an individual files an appeal with the Board under this paragraph, the order of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration is stayed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An individual substantially affected by an order of the Board under paragraph (5) of this subsection, or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration when the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration decides that an order of the Board under paragraph (5) will have a significant adverse impact on carrying out this part, may obtain judicial review of the order under <ref>section 46110 of this title</ref>. The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall be made a party to the judicial review proceedings. Findings of fact of the Board are conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may impose a penalty on a person (except an individual acting as a pilot, flight engineer, mechanic, or repairman) only after notice and an opportunity for a hearing on the record.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In an appeal from a decision of an administrative law judge as the result of a hearing under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall consider only whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> each finding of fact is supported by a preponderance of reliable, probative, and substantial evidence;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each conclusion of law is made according to applicable law, precedent, and public policy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the judge committed a prejudicial error that supports the appeal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Except for good cause, a civil action involving a penalty under this paragraph may not be initiated later than 2 years after the violation occurs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a violation of <ref>section 47107(b) of this title</ref> or any assurance made under such section—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a civil penalty shall not be assessed against an individual;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a civil penalty may be compromised as provided under subsection (f); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> judicial review of any order assessing a civil penalty may be obtained only pursuant to <ref>section 46110 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> The maximum civil penalty the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, or Board may impose under this subsection is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $400,000 if the violation was committed by a person other than an individual or small business concern before the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $50,000 if the violation was committed by an individual or small business concern before the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> $1,200,000 if the violation was committed by a person other than an individual or small business concern on or after the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> $100,000 if the violation was committed by an individual on or after the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> This subsection applies only to a violation occurring after <date date="1992-08-25">August 25, 1992</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining the amount of a civil penalty under subsection (a)(3) of this section related to transportation of hazardous material, the Secretary of Transportation shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior violations, the ability to pay, and any effect on the ability to continue doing business; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other matters that justice requires.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compromise and Setoff</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed for violating—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> chapter 401 (except sections 40103(a) and (d), 40105, 40116, and 40117), chapter 441 (except section 44109), section 44502(b) or (c), chapter 447 (except sections 44717 and 44719–44723), chapter 448, chapter 449 (except sections 44902, 44903(d), 44904, 44907(a)–(d)(1)(A) and (d)(1)(C)–(f), 44908, and 44909), or chapter 451 of this title; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a regulation prescribed or order issued under any provision to which clause (i) of this subparagraph applies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Postal Service may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under subsection (a)(1)(D) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this subsection from amounts it owes the person liable for the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An order of the Secretary or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration imposing a civil penalty may be reviewed judicially only under <ref>section 46110 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> This section does not apply to the following when performing official duties:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a civilian employee of the Department of Defense subject to the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The appropriate military authority is responsible for taking necessary disciplinary action and submitting to the Secretary (or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) a timely report on action taken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Small Business Concern Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “small business concern” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1231</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–305, title I, § 112(c)</ref>, title II, § 207(c), <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1575</ref>, 1588; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(60)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–264, title V, § 502(c)</ref>, title VIII, § 804(b), title XII, § 1220(b), <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3263</ref>, 3271, 3286; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(77)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–102, § 3(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2215</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title II, § 222</ref>, title V, §§ 503(c), 504(b), 519(c), title VII, §§ 707(b), 720, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 102</ref>, 133, 134, 149, 158, 163; <ref>Pub. L. 106–424, § 15</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1888</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 140(d)(1)</ref>–(4), <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVI, § 1602</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2312</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title V, § 503(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2557</ref>, 2558; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title IV, § 4027(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title XIII, § 1302(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. E, title V, § 542</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. D, title V, § 564(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title IV, § 415(b)</ref>, title VIII, § 803, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 96</ref>, 119; <ref>Pub. L. 113–188, title XV, § 1501(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2024</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–190, title II, § 2205(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 372(e)</ref>, title IV, § 436, div. K, title I, § 1991(g)(1), <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3312</ref>, 3344, 3643; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title III</ref>, §§ 345, 371, title V, §§ 504(b), 507(a), title VII, § 770(b), title XI, § 1101(t), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1102</ref>, 1139, 1191, 1193, 1295, 1414.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46302.</num>
<heading> False information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person that, knowing the information to be false, gives, or causes to be given, under circumstances in which the information reasonably may be believed, false information about an alleged attempt being made or to be made to do an act that would violate section 46502(a), 46504, 46505, or 46506 of this title, is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compromise and Setoff</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security and, for a violation relating to section 46504, the Secretary of Transportation, may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this section from amounts it owes the person liable for the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title IV, § 4027(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46303.</num>
<heading> Carrying a weapon</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual who, when on, or attempting to board, an aircraft in, or intended for operation in, air transportation or intrastate air transportation, has on or about the individual or the property of the individual a concealed dangerous weapon that is or would be accessible to the individual in flight is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compromise and Setoff</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this section from amounts it owes the individual liable for the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a law enforcement officer of a State or political subdivision of a State, or an officer or employee of the Government, authorized to carry arms in an official capacity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> another individual the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration or the Secretary of Homeland Security by regulation authorizes to carry arms in an official capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 140(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title IV, § 4027(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46304.</num>
<heading> Liens on aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aircraft Subject to Liens</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When an aircraft is involved in a violation referred to in section 46301(a)(1)(A)–(C) of this title and the violation is by the owner of, or individual commanding, the aircraft, the aircraft is subject to a lien for the civil penalty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seizure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An aircraft subject to a lien under this section may be seized summarily and placed in the custody of a person authorized to take custody of it under regulations of the Secretary of Transportation (or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration). A report on the seizure shall be submitted to the Attorney General. The Attorney General promptly shall bring a civil action in rem to enforce the lien or notify the Secretary or Administrator that the action will not be brought.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Release</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An aircraft seized under subsection (b) of this section shall be released from custody when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the civil penalty is paid;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a compromise amount agreed on is paid;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the aircraft is seized under a civil action in rem to enforce the lien;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Attorney General gives notice that a civil action will not be brought under subsection (b) of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a bond (in an amount and with a surety the Secretary or Administrator prescribes), conditioned on payment of the penalty or compromise, is deposited with the Secretary or Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1235</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title V, § 503(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2559</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, title I, § 1991(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46305.</num>
<heading> Actions to recover civil penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A civil penalty under this chapter may be collected by bringing a civil action against the person subject to the penalty, a civil action in rem against an aircraft subject to a lien for a penalty, or both. The action shall conform as nearly as practicable to a civil action in admiralty, regardless of the place an aircraft in a civil action in rem is seized. However, a party may demand a jury trial of an issue of fact in an action involving a civil penalty under this chapter (except a penalty imposed by the Secretary of Transportation that formerly was imposed by the Civil Aeronautics Board) if the value of the matter in controversy is more than $20. Issues of fact tried by a jury may be reexamined only under common law rules.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46306.</num>
<heading> Registration violations involving aircraft not providing air transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies only to aircraft not used to provide air transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided by subsection (c) of this section, a person shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both, if the person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully forges or alters a certificate authorized to be issued under this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly sells, uses, attempts to use, or possesses with the intent to use, such a certificate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully displays or causes to be displayed on an aircraft a mark that is false or misleading about the nationality or registration of the aircraft;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> obtains a certificate authorized to be issued under this part by knowingly and willfully falsifying or concealing a material fact, making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement, or making or using a false document knowing it contains a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or entry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> owns an aircraft eligible for registration under <ref>section 44102 of this title</ref> and knowingly and willfully operates, attempts to operate, or allows another person to operate the aircraft when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the aircraft is not registered under <ref>section 44103 of this title</ref> or the certificate of registration is suspended or revoked; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the owner knows or has reason to know that the other person does not have proper authorization to operate or navigate the aircraft without registration for a period of time after transfer of ownership;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> knowingly and willfully operates or attempts to operate an aircraft eligible for registration under <ref>section 44102 of this title</ref> knowing that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the aircraft is not registered under <ref>section 44103 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the certificate of registration is suspended or revoked; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the person does not have proper authorization to operate or navigate the aircraft without registration for a period of time after transfer of ownership;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully serves or attempts to serve in any capacity as an airman without an airman’s certificate authorizing the individual to serve in that capacity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully employs for service or uses in any capacity as an airman an individual who does not have an airman’s certificate authorizing the individual to serve in that capacity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> operates an aircraft with a fuel tank or fuel system that has been installed or modified knowing that the tank, system, installation, or modification does not comply with regulations and requirements of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Controlled Substance Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In this subsection, “controlled substance” has the same meaning given that term in section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<ref>21 U.S.C. 802</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A person violating subsection (b) of this section shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, if the violation is related to transporting a controlled substance by aircraft or aiding or facilitating a controlled substance violation and the transporting, aiding, or facilitating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is punishable by death or imprisonment of more than one year under a law of the United States or a State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is provided is related to an act punishable by death or imprisonment for more than one year under a law of the United States or a State related to a controlled substance (except a law related to simple possession of a controlled substance).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A term of imprisonment imposed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be served in addition to, and not concurrently with, any other term of imprisonment imposed on the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seizure and Forfeiture</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Administrator of Drug Enforcement or the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may seize and forfeit under the customs laws an aircraft whose use is related to a violation of subsection (b) of this section, or to aid or facilitate a violation, regardless of whether a person is charged with the violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An aircraft’s use is presumed to have been related to a violation of, or to aid or facilitate a violation of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subsection (b)(1) of this section if the aircraft certificate of registration has been forged or altered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subsection (b)(3) of this section if there is an external display of false or misleading registration numbers or country of registration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> subsection (b)(4) of this section if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the aircraft is registered to a false or fictitious person; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the application form used to obtain the aircraft certificate of registration contains a material false statement;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> subsection (b)(5) of this section if the aircraft was operated when it was not registered under <ref>section 44103 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> subsection (b)(9) of this section if the aircraft has a fuel tank or fuel system that was installed or altered—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in violation of a regulation or requirement of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if a certificate required to be issued for the installation or alteration is not carried on the aircraft.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, the Administrator of Drug Enforcement, and the Commissioner shall agree to a memorandum of understanding to establish procedures to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to State Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This part does not prevent a State from establishing a criminal penalty, including providing for forfeiture and seizure of aircraft, for a person that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully forges or alters an aircraft certificate of registration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly sells, uses, attempts to use, or possesses with the intent to use, a fraudulent aircraft certificate of registration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully displays or causes to be displayed on an aircraft a mark that is false or misleading about the nationality or registration of the aircraft; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> obtains an aircraft certificate of registration from the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully falsifying or concealing a material fact;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> making or using a false document knowing it contains a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or entry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1235</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(78)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46307.</num>
<heading> Violation of national defense airspace</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person that knowingly or willfully violates <ref>section 40103(b)(3) of this title</ref> or a regulation prescribed or order issued under section 40103(b)(3) shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46308.</num>
<heading> Interference with air navigation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, if the person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with intent to interfere with air navigation in the United States, exhibits in the United States a light or signal at a place or in a way likely to be mistaken for a true light or signal established under this part or for a true light or signal used at an air navigation facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> after a warning from the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, continues to maintain a misleading light or signal; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> knowingly interferes with the operation of a true light or signal.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46309.</num>
<heading> Concession and price violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty for Offering, Granting, Giving, or Helping To Obtain Concessions and Lower Prices</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An air carrier, foreign air carrier, ticket agent, or officer, agent, or employee of an air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent shall be fined under title 18 if the air carrier, foreign air carrier, ticket agent, officer, agent, or employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully offers, grants, or gives, or causes to be offered, granted, or given, a rebate or other concession in violation of this part; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by any means knowingly and willfully assists, or willingly allows, a person to obtain transportation or services subject to this part at less than the price lawfully in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty for Receiving Rebates, Privileges, and Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person shall be fined under title 18 if the person by any means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully solicits, accepts, or receives a rebate of a part of a price lawfully in effect for the foreign air transportation of property, or a service related to the foreign air transportation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly solicits, accepts, or receives a privilege or facility related to a matter the Secretary of Transportation requires be specified in a currently effective tariff applicable to the foreign air transportation of property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46310.</num>
<heading> Reporting and recordkeeping violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An air carrier or an officer, agent, or employee of an air carrier shall be fined under title 18 for intentionally—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> failing to make a report or keep a record under this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> falsifying, mutilating, or altering a report or record under this part; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> filing a false report or record under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Regulation Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An air carrier or an officer, agent, or employee of an air carrier shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, for intentionally falsifying or concealing a material fact, or inducing reliance on a false statement of material fact, in a report or record under section 44701(a) or (b) or any of sections 44702–44716 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(56)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4385</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46311.</num>
<heading> Unlawful disclosure of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, or an officer or employee of the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both, if the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, officer, or employee knowingly and willfully discloses information that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, officer, or employee acquires when inspecting the records of an air carrier; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is withheld from public disclosure under <ref>section 40115 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) of this section does not apply if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the officer or employee is directed by the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to disclose information that the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration had ordered withheld; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, officer, or employee is directed by a court of competent jurisdiction to disclose the information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withholding Information From Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not authorize the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to withhold information from a committee of Congress authorized to have the information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 140(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, title I, § 1991(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46312.</num>
<heading> Transporting hazardous material</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, if the person, in violation of a regulation or requirement related to the transportation of hazardous material prescribed by the Secretary of Transportation under this part or chapter 51—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> willfully delivers, or causes to be delivered, property containing hazardous material to an air carrier or to an operator of a civil aircraft for transportation in air commerce; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recklessly causes the transportation in air commerce of the property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Knowledge of Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of subsection (a), knowledge by the person of the existence of a regulation or requirement related to the transportation of hazardous material prescribed by the Secretary under this part or chapter 51 is not an element of an offense under this section but shall be considered in mitigation of the penalty.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title VII, § 7128(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46313.</num>
<heading> Refusing to appear or produce records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person not obeying a subpoena or requirement of the Secretary of Transportation (or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) to appear and testify or produce records shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 140(d)(7)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, title I, § 1991(g)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46314.</num>
<heading> Entering aircraft or airport area in violation of security requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person may not knowingly and willfully enter, in violation of security requirements prescribed under section 44901, 44903(b) or (c), or 44906 of this title, an aircraft or an airport area that serves an air carrier or foreign air carrier.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person violating subsection (a) of this section shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person violating subsection (a) of this section with intent to evade security procedures or restrictions or with intent to commit, in the aircraft or airport area, a felony under a law of the United States or a State shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice of Penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each operator of an airport in the United States that is required to establish an air transportation security program pursuant to section 44903(c) shall ensure that signs that meet such requirements as the Secretary of Homeland Security may prescribe providing notice of the penalties imposed under section 46301(a)(5)(A)(i) and subsection (b) of this section are displayed near all screening locations, all locations where passengers exit the sterile area, and such other locations at the airport as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of signs on penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual shall be subject to a penalty imposed under section 46301(a)(5)(A)(i) or subsection (b) of this section without regard to whether signs are displayed at an airport as required by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. D, title V, § 564(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 981</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46315.</num>
<heading> Lighting violations involving transporting controlled substances by aircraft not providing air transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies only to aircraft not used to provide air transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the person knowingly and willfully operates an aircraft in violation of a regulation or requirement of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration related to the display of navigation or anticollision lights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the person is knowingly transporting a controlled substance by aircraft or aiding or facilitating a controlled substance offense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the transporting, aiding, or facilitating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is punishable by death or imprisonment for more than one year under a law of the United States or a State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is provided in connection with an act punishable by death or imprisonment for more than one year under a law of the United States or a State related to a controlled substance (except a law related to simple possession of a controlled substance).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46316.</num>
<heading> General criminal penalty when specific penalty not provided</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided by subsection (b) of this section, when another criminal penalty is not provided under this chapter, a person that knowingly and willfully violates this part, a regulation prescribed or order issued by the Secretary of Transportation (or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) under this part, or any term of a certificate or permit issued under section 41102, 41103, or 41302 of this title shall be fined under title 18. A separate violation occurs for each day the violation continues.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) of this section does not apply to chapter 401 (except sections 40103(a) and (d), 40105, 40116, and 40117), chapter 441 (except section 44109), chapter 445, chapter 447 (except section 44718(a)), and chapter 449 (except sections 44902, 44903(d), 44904, and 44907–44909) of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(79)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–102, § 3(d)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2215</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–71, title I, § 140(d)(7)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, title I, § 1991(g)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46317.</num>
<heading> Criminal penalty for pilots operating in air transportation without an airman’s certificate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both, if that individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully serves or attempts to serve in any capacity as an airman operating an aircraft in air transportation without an airman’s certificate authorizing the individual to serve in that capacity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully employs for service or uses in any capacity as an airman to operate an aircraft in air transportation an individual who does not have an airman’s certificate authorizing the individual to serve in that capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Controlled Substance Criminal Penalty.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Controlled substances defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “controlled substance” has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<ref>21 U.S.C. 802</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual violating subsection (a) shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, if the violation is related to transporting a controlled substance by aircraft or aiding or facilitating a controlled substance violation and that transporting, aiding, or facilitating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is punishable by death or imprisonment of more than 1 year under a Federal or State law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is related to an act punishable by death or imprisonment for more than 1 year under a Federal or State law related to a controlled substance (except a law related to simple possession (as that term is used in section 46306(c)) of a controlled substance).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms of imprisonment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A term of imprisonment imposed under paragraph (2) shall be served in addition to, and not concurrently with, any other term of imprisonment imposed on the individual subject to the imprisonment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title V, § 509(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46318.</num>
<heading> Interference with cabin or flight crew</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual who physically or sexually assaults or threatens to physically or sexually assault a member of the flight crew or cabin crew of a civil aircraft or any other individual on the aircraft, or takes any action that poses an imminent threat to the safety of the aircraft or other individuals on the aircraft is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $35,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compromise and Setoff.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compromise</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Setoff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this section from amounts the Government owes the person liable for the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–181, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 142</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 339(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46319.</num>
<heading> Permanent closure of an airport without providing sufficient notice</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A public agency (as defined in section 47102) may not permanently close an airport listed in the national plan of integrated airport systems under section 47103 without providing written notice to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration at least 30 days before the date of the closure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication of Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall publish each notice received under subsection (a) in the Federal Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A public agency violating subsection (a) shall be liable for a civil penalty of $10,000 for each day that the airport remains closed without having given the notice required by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title I, § 185(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2517</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46320.</num>
<heading> Interference with wildfire suppression, law enforcement, or emergency response effort by operation of unmanned aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), an individual who operates an unmanned aircraft and in so doing knowingly or recklessly interferes with a wildfire suppression, law enforcement, or emergency response effort is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $20,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to the operation of an unmanned aircraft conducted by a unit or agency of the United States Government or of a State, tribal, or local government (including any individual conducting such operation pursuant to a contract or other agreement entered into with the unit or agency) for the purpose of protecting the public safety and welfare, including firefighting, law enforcement, or emergency response.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compromise and Setoff.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compromise</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Government may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Setoff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this section from the amounts the Government owes the person liable for the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Wildfire</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “wildfire” has the meaning given that term in section 2 of the Emergency Wildfire Suppression Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1856m</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Wildfire suppression</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “wildfire suppression” means an effort to contain, extinguish, or suppress a wildfire.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–190, title II, § 2205(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>