<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 285—</num>
<heading>COMMUTER RAIL MEDIATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 28501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Board” means the Surface Transportation Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “capital work” means maintenance, restoration, reconstruction, capacity enhancement, or rehabilitation work on trackage that would be treated, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, as a capital item rather than an expense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “commuter rail passenger transportation” has the meaning given that term in section 24102;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “public transportation authority” means a local governmental authority (as defined in section 5302) established to provide, or make a contract providing for, commuter rail passenger transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “rail carrier” means a person, other than a governmental authority, providing common carrier railroad transportation for compensation subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under chapter 105;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “segregated fixed guideway facility” means a fixed guideway facility constructed within the railroad right-of-way of a rail carrier but physically separate from trackage, including relocated trackage, within the right-of-way used by a rail carrier for freight transportation purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “trackage” means a railroad line of a rail carrier, including a spur, industrial, team, switching, side, yard, or station track, and a facility of a rail carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4955</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. C, § 30001(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 890</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 28502.</num>
<heading> Surface Transportation Board mediation of trackage use requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, after a reasonable period of negotiation, a public transportation authority cannot reach agreement with a rail carrier to use trackage of, and have related services provided by, the rail carrier for purposes of commuter rail passenger transportation, the public transportation authority or the rail carrier may apply to the Board for nonbinding mediation. The Board shall conduct the nonbinding mediation in accordance with the mediation process of section 1109.4 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4955</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 28503.</num>
<heading> Surface Transportation Board mediation of rights-of-way use requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, after a reasonable period of negotiation, a public transportation authority cannot reach agreement with a rail carrier to acquire an interest in a railroad right-of-way for the construction and operation of a segregated fixed guideway facility to provide commuter rail passenger transportation, the public transportation authority or the rail carrier may apply to the Board for nonbinding mediation. The Board shall conduct the nonbinding mediation in accordance with the mediation process of section 1109.4 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4956</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 28504.</num>
<heading> Applicability of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit a rail transportation provider’s right under section 28103(b) to enter into contracts that allocate financial responsibility for claims.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4956</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 28505.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Board shall issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–432, div. B, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4956</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>