<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 323—</num>
<heading>CONSUMER INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 32301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “crash avoidance” means preventing or mitigating a crash;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “crashworthiness” means the protection a passenger motor vehicle gives its passengers against personal injury or death from a motor vehicle accident; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “damage susceptibility” means the susceptibility of a passenger motor vehicle to damage in a motor vehicle accident.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1035</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title I, § 31305(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32302.</num>
<heading> Passenger motor vehicle information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall maintain a program for developing the following information on passenger motor vehicles:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> damage susceptibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> crashworthiness, crash avoidance, and any other areas the Secretary determines will improve the safety of passenger motor vehicles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the degree of difficulty of diagnosis and repair of damage to, or failure of, mechanical and electrical systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motor Vehicle Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To assist a consumer in buying a passenger motor vehicle, the Secretary shall provide to the public information developed under subsection (a) of this section. The information shall be in a simple and understandable form that allows comparison of the characteristics referred to in subsection (a)(1)–(3) of this section among the makes and models of passenger motor vehicles. The Secretary may require passenger motor vehicle dealers to distribute the information to prospective buyers. The Secretary, after providing an opportunity for public comment, shall study and report to Congress the most useful data, format, and method for providing simple and understandable damage susceptibility information to consumers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crash Avoidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Safety Through Informed Consumers Act of 2015, the Secretary shall promulgate a rule to ensure that crash avoidance information is indicated next to crashworthiness information on stickers placed on motor vehicles by their manufacturers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Motor Vehicle Defect Reporting Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Motor Vehicle and Highway Safety Improvement Act of 2012, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations that require passenger motor vehicle manufacturers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to affix, in the glove compartment or in another readily accessible location on the vehicle, a sticker, decal, or other device that provides, in simple and understandable language, information about how to submit a safety-related motor vehicle defect complaint to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to prominently print the information described in subparagraph (A) within the owner’s manual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to not place such information on the label required under section 3 of the Automobile Information Disclosure Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1232</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements under paragraph (1) shall apply to passenger motor vehicles manufactured in any model year beginning more than 1 year after the date on which a final rule is published under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Advanced Crash-avoidance Technologies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall publish a notice, for purposes of public review and comment, to establish, distinct from crashworthiness information, a means for providing to consumers information relating to advanced crash-avoidance technologies, in accordance with subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The notice under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an appropriate methodology for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determining which advanced crash-avoidance technologies shall be included in the information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> developing performance test criteria for use by manufacturers in evaluating advanced crash-avoidance technologies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> determining a distinct rating involving each advanced crash-avoidance technology to be included; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> updating overall vehicle ratings to incorporate advanced crash-avoidance technology ratings; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other information and analyses as the Secretary determines to be necessary to implement the rating of advanced crash-avoidance technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that describes a plan for implementing an advanced crash-avoidance technology information and rating system, in accordance with subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Vulnerable Road User Safety.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall publish a notice, for purposes of public review and comment, to establish a means for providing to consumers information relating to pedestrian, bicyclist, or other vulnerable road user safety technologies, in accordance with subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The notice under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an appropriate methodology for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determining which technologies shall be included in the information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> developing performance test criteria for use by manufacturers in evaluating the extent to which automated pedestrian safety systems in light vehicles attempt to prevent and mitigate, to the best extent possible, pedestrian injury;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> determining a distinct rating involving each technology to be included; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> updating overall vehicle ratings to incorporate vulnerable road user safety technology ratings; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other information and analyses as the Secretary determines to be necessary to implement the rating of vulnerable road user safety technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that describes a plan for implementing an information and rating system for vulnerable road user safety technologies, in accordance with subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1035</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title I</ref>, §§ 31305(b), 31306, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–252</ref>, §§ 1, 2(a), <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. B, title XXIV, § 24322</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title IV, § 24213(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32303.</num>
<heading> Insurance information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Reports and Information Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation may require an insurer, or a designated agent of the insurer, to make reports and provide the Secretary with information. The reports and information may include accident claim information by make, model, and model year of passenger motor vehicle about the kind and extent of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> physical damage and repair costs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personal injury.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In deciding which reports and information are to be provided under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consider the cost of preparing and providing the reports and information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consider the extent to which the reports and information will contribute to carrying out this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> consult with State authorities and public and private agencies the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To the extent possible, the Secretary shall obtain reports and information under this subsection on a voluntary basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requested Information on Crashworthiness, Damage Susceptibility, and Repair and Personal Injury Cost</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When requested by the Secretary, an insurer shall give the Secretary information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> about the extent to which the insurance premiums charged by the insurer are affected by damage susceptibility, crashworthiness, and the cost of repair and personal injury, for each make and model of passenger motor vehicle; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> available to the insurer about the effect of damage susceptibility, crashworthiness, and the cost of repair and personal injury for each make and model of passenger motor vehicle on the risk incurred by the insurer in insuring that make and model.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In distributing information received under this section, the Secretary may disclose identifying information about a person that may be an insured, a claimant, a passenger, an owner, a witness, or an individual involved in a motor vehicle accident, only with the consent of the person.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1036</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32304.</num>
<heading> Passenger motor vehicle country of origin labeling</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “allied supplier” means a supplier of passenger motor vehicle equipment that is wholly owned by the manufacturer, or if a joint venture vehicle assembly arrangement, a supplier that is wholly owned by one member of the joint venture arrangement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> “carline”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> means a name given a group of passenger motor vehicles that has a degree of commonality in construction such as body and chassis;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not consider a level of decor or opulence; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> except for light duty trucks, is not generally distinguished by characteristics such as roof line, number of doors, seats, or windows; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> light duty trucks are different carlines than passenger motor vehicles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “country of origin”, when referring to the origin of an engine or transmission, means the country from which the largest share of the dollar value added to an engine or transmission has originated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with the United States and Canada treated as separate countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the estimate of the percentage of the dollar value shall be based on the purchase price of direct materials, as received at individual engine or transmission plants, of engines of the same displacement and transmissions of the same transmission type, plus the assembly and labor costs incurred for the final assembly of such engines and transmissions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “dealer” means a person residing or located in the United States, including the District of Columbia or a territory or possession of the United States, and engaged in selling or distributing new passenger motor vehicles to the ultimate purchaser.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “final assembly place” means the plant, factory, or other place at which a new passenger motor vehicle is produced or assembled by a manufacturer, and from which the vehicle is delivered to a dealer or importer with all component parts necessary for the mechanical operation of the vehicle included with the vehicle, whether or not the component parts are permanently installed in or on the vehicle. Such term does not include facilities for engine and transmission fabrication and assembly and the facilities for fabrication of motor vehicle equipment component parts which are produced at the same final assembly place using forming processes such as stamping, machining, or molding processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “foreign content” means passenger motor vehicle equipment that is not of United States/Canadian origin.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> “manufacturer” means a person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engaged in manufacturing or assembling new passenger motor vehicles;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> importing new passenger motor vehicles for resale; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> acting for and under the control of such a manufacturer, assembler, or importer in connection with the distribution of new passenger motor vehicles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “new passenger motor vehicle” means a passenger motor vehicle for which a manufacturer, distributor, or dealer has never transferred the equitable or legal title to the vehicle to an ultimate purchaser.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> “of United States/Canadian origin”, when referring to passenger motor vehicle equipment, means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for an outside supplier—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the full purchase price of passenger motor vehicle equipment whose purchase price contains at least 70 percent value added in the United States and Canada; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that portion of the purchase price of passenger motor vehicle equipment containing less than 70 percent value added in the United States and Canada that is attributable to the percent value added in the United States and Canada when such percent is expressed to the nearest 5 percent; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for an allied supplier, that part of the individual passenger motor vehicle equipment whose purchase price the manufacturer determines remains after subtracting the total of the purchase prices of all material of foreign content purchased from outside suppliers, with the determination of the United States/Canadian origin or of the foreign content from outside suppliers being consistent with subclause (A) of this clause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “outside supplier” means a supplier of passenger motor vehicle equipment to a manufacturer’s allied supplier, or a person other than an allied supplier, who ships directly to the manufacturer’s final assembly place.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “passenger motor vehicle” has the same meaning given that term in <ref>section 32101(10) of this title</ref>, except that it includes any multi-purpose vehicle or light duty truck when that vehicle or truck is rated at not more than 8,500 pounds gross vehicle weight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> “passenger motor vehicle equipment”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a system, subassembly, or component received at the final vehicle assembly place for installation on, or attachment to, a passenger motor vehicle at the time of its first shipment by the manufacturer to a dealer for sale to an ultimate purchaser; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include minor parts (including nuts, bolts, clips, screws, pins, braces, and other attachment hardware) and other similar items the Secretary of Transportation may prescribe by regulation after consulting with manufacturers and labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> “percentage (by value)”, when referring to passenger motor vehicle equipment of United States/Canadian origin, means the percentage remaining after subtracting the percentage (by value) of passenger motor vehicle equipment that is not of United States/Canadian origin that will be installed or included on those vehicles produced in a carline, from 100 percent—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with value being expressed in terms of the purchase price; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for outside suppliers and allied suppliers, the value used is the purchase price of the equipment paid at the final assembly place.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> “value added in the United States and Canada” means a percentage determined by subtracting the total purchase price of foreign content from the total purchase price, and dividing the remainder by the total purchase price, excluding costs incurred or profits made at the final assembly place and beyond (including advertising, assembly, labor, interest payments, and profits), with the following groupings being used:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engines of same displacement produced at the same plant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transmissions of the same type produced at the same plant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Manufacturer Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each manufacturer of a new passenger motor vehicle manufactured after <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>, and distributed in commerce for sale in the United States, shall establish each year for each model year and cause to be attached in a prominent place on each of those vehicles, at least one label. The label shall contain the following information:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the percentage (by value) of passenger motor vehicle equipment of United States/Canadian origin installed on vehicles in the carline to which that vehicle belongs, identified by the words “U.S./Canadian content”.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the final assembly place for that vehicle by city, State (where appropriate) and country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if at least 15 percent (by value) of equipment installed on passenger motor vehicles in a carline originated in any country other than the United States and Canada, the names of at least the 2 countries in which the greatest amount (by value) of that equipment originated and the percentage (by value) of the equipment originating in each country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the country of origin of the engine and the transmission for each vehicle.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At the beginning of each model year, each manufacturer shall establish the percentages required for each carline to be indicated on the label under this subsection. Those percentages are applicable to that carline for the entire model year. A manufacturer may round those percentages to the nearest 5 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A manufacturer complying with the requirement of paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection satisfies the disclosure requirement of section 3(b) of the Automobile Information Disclosure Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1232(b)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vehicle Content Percentage by Assembly Plant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A manufacturer may display separately on the label required by subsection (b) the domestic content of a vehicle based on the assembly plant. Such display shall occur after the matter required to be in the label by subsection (b)(1)(A).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Value Added Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a manufacturer or allied supplier requests information in a timely manner from one or more of its outside suppliers concerning the United States/Canadian content of particular equipment, but does not receive that information despite a good faith effort to obtain it, the manufacturer or allied supplier may make its own good faith value added determinations, subject to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The manufacturer or allied supplier shall make the same value added determinations as would be made by the outside supplier, that is, whether 70 percent or more of the value of equipment is added in the United States and/or Canada.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manufacturer or allied supplier shall consider the amount of value added and the location in which the value was added for all of the stages that the outside supplier would be required to consider.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The manufacturer or allied supplier may determine that the value added in the United States and/or Canada is 70 percent or more only if it has a good faith basis to make that determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A manufacturer and its allied suppliers may, on a combined basis, make value added determinations for no more than 10 percent, by value, of a carline’s total parts content from outside suppliers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Value added determinations made by a manufacturer or allied supplier under this paragraph shall have the same effect as if they were made by the outside supplier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> This provision does not affect the obligation of outside suppliers to provide the requested information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Small Parts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The country of origin of nuts, bolts, clips, screws, pins, braces, gasoline, oil, blackout, phosphate rinse, windshield washer fluid, fasteners, tire assembly fluid, rivets, adhesives, and grommets, of any system, subassembly, or component installed in a vehicle shall be considered to be the country in which such parts were included in the final assembly of such vehicle.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dealer Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each dealer engaged in the sale or distribution of a new passenger motor vehicle manufactured after <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>, shall cause to be maintained on that vehicle the label required to be attached to that vehicle under subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form and Content of Label</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe by regulation the form and content of the label required under subsection (b) of this section and the manner and location in which the label is attached. The Secretary shall permit a manufacturer to comply with this section by allowing the manufacturer to disclose the information required under subsection (b)(1) on the label required by section 3 of the Automobile Information Disclosure Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1232</ref>), on the label required by <ref>section 32908 of this title</ref>, or on a separate label that is readily visible. A manufacturer may add to the label required under subsection (b) a line stating the country in which vehicle assembly was completed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In consultation with the Secretaries of Commerce and the Treasury, the Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations necessary to carry out this section, including regulations establishing a procedure to verify the label information required under subsection (b)(1) of this section. Those regulations shall provide the ultimate purchaser of a new passenger motor vehicle with the best and most understandable information possible about the foreign content and United States/Canadian origin of the equipment of the vehicles without imposing costly and unnecessary burdens on the manufacturers. The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe the regulations promptly to provide adequate lead time for each manufacturer to comply with this section. The regulations shall include provisions applicable to outside suppliers and allied suppliers to require those suppliers to certify whether passenger motor vehicle equipment provided by those suppliers is of United States origin, of United States/Canadian origin, or of foreign content and to provide other information the Secretary of Transportation decides is necessary to allow each manufacturer to comply reasonably with this section and to rely on that certification and information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preemption</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When a label content requirement prescribed under this section is in effect, a State or a political subdivision of a State may not adopt or enforce a law or regulation related to the content of vehicles covered by a requirement under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A State or a political subdivision of a State may prescribe requirements related to the content of passenger motor vehicles obtained for its own use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1036</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(29)</ref>, (30), <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title VII, § 7106(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32304A.</num>
<heading> Consumer tire information and standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consumer Tire Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of the Ten-in-Ten Fuel Economy Act, the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall, after notice and opportunity for comment, promulgate rules establishing a national tire fuel efficiency consumer information program for replacement tires designed for use on motor vehicles to educate consumers about the effect of tires on automobile fuel efficiency, safety, and durability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Items included in rule</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The rulemaking shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a national tire fuel efficiency rating system for motor vehicle replacement tires to assist consumers in making more educated tire purchasing decisions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requirements for providing information to consumers, including information at the point of sale and other potential information dissemination methods, including the Internet;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> specifications for test methods for manufacturers to use in assessing and rating tires to avoid variation among test equipment and manufacturers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a national tire maintenance consumer education program including,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002129">1</ref> information on tire inflation pressure, alignment, rotation, and tread wear to maximize fuel efficiency, safety, and durability of replacement tires.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall apply only to replacement tires covered under section 575.104(c) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, in effect on the date of the enactment of the Ten-in-Ten Fuel Economy Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Promulgation of Regulations for Tire Fuel Efficiency Minimum Performance Standards.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall promulgate regulations for tire fuel efficiency minimum performance standards for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> passenger car tires with a maximum speed capability equal to or less than 149 miles per hour or 240 kilometers per hour; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> passenger car tires with a maximum speed capability greater than 149 miles per hour or 240 kilometers per hour.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tire fuel efficiency minimum performance standards.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standard basis and test procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The minimum performance standards promulgated under paragraph (1) shall be expressed in terms of the rolling resistance coefficient measured using the test procedure specified in section 575.106 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002130">2</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No disparate effect on high performance tires</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the minimum performance standards promulgated under paragraph (1) will not have a disproportionate effect on passenger car high performance tires with a maximum speed capability greater than 149 miles per hour or 240 kilometers per hour.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection applies to new pneumatic tires for use on passenger cars.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to light truck tires, deep tread tires, winter-type snow tires, space-saver or temporary use spare tires, or tires with nominal rim diameters of 12 inches or less.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Promulgation of Regulations for Tire Wet Traction Minimum Performance Standards.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations for tire wet traction minimum performance standards to ensure that passenger tire wet traction capability is not reduced to achieve improved tire fuel efficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tire wet traction minimum performance standards.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basis of standard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The minimum performance standards promulgated under paragraph (1) shall be expressed in terms of peak coefficient of friction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Test procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any test procedure promulgated under this subsection shall be consistent with any test procedure promulgated under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Benchmarking</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall conduct testing to benchmark the wet traction performance of tire models available for sale in the United States as of the date of enactment of this Act <sup>2</sup> to ensure that the minimum performance standards promulgated under paragraph (1) are tailored to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> tires sold in the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the needs of consumers in the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection applies to new pneumatic tires for use on passenger cars.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to light truck tires, deep tread tires, winter-type snow tires, space-saver or temporary use spare tires, or tires with nominal rim diameters of 12 inches or less.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Coordination Among Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compatibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the test procedures and requirements promulgated under subsections (a), (b), and (c) are compatible and consistent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Combined effect of rules</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall evaluate the regulations promulgated under subsections (b) and (c) to ensure that compliance with the minimum performance standards promulgated under subsection (b) will not diminish wet traction performance of affected tires.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking deadlines</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall promulgate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the regulations under subsections (b) and (c) not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act; <sup>2</sup> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the regulations under subsection (c) not later than the date of promulgation of the regulations under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency on the means of conveying tire fuel efficiency consumer information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall conduct periodic assessments of the rules promulgated under this section to determine the utility of such rules to consumers, the level of cooperation by industry, and the contribution to national goals pertaining to energy consumption. The Secretary shall transmit periodic reports detailing the findings of such assessments to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Energy and Commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tire Marking</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall not require permanent labeling of any kind on a tire for the purpose of tire fuel efficiency information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application With State and Local Laws and Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section prohibits a State or political subdivision thereof from enforcing a law or regulation on tire fuel efficiency consumer information that was in effect on <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>. After a requirement promulgated under this section is in effect, a State or political subdivision thereof may adopt or enforce a law or regulation on tire fuel efficiency consumer information enacted or promulgated after <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>, if the requirements of that law or regulation are identical to the requirement promulgated under this section. Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt a State or political subdivision thereof from regulating the fuel efficiency of tires (including establishing testing methods for determining compliance with such standards) not otherwise preempted under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1506</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. B, title XXIV, § 24332</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1713</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32304B.</num>
<heading> Child safety</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Passenger motor vehicle</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “passenger motor vehicle” has the meaning given that term in section 32101.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rear-designated seating position</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “rear-designated seating position” means designated seating positions that are rearward of the front seat.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a final rule requiring all new passenger motor vehicles weighing less than 10,000 pounds gross vehicle weight to be equipped with a system to alert the operator to check rear-designated seating positions after the vehicle engine or motor is deactivated by the operator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Means</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The alert required under subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall include a distinct auditory and visual alert, which may be combined with a haptic alert; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be activated when the vehicle motor is deactivated by the operator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Phase-in</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The rule issued pursuant to subsection (b) shall require full compliance with the rule beginning on September 1st of the first calendar year that begins 2 years after the date on which the final rule is issued.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title IV, § 24222(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32305.</num>
<heading> Information and assistance from other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Request</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may request information necessary to carry out this chapter from a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government. The head of the department, agency, or instrumentality shall provide the information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detailing Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of a department, agency, or instrumentality may detail, on a reimbursable basis, personnel to assist the Secretary in carrying out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1040</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32306.</num>
<heading> Personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> appoint and fix the pay of employees without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointment in the competitive service and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make contracts with persons for research and preparation of reports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status of Advisory Committee Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of an advisory committee appointed under <ref>section 325 of this title</ref> to carry out this chapter is a special United States Government employee under chapter 11 of title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1040</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32307.</num>
<heading> Investigative powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> inspect and copy records of any person at reasonable times;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> order a person to file written reports or answers to specific questions, including reports or answers under oath; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct hearings, administer oaths, take testimony, and require (by subpena or otherwise) the appearance and testimony of witnesses and the production of records the Secretary considers advisable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Witness Fees and Mileage</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A witness summoned under subsection (a) of this section is entitled to the same fee and mileage the witness would have been paid in a court of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Actions To Enforce</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A civil action to enforce a subpena or order of the Secretary under subsection (a) of this section may be brought in the United States district court for the judicial district in which the proceeding by the Secretary is conducted. The court may punish a failure to obey an order of the court to comply with the subpena or order of the Secretary as a contempt of court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality of Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Information obtained by the Secretary under this section related to a confidential matter referred to in <ref>section 1905 of title 18</ref> may be disclosed only to another officer or employee of the United States Government for use in carrying out this chapter. This subsection does not authorize information to be withheld from a committee of Congress authorized to have the information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1040</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32308.</num>
<heading> General prohibitions, civil penalty, and enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fail to provide the Secretary of Transportation with information requested by the Secretary in carrying out this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fail to comply with applicable regulations prescribed by the Secretary in carrying out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person that violates subsection (a) of this section is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for each violation. Each failure to provide information or comply with a regulation in violation of subsection (a) is a separate violation. The maximum penalty under this subsection for a related series of violations is $400,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In determining the amount of a penalty or compromise, the appropriateness of the penalty or compromise to the size of the business of the person charged and the gravity of the violation shall be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this section from amounts it owes the person liable for the penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 32304A.—</heading>
<content>Any person who fails to comply with the national tire fuel efficiency information program under section 32304A is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Actions To Enforce</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may bring a civil action in a United States district court to enjoin a violation of subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> When practicable, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify a person against whom an action under this subsection is planned;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> give the person an opportunity to present that person’s views; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> give the person a reasonable opportunity to comply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The failure of the Secretary to comply with paragraph (2) of this subsection does not prevent a court from granting appropriate relief.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Venue and Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A civil action under this section may be brought in the judicial district in which the violation occurred or the defendant is found, resides, or does business. Process in the action may be served in any other judicial district in which the defendant resides or is found. A subpena for a witness in the action may be served in any judicial district.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title I, § 111(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32309.</num>
<heading> Civil penalty for labeling violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The definitions in <ref>section 32304 of this title</ref> apply to this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A manufacturer of a passenger motor vehicle distributed in commerce for sale in the United States that willfully fails to attach the label required under <ref>section 32304 of this title</ref> to a new passenger motor vehicle that the manufacturer manufactures or imports, or a dealer that fails to maintain that label as required under section 32304, is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for each violation. Each failure to attach or maintain that label for each vehicle is a separate violation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1042</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(31)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32310.</num>
<heading> New Car Assessment Program roadmap</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and not less frequently than once every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a roadmap for the implementation of the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A roadmap under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> cover a term of 10 years, consisting of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a mid-term component covering the initial 5 years of the term; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a long-term component covering the final 5 years of the term; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> be in accordance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 306 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 1115 of title 31</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> section 24401 of the FAST Act (<ref>49 U.S.C. 105</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 114–94</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other relevant plans of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A roadmap under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a plan for any changes to the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> descriptions of actions to be carried out to update the passenger motor vehicle information developed under section 32302(a), including the development of test procedures, test devices, test fixtures, and safety performance metrics, which shall, as applicable, incorporate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> objective criteria for evaluating safety technologies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reasonable time periods for compliance with new or updated tests;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> key milestones, including the anticipated start of an action, completion of an action, and effective date of an update; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> descriptions of the means by which an update will improve the passenger motor vehicle information developed under section 32302(a);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an identification and prioritization of safety opportunities and technologies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to the mid-term component of the roadmap under subsection (b)(1)(A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that are practicable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for which objective rating tests, evaluation criteria, and other consumer data exist for a market-based, consumer information approach; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to the long-term component of the roadmap under subsection (b)(1)(B), exist or are in development;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> an identification of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any safety opportunity or technology that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is identified through the activities carried out pursuant to subsection (d) or (e); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is not included in the roadmap under paragraph (2);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reasons why such a safety opportunity or technology is not included in the roadmap; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any developments or information that would be necessary for the Secretary to consider including such a safety opportunity or technology in a future roadmap; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> consideration of the benefits of consistency with other rating systems used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> within the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> internationally.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before finalizing a roadmap under this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make the roadmap available for public comment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review any public comments received under paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> incorporate in the roadmap under this section those comments, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stakeholder Engagement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary shall engage stakeholders that represent a diversity of technical backgrounds and viewpoints—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to identify—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> safety opportunities or technologies in development that could be included in future roadmaps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> opportunities to benefit from collaboration or harmonization with third-party safety rating programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist with long-term planning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide an interim update of the status and development of the following roadmap to be established under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to collect feedback or other information that the Secretary determines to be relevant to enhancing the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title IV, § 24213(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>