<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 42—</num>
<heading>RURAL WATER SUPPLY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>RECLAMATION RURAL WATER SUPPLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2401.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “construction” means the installation of infrastructure and the upgrading of existing facilities in locations in which the infrastructure or facilities are associated with the new infrastructure of a rural water project recommended by the Secretary pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal reclamation law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal reclamation law” means the Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date> (<ref>32 Stat. 388</ref>, chapter 1093), and Acts supplemental to and amendatory of that Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 371</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian” means an individual who is a member of an Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal project entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “non-Federal project entity” means a State, regional, or local authority, Indian tribe or tribal organization, or other qualifying entity, such as a water conservation district, water conservancy district, or rural water district or association.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operations, maintenance, and replacement costs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “operations, maintenance, and replacement costs” means all costs for the operation of a rural water supply project that are necessary for the safe, efficient, and continued functioning of the project to produce the benefits described in a feasibility study.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “operations, maintenance, and replacement costs” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> repairs of a routine nature that maintain a rural water supply project in a well kept condition;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> replacement of worn-out project elements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> rehabilitation activities necessary to bring a deteriorated project back to the original condition of the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “operations, maintenance, and replacement costs” does not include construction costs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the rural water supply program carried out under <ref>section 2402 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reclamation States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Reclamation States” means the States and areas referred to in the first section of the Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date> (<ref>43 U.S.C. 391</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rural water supply project</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “rural water supply project” means a project that is designed to serve a community or group of communities, each of which has a population of not more than 50,000 inhabitants, which may include Indian tribes and tribal organizations, dispersed homesites, or rural areas with domestic, industrial, municipal, and residential water.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “rural water supply project” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> incidental noncommercial livestock watering and noncommercial irrigation of vegetation and small gardens of less than 1 acre; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> a project to improve rural water infrastructure, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> pumps, pipes, wells, and other diversions;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> storage tanks and small impoundments;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> water treatment facilities for potable water supplies, including desalination facilities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> equipment and management tools for water conservation, groundwater recovery, and water recycling; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> appurtenances.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “rural water supply project” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> commercial irrigation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> major impoundment structures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “tribal organization” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the recognized governing body of an Indian tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any legally established organization of Indians that is controlled, sanctioned, or chartered by the governing body or democratically elected by the adult members of the Indian community to be served by the organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3346</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2402.</num>
<heading> Rural water supply program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, in cooperation with non-Federal project entities and consistent with this subchapter, may carry out a rural water supply program in Reclamation States to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> investigate and identify opportunities to ensure safe and adequate rural water supply projects for domestic, municipal, and industrial use in small communities and rural areas of the Reclamation States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> plan the design and construction, through the conduct of appraisal investigations and feasibility studies, of rural water supply projects in Reclamation States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> oversee, as appropriate, the construction of rural water supply projects in Reclamation States that are recommended by the Secretary in a feasibility report developed pursuant to <ref>section 2405 of this title</ref> and subsequently authorized by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal project entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any activity carried out under this subchapter shall be carried out in cooperation with a qualifying non-Federal project entity, consistent with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>, the Secretary shall, consistent with this subchapter, develop and publish in the Federal Register criteria for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> determining the eligibility of a rural community for assistance under the Program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prioritizing requests for assistance under the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The criteria developed under subsection (c) shall take into account such factors as whether—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a rural water supply project—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> serves—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> rural areas and small communities; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Indian tribes; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promotes and applies a regional or watershed perspective to water resources management;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> there is an urgent and compelling need for a rural water supply project that would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve the health or aesthetic quality of water;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> result in continuous, measurable, and significant water quality benefits; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> address current or future water supply needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a rural water supply project helps meet applicable requirements established by law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a rural water supply project is cost effective.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to the extent that connection provides a reliable water supply, a connection to pre-existing infrastructure (including impoundments and conveyance channels) as part of a rural water supply project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notwithstanding the limitation on population under <ref>section 2401(9)(A) of this title</ref>, a town or community with a population in excess of 50,000 inhabitants in an area served by a rural water supply project if, at the discretion of the Secretary, the town or community is considered to be a critical partner in the rural supply project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3347</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2403.</num>
<heading> Rural water programs assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Director of the Indian Health Service, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary shall develop an assessment of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the status of all rural water supply projects under the jurisdiction of the Secretary authorized but not completed prior to <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>, including appropriation amounts, the phase of development, total anticipated costs, and obstacles to completion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the current plan (including projected financial and workforce requirements) for the completion of the projects identified in paragraph (1) within the time frames established under the provisions of law authorizing the projects or the final engineering reports for the projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the demand for new rural water supply projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> rural water programs within other agencies and a description of the extent to which those programs provide support for rural water supply projects and water treatment programs in Reclamation States, including an assessment of the requirements, funding levels, and conditions of eligibility for the programs assessed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the extent of the demand that the Secretary can meet with the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> how the Program will complement authorities already within the jurisdiction of the Secretary and the heads of the agencies with whom the Secretary consults; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> improvements that can be made to coordinate and integrate the authorities of the agencies with programs evaluated under paragraph (4), including any recommendations to consolidate some or all of the activities of the agencies with respect to rural water supply.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before finalizing the assessment developed under subsection (a), the Secretary shall solicit comments from States with identified rural water needs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives a detailed report on the assessment conducted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2404.</num>
<heading> Appraisal investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On request of a non-Federal project entity with respect to a proposed rural water supply project that meets the eligibility criteria published under <ref>section 2402(c) of this title</ref> and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> receive and review an appraisal investigation that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> developed by the non-Federal project entity, with or without support from the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submitted to the Secretary by the non-Federal project entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct an appraisal investigation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> provide a grant to, or enter into a cooperative agreement with, the non-Federal project entity to conduct an appraisal investigation, if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the non-Federal project entity is qualified to complete the appraisal investigation in accordance with the criteria published under <ref>section 2402(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> using the non-Federal project entity to conduct the appraisal investigation is a cost-effective alternative for completing the appraisal investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An appraisal investigation conducted under subsection (a) shall be scheduled for completion not later than 2 years after the date on which the appraisal investigation is initiated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appraisal report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with subsection (f), after an appraisal investigation is submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a)(1) or completed under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a), the Secretary shall prepare an appraisal report that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> considers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> whether the project meets—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the appraisal criteria developed under subsection (d); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the eligibility criteria developed under <ref>section 2402(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether viable water supplies and water rights exist to supply the project, including all practicable water sources such as lower quality waters, nonpotable waters, and water reuse-based water supplies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether the project has a positive effect on public health and safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether the project will meet water demand, including projected future needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the extent to which the project provides environmental benefits, including source water protection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> whether the project applies a regional or watershed perspective and promotes benefits in the region in which the project is carried out;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> whether the project—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> implements an integrated resources management approach; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> enhances water management flexibility, including providing for—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> local control to manage water supplies under varying water supply conditions; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> participation in water banking and markets for domestic and environmental purposes; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> promotes long-term protection of water supplies;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> preliminary cost estimates for the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> whether the non-Federal project entity has the capability to pay 100 percent of the costs associated with the operations, maintenance, and replacement of the facilities constructed or developed as part of the rural water supply project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides recommendations on whether a feasibility study should be initiated under <ref>section 2405(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appraisal criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>, the Secretary shall promulgate criteria (including appraisal factors listed under subsection (c)) against which the appraisal investigations shall be assessed for completeness and appropriateness for a feasibility study.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To minimize the cost of a rural water supply project to a non-Federal project entity, the Secretary shall include in the criteria methods to scale the level of effort needed to complete the appraisal investigation relative to the total size and cost of the proposed rural water supply project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of appraisal investigation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the date of submission of an appraisal investigation under paragraph (1) or (3) of subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide to the non-Federal entity that conducted the investigation a determination of whether the investigation has included the information necessary to determine whether the proposed rural water supply project satisfies the criteria promulgated under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No satisfaction of criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that the appraisal investigation submitted by a non-Federal entity does not satisfy the criteria promulgated under subsection (d), the Secretary shall inform the non-Federal entity of the reasons why the appraisal investigation is deficient.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If an appraisal investigation as first submitted by a non-Federal entity does not provide all necessary information, as defined by the Secretary, the Secretary shall have no obligation to conduct further analysis until the non-Federal project entity submitting the appraisal study conducts additional investigation and resubmits the appraisal investigation under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appraisal report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Once the Secretary has determined that an investigation provides the information necessary under subsection (e), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> complete the appraisal report required under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make available to the public, on request, the appraisal report prepared under this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promptly publish in the Federal Register a notice of the availability of the results.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal share of an appraisal investigation conducted under subsection (a) shall be 100 percent of the total cost of the appraisal investigation, up to $200,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), if the cost of conducting an appraisal investigation is more than $200,000, the non-Federal share of the costs in excess of $200,000 shall be 50 percent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may reduce the non-Federal share required under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that there is an overwhelming Federal interest in the appraisal investigation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The non-Federal share under subparagraph (A) may be in the form of any in-kind services that the Secretary determines would contribute substantially toward the conduct and completion of the appraisal investigation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation; identification of funding sources</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In conducting an appraisal investigation under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult and cooperate with the non-Federal project entity and appropriate State, tribal, regional, and local authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> consult with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that the proposed rural water supply project does not duplicate a project carried out under the authority of the agency head; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if a duplicate project is being carried out, identify the authority under which the duplicate project is being carried out; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify what funding sources are available for the proposed rural water supply project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2405.</num>
<heading> Feasibility studies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On completion of an appraisal report under <ref>section 2404(c) of this title</ref> that recommends undertaking a feasibility study and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in cooperation with a non-Federal project entity, carry out a study to determine the feasibility of the proposed rural water supply project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> receive and review a feasibility study that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> developed by the non-Federal project entity, with or without support from the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submitted to the Secretary by the non-Federal project entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> provide a grant to, or enter into a cooperative agreement with, a non-Federal project entity to conduct a feasibility study, for submission to the Secretary, if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the non-Federal entity is qualified to complete the feasibility study in accordance with the criteria promulgated under subsection (d); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> using the non-Federal project entity to conduct the feasibility study is a cost-effective alternative for completing the appraisal investigation; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Secretary determines not to provide a grant to, or enter into a cooperative agreement with, a non-Federal project entity under subparagraph (A), provide to the non-Federal project entity notice of the determination, including an explanation of the reason for the determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of non-Federal feasibility studies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In conducting a review of a feasibility study submitted under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in accordance with the feasibility factors described in subsection (c) and the criteria promulgated under subsection (d), assess the completeness of the feasibility study; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Secretary determines that a feasibility study is not complete, notify the non-Federal entity of the determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary determines under paragraph (1)(B) that a feasibility study is not complete, the non-Federal entity shall pay any costs associated with revising the feasibility study.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Feasibility factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Feasibility studies authorized or reviewed under this subchapter shall include an assessment of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> near- and long-term water demand in the area to be served by the rural water supply project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advancement of public health and safety of any existing rural water supply project and other benefits of the proposed rural water supply project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> alternative new water supplies in the study area, including any opportunities to treat and use low-quality water, nonpotable water, water reuse-based supplies, and brackish and saline waters through innovative and economically viable treatment technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> environmental quality and source water protection issues related to the rural water supply project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> innovative opportunities for water conservation in the study area to reduce water use and water system costs, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> nonstructural approaches to reduce the need for the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> demonstration technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the extent to which the project and alternatives take advantage of economic incentives and the use of market-based mechanisms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the construction costs and projected operations, maintenance, and replacement costs of all alternatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the economic feasibility and lowest cost method of obtaining the desired results of each alternative, taking into account the Federal cost-share;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the availability of guaranteed loans for a proposed rural water supply project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the financial capability of the non-Federal project entity to pay the non-Federal project entity’s proportionate share of the design and construction costs and 100 percent of operations, maintenance, and replacement costs, including the allocation of costs to each non-Federal project entity in the case of multiple entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> whether the non-Federal project entity has developed an operations, management, and replacement plan to assist the non-Federal project entity in establishing rates and fees for beneficiaries of the rural water supply project that includes a schedule identifying the annual operations, maintenance, and replacement costs that should be allocated to each non-Federal entity participating in the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the non-Federal project entity administrative organization that would implement construction, operations, maintenance, and replacement activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the fiscal, administrative, and operational controls to be implemented to manage the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the extent to which assistance for rural water supply is available under other Federal authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the engineering, environmental, and economic activities to be undertaken to carry out the proposed rural water supply project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the extent to which the project involves partnerships with other State, local, or tribal governments or Federal entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> in the case of a project intended for Indian tribes and tribal organizations, the extent to which the project addresses the goal of economic self-sufficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Feasibility study criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>, the Secretary shall promulgate criteria (including the feasibility factors listed under subsection (c)) under which the feasibility studies shall be assessed for completeness and appropriateness.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall include in the criteria promulgated under paragraph (1) methods to scale the level of effort needed to complete the feasibility assessment relative to the total size and cost of the proposed rural water supply project and reduce total costs to non-Federal entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Feasibility report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002180">1</ref> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After completion of appropriate feasibility studies for rural water supply projects that address the factors described in subsection (c) and the criteria promulgated under subsection (d), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> develop a feasibility report that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> a recommendation of the Secretary on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> whether the rural water supply project should be authorized for construction; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> the appropriate non-Federal share of construction costs, which shall be—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> at least 25 percent of the total construction costs; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> determined based on an analysis of the capability-to-pay information considered under subsections (c)(9) and (f); and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if the Secretary recommends that the project should be authorized for construction—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> what amount of grants, loan guarantees, or combination of grants and loan guarantees should be used to provide the Federal cost share;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a schedule that identifies the annual operations, maintenance, and replacement costs that should be allocated to each non-Federal entity participating in the rural water supply project; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> an assessment of the financial capability of each non-Federal entity participating in the rural water supply project to pay the allocated annual operation, maintenance, and replacement costs for the rural water supply project;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit the report to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make the report publicly available, along with associated study documents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> publish in the Federal Register a notice of the availability of the results.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capability-to-pay</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In evaluating a proposed rural water supply project under this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consider the financial capability of any non-Federal project entities participating in the rural water supply project to pay 25 percent or more of the capital construction costs of the rural water supply project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommend an appropriate Federal share and non-Federal share of the capital construction costs, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In determining the financial capability of non-Federal project entities to pay for a rural water supply project under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall evaluate factors for the project area, relative to the State average, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> per capita income;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> median household income;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the poverty rate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the ability of the non-Federal project entity to raise tax revenues or assess fees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the strength of the balance sheet of the non-Federal project entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the existing cost of water in the region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In determining the capability-to-pay of Indian tribe project beneficiaries, the Secretary may consider deferring the collection of all or part of the non-Federal construction costs apportioned to Indian tribe project beneficiaries unless or until the Secretary determines that the Indian tribe project beneficiaries should pay—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the costs allocated to the beneficiaries; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an appropriate portion of the costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-sharing requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the Federal share of the cost of a feasibility study carried out under this section shall not exceed 50 percent of the study costs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The non-Federal share under paragraph (1) may be in the form of any in-kind services that the Secretary determines would contribute substantially toward the conduct and completion of the study.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial hardship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may increase the Federal share of the costs of a feasibility study if the Secretary determines, based on a demonstration of financial hardship, that the non-Federal participant is unable to contribute at least 50 percent of the costs of the study.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Larger communities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In conducting a feasibility study of a rural water supply system that includes a community with a population in excess of 50,000 inhabitants, the Secretary may require the non-Federal project entity to pay more than 50 percent of the costs of the study.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the non-Federal project entity, the Secretary shall consult and cooperate with appropriate Federal, State, tribal, regional, and local authorities during the conduct of each feasibility assessment and development of the feasibility report conducted under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3351</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2406.</num>
<heading> Miscellaneous</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into contracts, financial assistance agreements, and such other agreements, and promulgate such regulations, as are necessary to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter authorizes the transfer of pre-existing facilities or pre-existing components of any water system from Federal to private ownership or from private to Federal ownership.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal reclamation law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter supersedes or amends any Federal law associated with a project, or portion of a project, constructed under Federal reclamation law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate the Program carried out under this subchapter with existing Federal and State rural water and wastewater programs to facilitate the most efficient and effective solution to meeting the water needs of the non-Federal project sponsors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which a contract is entered into with, or a grant is made, to <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002181">1</ref> an organization to perform services benefitting more than 1 Indian tribe under this subchapter, the approval of each such Indian tribe shall be a prerequisite to entering into the contract or making the grant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ownership of facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Title to any facility planned, designed, and recommended for construction under this subchapter shall be held by the non-Federal project entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that a community to be served by a proposed rural water supply project has urgent and compelling water needs, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, expedite appraisal investigations and reports conducted under <ref>section 2404 of this title</ref> and feasibility studies and reports conducted under <ref>section 2405 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on State water law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subchapter preempts or affects State water law or an interstate compact governing water.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall comply with State water laws in carrying out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No additional requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter requires a feasibility study for, or imposes any other additional requirements with respect to, rural water supply projects or programs that are authorized before <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2407.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning in fiscal year 2007, and each fiscal year thereafter through fiscal year 2012, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives an annual report that describes the number and type of full-time equivalent positions in the Department of the Interior and the amount of overhead costs of the Department of the Interior that are allocated to carrying out this subchapter for the applicable fiscal year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2408.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subchapter $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2016, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rural water programs assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts made available under subsection (a), not more than $1,000,000 may be made available to carry out <ref>section 2403 of this title</ref> for each of fiscal years 2007 and 2008.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No amounts made available under this section shall be used to pay construction costs associated with any rural water supply project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2409.</num>
<heading> Termination of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary to carry out this subchapter terminates on <date date="2016-09-30">September 30, 2016</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>TWENTY-FIRST CENTURY WATER WORKS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2421.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lender</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “lender” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a non-Federal qualified institutional buyer (as defined in section 230.144A(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002182">1</ref> (or any successor regulation), known as Rule 144A(a) of the Securities and Exchange Commission and issued under the Securities Act of 1933 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 77a</ref> et seq.)); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a clean renewable energy bond lender (as defined in section 54(j)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002183">2</ref> of title 26 (as in effect on <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan guarantee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “loan guarantee” has the meaning given the term “loan guarantee” in <ref>section 661a of title 2</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal borrower</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “non-Federal borrower” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State (including a department, agency, or political subdivision of a State); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a conservancy district, irrigation district, canal company, water users’ association, Indian tribe, an agency created by interstate compact, or any other entity that has the capacity to contract with the United States under Federal reclamation law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “obligation” means a loan or other debt obligation that is guaranteed under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “project” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a rural water supply project (as defined in <ref>section 2401(9) of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> an extraordinary operation and maintenance activity for, or the rehabilitation or replacement of, a facility—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is authorized by Federal reclamation law and constructed by the United States under such law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in connection with which there is a repayment or water service contract executed by the United States under Federal reclamation law; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> an improvement to water infrastructure directly associated with a reclamation project that, based on a determination of the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> improves water management; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> fulfills other Federal goals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2422.</num>
<heading> Project eligibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall develop and publish in the Federal Register criteria for determining the eligibility of a project for financial assistance under <ref>section 2423 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Eligibility criteria shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submission of an application by the lender to the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> demonstration of the creditworthiness of the project, including a determination by the Secretary that any financing for the project has appropriate security features to ensure repayment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> demonstration by the non-Federal borrower, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, of the ability of the non-Federal borrower to repay the project financing from user fees or other dedicated revenue sources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> demonstration by the non-Federal borrower, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, of the ability of the non-Federal borrower to pay all operations, maintenance, and replacement costs of the project facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such other criteria as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may waive any of the criteria in subsection (a)(2) that the Secretary determines to be duplicative or rendered unnecessary because of an action already taken by the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects previously authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A project that was authorized for construction under Federal reclamation laws prior to <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>, shall be eligible for assistance under this subchapter, subject to the criteria established by the Secretary under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for rural water supply projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A rural water supply project that is determined to be feasible under <ref>section 2405 of this title</ref> is eligible for a loan guarantee under <ref>section 2423 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2423.</num>
<heading> Loan guarantees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may make available to lenders for a project meeting the eligibility criteria established in <ref>section 2422 of this title</ref> loan guarantees to supplement private-sector or lender financing for the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Loan guarantees under this section for a project shall be on such terms and conditions and contain such covenants, representations, warranties, and requirements as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to protect the financial interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Loan guarantees by the Secretary shall not exceed an amount equal to 90 percent of the cost of the project that is the subject of the loan guarantee, as estimated at the time at which the loan guarantee is issued.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An obligation shall bear interest at a rate that does not exceed a level that the Secretary determines to be appropriate, taking into account the prevailing rate of interest in the private sector for similar loans and risks.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amortization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A loan guarantee under this section shall provide for complete amortization of the loan guarantee within not more than 40 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonsubordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An obligation shall be subject to the condition that the obligation is not subordinate to other financing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prepayment and refinancing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any prepayment or refinancing terms on a loan guarantee shall be negotiated between the non-Federal borrower and the lender with the consent of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3358</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2424.</num>
<heading> Defaults</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments by Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a borrower defaults on the obligation, the holder of the loan guarantee shall have the right to demand payment of the unpaid amount from the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">By such date as may be specified in the loan guarantee or related agreements, the Secretary shall pay to the holder of the loan guarantee the unpaid interest on, and unpaid principal of, the obligation with respect to which the borrower has defaulted, unless the Secretary finds that there was not default by the borrower in the payment of interest or principal or that the default has been remedied.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forbearance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection precludes any forbearance by the holder of the obligation for the benefit of the non-Federal borrower that may be agreed on by the parties to the obligation and approved by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subrogation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Secretary makes a payment under subsection (a), the Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the recipient of the payment as specified in the loan guarantee or related agreements, including, as appropriate, the authority (notwithstanding any other provision of law) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> complete, maintain, operate, lease, or otherwise dispose of any property acquired pursuant to the loan guarantee or related agreements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permit the non-Federal borrower, pursuant to an agreement with the Secretary, to continue to pursue the purposes of the project if the Secretary determines the purposes to be in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Superiority of rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rights of the Secretary, with respect to any property acquired pursuant to a loan guarantee or related agreement, shall be superior to the rights of any other person with respect to the property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of principal and interest by Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to any obligation guaranteed under this section, the Secretary may enter into a contract to pay, and pay, holders of the obligation, for and on behalf of the non-Federal borrower, from funds appropriated for that purpose, the principal and interest payments that become due and payable on the unpaid balance of the obligation if the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the non-Federal borrower is unable to meet the payments and is not in default;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> it is in the public interest to permit the non-Federal borrower to continue to pursue the purposes of the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the probable net benefit to the Federal Government in paying the principal and interest will be greater than that which would result in the event of a default;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of the payment that the Secretary is authorized to pay shall be no greater than the amount of principal and interest that the non-Federal borrower is obligated to pay under the agreement being guaranteed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the borrower agrees to reimburse the Secretary for the payment (including interest) on terms and conditions that are satisfactory to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action by Attorney General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the non-Federal borrower defaults on an obligation, the Secretary shall notify the Attorney General of the default.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On notification, the Attorney General shall take such action as is appropriate to recover the unpaid principal and interest due from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such assets of the defaulting non-Federal borrower as are associated with the obligation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other security pledged to secure the obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3358</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2425.</num>
<heading> Operations, maintenance, and replacement costs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The non-Federal share of operations, maintenance, and replacement costs for a project receiving Federal assistance under this subchapter shall be 100 percent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On request of the non-Federal borrower, the Secretary may assist in the development of an operation, maintenance, and replacement plan to provide the necessary framework to assist the non-Federal borrower in establishing rates and fees for project beneficiaries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2426.</num>
<heading> Title to newly constructed facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New projects and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All new projects or facilities constructed in accordance with this subchapter shall remain under the jurisdiction and control of the non-Federal borrower subject to the terms of the repayment agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing projects and facilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter affects the title of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reclamation projects authorized prior to <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> works supplemental to existing reclamation projects; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> works constructed to rehabilitate existing reclamation projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2427.</num>
<heading> Water rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter preempts or affects State water law or an interstate compact governing water.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall comply with State water laws in carrying out this subchapter. Nothing in this subchapter affects or preempts State water law or an interstate compact governing water.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2428.</num>
<heading> Interagency coordination and cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Agriculture before promulgating criteria with respect to financial appraisal functions and loan guarantee administration for activities carried out under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memorandum of agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall enter into a memorandum of agreement providing for Department of Agriculture financial appraisal functions and loan guarantee administration for activities carried out under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2429.</num>
<heading> Records; audits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A recipient of a loan guarantee shall keep such records and other pertinent documents as the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation, including such records as the Secretary may require to facilitate an effective audit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, or their duly authorized representatives, shall have access, for the purpose of audit, to the records and other pertinent documents.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2430.</num>
<heading> Full faith and credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The full faith and credit of the United States is pledged to the payment of all guarantees issued under this section with respect to principal and interest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2431.</num>
<heading> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the eligibility criteria are published in the Federal Register under <ref>section 2422(a) of this title</ref>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes the implementation of the loan guarantee program under <ref>section 2423 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2432.</num>
<heading> Effect on the reclamation laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reclamation projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter supersedes or amends any Federal law associated with a project, or a portion of a project, constructed under the reclamation laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No new or supplemental benefits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any assistance provided under this subchapter shall not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be considered to be a new or supplemental benefit for purposes of the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 (<ref>43 U.S.C. 390aa</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> affect any contract in existence on <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>, that is executed under the reclamation laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2433.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this subchapter, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2434.</num>
<heading> Termination of authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), the authority of the Secretary to carry out this subchapter terminates on the date that is 10 years after <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The termination of authority under subsection (a) shall have no effect on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any loans guaranteed by the United States under this subchapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the administration of any loan guaranteed under this subchapter before the effective date of the termination of authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–451, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>