<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 39—</num>
<heading>ABANDONED SHIPWRECKS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2101.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> States have the responsibility for management of a broad range of living and nonliving resources in State waters and submerged lands; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> included in the range of resources are certain abandoned shipwrecks, which have been deserted and to which the owner has relinquished ownership rights with no retention.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–298, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> the term “embedded” means firmly affixed in the submerged lands or in coralline formations such that the use of tools of excavation is required in order to move the bottom sediments to gain access to the shipwreck, its cargo, and any part thereof;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> the term “National Register” means the National Register of Historic Places maintained by the Secretary of the Interior under section 101 of the National Historic Preservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 470a</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002175">1</ref></content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> the terms “public lands”, “Indian lands”, and “Indian tribe” have the same meaning given the terms in the Archaeological Resource <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002176">2</ref> Protection Act of 1979 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 470aa–470</ref><i>ll</i>);</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> the term “shipwreck” means a vessel or wreck, its cargo, and other contents;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> the term “submerged lands” means the lands—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that are “lands beneath navigable waters,” as defined in <ref>section 1301 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of Puerto Rico, as described in <ref>section 749 of title 48</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> of Guam, the Virgin Islands and American Samoa, as described in <ref>section 1705 of title 48</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, as described in <ref>section 801 of Public Law 94–241</ref>.<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–298, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103.</num>
<heading> Rights of access</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> clarify that State waters and shipwrecks offer recreational and educational opportunities to sport divers and other interested groups, as well as irreplaceable State resources for tourism, biological sanctuaries, and historical research; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide that reasonable access by the public to such abandoned shipwrecks be permitted by the State holding title to such shipwrecks pursuant to <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">it is the declared policy of the Congress that States carry out their responsibilities under this chapter to develop appropriate and consistent policies so as to—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protect natural resources and habitat areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> guarantee recreational exploration of shipwreck sites; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> allow for appropriate public and private sector recovery of shipwrecks consistent with the protection of historical values and environmental integrity of the shipwrecks and the sites.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parks and protected areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In managing the resources subject to the provisions of this chapter, States are encouraged to create underwater parks or areas to provide additional protection for such resources. Funds available to States from grants from the Historic Preservation Fund shall be available, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 3029 of title 54, for the study, interpretation, protection, and preservation of historic shipwrecks and properties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–298, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104.</num>
<heading> Preparation of guidelines</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of guidelines; publication in Federal Register</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to encourage the development of underwater parks and the administrative cooperation necessary for the comprehensive management of underwater resources related to historic shipwrecks, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, shall within nine months after <date date="1988-04-28">April 28, 1988</date>, prepare and publish guidelines in the Federal Register which shall seek to:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maximize the enhancement of cultural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> foster a partnership among sport divers, fishermen, archeologists, salvors, and other interests to manage shipwreck resources of the States and the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> facilitate access and utilization by recreational interests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recognize the interests of individuals and groups engaged in shipwreck discovery and salvage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such guidelines shall be developed after consultation with appropriate public and private sector interests (including the Secretary of Commerce, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, sport divers, State Historic Preservation Officers, professional dive operators, salvors, archeologists, historic preservationists, and fishermen).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of guidelines in developing legislation and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such guidelines shall be available to assist States and the appropriate Federal agencies in developing legislation and regulations to carry out their responsibilities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–298, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2105.</num>
<heading> Rights of ownership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States title</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States asserts title to any abandoned shipwreck that is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> embedded in submerged lands of a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> embedded in coralline formations protected by a State on submerged lands of a State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> on submerged lands of a State and is included in or determined eligible for inclusion in the National Register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of shipwreck location; eligibility determination for inclusion in National Register of Historic Places</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The public shall be given adequate notice of the location of any shipwreck to which title is asserted under this section. The Secretary of the Interior, after consultation with the appropriate State Historic Preservation Officer, shall make a written determination that an abandoned shipwreck meets the criteria for eligibility for inclusion in the National Register of Historic Places under clause (a)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of title to States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The title of the United States to any abandoned shipwreck asserted under subsection (a) of this section is transferred to the State in or on whose submerged lands the shipwreck is located.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any abandoned shipwreck in or on the public lands of the United States is the property of the United States Government. Any abandoned shipwreck in or on any Indian lands is the property of the Indian tribe owning such lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation of rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section does not affect any right reserved by the United States or by any State (including any right reserved with respect to Indian lands) under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 1311, 1313, or 1314 of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> section 414 or 415 of title 33.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–298, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2106.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law of salvage and law of finds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The law of salvage and the law of finds shall not apply to abandoned shipwrecks to which <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Laws of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not change the laws of the United States relating to shipwrecks, other than those to which this chapter applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not affect any legal proceeding brought prior to <date date="1988-04-28">April 28, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–298, § 7</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>