<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES GEOLOGICAL SURVEY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 31.</num>
<heading> Director of United States Geological Survey</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of office; appointment and duties; examination of geological structure, mineral resources, and products of national domain; prohibitions in respect to lands and surveys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the United States Geological Survey, which office is established, under the Interior Department, shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. This officer shall have the direction of the United States Geological Survey, and the classification of the public lands and examination of the geological structure, mineral resources, and products of the national domain. The Director and members of the United States Geological Survey shall have no personal or private interests in the lands or mineral wealth of the region under survey, and shall execute no surveys or examinations for private parties or corporations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Examination of geological structure, mineral resources, and products outside national domain</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary of the Interior, exercised through the United States Geological Survey of the Department of the Interior, to examine the geological structure, mineral resources, and products of the national domain, is expanded to authorize such examinations outside the national domain where determined by the Secretary to be in the national interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1879, ch. 182</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 394</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–626</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1962-09-05">Sept. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–608, § 2(6)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1971</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1081(e)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31a.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> although significant progress has been made in the production of geologic maps since the establishment of the national cooperative geologic mapping program in 1992, no modern, digital, geologic map exists for approximately 75 percent of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> geologic maps are the primary data base for virtually all applied and basic earth-science investigations, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> exploration for and development of mineral, energy, and water resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> screening and characterizing sites for toxic and nuclear waste disposal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> land use evaluation and planning for homeland and environmental protection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> earthquake hazards reduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identifying volcanic hazards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> design and construction of infrastructure requirements such as utility lifelines, transportation corridors, and surface-water impoundments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> reducing losses from landslides and other ground failures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> mitigating effects of coastal and stream erosion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> siting of critical facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> recreation and public awareness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> basic earth-science research;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Federal agencies, State and local governments, private industry, and the general public depend on the information provided by geologic maps to determine the extent of potential environmental damage before embarking on projects that could lead to preventable, costly environmental problems or litigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the combined capabilities of State, Federal, and academic groups to provide geologic mapping are not sufficient to meet the present and future needs of the United States for national security, environmental protection, and energy self-sufficiency of the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> States are willing to contribute 50 percent of the funding necessary to complete the mapping of the geology within the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the lack of proper geologic maps has led to the poor design of such structures as dams and waste-disposal facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> geologic maps have proven indispensable in the search for needed fossil-fuel and mineral resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> geologic map information is required for the sustainable and balanced development of natural resources of all types, including energy, minerals, land, water, and biological resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> advances in digital technology and geographical information system science have made geologic map databases increasingly available as decision support tools for land and resource management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> a comprehensive nationwide program of geologic mapping of surficial and bedrock deposits is required in order to systematically build the Nation’s geologic-map data base at a pace that responds to increasing demand.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of sections 31a to 31h of this title is to expedite the production of a geologic-map data base for the Nation, to be located within the United States Geological Survey, which can be applied to land-use management, assessment, and utilization, conservation of natural resources, groundwater management, and environmental protection and management.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 166</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XI, § 11001(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1414</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31b.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In sections 31a to 31h of this title:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “advisory committee” means the advisory committee established under <ref>section 31d of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Association</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Association” means the Association of American State Geologists.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the United States Geological Survey.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Education component</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “education component” means the education component of the geologic mapping program described in <ref>section 31c(d)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal component</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal component” means the Federal component of the geologic mapping program described in <ref>section 31c(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geologic mapping program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “geologic mapping program” means the National Cooperative Geologic Mapping Program established by <ref>section 31c(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State component</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State component” means the State component of the geologic mapping program described in <ref>section 31c(d)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Survey” means the United States Geological Survey.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 167</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–36, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 3</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title V, § 5002(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31c.</num>
<heading> Geologic mapping program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established a national cooperative geologic mapping program between the United States Geological Survey and the State geological surveys, acting through the Association.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Design, development, and administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The cooperative geologic mapping program shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designed and administered to achieve the objectives set forth in subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> developed in consultation with the advisory committee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> administered through the Survey.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of the Survey</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Survey shall be the lead Federal agency responsible for planning, developing national priorities and standards for, coordinating, and managing the geologic mapping program. In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop a 5-year strategic plan for the geologic mapping program in accordance with <ref>section 31e of this title</ref>, which plan shall be submitted to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate not later than 1 year after <date date="2019-03-12">March 12, 2019</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appoint, with the advice and consultation of the Association, the advisory committee not later than 1 year after <date date="2019-03-12">March 12, 2019</date>, in accordance with <ref>section 31d of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> submit biennially a report to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives identifying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> how the Survey and the Association are coordinating the development and implementation of the geologic mapping program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how the Survey and the Association establish goals, mapping priorities, and target dates for implementation of the geologic mapping program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> how long-term staffing plans for the various components of the geologic mapping program affect successful implementation of the geologic mapping program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of the Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to paragraph (1), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall be responsible for developing, as soon as practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in cooperation with the Association, other Federal and State agencies, public and private sector organizations and academia, the geologic-map data base; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> maps and mapping techniques which achieve the objectives specified in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The objectives of the geologic mapping program shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> determining the Nation’s geologic framework through systematic development of geologic maps at scales appropriate to the geologic setting and the perceived applications, such maps to be contributed to the national geologic map data base;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> development of a complementary national geochronologic and paleontologic data base that provides value-added descriptive and interpretative information to the geologic-map data base;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> application of cost-effective mapping techniques that assemble, produce, translate and disseminate geologic-map information and that render such information of greater application and benefit to the public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> development of public awareness of the role and application of geologic-map information to the resolution of national issues of land use management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program components</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal component</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The geologic mapping program shall include a Federal geologic mapping component, the objective of which shall be to determine the geologic framework of areas determined to be vital to the economic, social, environmental, or scientific welfare of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mapping priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For the Federal component, mapping priorities—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be described in the 5-year plan under <ref>section 31e of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> shall be based on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> national requirements for geologic map information in areas of multiple-issue need or areas of compelling single-issue need;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> national requirements for geologic map information in areas where mapping is required to solve critical earth science problems; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the needs of land management agencies of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interdisciplinary studies</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Federal component shall include interdisciplinary studies that add value to geologic mapping.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representative categories</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Interdisciplinary studies under clause (i) may include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> establishment of a national geologic map database under <ref>section 31f of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> studies that lead to the implementation of cost-effective digital methods for the acquisition, compilation, analysis, cartographic production, and dissemination of geologic map information;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> paleontologic, geochrono-logic, and isotopic investigations that provide information critical to understanding the age and history of geologic map units;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> geophysical investigations that assist in delineating and mapping the physical characteristics and 3-dimensional distribution of geologic materials and geologic structures; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> geochemical investigations and analytical operations that characterize the composition of geologic map units.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The results of investigations under clause (ii) shall be contributed to national databases.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State component</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The geologic mapping program shall include a State geologic mapping component, the objective of which shall be to establish the geologic framework of areas determined to be vital to the economic, social, environmental, or scientific welfare of individual States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mapping priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For the State component, mapping priorities—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be determined by State panels representing a broad range of users of geologic maps; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> shall be based on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> State requirements for geologic map information in areas of multiple-issue need or areas of compelling single-issue need; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> State requirements for geologic map information in areas where mapping is required to solve critical earth science problems.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integration of Federal and State priorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A national panel including representatives of the Survey shall integrate the State mapping priorities under this paragraph with the Federal mapping priorities under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Survey and recipients of grants under the State component shall not use more than 15.25 percent of the Federal funds made available under the State component for any fiscal year to pay indirect, servicing, or program management charges.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal share of the cost of activities under the State component for any fiscal year shall not exceed 50 percent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Education component</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The geologic mapping program shall include a geologic mapping education component for the training of geologic mappers, the objectives of which shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to provide for broad education in geologic mapping and field analysis through support of field studies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to develop academic programs that teach students of earth science the fundamental principles of geologic mapping and field analysis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The education component may include the conduct of investigations, which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be integrated with the Federal component and the State component; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall respond to mapping priorities identified for the Federal component and the State component.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Survey and recipients of grants under the education component shall not use more than 15.25 percent of the Federal funds made available under the education component for any fiscal year to pay indirect, servicing, or program management charges.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal share of the cost of activities under the education component for any fiscal year shall not exceed 50 percent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abandoned mine land and mine waste component</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The geologic mapping program shall include an abandoned mine land and mine waste geologic mapping component, the objective of which shall be to establish the geologic framework of abandoned mine land and other land containing mine waste.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mapping priorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For the component described in subparagraph (A), the priority shall be mapping abandoned mine land and other land containing mine waste where multiple critical mineral (as defined in <ref>section 1606(a) of title 30</ref>) and metal commodities are anticipated to be present, rather than single mineral resources.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 4</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 167</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 16(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–36, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 4</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XI, § 11001(c)</ref>–(e), <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1414</ref>, 1415; <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title V, § 5002(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title II, § 40202(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 959</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31d.</num>
<heading> Advisory committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be established a 11-member geologic mapping advisory committee to advise the Director on planning and implementation of the geologic mapping program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members ex officio</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal agency members shall include the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency or a designee, the Secretary of the Interior or a designee from a land management agency of the Department of the Interior, the Secretary of Energy or a designee, and the Secretary of Agriculture or a designee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointed members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In consultation with the Association, the Secretary shall appoint to the advisory committee two representatives from the Survey (including the Associate Director for Core Science Systems, as Chair), two representatives from the State geological surveys, one representative from academia, and 2 representatives from the private sector.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The advisory committee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review and update the 5-year plan prepared by the Director pursuant to <ref>section 31e of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review the scientific progress of the geologic mapping program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide a scientific overview of geologic maps (including maps of geologic-based hazards) used or disseminated by Federal agencies for regulation or land-use planning; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> submit an annual report to the Secretary that evaluates the progress of the Federal, State, and university mapping activities and evaluates the progress made toward fulfilling the purposes of sections 31c through 31f of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 5</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–36, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 5</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XI, § 11001(f)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title V, § 5002(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31e.</num>
<heading> Geologic mapping program 5-year plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall, with the advice and review of the advisory committee, prepare a 5-year plan for the geologic mapping program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The 5-year plan shall identify—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> overall priorities for the geologic mapping program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> implementation of the overall management structure and operation of the geologic mapping program, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the role of the Survey in the capacity of overall management lead, including the responsibility for developing the national geologic mapping program that meets Federal needs while fostering State needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the responsibilities of the State geological surveys, with emphasis on mechanisms that incorporate the needs, missions, capabilities, and requirements of the State geological surveys, into the nationwide geologic mapping program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> mechanisms for identifying short- and long-term priorities for each component of the geologic mapping program, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> for the Federal component, a priority-setting mechanism that responds to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Federal mission requirements for geologic map information;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> critical scientific problems that require geologic maps for their resolution; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> shared Federal and State needs for geologic maps, in which joint Federal-State geologic mapping projects are in the national interest;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> for the State component, a priority-setting mechanism that responds to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> specific intrastate needs for geologic map information; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> interstate needs shared by adjacent States that have common requirements; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> for the education component, a priority-setting mechanism that responds to requirements for geologic map information that are dictated by Federal and State mission requirements;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> a mechanism for adopting scientific and technical mapping standards for preparing and publishing general- and special-purpose geologic maps to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ensure uniformity of cartographic and scientific conventions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide a basis for assessing the comparability and quality of map products; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a mechanism for monitoring the inventory of published and current mapping investigations nationwide to facilitate planning and information exchange and to avoid redundancy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 6</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 6</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1722</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31f.</num>
<heading> National geologic map database</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Survey shall establish a national geologic-map database.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Function</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The database shall serve as a national catalog and archive, distributed through links to Federal and State geologic map holdings, that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all maps developed with funding provided by the National Cooperative Geologic Mapping Program, including under the Federal, State, and education components;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the databases developed in connection with investigations under subclauses (III), (IV), and (V) of <ref>section 31c(d)(1)(C)(ii) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other maps and data that the Survey and the Association consider appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standardization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Geologic maps contributed to the national archives shall have format, symbols, and technical attributes that adhere to standards so that archival information can be accessed, exchanged, and compared efficiently and accurately, as required by Executive Order 12906 (59 Fed. Reg. 17,671 (1994)), which established the National Spatial Data Infrastructure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Entities that contribute geologic maps to the national archives shall develop the standards described in paragraph (1) in cooperation with the Federal Geographic Data Committee, which is charged with standards development and other data coordination activities as described in Office of Management and Budget revised Circular A–16.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 7</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 171</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–36, § 3(e)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 7</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XI, § 11001(g)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31g.</num>
<heading> Biennial report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2009-03-30">March 30, 2009</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes the status of the national geologic mapping program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describes and evaluates the progress achieved during the preceding 2 years in developing the national geologic map database; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> includes any recommendations that the Secretary may have for legislative or other action to achieve the purposes of sections 31c through 31f of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 8</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1724</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XI, § 11001(h)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31h.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out sections 31a to 31h of this title $64,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2031.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of any amounts appropriated for any fiscal year in excess of the amount appropriated for fiscal year 2005—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 50 percent shall be available for the State component; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 4 percent shall be available for the education component.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–285, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–148, § 9</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1724</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–11, title XI, § 11001(i)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title V, § 5002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title II, § 40202(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 959</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31i.</num>
<heading> Report on resource research activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Once every five years the National Academy of Sciences shall review and report on the resource research activities of the Survey.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(c) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1321–156</ref>, 1321–165; renumbered title I, <ref>Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31j.</num>
<heading> Biological research activity of Survey; review and report by National Academy of Sciences</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning in fiscal year 1998 and once every five years thereafter, the National Academy of Sciences shall review and report on the biological research activity of the Survey.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(d) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–181</ref>, 3009–189.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31k.</num>
<heading> National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of Commerce</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary of Commerce” means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “System” means the National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System established under subsection (b)(1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Volcanic Ash Advisory Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Volcanic Ash Advisory Center” means an entity designated by the International Civil Aviation Organization that is responsible for informing aviation interests about the presence of volcanic ash in the airspace.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish within the United States Geological Survey a system, to be known as the “National Volcano Early Warning and Monitoring System”, to monitor, warn, and protect citizens of the United States from undue and avoidable harm from volcanic activity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The purposes of the System are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to organize, modernize, standardize, and stabilize the monitoring systems of the volcano observatories in the United States, which includes the Alaska Volcano Observatory, California Volcano Observatory, Cascades Volcano Observatory, Hawaiian Volcano Observatory, and Yellowstone Volcano Observatory;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to unify the monitoring systems of volcano observatories in the United States into a single interoperative system; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to strengthen the warning and monitoring systems of volcano observatories in the United States by integrating relevant capacities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including with the Volcanic Ash Advisory Centers located in Anchorage, Alaska, and Washington, D.C., to observe and model emissions of gases, aerosols, and ash, atmospheric dynamics and chemistry, and ocean chemistry resulting from volcanic eruptions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objective</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The objective of the System is to monitor all the volcanoes in the United States at a level commensurate with the threat posed by the volcanoes by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> upgrading existing networks on monitored volcanoes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> installing new networks on unmonitored volcanoes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> employing geodetic and other components when applicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> System components</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The System shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a national volcano watch office that is operational 24 hours a day and 7 days a week;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a national volcano data center; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an external grants program to support research in volcano monitoring science and technology.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modernization activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Modernization activities under the System shall include the comprehensive application of emerging technologies, including digital broadband seismometers, real-time continuous Global Positioning System receivers, satellite and airborne radar interferometry, acoustic pressure sensors, spectrometry to measure gas emissions, and unoccupied aerial vehicles.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memorandum of understanding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary and the Secretary of Commerce shall develop and execute a memorandum of understanding to establish cooperative support for the activities of the System from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including environmental observations, modeling, and temporary duty assignments of personnel to support emergency activities, as necessary or appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management plan</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-03-12">March 12, 2019</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a 5-year management plan for establishing and operating the System.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The management plan submitted under clause (i) shall include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> annual cost estimates for modernization activities and operation of the System;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> annual milestones, standards, and performance goals; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> recommendations for, and progress towards, establishing new, or enhancing existing, partnerships to leverage resources.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Update</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration cost estimates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Secretary annual cost estimates for modernization activities and support of the System for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Update of management plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Secretary shall update the management plan submitted under clause (i) to include the cost estimates submitted under subclause (I).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to assist the Secretary in implementing the System, to be comprised of representatives of relevant agencies and members of the scientific community, to be appointed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with institutions of higher education and State agencies designating the institutions of higher education and State agencies as volcano observatory partners for the System.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall coordinate the activities under this section with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Transportation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collaboration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Commerce shall collaborate with the Secretary to implement activities carried out under this section related to the expertise of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including observations and modeling of emissions of gases, aerosols, and ash, atmospheric dynamics and chemistry, and ocean chemistry resulting from volcanic eruptions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Annually, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes the activities carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations, United States Geological Survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the United States Geological Survey to carry out this section $55,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2024.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other sources of Federal funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts made available under this subsection shall supplement, and not supplant, Federal funds made available for other hazards activities and programs of the United States Geological Survey and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–9, title V, § 5001</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 766</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CV, § 10501(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3993</ref>, 3994.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31l.</num>
<heading> Earth Mapping Resources Initiative</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of critical mineral</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “critical mineral” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1606(a) of title 30</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the United States Geological Survey an initiative, to be known as the “Earth Mapping Resources Initiative” (referred to in this section as the “Initiative”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of the Initiative shall be to accelerate efforts to carry out the fundamental resources and mapping mission of the United States Geological Survey by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> providing integrated topographic, geologic, geochemical, and geophysical mapping;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accelerating the integration and consolidation of geospatial and resource data; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> providing interpretation of subsurface and above-ground mineral resources data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the Initiative, the Director of the United States Geological Survey may enter into cooperative agreements with State geological surveys.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (1) precludes the Director of the United States Geological Survey from using existing contracting authorities in carrying out the Initiative.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive mapping modernization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 10 years after <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the Initiative shall complete an initial comprehensive national modern surface and subsurface mapping and data integration effort.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approach</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1) with regard to minerals, mineralization, and mineral deposits, the Initiative shall focus on the full range of minerals, using a whole ore body approach rather than a single commodity approach, to emphasize all of the recoverable critical minerals in a given surface or subsurface deposit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1) with regard to minerals, mineralization, and mineral deposits, the Initiative shall prioritize mapping and assessing critical minerals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Initiative shall also—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> map and collect data for areas containing mine waste to increase understanding of above-ground critical mineral resources in previously disturbed areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for analysis of samples, including samples within the National Geological and Geophysical Data Preservation Program established under <ref>section 15908(b) of title 42</ref> for the occurrence of critical minerals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Initiative shall make the geospatial data and metadata gathered by the Initiative under subsection (e)(1) electronically publicly accessible on an ongoing basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integration of data sources</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Initiative shall integrate data sources, including data from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the National Cooperative Geologic Mapping Program established by <ref>section 31c(a)(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the National Geological and Geophysical Data Preservation Program established under <ref>section 15908(b) of title 42</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the USMIN Mineral Deposit Database of the United States Geological Survey;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the 3D Elevation Program established under <ref>section 3104(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> other relevant sources, including sources providing geothermal resources data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $320,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title II, § 40201</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 32.</num>
<heading> Acting Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may authorize one of the geologists to act as Director of the United States Geological Survey in the absence of that officer.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 31, 1894, ch. 174, § 1</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 197</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 33.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 34.</num>
<heading> Scientific employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The scientific employees of the United States Geological Survey shall be selected by the Director, subject to the approval of the Secretary of the Interior exclusively for their qualifications as professional experts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 7, 1884, ch. 332</ref>, <ref>23 Stat. 212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 35.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–304, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 664</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36.</num>
<heading> Purchase of books</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purchase of professional and scientific books and periodicals needed for statistical purposes by the scientific divisions of the United States Geological Survey is authorized to be made and paid for out of appropriations made for the said Survey.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1902, ch. 1301, § 1</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 455</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36a.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of scientific or technical books, maps, etc., for library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the United States Geological Survey, under the general supervision of the Secretary of the Interior, is authorized to acquire for the United States, by gift or devise, scientific or technical books, manuscripts, maps, and related materials, and to deposit the same in the library of the United States Geological Survey for reference and use as authorized by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 14, 1940, ch. 190</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36b.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of lands or interests therein for use in gaging streams or underground water resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may, on behalf of the United States and for use by the United States Geological Survey in gaging streams and underground water resources, acquire lands by donation or when funds have been appropriated by Congress by purchase or condemnation, but not in excess of ten acres for any one stream gaging station or observation well site. For the same purpose the Secretary of the Interior may obtain easements, licenses, rights-of-way, and leases limited to run for such a period of time or term of years as may be required for the effective performance of the function of gaging streams and underground water resources: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting or intended to affect or in any way to interfere with the laws of any State or Territory relating to the control, appropriation, use, or distribution of water used in irrigation, or any vested right acquired thereunder, and the Secretary of the Interior, in carrying out the provisions of this section, shall proceed in conformity with such laws, and nothing in this section shall in any way affect any right of any State or of the Federal Government or of any landowner, appropriator, or user of water, in, to, or from any interstate stream or the waters thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Dec. 24, 1942, ch. 822</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 1086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–406</ref>, <date date="1960-04-04">Apr. 4, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 14</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36c.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of contributions from public and private sources; cooperation with other agencies in prosecution of projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 1987 and thereafter the United States Geological Survey is authorized to accept lands, buildings, equipment, and other contributions from public and private sources and to prosecute projects in cooperation with other agencies, Federal, State, or private.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(h) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, 1783–252, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(h) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>, 3341–252; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36d.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of the Federal Grant and Cooperative Agreement Act of 1977 (<ref>31 U.S.C. 6301–630</ref>8), the United States Geological Survey is authorized to continue existing, and on and after <date date="2003-11-10">November 10, 2003</date>, to enter into new cooperative agreements directed towards a particular cooperator, in support of joint research and data collection activities with Federal, State, and academic partners funded by appropriations herein, including those that provide for space in cooperator facilities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–108, title I</ref>, <date date="2003-11-10">Nov. 10, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 37.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 38.</num>
<heading> Topographic surveys; marking elevations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making topographic surveys west of the ninety-fifth meridian elevations above a base level located in each area under survey shall be determined and marked on the ground by iron or stone posts or permanent bench marks, at least two such posts or bench marks to be established in each township, or equivalent area, except in the forest-clad and mountain areas, where at least one shall be established, and these shall be placed, whenever practicable, near the township corners of the public-land surveys; and in the areas east of the ninety-fifth meridian at least one such post or bench mark shall be similarly established in each area equivalent to the area of a township of the public land surveys.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 11, 1896, ch. 420</ref>, <ref>29 Stat. 435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 39, 40.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41.</num>
<heading> Publications and reports; preparation and sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in <ref>section 1318 of title 44</ref>, the publications of the United States Geological Survey shall consist of geological and economic maps, illustrating the resources and classification of the lands, and reports upon general and economic geology and paleontology. All special memoirs and reports of said survey shall be issued in uniform quarto series if deemed necessary by the director, but otherwise in ordinary octavos. Three thousand copies of each shall be published for scientific exchanges and for sale at the price of publication, and all literary and cartographic materials received in exchange shall be the property of the United States and form a part of the library of the organization; and the money resulting from the sale of such publications shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States, under the direction of the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1879, ch. 182</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 394</ref>; <ref>Aug. 7, 1946, ch. 770, § 1(10)</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 867</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 42.</num>
<heading> Distribution of maps and atlases, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the United States Geological Survey is authorized and directed, on the approval of the Secretary of the Interior, to dispose of the topographic and geologic maps and atlases of the United States, made and published by the United States Geological Survey, at such prices and under such regulations as may from time to time be fixed by him and approved by the Secretary of the Interior; and a number of copies of each map or atlas, not exceeding five hundred, shall be distributed gratuitously among foreign governments and departments of our own Government to literary and scientific associations, and to such educational institutions or libraries as may be designated by the Director of the Survey and approved by the Secretary of the Interior. On and after <date date="1924-06-07">June 7, 1924</date>, the distribution of geological publications to libraries designated as special depositaries of such publications shall be discontinued.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<date date="1897-02-18">Feb. 18, 1897</date>, No. 13, § 1, <ref>29 Stat. 701</ref>; <ref>June 7, 1924, ch. 303</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 42a.</num>
<heading> Use of receipts from sale of maps for map printing and distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 1984 and thereafter, all receipts from the sale of maps sold or stored by the United States Geological Survey shall be available for map printing and distribution to supplement funds otherwise available, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–146, title I</ref>, <date date="1983-11-04">Nov. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 43.</num>
<heading> Copies to Senators, Representatives, and Delegates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">One copy of each map and atlas shall be sent to each Senator and each Representative and Delegate in Congress, if published within his term; and a second copy shall be placed at the disposal of each such Senator, Representative and Delegate</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<date date="1897-02-18">Feb. 18, 1897</date>, No. 13, § 2, <ref>29 Stat. 701</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 44.</num>
<heading> Sale of transfers or copies of data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the United States Geological Survey shall, if the regular map work of the Survey is in no wise interfered with thereby, furnish to any person, concern, institution, State or foreign government, that shall pay in advance the whole cost thereof with 10 per centum added, transfers or copies of any cartographic or other engraved or lithographic data in the division of engraving and printing of the Survey, and the moneys received by the Director for such transfers or copies shall be deposited in the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 30, 1906, ch. 3914</ref>, <ref>34 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 45.</num>
<heading> Production and sale of copies of photographs and records; disposition of receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the United States Geological Survey on and after <date date="1909-03-04">March 4, 1909</date> may produce and sell on a reimbursable basis to interested persons, concerns, and institutions, copies of aerial or other photographs and mosaics that have been obtained in connection with the authorized work of the United States Geological Survey and photographic or photostatic reproductions of records in the official custody of the Director at such prices (not less than the estimated cost of furnishing such copies or reproductions) as the Director, with the approval of the Secretary of the Interior, may determine, the money received from such sales to be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the appropriation then current and chargeable for the cost of furnishing copies or reproductions as herein authorized.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 299</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 989</ref>; <ref>July 21, 1947, ch. 273</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 46.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 7, 1946, ch. 770, § 1(11)</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 867</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 48.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49.</num>
<heading> Extension of cooperative work to Puerto Rico</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of law authorizing the making of topographic and geological surveys and conducting investigations relating to mineral and water resources by the United States Geological Survey in various portions of the United States be, and the same are, extended to authorize such surveys and investigations in Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 17, 1935, ch. 268</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 386</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50.</num>
<heading> Survey’s share of cost of topographic mapping or water resources investigations carried on with States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The share of the United States Geological Survey in any topographic mapping or water resources data collection and investigations carried on in cooperation with any State or municipality shall not exceed 50 per centum of the cost thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–42, div. E, title I</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50–1.</num>
<heading> Funds for mappings and investigations considered intragovernmental funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, and thereafter, funds received from any State, territory, possession, country, international organization, or political subdivision thereof, for topographic, geologic, or water resources mapping or investigations involving cooperation with such an entity shall be considered as intragovernmental funds as defined in the publication titled “A Glossary of Terms Used in the Federal Budget Process”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–512, title I</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50a.</num>
<heading> Working capital fund for United States Geological Survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a working capital fund to assist in the management of certain support activities of the United States Geological Survey (hereafter referred to as the “Survey”), Department of the Interior. The fund shall be available on and after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, without fiscal year limitation for expenses necessary for furnishing materials, supplies, equipment, work, facilities, and services in support of Survey programs, and, as authorized by law, to agencies of the Federal Government and others. Such expenses may include laboratory modernization and equipment replacement, computer operations, maintenance, and telecommunications services; requirements definition, systems analysis, and design services; acquisition or development of software; systems support services such as implementation assistance, training, and maintenance; acquisition and replacement of computer, publications, scientific instrumentation, telecommunications, and related automatic data processing equipment; and, such other activities as may be approved by the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be transferred to the fund, at fair and reasonable values at the time of transfer, inventories, equipment, receivables, and other assets, less liabilities, related to the functions to be financed by the fund as determined by the Secretary of the Interior: <i>Provided</i>, That the fund shall be credited with appropriations and other funds of the Survey, and other agencies of the Department of the Interior, other Federal agencies, and other sources, for providing materials, supplies, equipment, work, and services as authorized by law and such payments may be made in advance or upon performance: <i>Provided further</i>, That charges to users will be at rates approximately equal to the costs of furnishing the materials, supplies, equipment, facilities, and services, including such items as depreciation of equipment and facilities, and accrued annual leave: <i>Provided further</i>, That all existing balances as of <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, from amortization fees resulting from the Survey providing telecommunications services and deposited in a special fund established on the books of the Treasury and available for payment of replacement or expansion of telecommunications services as authorized by <ref>Public Law 99–190</ref>, are hereby transferred to and merged with the working capital fund, to be used for the same purposes as originally authorized: <i>Provided further</i>, That funds that are not necessary to carry out the activities to be financed by the fund, as determined by the Secretary, shall be covered into miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–512, title I</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1924</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–332, title I</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50b.</num>
<heading> Recording of obligations against accounts receivable and crediting of amounts received; work involving cooperation with State, Territory, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before, on, and after <date date="1986-10-18">October 18, 1986</date>, in carrying out work involving cooperation with any State, Territory, possession, or political subdivision thereof, the United States Geological Survey may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, record obligations against accounts receivable from any such entities and shall credit amounts received from such entities to this appropriation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(h) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, 1783–252, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(h) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>, 3341–252; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50c.</num>
<heading> Payment of costs incidental to utilization of services of volunteers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations herein and on and after <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, made shall be available for paying costs incidental to the utilization of services contributed by individuals who serve without compensation as volunteers in aid of work of the United States Geological Survey, and that within appropriations herein and on and after <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, provided, United States Geological Survey officials may authorize either direct procurement of or reimbursement for expenses incidental to the effective use of volunteers such as, but not limited to, training, transportation, lodging, subsistence, equipment, and supplies: <i>Provided further</i>, That provision for such expenses or services is in accord with volunteer or cooperative agreements made with such individuals, private organizations, educational institutions, or State or local government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(g) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–213</ref>, 1329–224; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50d.</num>
<heading> Services of students or recent graduates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Geological Survey may on and after <date date="1999-11-29">November 29, 1999</date>, contract directly with individuals or indirectly with institutions or nonprofit organizations, without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>, for the temporary or intermittent services of students or recent graduates, who shall be considered employees for the purposes of chapters 57 and 81 of title 5, relating to compensation for travel and work injuries, and chapter 171 of title 28, relating to tort claims, but shall not be considered to be Federal employees for any other purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–146.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50e.</num>
<heading> USGS energy and minerals research facility</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the United States Geological Survey (referred to in this section as the “Director”),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref> shall fund, through a cooperative agreement with an academic partner, the design, construction, and tenant build-out of a facility to support energy and minerals research and appurtenant associated structures.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ownership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Geological Survey shall retain ownership of the facility and associated structures described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director may enter into agreements with, and to collect and expend funds or in-kind contributions from, academic, Federal, State, or other tenants over the life of the facility described in subsection (a) for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> facility planning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> design;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> maintenance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> operation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> facility improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may enter into a lease or other agreement with the academic partner with which the Director has entered into a cooperative agreement under subsection (a), at no cost to the Federal Government, to obtain land on which to construct the facility described in that subsection for a term of not less than 99 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director shall submit to Congress annual reports on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the facility described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the authorities used under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior to carry out this section $167,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title II, § 40204</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 960</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>