<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 7—</num>
<heading>HOMESTEADS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 161 to 164.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 165.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 166 to 175.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 176.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 705(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2792</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 177.</num>
<heading> Patents for lands in New Mexico held under color of title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever it shall be shown to the satisfaction of the Secretary of the Interior that a tract or tracts of public land, not known to be mineral, in the State of New Mexico, not exceeding in the aggregate one hundred and sixty acres, has or have been held in good faith and in peaceful, adverse possession by a citizen of the United States, his ancestors or grantors, for more than twenty years under claim or color of title, and that valuable improvements have been placed on such land, or some part thereof has been reduced to cultivation, the Secretary may, in his discretion, upon the payment of $1.25 per acre, cause a patent or patents to issue for such land to any such citizen: <i>Provided</i>, That where the area or areas so held by any such citizen is in excess of one hundred and sixty acres the Secretary may determine what particular subdivisions, not exceeding one hundred and sixty acres in the aggregate, to any such citizen may be patented under this section: <i>Provided further</i>, That the term “citizen” as used in this section shall be held to include a corporation organized under the laws of the United States or any State or Territory thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 8, 1926, ch. 501</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 178.</num>
<heading> Patents for lands in New Mexico; lands contiguous to Spanish or Mexican land grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever it shall be shown to the satisfaction of the Secretary of the Interior that a tract or tracts of public land, contiguous to a Spanish or Mexican land grant, in the State of New Mexico, not exceeding in the aggregate one hundred and sixty acres, has or have been held in good faith and in peaceful, adverse possession by a citizen of the United States, his ancestors or grantors, for more than twenty years under claim or color of title, and that valuable improvements have been placed on such land, or some part thereof has been reduced to cultivation, the Secretary may, in his discretion, upon the payment of $1.25 per acre, cause a patent or patents to issue for such land to any such citizens: <i>Provided</i>, That where the area or areas so held by any such citizen is in excess of one hundred and sixty acres the Secretary may determine what particular subdivisions, not exceeding one hundred and sixty acres in the aggregate, to any such citizen may be patented hereunder: <i>Provided further</i>, That coal and all other minerals contained therein are reserved to the United States; that said coal and other minerals shall be subject to sale or disposal by the United States under applicable leasing and mineral land laws, and permittees, lessees, or grantees of the United States shall have the right to enter upon said lands for the purpose of prospecting for and mining such deposits: <i>Provided further</i>, That the term “citizen”, as used in this section, shall be held to include a corporation organized under the laws of the United States or any State or Territory thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 23, 1932, ch. 52</ref>, <ref>47 Stat. 53</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 179, 180.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>RIGHT OF PARTICULAR PERSONS TO MAKE ENTRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 181.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Dec. 16, 1930, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1029</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 182 to 191.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>LANDS SUBJECT TO ENTRY</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 201 to 208.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 209.</num>
<heading> Extension of public-land laws to certain lands in Oklahoma</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The public-land laws of the United States be, and the same are, extended to the public lands in that part of the Red River between the medial line and the south bank of the river, in Oklahoma, between the ninety-eighth meridian and the east boundary of the territory established as Greer County by the Act of <date date="1896-05-04">May 4, 1896</date> (<ref>29 Stat. 113</ref>): <i>Provided</i>, That such lands shall not be subject to disposition, settlement, or occupation until after the same have been classified and opened to entry, and other disposal by the Secretary of the Interior according to law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 22, 1948, ch. 605, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 576</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 210.</num>
<heading> Recognition of equitable claims on certain lands in Oklahoma; validation of homestead entries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to recognize equitable claims to such lands based on settlement made prior to <date date="1934-01-01">January 1, 1934</date>, and all homestead entries of such lands, the allowance of which was erroneous because the lands were not subject to entry, and all suspended entries and applications to make final proof, are validated if otherwise regular, as of the date of the regular application.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 22, 1948, ch. 605, § 2</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 576</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>LIMITATION AS TO AMOUNT AND ADDITIONAL AND ENLARGED ENTRIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 211 to 224.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>LEAVES OF ABSENCE AND EXCUSES FOR NONRESIDENCE OR NONCULTIVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 231 to 240.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 241, 242.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 17, 1940, ch. 888</ref>, article V, § 503(3), <ref>54 Stat. 1187</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 243, 243a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>FINAL PROOF GENERALLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 251 to 256b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>PAYMENTS AND REFUNDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 261.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 262.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Dec. 16, 1930, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1029</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 263.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>ALASKA HOMESTEADS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 270.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2789</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 270–1 to 270–3.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 92–203, § 18(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 710</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 270–4.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2789</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 270–5 to 270–10.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2789</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 270–11.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2789</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 270–12.</num>
<heading> Disposal by United States of coal, oil, or gas deposits reserved to United States; entry, reentry, etc., on lands for prospecting, mining, and re­moval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The coal, oil, or gas deposits reserved to the United States in accordance with the act of <date date="1922-03-08">March 8, 1922</date> (<ref>42 Stat. 415</ref>; <ref>43 U.S.C. 270–11</ref> et seq.), as added to by the Act of <date date="1961-08-17">August 17, 1961</date> (<ref>75 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>43 U.S.C. 270–13</ref>), and amended by the Act of <date date="1962-10-03">October 3, 1962</date> (<ref>76 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>43 U.S.C. 270–13</ref>), shall be subject to disposal by the United States in accordance with the provisions of the laws applicable to coal, oil, or gas deposits or coal, oil, or gas lands in Alaska in force at the time of such disposal. Any person qualified to acquire coal, oil, or gas deposits, or the right to mine or remove the coal or to drill for and remove the oil or gas under the laws of the United States shall have the right at all times to enter upon the lands patented under the Act of <date date="1922-03-08">March 8, 1922</date>, as amended, and in accordance with the provisions hereof, for the purpose of prospecting for coal, oil, or gas therein, upon the approval by the Secretary of the Interior of a bond or undertaking to be filed with him as security for the payment of all damages to the crops and improvements on such lands by reason of such prospecting. Any person who has acquired from the United States the coal, oil, or gas deposits in any such land, or the right to mine, drill for, or remove the same, may reenter and occupy so much of the surface thereof incident to the mining and removal of the coal, oil, or gas therefrom, and mine and remove the coal or drill for and remove oil and gas upon payment of the damages caused thereby to the owner thereof, or upon giving a good and sufficient bond or undertaking in an action instituted in any competent court to ascertain and fix said damages: Provided, That the owner under such limited patent shall have the right to mine the coal for use on the land for domestic purposes at any time prior to the disposal by the United States of the coal deposits: Provided further, That nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the exploration upon or entry of any coal deposits withdrawn from such exploration and purchase.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 8, 1922, ch. 96, § 2</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–725, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-23">Aug. 23, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2791</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 270–13 to 270–17.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2789</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IX—</num>
<heading>SOLDIERS’ AND SAILORS’ HOMESTEAD</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 271 to 284.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER X—</num>
<heading>STOCK-RAISING HOMESTEAD</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 291 to 298.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 299.</num>
<heading> Reservation of coal and mineral rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All entries made and patents issued under the provisions of this subchapter shall be subject to and contain a reservation to the United States of all the coal and other minerals in the lands so entered and patented, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. The coal and other mineral deposits in such lands shall be subject to disposal by the United States in accordance with the provisions of the coal and mineral land laws in force at the time of such disposal. Any person qualified to locate and enter the coal or other mineral deposits, or having the right to mine and remove the same under the laws of the United States, shall have the right at all times to enter upon the lands entered or patented, as provided by this subchapter, for the purpose of prospecting for coal or other mineral therein, provided he shall not injure, damage, or destroy the permanent improvements of the entryman or patentee, and shall be liable to and shall compensate the entryman or patentee for all damages to the crops on such lands by reason of such prospecting. Any person who has acquired from the United States the coal or other mineral deposits in any such land, or the right to mine and remove the same, may reenter and occupy so much of the surface thereof as may be required for all purposes reasonably incident to the mining or removal of the coal or other minerals, first, upon securing the written consent or waiver of the homestead entryman or patentee; second, upon payment of the damages to crops or other tangible improvements to the owner thereof, where agreement may be had as to the amount thereof; or, third, in lieu of either of the foregoing provisions, upon the execution of a good and sufficient bond or undertaking to the United States for the use and benefit of the entryman or owner of the land, to secure the payment of such damages to the crops or tangible improvements of the entryman or owner, as may be determined and fixed in an action brought upon the bond or undertaking in a court of competent jurisdiction against the principal and sureties thereon, such bond or undertaking to be in form and in accordance with rules and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior and to be filed with and approved by the officer designated by the Secretary of the Interior of the local land office of the district wherein the land is situate, subject to appeal to the Secretary of the Interior or such officer as he may designate: <i>Provided</i>, That all patents issued for the coal or other mineral deposits herein reserved shall contain appropriate notations declaring them to be subject to the provisions of this subchapter with reference to the disposition, occupancy, and use of the land as permitted to an entryman under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exploration; location of mining claims; notices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (a) and any other provision of law to the contrary, after the effective date of this subsection no person other than the surface owner may enter lands subject to this subchapter to explore for, or to locate, a mining claim on such lands without—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> filing a notice of intention to locate a mining claim pursuant to paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> providing notice to the surface owner pursuant to paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any person who has complied with the requirements referred to in subparagraph (A) may, during the authorized exploration period, in order to locate a mining claim, enter lands subject to this subchapter to undertake mineral activities related to exploration that cause no more than a minimal disturbance of surface resources and do not involve the use of mechanized earthmoving equipment, explosives, the construction of roads, drill pads, or the use of toxic or hazardous materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The authorized exploration period referred to in subparagraph (B) shall begin 30 days after notice is provided under paragraph (3) with respect to lands subject to such notice and shall end with the expiration of the 90-day period referred to in paragraph (2)(A) or any extension provided under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of intention to locate a mining claim</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any person seeking to locate a mining claim on lands subject to this subchapter in order to engage in the mineral activities relating to exploration referred to under paragraph (1)(B) shall file with the Secretary of the Interior a notice of intention to locate a claim on the lands concerned. The notice shall be in such form as the Secretary shall prescribe. The notice shall contain the name and mailing address of the person filing the notice and a legal description of the lands to which the notice applies. The legal description shall be based on the public land survey or on such other description as is sufficient to permit the Secretary to record the notice on the land status records of the Secretary. Whenever any person has filed a notice under this paragraph with respect to any lands, during the 90-day period following the date of such filing, or any extension thereof pursuant to this paragraph, no other person (including the surface owner) may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> file such a notice with respect to any portions of such lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> explore for minerals or locate a mining claim on any portion of such lands; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> file an application to acquire any interest in any portion of such lands pursuant to <ref>section 1719 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If, within such 90-day period, the person who filed a notice under this paragraph files a plan of operations with the Secretary pursuant to subsection (f), such 90-day period shall be extended until the approval or disapproval of the plan by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (f).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to surface owner</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any person who has filed a notice of intention to locate a mining claim under paragraph (2) for any lands subject to this subchapter shall provide written notice of such filing, by registered or certified mail with return receipt, to the surface owner (as evidenced by local tax records) of the lands covered by the notice under paragraph (2). The notice shall be provided at least 30 days before entering such lands and shall contain each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A brief description of the proposed mineral activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A map and legal description of the lands to be subject to mineral exploration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The name, address and phone number of the person managing such activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A statement of the dates on which such activities will take place.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acreage limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The total acreage covered at any time by notices of intention to locate a mining claim under paragraph (2) filed by any person and by affiliates of such person may not exceed 6,400 acres of lands subject to this subchapter in any one State and 1,280 acres of such lands for a single surface owner. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “affiliate” means, with respect to any person, any other person which controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, such person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a) and any other provision of law, after the effective date of this subsection no person may engage in the conduct of mineral activities (other than those relating to exploration referred to in subsection (b)(1)B)) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> on a mining claim located on lands subject to this subchapter without the written consent of the surface owner thereof unless the Secretary has authorized the conduct of such activities under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized mineral activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall authorize a person to conduct mineral activities (other than those relating to exploration referred to in subsection (b)(1)(B)) on lands subject to this subchapter without the consent of the surface owner thereof if such person complies with the requirements of subsections (e) and (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bond</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before the Secretary may authorize any person to conduct mineral activities the Secretary shall require such person to post a bond or other financial guarantee in an amount to insure the completion of reclamation pursuant to this subchapter. Such bond or other financial guarantee shall ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> payment to the surface owner, after the completion of such mineral activities and reclamation, compensation for any permanent damages to crops and tangible improvements of the surface owner that resulted from mineral activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> payment to the surface owner of compensation for any permanent loss of income of the surface owner due to loss or impairment of grazing, or other uses of the land by the surface owner to the extent that reclamation required by the plan of operations would not permit such uses to continue at the level existing prior to the commencement of mineral activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In determining the bond amount to cover permanent loss of income under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall consider, where appropriate, the potential loss of value due to the estimated permanent reduction in utilization of the land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan of operations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before the Secretary may authorize any person to conduct mineral activities on lands subject to this subchapter, the Secretary shall require such person to submit a plan of operations. Such plan shall include procedures for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the minimization of damages to crops and tangible improvements of the surface owner;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the minimization of disruption to grazing or other uses of the land by the surface owner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> payment of a fee for the use of surface during mineral activities equivalent to the loss of income to the ranch operation as established pursuant to subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide a copy of the proposed plan of operations to the surface owner at least 45 days prior to the date the Secretary makes a determination as to whether such plan complies with the requirements of this subsection. During such 45-day period the surface owner may submit comments and recommend modifications to the proposed plan of operations to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall, within 60 days of receipt of the plan, approve the plan of operations if it complies with the requirements of this subchapter, including each of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The proposed plan of operations is complete and accurate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The person submitting the proposed plan of operations has demonstrated that all other applicable Federal and State requirements have been met.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall notify the person submitting a plan of operations of any modifications to such plan required to bring it into compliance with the requirements of this subchapter. If the person submitting the plan agrees to modify such plan in a manner acceptable to the Secretary, the Secretary shall approve the plan as modified. In the event no agreement can be reached on the modifications to the plan which, in the opinion of the Secretary, will bring such plan into compliance with the requirements of this subchapter, then the Secretary shall disapprove the plan and notify both the surface owner and the person submitting the plan of the decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The 60-day period referred to in subparagraph (A) may be extended by the Secretary where additional time is required to comply with other applicable requirements of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall suspend or revoke a plan of operation whenever the Secretary determines, on the Secretary’s own motion or on a motion made by the surface owner, that the person conducting mineral activities is in substantial noncompliance with the terms and conditions of an approved plan of operations and has failed to remedy a violation after notice from the Secretary within the time required by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Final approval of a plan of operations under this subsection shall be conditioned upon compliance with subsections (e) and (g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The fee referred to in subsection (f)(1) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> paid to the surface owner by the person submitting the plan of operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> paid in advance of any mineral activities or at such other time or times as may be agreed to by the surface owner and the person conducting such activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> established by the Secretary taking into account the acreage involved and the degree of potential disruption to existing surface uses during mineral activities (including the loss of income to the surface owner and such surface owner’s operations due to the loss or impairment of existing surface uses for the duration of the mineral activities), except that such fee shall not exceed the fair market value for the surface of the land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reclamation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Lands affected by mineral activities under a plan of operations approved pursuant to subsection (f)(3) shall be reclaimed, to the maximum extent practicable, to a condition capable of supporting the uses to which such lands were capable of supporting prior to surface disturbance. Reclamation shall proceed as contemporaneously as practicable with the conduct of mineral activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State law</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as affecting any reclamation, bonding, inspection, enforcement, air or water quality standard or requirement of any State law or regulation which may be applicable to mineral activities on lands subject to this subchapter to the extent that such law or regulation is not inconsistent with this title.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as affecting in any way the right of any person to enforce or protect, under applicable law, the interest of such person in water resources affected by mineral activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Should any surface owner of land subject to this subchapter have reason to believe that they are or may be adversely affected by mineral activities due to any violation of the terms and conditions of a plan of operations approved under subsection (f), such surface owner may request an inspection of such lands. The Secretary shall determine within 10 days of the receipt of the request whether the request states a reason to believe that a violation exists, except in the event the surface owner alleges and provides reason to believe that an imminent danger exists, the 10-day period shall be waived and the inspection conducted immediately. When an inspection is conducted under this paragraph, the Secretary shall notify the surface owner and such surface owner shall be allowed to accompany the inspector on the inspection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Damages for failure to comply</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever the surface owner of any land subject to this subchapter has suffered any permanent damages to crops or tangible improvements of the surface owner, or any permanent loss of income due to loss or impairment of grazing, or other uses of the land by the surface owner, if such damages or loss result from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any mineral activity undertaken without the consent of the surface owner under subsection (c) or an authorization by the Secretary under subsection (d); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the failure of the person conducting mineral activities to remedy to the satisfaction of the Secretary any substantial noncompliance with the terms and conditions of a plan under subsection (f);</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the surface owner may bring an action in the appropriate United States district court for, and the court may award, double damages plus costs for willful misconduct or gross negligence.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The surface owner of any land subject to this subchapter may also bring an action in the appropriate United States district court for double damages plus costs for willful misconduct or gross negligence against any person undertaking any mineral activities on lands subject to this subchapter in violation of any requirement of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any double damages plus costs awarded by the court under this subsection shall be reduced by the amount of any compensation which the surface owner has received (or is eligible to receive) pursuant to the bond or financial guarantee required under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of financial guarantee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The surface owner of any land subject to this subchapter may petition the Secretary for payment of all or any portion of a bond or other financial guarantee required under subsection (e) as compensation for any permanent damages to crops and tangible improvements of the surface owner, or any permanent loss of income due to loss or impairment of grazing, or other uses of the land by the surface owner. Pursuant to such a petition, the Secretary may use such bond or other guarantee to provide compensation to the surface owner for such damages and to insure the required reclamation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bond release</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall release the bond or other financial guarantee required under subsection (e) upon the successful completion of all requirements pursuant to a plan of operations approved under subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conveyance to surface owner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to simplify the procedures which must be complied with by surface owners of lands subject to this subchapter who apply to the Secretary to obtain title to interests in such lands owned by the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of subsections (b) through (n)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “mineral activities” means any activity for, related to or incidental to mineral exploration, mining, and beneficiation activities for any locatable mineral on a mining claim. When used with respect to this term—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “exploration” means those techniques employed to locate the presence of a locatable mineral deposit and to establish its nature, position, size, shape, grade and value;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “mining” means the processes employed for the extraction of a locatable mineral from the earth; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “beneficiation” means the crushing and grinding of locatable mineral ore and such processes are employed to free the mineral from the other constituents, including but not necessarily limited to, physical and chemical separation techniques.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “mining claim” means a claim located under the general mining laws of the United States (which generally comprise 30 U.S.C. chapters 2, 12A, and 16, and sections 161 and 162) subject to the terms and conditions of subsections (b) through (p) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “tangible improvements” includes agricultural, residential and commercial improvements, including improvements made by residential subdividers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minerals covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsections (b) through (<i>o</i>) of this section apply only to minerals not subject to disposition under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Mineral Leasing Act (<ref>30 U.S.C. 181</ref> and following);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 [<ref>30 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1947-07-31">July 31, 1947</date>, commonly known as the Materials Act of 1947 (<ref>30 U.S.C. 601</ref> and following).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Dec. 29, 1916, ch. 9, § 9</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 864</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1921, ch. 114, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 462</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1145</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7876, <ref>60 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–23, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1993-04-16">Apr. 16, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 60</ref>, 65.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 300.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 704(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2792</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 301.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to make all necessary rules and regulations in harmony with the provisions and purposes of this subchapter for the purpose of carrying the same into effect.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Dec. 29, 1916, ch. 9, § 11</ref>, <ref>39 Stat. 865</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2787</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>