<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32A—</num>
<heading>COLORADO RIVER BASIN SALINITY CONTROL</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PROGRAMS DOWNSTREAM FROM IMPERIAL DAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1571.</num>
<heading> Water quality improvement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to proceed with program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”, is authorized and directed to proceed with a program of works of improvement for the enhancement and protection of the quality of water available in the Colorado River for use in the United States and the Republic of Mexico, and to enable the United States to comply with its obligations under the agreement with Mexico of <date date="1973-08-30">August 30, 1973</date> (Minute No. 242 of the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico), concluded pursuant to the Treaty of <date date="1944-02-03">February 3, 1944</date> (TS 994), in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Desalting complexes and plants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain a desalting complex, including (1) a desalting plant to reduce the salinity of drain water from the Wellton-Mohawk division of the Gila project, Arizona (hereinafter referred to as the division), including a pretreatment plant for settling, softening, and filtration of the drain water to be desalted; (2) the necessary appurtenant works including the intake pumping plant system, product waterline, power transmission facilities, and permanent operating facilities; (3) the necessary extension in the United States and Mexico of the existing bypass drain to carry the reject stream from the desalting plant and other drainage waters to the Santa Clara Slough in Mexico, with the part in Mexico, subject to arrangements made pursuant to subsection (d); (4) replacement of the metal flume in the existing main outlet drain extension with a concrete siphon; (5) reduction of the quantity of irrigation return flows through acquisition of lands to reduce the size of the division, and irrigation efficiency improvements to minimize return flows; (6) acquire on behalf of the United States such lands or interest in lands in the Painted Rock Reservoir as may be necessary to operate the project in accordance with the obligations of Minute No. 242, and (7) all associated facilities including roads, railroad spur, and transmission lines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The desalting plant shall be designed to treat approximately one hundred and twenty-nine million gallons a day of drain water using advanced technology commercially available. The plant shall effect recovery initially of not less than 70 per centum of the drain water as product water, and shall effect reduction of not less than 90 per centum of the dissolved solids in the feed water. The Secretary shall use sources of electric power supply for the desalting complex that will not diminish the supply of power to preference customers from Federal power systems operated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to use electrical power and energy available from the Navajo Generating Station which is in excess of the Central Arizona Project pumping requirements for the purpose of supplying power and energy requirements of the desalting plant and protective pumping well field constructed pursuant to this subchapter: <i>Provided</i>, That revenues credited to the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund shall not be diminished below those amounts which would have accrued had the power been marketed at the rate determined by the Secretary of Energy for the sale of power from the Navajo Generating Station to utilities and public entities, as a result of the use of power and energy for the desalting, protective pumping works, and other uses authorized by law, and that power and energy from the Navajo Generating Station shall be used first to meet the pumping requirements of the Central Arizona Project and after those needs have been met, for the desalting and protective pumping facilities constructed pursuant to this subchapter, and finally for other uses: <i>Provided further</i>, That prior to obtaining power from the Navajo Generating Station under the authority of this subsection, the Secretary shall complete an analysis of alternative sources of supply, including but not limited to the possibility of developing an agreement with the Republic of Mexico whereby the United States (or a non-Federal entity) would enter into contractual arrangements with Mexico for a sufficient supply of power to operate the desalting plant, the regulatory pumping fields and appurtenant facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Effective <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, and to such extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to purchase supplemental power and energy as required for the purposes of supplying the power and energy requirements of the desalting plant and protective pumping well field.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Replacement water studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Replacement of the reject stream from the desalting plant, Colorado River waters used for the mitigation of fish and wildlife habitat losses and of any Wellton-Mohawk drainage water bypassed to the Santa Clara Slough to accomplish essential operation except at such times when there exists surplus water of the Colorado River under the terms of the Mexican Water Treaty of 1944, is recognized as a national obligation as provided in <ref>section 1512 of this title</ref>. Studies to identify feasible measures to provide adequate replacement water shall be completed not later than <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>. Said studies shall be limited to potential sources within the States of Arizona, California, Colorado, New Mexico, and those portions of Nevada, Utah, and Wyoming which are within the natural drainage basin of the Colorado River. Measures found necessary to replace the reject stream from the desalting plant, Colorado River waters used for the mitigation of fish and wildlife habitat losses and any Wellton-Mohawk drainage bypassed to the Santa Clara Slough to accomplish essential operations may be undertaken independently of the national obligation set forth in <ref>section 1512 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advancement of funds for that portion of bypass drain within Mexico</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby authorized to advance funds to the United States section, International Boundary and Water Commission (IBWC), for construction, operation, and maintenance by Mexico pursuant to Minute No. 242 of that portion of the bypass drain within Mexico. Such funds shall be transferred to an appropriate Mexican agency, under arrangements to be concluded by the IBWC providing for the construction, operation, and maintenance of such facility by Mexico.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Desalted water exchange</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any desalted water not needed for the purposes of this subchapter may be exchanged at prices and under terms and conditions satisfactory to the Secretary and the proceeds therefrom shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury. The city of Yuma, Arizona, shall have first right of refusal to any such water.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return flow reduction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of reducing the return flows from the division to one hundred and seventy-five thousand acre-feet or less, annually, the Secretary is authorized to:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Accelerate the cooperative program of Irrigation Management Services with the Wellton-Mohawk Irrigation and Drainage District, hereinafter referred to as the district, for the purpose of improving irrigation efficiency. The district shall bear its share of the cost of such program as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Acquire by purchase or through eminent domain or exchange, to the extent determined by him to be appropriate, lands or interests in lands to reduce the existing seventy-five thousand developed and undeveloped irrigable acres authorized by the Act of <date date="1947-07-30">July 30, 1947</date> (<ref>61 Stat. 628</ref>), known as the Gila Reauthorization Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 613</ref> et seq.]. The initial reduction in irrigable acreage shall be limited to approximately ten thousand acres. If the Secretary determines that the irrigable acreage of the division must be reduced below sixty-five thousand acres of irrigable lands to carry out the purpose of this section, the Secretary is authorized, with the consent of the district, to acquire additional lands, as may be deemed by him to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposal of acquired lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to dispose of the acquired lands and interests therein on terms and conditions satisfactory to him and meeting the objective of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to water users for installation of system improvements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized, either in conjunction with or in lieu of land acquisition, to assist water users in the division in installing system improvements, such as ditch lining, change of field layouts, automatic equipment, sprinkler systems and bubbler systems, as a means of increasing irrigation efficiencies: <i>Provided, however</i>, That all costs associated with the improvements authorized herein and allocated to the water users on the basis of benefits received, as determined by the Secretary, shall be reimbursed to the United States in amounts and on terms and conditions satisfactory to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract amendment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to amend the contract between the United States and the district dated <date date="1952-03-04">March 4, 1952</date>, as amended, to provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the portion of the existing repayment obligation owing to the United States allocable to irrigable acreage eliminated from the division for the purposes of this subchapter, as determined by the Secretary, shall be nonreimbursable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if deemed appropriate by the Secretary, the district shall be given credit against its outstanding repayment obligation to offset any increase in operation and maintenance assessments per acre which may result from the district’s decreased operation and maintenance base, all as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of land for storage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to acquire through the Corps of Engineers fee title to, or other necessary interests in, additional lands above the Painted Rock Dam in Arizona that are required for the temporary storage capacity needed to permit operation of the dam and reservoir in times of serious flooding in accordance with the obligations of the United States under Minute No. 242. No funds shall be expended for acquisition of land or interests therein until it is finally determined by a Federal court of competent jurisdiction that the Corps of Engineers presently lacks legal authority to use said lands for this purpose. Nothing contained in this subchapter nor any action taken pursuant to it shall be deemed to be a recognition or admission of any obligation to the owners of such land on the part of the United States or a limitation or deficiency in the rights or powers of the United States with respect to such lands or the operation of the reservoir.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent desirable to carry out subsections (f)(1) and (h), the Secretary may transfer funds to the Secretary of Agriculture as may be required for technical assistance to farmers, conduct of research and demonstrations, and such related investigations as are required to achieve higher on-farm irrigation efficiencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonreimbursable costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All cost associated with the desalting complex shall be nonreimbursable except as provided in subsections (f) and (h).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–336</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1063</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1572.</num>
<heading> Canal or canal lining</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist in meeting salinity control objectives of Minute No. 242 during an interim period, the Secretary is authorized to construct a new concrete-lined canal or, to line the presently unlined portion of the Coachella Canal of the Boulder Canyon project, California, from station 2 plus 26 to the beginning of siphon numbered 7, a length of approximately forty-nine miles. The United States shall be entitled to temporary use of a quantity of water, for the purpose of meeting the salinity control objectives of Minute No. 242, during an interim period, equal to the quantity of water conserved by constructing or lining the said canal. The interim period shall commence on completion of construction or lining said canal and shall end the first year that the Secretary delivers main stream Colorado River water to California in an amount less than the sum of the quantities requested by (1) the California agencies under contracts made pursuant to <ref>section 617d of this title</ref>, and (2) Federal establishments to meet their water rights acquired in California in accordance with the Supreme Court decree in Arizona against California (376 U.S. 340).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The charges for total construction shall be repayable without interest in equal annual installments over a period of forty years beginning in the year following completion of construction: <i>Provided</i>, That, repayment shall be prorated between the United States and the Coachella Valley County Water District, and the Secretary is authorized to enter into a repayment contract with Coachella Valley County Water District for that purpose. Such contract shall provide that annual repayment installments shall be nonreimbursable during the interim period, defined in subsection (a) and shall provide that after the interim period, said annual repayment installments or portions thereof, shall be paid by Coachella Valley County Water District.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of private lands</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to acquire by purchase, eminent domain, or exchange private lands or interests therein, as may be determined by him to be appropriate, within the Imperial Irrigation District on the Imperial East Mesa which receive, or which have been granted rights to receive, water from Imperial Irrigation District’s capacity in the Coachella Canal. Costs of such acquisitions shall be nonreimbursable and the Secretary shall return such lands to the public domain. The United States shall not acquire any water rights by reason of this land acquisition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit to Imperial Irrigation District against final payments for relinquished capacity in Coachella Canal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to credit Imperial Irrigation District against its final payments for certain outstanding construction charges payable to the United States on account of capacity to be relinquished in the Coachella Canal as a result of the canal lining program, all as determined by the Secretary: <i>Provided</i>, That, relinquishment of capacity shall not affect the established basis for allocating operation and maintenance costs of the main All-American Canal to existing contractors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of lands to Cocopah Tribe of Indians</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed to cede the following land to the Cocopah Tribe of Indians, subject to rights-of-way for existing levees, to be held in trust by the United States for the Cocopah Tribe of Indians:</p>
<p class="indent1" role="listItem">Township 9 south, range 25 west of the Gila and Salt River meridian, Arizona;</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">Section 25: Lots 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, and 23;</p>
<p class="indent2">Section 26: Lots 1, 12, 13, 14, and 15;</p>
<p class="indent2">Section 27: Lot 3; and all accretion to the above described lands.</p>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed to construct three bridges, one of which shall be capable of accommodating heavy vehicular traffic, over the portion of the bypass drain which crosses the reservation of the Cocopah Tribe of Indians. The transfer of lands to the Cocopah Indian Reservation and the construction of bridges across the bypass drain shall constitute full and complete payment to said tribe for the rights-of-way required for construction of the bypass drain and electrical transmission lines for works authorized by this subchapter.</continuation>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 268</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1573.</num>
<heading> Construction and maintenance of well fields; land acquisition; land replacement; nonreimbursable costs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary is authorized to:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Construct, operate, and maintain, consistent with Minute No. 242, well fields capable of furnishing approximately one hundred and sixty thousand acre-feet of water per year for use in the United States and for delivery to Mexico in satisfaction of the 1944 Mexican Water Treaty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Acquire by purchase, eminent domain, or exchange, to the extent determined by him to be appropriate, approximately twenty-three thousand five hundred acres of lands or interests therein with approximately five miles of the Mexican border on the Yuma Mesa: <i>Provided, however</i>, That any such lands which are presently owned by the State of Arizona may be acquired or exchanged for Federal lands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any lands removed from the jurisdiction of the Yuma Mesa Irrigation and Drainage District pursuant to clause (2) of this subsection which were available for use under the Gila Reauthorization Act (<ref>61 Stat. 628</ref>) [<ref>43 U.S.C. 613</ref> et. seq.], shall be replaced with like lands within or adjacent to the Yuma Mesa division of the project. In the development of these substituted lands or any other lands within the Gila project, the Secretary may provide for full utilization of the Gila Gravity Main Canal in addition to contracted capacities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Effective <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, and to such extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts, enter into contracts under the terms and conditions of the Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date> (<ref>43 U.S.C. 371</ref> et seq.) as amended and supplemented for the delivery of water from said well field to entities within the United States for municipal and industrial or irrigation purposes: <i>Provided</i>, That such contracts for municipal and industrial purposes shall contain terms and conditions as substantially provided in <ref>section 485h(c)(1) of this title</ref>, and that contracts for replacement irrigation water supplies to prevent damage to existing water users on privately developed lands include water charges no greater than if such water users had continued to pump their own wells without the United States lowering the water table and that the acreage limitation and related provisions of the Reclamation Law will not be applicable to such privately developed lands: <i>Provided further</i>, That no contract shall be entered which will impair the ability of the United States to continue to deliver to Mexico on the land boundary at San Luis and in the Limitrophe Section of the Colorado River downstream from Morelos Dam approximately one hundred and forty thousand acre-feet annually, consistent with the terms contained in Minute No. 242 of the IBWC.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The cost of work provided for in this section, including delivery of water to Mexico, shall be nonreimbursable; except to the extent that the waters furnished are used in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 269</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–336, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1063</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1574.</num>
<heading> Modification of projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to provide for modifications of the projects authorized by this subchapter to the extent he determines appropriate for purposes of meeting the international settlement objective of this subchapter at the lowest overall cost to the United States. No funds for any such modification shall be expended until the expiration of sixty days after the proposed modification has been submitted to the appropriate committees of the Congress, unless the Congress approves an earlier date by concurrent resolution. The Secretary shall notify the Governors of the Colorado River Basin States of such modifications.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1575.</num>
<heading> Contract authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts that he deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter in advance of the appropriation of funds therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1575a.</num>
<heading> Administration and disposition of lands and constructed facilities; revenues credited to general fund of Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby authorized to administer and dispose of lands and interests in lands acquired, and facilities constructed under this subchapter, and revenues received in connection with this authority shall be credited to the general fund of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 106</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–336, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1576.</num>
<heading> Interagency cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary shall consult and cooperate with the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, and other affected Federal, State, and local agencies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 107</ref>, formerly § 106, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 270</ref>; renumbered § 107, <ref>Pub. L. 96–336, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1577.</num>
<heading> Existing Federal laws not modified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to modify the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.], the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended [<ref>33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.], or, except as expressly stated herein, the provisions of any other Federal law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 108</ref>, formerly § 107, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 270</ref>; renumbered § 108, <ref>Pub. L. 96–336, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1578.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated the sum of $356,400,000 for the construction of the works and accomplishment of the purposes authorized in sections 1571, 1572, 1573, and 1579 of this title, of which $3,579,000 is authorized for mitigation of fish and wildlife losses associated with replacement of the Coachella Canal in California, and $6,960,000 is authorized for mitigation of fish and wildlife losses associated with the Desalting Complex Unit and the Protective and Regulatory Pumping Unit in Arizona, based on January 1979, prices plus or minus such amounts as may be justified by reason of ordinary fluctuation in construction costs involved therein, and such sums as may be required to operate and maintain such works and to provide for such modifications as may be made pursuant to <ref>section 1574 of this title</ref>. In order to provide for the utilization of significant improvements in desal­inization technologies which may have been developed since the Bureau’s evaluation, the Secretary is directed to evaluate such cost effective improvements and implement such improved designs into the plant operations when the evaluation indicates that cost savings will result: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no more than five percent of the amount authorized to be appropriated is used for these purposes. There is further authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to pay condemnation awards in excess of appraised values and to cover costs required in connection with the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4601</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 109</ref>, formerly § 108, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 270</ref>; renumbered § 109 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–336</ref>, §§ 4, 5, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1579.</num>
<heading> Fish and wildlife habitat; mitigation of losses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, and to such extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002101">1</ref> Acts, in order to provide measures determined by the Secretary of the Interior to be appropriated to mitigate loss of fish and wildlife habitat associated with other measures taken under this subchapter:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriation of funds; acquisition and disposal of lands; facilities undertakings; funds restriction for non-Federal facilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire lands by purchase, eminent domain, or exchange;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> dispose of land, facilities, and equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> construct, operate, maintain, and make replacements of facilities: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no funds will be provided for operation, maintenance, or replacement of non-Federal facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonreimbursable costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">All costs authorized by this section are nonreimbursable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 110</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–336, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1580.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Navajo Generating Station means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States entitlement to a portion of the output of power and energy from the Navajo Generating Station, Page, Arizona, pursuant to United States participation in that generating station;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the event that said United States entitlement is integrated with other generating facilities, then Navajo Generating Station means that amount of power and energy from the integrated system which is attributable to the United States Navajo entitlement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> when the Navajo Generating Station is replaced at the end of its useful life or an alternative resource is established, then Navajo Generating Station means an amount of power and energy equivalent to the present United States entitlement from Navajo, from the replacement resource.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> All terms used herein that are defined in the Colorado River Compact shall have the meanings therein defined.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 111</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–336, § 7</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1065</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MEASURES UPSTREAM FROM IMPERIAL DAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1591.</num>
<heading> Salinity control policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation by Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall implement the salinity control policy adopted for the Colorado River in the “Conclusions and Recommendations” published in the Proceedings of the Reconvened Seventh Session of the Conference in the Matter of Pollution of the Interstate Waters of the Colorado River and Its Tributaries in the States of California, Colorado, Utah, Arizona, Nevada, New Mexico, and Wyoming, held in Denver, Colorado, on April 26–27, 1972, under the authority of section 10 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1160</ref>), and approved by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency on <date date="1972-06-09">June 9, 1972</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expeditious investigation, planning, and implementation of salinity control program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby directed to expedite the investigation, planning, and implementation of the salinity control program generally as described in chapter VI of the Secretary’s report entitled, “Colorado River Water Quality Improvement Program, February 1972”. In determining the relative priority of implementing additional units or new self-contained portions of units authorized by <ref>section 1592 of this title</ref>, the Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, shall give preference to those additional units or new self-contained portions of units which reduce salinity of the Colorado River at the least cost per unit of salinity reduction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In conformity with subsection (a) and the authority of the Environmental Protection Agency under Federal laws, the Secretary, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Secretary of Agriculture are directed to cooperate and coordinate their activities effectively to carry out the objective of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–569, § 1</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2933</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1592.</num>
<heading> Authorization to construct, operate, and maintain salinity control units and salinity control programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain the following salinity control units and salinity control programs as the initial stage of the Colorado River Basin salinity control program:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Paradox Valley unit, Montrose County, Colorado, consisting of facilities for collection and disposition of saline ground water of Paradox Valley, including wells, pumps, pipelines, solar evaporation ponds, and all necessary appurtenant and associated works such as roads, fences, dikes, power transmission facilities, and permanent operating facilities, and consisting of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Grand Valley unit, Colorado, consisting of measures and all necessary appurtenant and associated works to reduce the seepage of irrigation water from the irrigated lands of Grand Valley into the ground water and thence into the Colorado River. Measures shall include lining of canals and laterals, replacing canals and laterals with pipe, and the combining of existing canals and laterals into fewer and more efficient facilities implementing other measures to reduce salt contributions from the Grand Valley to the Colorado River, and implementing measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone..<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002102">1</ref> Prior to initiation of construction of the Grand Valley unit, or portion thereof, the Secretary shall enter into contracts through which the non-Federal entities owning, operating, and maintaining the water distribution systems, or portions thereof, in Grand Valley, singly or in concert, will assume the obligations specified in subsection (b)(2) relating to the continued operation and maintenance of the unit’s facilities to the end that the maximum reduction of salinity inflow to the Colorado River will be achieved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Las Vegas Wash unit, Nevada, consisting of facilities for collection and disposition of saline ground water of Las Vegas Wash, including infiltration galleries, pumps, desalter, pipelines, solar evaporation facilities, and all appurtenant works including but not limited to roads, fences, power transmission facilities, and operating facilities, and consisting of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Stage I of the Lower Gunnison Basin unit, Colorado, consisting of measures and all necessary appurtenant and associated works to reduce seepage from canals and laterals in the Uncompahgre Valley, and consisting of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, essentially as described in the feasibility report and final environmental statement dated <date date="1984-02-10">February 10, 1984</date>. Prior to initiation of construction of stage I of the Lower Gunnison Basin unit, or of a portion of stage I, the Secretary shall enter into contracts through which the non-Federal entities owning, operating, and maintaining the water distribution systems, or portions thereof, in the Uncompahgre Valley, singly or in concert, will assume the obligations specified in subsection (b)(2) relating to the continued operation and maintenance of the unit’s facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Portions of the McElmo Creek unit, Colorado, as components of the Dolores participating project, Colorado River Storage project, authorized by <ref>Public Law 90–537</ref> [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.] and <ref>Public Law 84–485</ref> [<ref>43 U.S.C. 620</ref> et seq.], consisting of all measures and all necessary appurtenant and associated works to reduce seepage only from the Towaoc-Highline combined canal, Rocky Ford laterals, Lone Pine lateral, and Upper Hermana lateral, and consisting of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone. The Dolores participating project shall have salinity control as a project purpose insofar as these specific facilities are concerned: <i>Provided</i>, That the costs of construction and replacement of these specific facilities shall be allocated by the Secretary to salinity control and irrigation only after consultation with the State of Colorado, the Montezuma Valley Irrigation District, Colorado, and the Dolores Water Conservancy District, Colorado: <i>And provided further</i>, That such allocation of costs to salinity control will include only the separable and specific costs of these specific facilities and will not include any joint costs of any other facilities of the Dolores participating project. Repayment of costs allocated to salinity control shall be subject to this chapter. Repayment of costs allocated to irrigation shall be subject to the Acts which authorized the Dolores participating project, the Reclamation Act of 1902, and Acts amendatory and supplementary thereto. Prior to initiation of construction of these specific facilities, or a portion thereof, the Secretary shall enter into contracts through which the non-Federal entities owning, operating, and maintaining the water distribution systems, or portions thereof, in the Montezuma Valley, singly or in concert, will assume the obligations specified in subsection (b)(2) relating to the continued operation and maintenance of the unit’s facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A basinwide salinity control program that the Secretary, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, shall implement. The Secretary may carry out the purposes of this paragraph directly, or may make grants, commitments for grants, or advances of funds to non-Federal entities under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may require. Such program shall consist of cost-effective measures and associated works to reduce salinity from saline springs, leaking wells, irrigation sources, industrial sources, erosion of public and private land, or other sources that the Secretary considers appropriate. Such program shall provide for the mitigation of incidental fish and wildlife values that are lost as a result of the measures and associated works. The Secretary shall submit a planning report concerning the program established under this paragraph to the appropriate committees of Congress. The Secretary may not expend funds for any implementation measure under the program established under this paragraph before the expiration of a 30-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits such report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Basin states program.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Basin States Program that the Secretary, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, shall implement to carry out salinity control activities in the Colorado River Basin using funds made available under <ref>section 1595(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in consultation with the Colorado River Basin Salinity Control Advisory Council, shall carry out this paragraph using funds described in subparagraph (A) directly or by providing grants, grant commitments, or advance funds to Federal or non-Federal entities under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds described in subparagraph (A) shall be used to carry out, as determined by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> cost-effective measures and associated works to reduce salinity from saline springs, leaking wells, irrigation sources, industrial sources, erosion of public and private land, or other sources;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> operation and maintenance of salinity control features constructed under the Colorado River Basin salinity control program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> studies, planning, and administration of salinity control activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days before implementing the program established under this paragraph, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a planning report that describes the proposed implementation of the program.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not expend funds to implement the program established under this paragraph before the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits the report, or any revision to the report, under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of authorized units</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In implementing the units authorized to be constructed pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall carry out the following directions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As reports are completed describing final implementation plans for the unit, or any portion thereof, authorized by paragraph (5) of subsection (a), and prior to expenditure of funds for related construction activities, the Secretary shall submit such reports to the appropriate committees of the Congress and to the governors of the Colorado River Basin States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Non-Federal entities shall be required by the Secretary to contract for the long-term operation and maintenance of canal and lateral systems constructed pursuant to activities provided for in subsection (a): <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary shall reimburse such non-Federal entities for the costs of such operation and maintenance to the extent the costs exceed the expenses that would have been incurred by them in the thorough and timely operation and maintenance of their canal and lateral systems absent the construction of a unit, said expenses to be determined by the Secretary after consultation with the involved non-Federal entities. The operation and maintenance for which non-Federal entities shall be responsible shall include such repairing and replacing of a unit’s facilities as are associated with normal annual maintenance activities in order to keep such facilities in a condition which will assure maximum reduction of salinity inflow to the Colorado River. These non-Federal entities shall not be responsible, nor incur any costs, for the replacement of a unit’s facilities, including measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone. The term replacement shall be defined for the purposes of this subchapter as a major modification or reconstruction of a completed unit, or portion thereof, which is necessitated, through no fault of the non-Federal entity or entities operating and maintaining a unit, by design or construction inadequacies or by normal limits on the useful life of a facility. The Secretary is authorized to provide continuing technical assistance to non-Federal entities to assure the effective and efficient operation and maintenance of a unit’s facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, under authority of this subchapter, and limited to the purposes of this chapter, fund through a grant or contract, for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts, a non-Federal entity to organize private canal and lateral owners into formal organizations with which the Secretary may enter into a grant or contract to construct, operate, and maintain a unit’s facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In implementing the units authorized to be constructed or the programs pursuant to paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7) of subsection (a), the Secretary shall comply with procedural and substantive State water laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, under authority of this subchapter and limited to the purposes of this chapter, fund through a grant or contract, for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts, a non-Federal entity to operate and maintain measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In implementing the units authorized to be constructed pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall implement measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone concurrently with the implementation of a unit’s, or a portion of a unit’s, related features.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Salinity control measures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall carry out salinity control measures (including watershed enhancement and cost-share measures with livestock and crop producers) in the Colorado River Basin as part of the environmental quality incentives program established under subchapter A of chapter 4 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 [<ref>16 U.S.C. 3839aa</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–569, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2933</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–20, § 1(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="1995-07-28">July 28, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 255</ref>, 256; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1006</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title II, § 2806(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title II, § 2806(a), (b)(1), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1817; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title II, § 2301(d)(2)(G)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1593.</num>
<heading> Planning reports; research and demonstration projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary is authorized and directed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Expedite completion of the planning reports on the following units, described in the Secretary’s report, “Colorado River Water Quality Improvement Program, February 1972”;</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Irrigation source control:<p class="indent2" role="listItem">Lower Gunnison</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">Uintah Basin</p>
<p class="indent2">Colorado River Indian Reservation</p>
<p class="indent2">Palo Verde Irrigation District</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Point source control:<p class="indent2" role="listItem">LaVerkin Springs</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">Littlefield Springs</p>
<p class="indent2">Glenwood-Dotsero Springs</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Diffuse source control:<p class="indent2" role="listItem">Price River</p>
<p class="indent2" role="listItem">San Rafael River</p>
<p class="indent2">Dirty Devil River</p>
<p class="indent2">McElmo Creek</p>
<p class="indent2">Big Sandy River</p>
</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Submit each planning report on the units named in paragraph (1) of this subsection promptly to the Colorado River Basin States and to such other parties as the Secretary deems appropriate for their review and comments. After receipt of comments on a unit and careful consideration thereof, the Secretary shall submit each final report with his recommendations, simultaneously, to the President, other concerned Federal departments and agencies, the Congress, and the Colorado River Basin States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary is directed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the investigation, planning, construction, and implementation of any salinity control unit involving control of salinity from irrigation sources, to cooperate with the Secretary of Agriculture in carrying out research and demonstration projects and in implementing on-the-farm improvements and farm management practices and programs which will further the objective of this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to undertake research on additional methods for accomplishing the objective of this subchapter, utilizing to the fullest extent practicable the capabilities and resources of other Federal departments and agencies, interstate institutions, States, and private organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to develop a comprehensive program for minimizing salt contributions to the Colorado River from lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management and submit a report which describes the program and recommended implementation actions to the Congress and to the members of the advisory council established by <ref>section 1594(a) of this title</ref> by <date date="1987-07-01">July 1, 1987</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to undertake feasibility investigations of saline water use and disposal opportunities, including measures and all necessary appurtenant and associated works, to demonstrate saline water use technology and to beneficially use and dispose of saline and brackish waters of the Colorado River Basin in joint ventures with current and future industrial water users, using, but not limited to, the concepts generally described in the Bureau of Reclamation Special Report of September 1981, entitled “Saline water use and disposal opportunities”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to undertake advance planning activities on the Sinbad Valley Unit, Colorado, as described in the Bureau of Land Management Salinity Status Report, covering the period 1978–1979 and dated February 1980.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–569, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2937</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1594.</num>
<heading> Colorado River Basin Salinity Control Ad­visory Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is created the Colorado River Basin Salinity Control Advisory Council composed of no more than three members from each State appointed by the Governor of each of the Colorado River Basin States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Council shall be advisory only and shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> act as liaison between both the Secretaries of Interior and Agriculture and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the States in accomplishing the purposes of this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> receive reports from the Secretary on the progress of the salinity control program and review and comment on said reports; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recommend to both the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency appropriate studies of further projects, techniques, or methods for accomplishing the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1595.</num>
<heading> Salinity control units; authority and functions of the Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall allocate the total costs (excluding costs borne by non-Federal participants) of the on-farm measures authorized by <ref>section 1592(c) of this title</ref>, of all measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by <ref>section 1592(a) of this title</ref>, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonreimbursable costs; reimbursable costs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonreimbursable costs</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In recognition of Federal responsibility for the Colorado River as an interstate stream and for international comity with Mexico, Federal ownership of the land of the Colorado River Basin from which most of the dissolved salts originate, and the policy established in the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.) and except as provided in clause (ii), the following shall be nonreimbursable:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> 75 percent of the total costs of construction and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by <ref>section 1592(a)(1) of this title</ref>, including 90 percent of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the costs of operation and maintenance of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by that section; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the total costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> 75 percent of the total costs of construction and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by <ref>section 1592(a)(2) of this title</ref>, including 100 percent of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the costs of operation and maintenance of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by that section; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the total costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> 75 percent of the total costs of construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by <ref>section 1592(a)(3) of this title</ref>, including 75 percent of the total costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> 70 percent of the total costs of construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by paragraphs (4) and (6) of <ref>section 1592(a) of this title</ref>, including 70 percent of the total costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<chapeau> 70 percent of the total costs of construction and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by <ref>section 1592(a)(5) of this title</ref>, including 100 percent of—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the costs of operation and maintenance of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by that section; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the total costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> 85 percent of the total costs of implementation of the on-farm measures authorized by <ref>section 1592(c) of this title</ref>, including 85 percent of the total costs of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for nonreimbursable costs for fiscal years 2024 and 2025</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Notwithstanding clause (i), for each of fiscal years 2024 and 2025, the following shall be nonreimbursable:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 75 percent of all costs described in clause (i)(I).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 75 percent of all costs described in clause (i)(II).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> 70 percent of all costs described in clause (i)(V).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> The percentages of all costs described in subclauses (III), (IV), and (VI) of clause (i).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursable costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The total costs remaining after the allocations under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall be reimbursable as provided for in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The reimbursable portion of the total costs shall be allocated between the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund established by section 5(a) of the Colorado River Storage Project Act (<ref>70 Stat. 107</ref>) [<ref>43 U.S.C. 620d(a)</ref>] and the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund established by <ref>section 1543(a) of this title</ref>, after consultation with the Advisory Council created in <ref>section 1594(a) of this title</ref> and consideration of the following items:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> benefits to be derived in each basin from the use of water of improved quality and the use of works for improved water management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> causes of salinity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> availability of revenues in the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund and increased revenues to the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund made available under <ref>section 620d(d)(5) of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That costs allocated to the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund under this paragraph (2) shall not exceed 15 per centum of the costs allocated to the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund and the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Costs of construction and replacement of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002103">1</ref> 1592(a)(1), (2), and (3) of this title and costs of construction of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, when such measures are a part of the units authorized by sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002103">1</ref> 1592(a)(1), (2), and (3) of this title, allocated to the upper basin and to the lower basin under subsection (a)(2) shall be repaid within a fifty-year period or within a period equal to the estimated life of the unit, separable feature thereof, or replacement, whichever is less, without interest from the date such unit, separable feature, or replacement is determined by the Secretary to be in operation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Costs of construction and replacement of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by paragraphs (4) through (6) of section 1592 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">2</ref> of this title, costs of construction of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, when such measures are a part of the on-farm measures authorized by <ref>section 1592(c) of this title</ref> or of the units authorized by paragraphs (4) through (6) of section 1592 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">2</ref> of this title, and costs of implementation of the on-farm measures authorized by <ref>section 1592(c) of this title</ref> allocated to the upper basin and to the lower basin under subsection (a)(2) shall be repaid as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii), respectively, of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Costs allocated to the upper basin shall be repaid with interest within a fifty-year period, or within a period equal to the estimated life of the unit, separable feature thereof, replacement, or on-farm measure, whichever is less, from the date such unit, separable feature thereof, replacement, or on-farm measure is determined by the Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture to be in operation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Costs allocated to the lower basin shall be repaid without interest as such costs are incurred to the extent that money is available from the Lower Colorado River Basin development fund to repay costs allocated to the lower basin. If in any fiscal year the money available from the Lower Colorado River Basin development fund for such repayment is insufficient to repay the costs allocated to the lower basin, as provided in the preceding sentence, the deficiency shall be repaid with interest as soon as money becomes available in the fund for repayment of those costs.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The interest rates used pursuant to this chapter shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration average market yields on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the reimbursement period during the month preceding <date date="1984-10-30">October 30, 1984</date>, for costs outstanding at that date, or, in the case of costs incurred subsequent to <date date="1984-10-30">October 30, 1984</date>, during the month preceding the fiscal year in which the costs are incurred.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Costs of operation and maintenance of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by <ref>section 1592(a) of this title</ref> and of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone allocated to the upper basin and to the lower basin under subsection (a)(2) shall be repaid without interest in the fiscal year next succeeding the fiscal year in which such costs are incurred. In the event that revenues are not available to repay the portion of operation and maintenance costs allocated to the Upper Colorado River Basin fund and to the Lower Colorado River Basin development fund in the year next succeeding the fiscal year in which such costs are incurred, the deficiency shall be repayed <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002105">3</ref> with interest calculated in the same manner as provided in subsection (a)(4)(iv). Any reimbursement due non-Federal entities pursuant to <ref>section 1592(b)(2) of this title</ref> shall be repaid without interest in the fiscal year next succeeding the fiscal year in which such operation and maintenance costs are incurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs payable from Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Costs of construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by <ref>section 1592(a) of this title</ref>, costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and costs of implementation of the on-farm measures authorized by <ref>section 1592(c) of this title</ref>, allocated for repayment by the lower basin under subsection (a)(2) shall be paid in accordance with <ref>section 1543(g)(2) of this title</ref>, from the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Omitted</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs payable from Upper Colorado River Basin Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Costs of construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by <ref>section 1592(a) of this title</ref>, costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and costs of implementation of the on-farm measures authorized by <ref>section 1592(c) of this title</ref> allocated for repayment by the upper basin under subsection (a)(2) shall be paid in accordance with <ref>section 620d(d)(5) of this title</ref> from the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund within the limit of the funds made available under subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Upward adjustment of rates for electrical energy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make upward adjustments in rates charged for electrical energy under all contracts administered by the Secretary under the Colorado River Storage Project Act (<ref>70 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>43 U.S.C. 620</ref>) as soon as practicable and to the extent necessary to cover the costs allocated to the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund under subsection (a)(2) and in conformity with subsection (a)(3), subsection (a)(4) and subsection (a)(5): <i>Provided</i>, That revenues derived from said rate adjustments shall be available solely for the construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of salinity control units, for the construction, operation, and maintenance of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and for the implementation of on-farm measures in the Colorado River Basin herein authorized.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Up-front cost share</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Effective beginning on the date of enactment of this paragraph, subject to paragraph (3), the cost share obligations required by this section shall be met through an up-front cost share from the Basin Funds, in the same proportions as the cost allocations required under subsection (a), as provided in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basin States Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall expend the required cost share funds described in paragraph (1) through the Basin States Program for salinity control activities established under <ref>section 1592(a)(7) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing salinity control activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The cost share contribution required by this section shall continue to be met through repayment in a manner consistent with this section for all salinity control activities for which repayment was commenced prior to the date of enactment of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–569, § 4(a)</ref>–(f)(1), (g), (i), <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2937–2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–20, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-07-28">July 28, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1006</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title II, § 2806(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title II, § 2806(b)(2), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1818; <ref>Pub. L. 118–183, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1596.</num>
<heading> Biennial report to President, Congress, and Advisory Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commencing on <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, and every two years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit, simultaneously, to the President, the Congress, and the Advisory Council created in <ref>section 1594(a) of this title</ref>, a report on the Colorado River salinity control program authorized by this subchapter covering the progress of investigations, planning, and construction of salinity control units for the previous fiscal year, the effectiveness of such units, anticipated work needed to be accomplished in the future to meet the objectives of this subchapter, with emphasis on the needs during the five years immediately following the date of each report, and any special problems that may be impeding progress in attaining an effective salinity control program. Said report may be included in the biennial report on the quality of water of the Colorado River Basin prepared by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 620n of this title</ref>, <ref>section 615ww of this title</ref>, and <ref>section 616e of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1597.</num>
<heading> Construction of provisions of subchapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in sections 620d(d)(5), 1543(g)(2), and 1595(b) of this title, with respect to the Colorado River Basin Project Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.] and the Colorado River Storage Project Act [<ref>43 U.S.C. 620</ref> et seq.], respectively, nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to alter, amend, repeal, modify, interpret, or be in conflict with the provisions of the Colorado River Compact (<ref>45 Stat. 1057</ref>), the Upper Colorado River Basin Compact (<ref>63 Stat. 31</ref>), the Water Treaty of 1944 with the United Mexican States (Treaty Series 994; <ref>59 Stat. 1219</ref>), the decree entered by the Supreme Court of the United States in Arizona against California and others (376 U.S. 340), the Boulder Canyon Project Act (<ref>45 Stat. 1057</ref>) [<ref>43 U.S.C. 617</ref> et seq.], Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act (<ref>54 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>43 U.S.C. 618a</ref>) [<ref>43 U.S.C. 618</ref> et seq.], section 15 of the Colorado River Storage Project Act (<ref>70 Stat. 111</ref>; <ref>43 U.S.C. 620n</ref>), the Colorado River Basin Project Act (<ref>82 Stat. 885</ref>), section 6 of the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project Act (<ref>76 Stat. 393</ref>) [<ref>43 U.S.C. 616e</ref>], section 15 of the Navajo Indian irrigation project and initial stage of the San Juan-Chama Project Act (<ref>76 Stat. 102</ref>) [<ref>43 U.S.C. 615ww</ref>], the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.], and the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended [<ref>33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 207</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1598.</num>
<heading> Achieving project objectives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to provide for modifications of the projects authorized by this subchapter as determined to be appropriate for purposes of meeting the objective of this subchapter. No funds for any such modification shall be expended until the expiration of sixty days after the proposed modification has been submitted to appropriate committees of the Congress, except that funds may be expended prior to the expiration of such sixty days in any case in which the Congress approves an earlier date by concurrent resolution. The Governors of the Colorado River Basin States shall be notified of these changes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract authority; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby authorized to enter into contracts that he deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, in advance of the appropriation of funds therefor. There is hereby authorized to be appropriated the sum of $125,100,000 for the construction of the works and for other purposes authorized in section 1592(a) or (b) of this title, based on April 1973 prices, plus or minus such amounts as may be justified by reason of ordinary fluctuations in costs involved therein, and such sums as may be required to operate and maintain such works. The funds authorized to be appropriated by this section may be used for construction of any or all of the works or portions thereof and for other purposes authorized in subsection (a), including measures as provided for in subsection (b) of <ref>section 1592 of this title</ref>. There is further authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to pay condemnation awards in excess of appraised values and to cover costs required in connection with the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4601</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of basinwide salinity control program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (b), there are authorized to be appropriated $175,000,000 for <ref>section 1592(a) of this title</ref>, including constructing the works described in paragraph (6) of <ref>section 1592(a) of this title</ref> and carrying out the measures described in such paragraph. Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary may implement the program under <ref>section 1592(a)(6) of this title</ref> only to the extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–569, § 5</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–20, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1995-07-28">July 28, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–459, § 1</ref>, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> all terms that are defined in the Colorado River Compact shall have the meanings therein defined;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> “Colorado River Basin States” means the States of Arizona, California, Colorado, Nevada, New Mexico, Utah, and Wyoming.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 275</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>