<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>ORGANIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to the definitions in sections 1–5 of title 1, the following definitions apply in this title:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For purposes of other laws relating to the militia, the National Guard, the Army National Guard of the United States, and the Air National Guard of the United States, the term “Territory” includes Guam and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Armed forces” means the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “National Guard” means the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “Army National Guard” means that part of the organized militia of the several States and Territories, Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia, active and inactive, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a land force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is trained, and has its officers appointed, under the sixteenth clause of section 8, article I, of the Constitution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is organized, armed, and equipped wholly or partly at Federal expense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is federally recognized.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “Army National Guard of the United States” means the reserve component of the Army all of whose members are members of the Army National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> “Air National Guard” means that part of the organized militia of the several States and Territories, Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia, active and inactive, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an air force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is trained, and has its officers appointed, under the sixteenth clause of section 8, article I of the Constitution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is organized, armed, and equipped wholly or partly at Federal expense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is federally recognized.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “Air National Guard of the United States” means the reserve component of the Air Force all of whose members are members of the Air National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “Officer” means commissioned or warrant officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “Enlisted member” means a person enlisted in, or inducted, called, or conscripted into, an armed force in an enlisted grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “Grade” means a step or degree, in a graduated scale of office or military rank, that is established and designated as a grade by law or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “Rank” means the order of precedence among members of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “Active duty” means full-time duty in the active military service of the United States. It includes such Federal duty as full-time training duty, annual training duty, and attendance, while in the active military service, at a school designated as a service school by law or by the Secretary of the military department concerned. It does not include full-time National Guard duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> “Supplies” includes material, equipment, and stores of all kinds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> “Shall” is used in an imperative sense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> “May” is used in a permissive sense. The words “no person may * * *” mean that no person is required, authorized, or permitted to do the act prescribed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> “Includes” means “includes but is not limited to”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> “Pay” includes basic pay, special pay, incentive pay, retired pay, and equivalent pay, but does not include allowances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> “Spouse” means husband or wife, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> “Full-time National Guard duty” means training or other duty, other than inactive duty, performed by a member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States in the member’s status as a member of the National Guard of a State or territory, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or the District of Columbia under section 316, 502, 503, 504, or 505 of this title for which the member is entitled to pay from the United States or for which the member has waived pay from the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1542</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 27</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 22</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–492, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 810</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–600, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title IV, § 414(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> General policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with the traditional military policy of the United States, it is essential that the strength and organization of the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard as an integral part of the first line defenses of the United States be maintained and assured at all times. Whenever Congress determines that more units and organizations are needed for the national security than are in the regular components of the ground and air forces, the Army National Guard of the United States and the Air National Guard of the United States, or such parts of them as are needed, together with such units of other reserve components as are necessary for a balanced force, shall be ordered to active Federal duty and retained as long as so needed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 597</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Branches and organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Army National Guard of each State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, and the Virgin Islands includes such members of the staff corps corresponding to the staff corps of the Army as the Secretary of the Army may authorize.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 104.</num>
<heading> Units: location; organization; command</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands may fix the location of the units and headquarters of its National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise specifically provided in this title, the organization of the Army National Guard and the composition of its units shall be the same as those prescribed for the Army, subject, in time of peace, to such general exceptions as the Secretary of the Army may authorize; and the organization of the Air National Guard and the composition of its units shall be the same as those prescribed for the Air Force, subject, in time of peace, to such general exceptions as the Secretary of the Air Force may authorize.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> To secure a force the units of which when combined will form complete higher tactical units, the President may designate the units of the National Guard, by branch of the Army or organization of the Air Force, to be maintained in each State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, and the Virgin Islands. However, no change in the branch, organization, or allotment of a unit located entirely within a State may be made without the approval of its governor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> To maintain appropriate organization and to assist in training and instruction, the President may assign the National Guard to divisions, wings, and other tactical units, and may detail commissioned officers of the National Guard or of the Regular Army or the Regular Air Force, as the case may be, to command those units. However, the commanding officer of a unit organized wholly within a State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, or the Virgin Islands may not be displaced under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> To insure prompt mobilization of the National Guard in time of war or other emergency, the President may, in time of peace, detail a commissioned officer of the Regular Army to perform the duties of chief of staff for each fully organized division of the Army National Guard, and a commissioned officer of the Regular Air Force to perform the duties of the corresponding position for each fully organized wing of the Air National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> Unless the President consents—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an organization of the National Guard whose members have received compensation from the United States as members of the National Guard may not be disbanded; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the actual strength of such an organization in commissioned officers or enlisted members may not be reduced below the minimum strength prescribed by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(2)</ref>–(4), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 105.</num>
<heading> Inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by such Secretary, the Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Air Force shall each have an inspection made by inspectors general, or by any other commissioned officers of the Regular Army or the Regular Air Force detailed for that purpose, to determine whether—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount and condition of property held by the Army National Guard or Air National Guard are satisfactory;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Army National Guard or Air National Guard is organized as provided in this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the members of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard meet prescribed physical and other qualifications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Army National Guard or Air National Guard and its organization are properly uniformed, armed, and equipped and are being trained and instructed for active duty in the field, or for coast defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Army National Guard or Air National Guard records are being kept in accordance with this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the accounts and records of each prop­erty and fiscal officer are properly maintained;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the units of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard meet requirements for deployment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the units and members of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard comply with Federal law and policy applicable to the National Guard, including policies issued by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the military department concerned, or the Chief of the National Guard Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The reports of inspections under subsection (a) are the basis for determining whether the National Guard is entitled to the issue of military property as authorized under this title and to retain that property; and for determining which organizations and persons constitute units and members of the National Guard; and for determining which units of the National Guard meet deployability standards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Chief of the National Guard Bureau may have an inspection described in subsection (a) made by inspectors general, or by commissioned officers of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States detailed for that purpose, on behalf of the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force. Any such inspection may be made only with the approval of the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force, as applicable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–79, title VIII, § 804(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-07-30">July 30, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XI, § 1122</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2540</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 517</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2565</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 106.</num>
<heading> Annual appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sums will be appropriated annually, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the support of the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard, including the issue of arms, ordnance stores, quartermaster stores, camp equipage, and other military supplies, and for the payment of other expenses authorized by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 599</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 107.</num>
<heading> Availability of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, appropriations for the National Guard are available for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the necessary expenses of members of a regular or reserve component of the Army or the Air Force traveling on duty in connection with the National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the necessary expenses of members of the Regular Army or the Regular Air Force on duty in the National Guard Bureau or with the Army Staff or the Air Staff, traveling to and from annual conventions of the Enlisted Association of the National Guard of the United States, the National Guard Association of the United States, or the Adjutants General Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the transportation of supplies furnished to the National Guard as permanent equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the office rent and necessary office expenses of officers of a regular or reserve component of the Army or the Air Force on duty with the National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the expenses of the National Guard Bureau, including clerical services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the promotion of rifle practice, including the acquisition, construction, maintenance, and equipment of shooting galleries and suitable target ranges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> such incidental expenses of authorized encampments, maneuvers, and field instruction as the Secretary considers necessary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> other expenses of the National Guard authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The expenses of enlisted members of the Regular Army or the Regular Air Force on duty with the National Guard shall be paid from appropriations for the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard, as the case may be, but not from the allotment of a State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, or the Virgin Islands. Payable expenses include allowances for subsistence and housing under sections 402 and 403 of title 37 and expenses for medicine and medical attendance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The pay and allowances for the Chief of the National Guard Bureau and officers of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States called to active duty under <ref>section 12402 of title 10</ref> shall be paid from appropriations for the pay of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 4</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–119, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-08-13">Aug. 13, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(h)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1676(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3019</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VI, § 603(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 108.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture of Federal benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, within a time fixed by the President, a State fails to comply with a requirement of this title, or a regulation prescribed under this title, the National Guard of that State is barred, in whole or in part, as the President may prescribe, from receiving money or any other aid, benefit, or privilege authorized by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 904(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 109.</num>
<heading> Maintenance of other troops</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In time of peace, a State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, or the Virgin Islands may maintain no troops other than those of its National Guard and defense forces authorized by subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this title limits the right of a State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, or the Virgin Islands to use its National Guard or its defense forces authorized by subsection (c) within its borders in time of peace, or prevents it from organizing and maintaining police or constabulary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In addition to its National Guard, if any, a State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, or the Virgin Islands may, as provided by its laws, organize and maintain defense forces. A defense force established under this section may be used within the jurisdiction concerned, as its chief executive (or commanding general in the case of the District of Columbia) considers necessary, but it may not be called, ordered, or drafted into the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A member of a defense force established under subsection (c) is not, because of that membership, exempt from service in the armed forces, nor is he entitled to pay, allowances, subsistence, transportation, or medical care or treatment, from funds of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A person may not become a member of a defense force established under subsection (c) if he is a member of a reserve component of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 2(2)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1542</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(h)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4377</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall prescribe regulations, and issue orders, necessary to organize, discipline, and govern the National Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 111.</num>
<heading> Suspension of certain provisions of this title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In time of war, or of emergency declared by Congress, the President may suspend the operation of any provision of sections 307(e), 309, 310, and 323(d) and (e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref> of this title with respect to the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112.</num>
<heading> Drug interdiction and counter-drug activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may provide funds to the Governor of a State who submits to the Secretary a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan satisfying the requirements of subsection (c). Such funds shall be used for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The pay, allowances, clothing, subsistence, gratuities, travel, and related expenses, as authorized by State law, of personnel of the National Guard of that State used, while not in Federal service, for the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The operation and maintenance of the equipment and facilities of the National Guard of that State used for the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The procurement of services and equipment, and the leasing of equipment, for the National Guard of that State used for the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities. However, the use of such funds for the procurement of equipment may not exceed $15,000 per item, unless approval for procurement of equipment in excess of that amount is granted in advance by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Personnel Performing Full-Time National Guard Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, personnel of the National Guard of a State may, in accordance with the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan referred to in subsection (c), be ordered to perform full-time National Guard duty under <ref>section 502(f) of this title</ref> for the purpose of carrying out drug interdiction and counter-drug activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A member of the National Guard serving on full-time National Guard duty under orders authorized under paragraph (1) shall participate in the training required under <ref>section 502(a) of this title</ref> in addition to the duty performed for the purpose authorized under that paragraph. The pay, allowances, and other benefits of the member while participating in the training shall be the same as those to which the member is entitled while performing duty for the purpose of carrying out drug interdiction and counter-drug activities. The member is not entitled to additional pay, allowances, or other benefits for participation in training required under <ref>section 502(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Appropriations available for the Department of Defense for drug interdiction and counter-drug activities may be used for paying costs associated with a member’s participation in training described in subparagraph (A). The appropriation shall be reimbursed in full, out of appropriations available for paying those costs, for the amounts paid. Appropriations available for paying those costs shall be available for making the reimbursements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> To ensure that the use of units and personnel of the National Guard of a State pursuant to a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan does not degrade the training and readiness of such units and personnel, the following requirements shall apply in determining the drug interdiction and counter-drug activities that units and personnel of the National Guard of a State may perform:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The performance of the activities may not adversely affect the quality of that training or otherwise interfere with the ability of a member or unit of the National Guard to perform the military functions of the member or unit.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> National Guard personnel will not degrade their military skills as a result of performing the activities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The performance of the activities will not result in a significant increase in the cost of training.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> In the case of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities performed by a unit organized to serve as a unit, the activities will support valid unit training requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A unit or member of the National Guard of a State may be used, pursuant to a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan approved by the Secretary of Defense under this section, to provide services or other assistance (other than air transportation) to an organization eligible to receive services under <ref>section 508 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan specifically recognizes the organization as being eligible to receive the services or assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of services, the performance of the services meets the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) of <ref>section 508 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the services or assistance is authorized under subsection (b) or (c) of such section or in the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plan Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specify how personnel of the National Guard of that State are to be used in drug interdiction and counter-drug activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> certify that those operations are to be conducted at a time when the personnel involved are not in Federal service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> certify that participation by National Guard personnel in those operations is service in addition to training required under <ref>section 502 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> certify that any engineer-type activities (as defined by the Secretary of Defense) under the plan will be performed only by units and members of the National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> include a certification by the Attorney General of the State (or, in the case of a State with no position of Attorney General, a civilian official of the State equivalent to a State attorney general) that the use of the National Guard of the State for the activities proposed under the plan is authorized by, and is consistent with, State law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> certify that the Governor of the State or a civilian law enforcement official of the State designated by the Governor has determined that any activities included in the plan that are carried out in conjunction with Federal law enforcement agencies serve a State law enforcement purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Examination of Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Before funds are provided to the Governor of a State under this section and before members of the National Guard of that State are ordered to full-time National Guard duty as authorized in subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense shall examine the adequacy of the plan submitted by the Governor under subsection (c). The plan as approved by the Secretary may provide for the use of personnel and equipment of the National Guard of that State to assist the Immigration and Naturalization Service in the transportation of aliens who have violated a Federal or State law prohibiting or regulating the possession, use, or distribution of a controlled substance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall carry out paragraph (1) in consultation with the Director of National Drug Control Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (2) shall not apply if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Governor of a State submits a plan under subsection (c) that is substantially the same as a plan submitted for that State for a previous fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pursuant to the plan submitted for a previous fiscal year, funds were provided to the State in accordance with subsection (a) or personnel of the National Guard of the State were ordered to perform full-time National Guard duty in accordance with subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">End Strength Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), at the end of a fiscal year there may not be more than 4000 members of the National Guard—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on full-time National Guard duty under <ref>section 502(f) of this title</ref> to perform drug interdiction or counter-drug activities pursuant to an order to duty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on duty under State authority to perform drug interdiction or counter-drug activities pursuant to an order to duty with State pay and allowances being reimbursed with funds provided under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may increase the end strength authorized under paragraph (1) by not more than 20 percent for any fiscal year if the Secretary determines that such an increase is necessary in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress an annual report regarding assistance provided and activities carried out under this section during the preceding fiscal year. The report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of members of the National Guard excluded under subsection (e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref> from the computation of end strengths.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the drug interdiction and counter-drug activities conducted under State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plans referred to in subsection (c) with funds provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An accounting of the amount of funds provided to each State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A description of the effect on military training and readiness of using units and personnel of the National Guard to perform activities under the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutory Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as a limitation on the authority of any unit of the National Guard of a State, when such unit is not in Federal service, to perform law enforcement functions authorized to be performed by the National Guard by the laws of the State concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “drug interdiction and counter-drug activities”, with respect to the National Guard of a State, means the use of National Guard personnel in drug interdiction and counter-drug law enforcement activities, including drug demand reduction activities, authorized by the law of the State and requested by the Governor of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Governor of a State” means, in the case of the District of Columbia, the Commanding General of the National Guard of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XII, § 1207(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1564</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–396, title IX, § 9099A</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title VI, § 660</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1022</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 746</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(k)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1869</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1012</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 113.</num>
<heading> Federal financial assistance for support of additional duties assigned to the Army National Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army may provide financial assistance to a State to support activities carried out by the Army National Guard of the State in the performance of duties that the Secretary has assigned, with the consent of the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, to the Army National Guard of the State. The Secretary shall determine the amount of the assistance that is appropriate for the purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), financial assistance may be provided for the performance of an activity by the Army National Guard under subsection (a) only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the activity is carried out in the performance of a responsibility of the Secretary of the Army under paragraph (6), (10), or (11) of <ref>section 7013(b) of title 10</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Army National Guard was selected to perform the activity under competitive procedures that permit all qualified public-sector and private-sector sources to submit offers and be considered for selection to perform the activity on the basis of the offers, subject to the exceptions provided in <ref>section 3204(a) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1)(B) does not apply to an activity that, on <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>, was performed for the Federal Government by employees of the Federal Government or employees of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disbursement Through National Guard Bureau</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army shall disburse any contribution under this section through the Chief of the National Guard Bureau.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds appropriated for the Army for a fiscal year are available for providing financial assistance under this section in support of activities carried out by the Army National Guard during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 386(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1712</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title III, § 375(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(j)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1843</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 114.</num>
<heading> Funeral honors functions at funerals for veterans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to such regulations and restrictions as may be prescribed by the Secretary concerned, the performance of funeral honors functions by members of the National Guard at funerals for veterans of the armed forces may be treated by the Secretary concerned as a Federal function for which appropriated funds may be used. Any such performance of funeral honors functions at such a funeral may not be considered to be a period of drill or training, but may be performed as funeral honors duty under <ref>section 115 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 517(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1733</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 567(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2031</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 578(g)(1)</ref>, (k)(3)(A), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 627</ref>, 631.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 115.</num>
<heading> Funeral honors duty performed as a Federal function</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order to Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may be ordered to funeral honors duty, with the consent of the member, to prepare for or perform funeral honors functions at the funeral of a veteran under <ref>section 1491 of title 10</ref>. However, a member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may not be ordered to perform funeral honors functions under this section without the consent of the Governor or other appropriate authority of the State concerned. Performance of funeral honors duty by such a member not on active duty or full-time National Guard duty shall be treated as inactive-duty training (including with respect to travel to and from such duty) for purposes of any provision of law other than sections 206 and 435 of title 37.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service Credit</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member ordered to funeral honors duty under this section shall be required to perform a minimum of two hours of such duty in order to receive—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> service credit under <ref>section 12732(a)(2)(E) of title 10</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> as directed by the Secretary concerned, either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the allowance under <ref>section 435 of title 37</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compensation under <ref>section 206 of title 37</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursable Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member who performs funeral honors duty under this section may be reimbursed for travel and transportation expenses incurred in conjunction with such duty as authorized under <ref>section 452 of title 37</ref> if such duty is performed at a location 50 miles or more from the member’s residence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The exercise of authority under subsection (a) is subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 578(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 627</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 575(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–138; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 562(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(f)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(e)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2629</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>