<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>TRAINING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Training generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The discipline, including training, of the Army National Guard shall conform to that of the Army. The discipline, including training, of the Air National Guard shall conform to that of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The training of the National Guard shall be conducted by the several States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, and the Virgin Islands in conformity with this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Required drills and field exercises</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, each company, battery, squadron, and detachment of the National Guard, unless excused by the Secretary concerned, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assemble for drill and instruction, including indoor target practice, at least 48 times each year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> participate in training at encampments, maneuvers, outdoor target practice, or other exercises, at least 15 days each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">However, no member of such unit who has served on active duty for one year or longer shall be required to participate in such training if the first day of such training period falls during the last one hundred and twenty days of his required membership in the National Guard.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An assembly for drill and instruction may consist of a single ordered formation of a company, battery, squadron, or detachment, or, when authorized by the Secretary concerned, a series of ordered formations of parts of those organizations. However, to have a series of formations credited as an assembly for drill and instruction, all parts of the unit must be included in the series within 90 consecutive days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The total attendance at the series of formations constituting an assembly shall be counted as the attendance at that assembly for the required period. No member may be counted more than once or receive credit for more than one required period of attendance, regardless of the number of formations that he attends during the series constituting the assembly for the required period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> No organization may receive credit for an assembly for drill or indoor target practice unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of members present equals or exceeds the minimum number prescribed by the President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the period of military duty or instruction for which a member is credited is at least one and one-half hours; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the training is of the type prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> An appropriately rated member of the National Guard who performs an aerial flight under competent orders may receive credit for attending drill for the purposes of this section, if the flight prevented him from attending a regularly scheduled drill.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau>Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Army or Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, a member of the National Guard may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> without his consent, but with the pay and allowances provided by law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with his consent, either with or without pay and allowances;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">be ordered to perform training or other duty in addition to that prescribed under subsection (a).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The training or duty ordered to be performed under paragraph (1) may include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Support of operations or missions undertaken by the member’s unit at the request of the President or Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Support of training operations and training missions assigned in whole or in part to the National Guard by the Secretary concerned, but only to the extent that such training missions and training operations—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are performed in the United States or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or possessions of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are only to instruct active duty military, foreign military (under the same authorities and restrictions applicable to active duty troops), Department of Defense contractor personnel, or Department of Defense civilian employees.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Duty without pay shall be considered for all purposes as if it were duty with pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–621, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–168, § 4</ref>, <date date="1967-12-01">Dec. 1, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 526</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–156, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="1971-11-17">Nov. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 425</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 524(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 525(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Participation in field exercises</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the President may prescribe, the Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, may provide for the participation of the National Guard in encampments, maneuvers, outdoor target practice, or other exercises for field or coast-defense instruction, independently of or in conjunction with the Army or the Air Force, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) includes authority to provide for participation of the National Guard in conjunction with the Army or the Air Force, or both, in joint exercises for instruction to prepare the National Guard for response to civil emergencies and disasters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Amounts necessary for the pay, subsistence, transportation, and other proper expenses of any part of the National Guard of a State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, or the Virgin Islands participating in an exercise under subsection (a) may be set aside from funds allocated to it from appropriations for field or coast-defense instruction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Members of the National Guard participating in an exercise under subsection (a) may, after being mustered, be paid for the period beginning with the date of leaving home and ending with the date of return, as determined in advance. If otherwise correct, such a payment passes to the credit of the disbursing officer.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 517</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> National Guard schools and small arms competitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Army or Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, members of the National Guard may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> attend schools conducted by the Army or the Air Force, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct or attend schools conducted by the National Guard; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> participate in small arms competitions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Activities authorized under subsection (a) for members of the National Guard of a State or territory, Puerto Rico, or the District of Columbia may be held inside or outside its boundaries.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–621, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Army and Air Force schools and field exercises</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under such regulations as the President may prescribe and upon the recommendation of the governor of any State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands or of the commanding general of the National Guard of the District of Columbia, the Secretary of the Army may authorize a limited number of members of its Army National Guard to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> attend any service school except the United States Military Academy, and to pursue a regular course of study at the school; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be attached to an organization of the branch of the Army corresponding to the organization of the Army National Guard to which the member belongs, for routine practical instruction at or near an Army post during field training or other outdoor exercise.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Similarly, the Secretary of the Air Force may authorize a limited number of members of the Air National Guard to—</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> attend any service school except the United States Air Force Academy, and to pursue a regular course of study at the school; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be attached to an organization of the Air Force corresponding to the organization of the Air National Guard to which the member belongs, for routine practical instruction at an air base during field training or other outdoor exercise.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Assignment and detail of members of Regular Army or Regular Air Force for instruction of National Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall assign for instruction of the National Guard such members of the Regular Army or the Regular Air Force as he considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may detail members of the Regular Army to attend an encampment, maneuver, or other exercise, for field or coast-defense instruction of the Army National Guard. Similarly, the Secretary of the Air Force may detail members of the Regular Air Force to attend exercises for field or coast-defense instruction of the Air National Guard. Members so detailed shall instruct the members of the National Guard at the exercise, as directed by the Secretary concerned, or as requested by the governor or commanding officer of the National Guard there assembled.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507.</num>
<heading> Instruction in firing; supply of ammunition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Ammunition for instruction in firing and for target practice may be furnished, in such amounts as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, to units of the National Guard encamped at a post, camp, or air base. The instruction shall be under the direction of a commissioned officer selected for that purpose by the proper military commander.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 508.</num>
<heading> Assistance for certain youth and charitable organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Provide Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Members and units of the National Guard may provide the services described in subsection (b) to an eligible organization in conjunction with training required under this chapter in any case in which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provision of such services does not adversely affect the quality of that training or otherwise interfere with the ability of a member or unit of the National Guard to perform the military functions of the member or unit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the services to be provided are not commercially available, or any commercial entity that would otherwise provide such services has approved, in writing, the provision of such services by the National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> National Guard personnel will enhance their military skills as a result of providing such services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the provision of the services will not result in a significant increase in the cost of the training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The services authorized to be provided under subsection (a) are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Ground transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Air transportation in support of Special Olympics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Administrative support services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Technical training services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Emergency medical assistance and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Communications services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Authorized Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Facilities and equipment of the National Guard, including military property of the United States issued to the National Guard and General Services Administration vehicles leased to the National Guard, and General Services Administration vehicles leased to the Department of Defense, may be used in connection with providing services to any eligible organization under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The organizations eligible to receive services under this section are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Boy Scouts of America.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Girl Scouts of America.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Boys Clubs of America.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Girls Clubs of America.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Young Men’s Christian Association.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Young Women’s Christian Association.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Civil Air Patrol.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The United States Olympic Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Special Olympics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Campfire Boys.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The Campfire Girls.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The 4–H Club.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The Police Athletic League.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Any other youth or charitable organization designated by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 385(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509.</num>
<heading> National Guard Youth Challenge Program of opportunities for civilian youth</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Authority and Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may use the National Guard to conduct a civilian youth opportunities program, to be known as the “National Guard Youth Challenge Program”, which shall consist of at least a 22-week residential program and a 12-month post-residential mentoring period. The Program shall seek to improve life skills and employment potential of participants by providing military-based training and supervised work experience, together with the core program components of assisting participants to receive a high school diploma or its equivalent, leadership development, promoting fellowship and community service, developing life coping skills and job skills, and improving physical fitness and health and hygiene.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conduct of the Program</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall provide for the conduct of the Program in such States as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall carry out the Program using—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> funds appropriated directly to the Secretary of Defense for the Program, except that the amount of funds appropriated directly to the Secretary and expended for the Program in fiscal year 2001 or 2002 may not exceed $62,500,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> nondefense funds made available or transferred to the Secretary of Defense by other Federal agencies to support the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Federal funds made available or transferred to the Secretary of Defense under paragraph (2)(B) by other Federal agencies to support the Program may be expended for the Program in excess of the fiscal year limitation specified in paragraph (2)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall remain the executive agent to carry out the Program regardless of the source of funds for the Program or any transfer of jurisdiction over the Program within the executive branch. As provided in subsection (a), the Secretary may use the National Guard to conduct the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To carry out the Program in a State, the Secretary of Defense shall enter into an agreement with the Governor of the State or, in the case of the District of Columbia, with the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard, under which the Governor or the commanding general will establish, organize, and administer the Program in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The agreement may provide for the Secretary to provide funds to the State for civilian personnel costs attributable to the use of civilian employees of the National Guard in the conduct of the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matching Funds Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The amount of assistance provided by the Secretary of Defense to a State program of the Program for a fiscal year under this section may not exceed 75 percent of the costs of operating the State program during that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The limitation in paragraph (1) may not be construed as a limitation on the amount of assistance that may be provided to a State program of the Program for a fiscal year from sources other than the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Persons Eligible To Participate in Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A school dropout from secondary school shall be eligible to participate in the Program. The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the standards and procedures for selecting participants from among school dropouts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Benefits for Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent provided in an agreement entered into in accordance with subsection (c) and subject to the approval of the Secretary of Defense, a person selected for training in the Program may receive the following benefits in connection with that training:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Allowances for travel expenses, personal expenses, and other expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Quarters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Subsistence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Clothing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Recreational services and supplies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Other services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), a temporary stipend upon the successful completion of the training, as characterized in accordance with procedures provided in the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a person selected for training in the Program who afterwards becomes a member of the Civilian Community Corps under subtitle E of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12611</ref> et seq.), the person may not receive a temporary stipend under paragraph (1)(I) while the person is a member of that Corps. The person may receive the temporary stipend after completing service in the Corps unless the person elects to receive benefits provided under subsection (f) or (g) of section 158 of such Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12618</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Personnel of the National Guard of a State in which the Program is conducted may serve on full-time National Guard duty for the purpose of providing command, administrative, training, or supporting services for the Program. For the performance of those services, any such personnel may be ordered to duty under <ref>section 502(f) of this title</ref> for not longer than the period of the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A Governor participating in the Program and the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard (if the District of Columbia National Guard is participating in the Program) may procure by contract the temporary full time services of such civilian personnel as may be necessary to augment National Guard personnel in carrying out the Program in that State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Civilian employees of the National Guard performing services for the Program and contractor personnel performing such services may be required, when appropriate to achieve the purposes of the Program, to be members of the National Guard and to wear the military uniform.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equipment and Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Equipment and facilities of the National Guard, including military property of the United States issued to the National Guard, may be used in carrying out the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Equipment and facilities of the Department of Defense may be used by the National Guard for purposes of carrying out the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Activities under the Program shall be considered noncombat activities of the National Guard for purposes of <ref>section 710 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status of Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A person receiving training under the Program shall be considered an employee of the United States for the purposes of the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5 (relating to compensation of Federal employees for work injuries).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Section 1346(b) and chapter 171 of title 28 and any other provision of law relating to the liability of the United States for tortious conduct of employees of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the application of the provisions of law referred to in paragraph (1)(A) to a person referred to in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the person shall not be considered to be in the performance of duty while the person is not at the assigned location of training or other activity or duty authorized in accordance with a Program agreement referred to in subsection (c), except when the person is traveling to or from that location or is on pass from that training or other activity or duty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the person’s monthly rate of pay shall be deemed to be the minimum rate of pay provided for grade GS–2 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the entitlement of a person to receive compensation for a disability shall begin on the day following the date on which the person’s participation in the Program is terminated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A person referred to in paragraph (1) may not be considered an employee of the United States for any purpose other than a purpose set forth in that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supplemental Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out the Program in a State, the Governor of the State or, in the case of the District of Columbia, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard may supplement funds made available under the Program out of other resources (including gifts) available to the Governor or the commanding general. The Governor or the commanding general may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of money, other property, or services for the Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the design, conduct, and effectiveness of the Program during the preceding fiscal year. In preparing the report, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Governor of each State in which the Program is carried out and, if the Program is carried out in the District of Columbia, with the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the territories, and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “school dropout” means an individual who is no longer attending any school and who has not received a secondary school diploma or a certificate from a program of equivalency for such a diploma.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Program” means the National Guard Youth Challenge Program carried out pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out the Program. The regulations shall address at a minimum the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms to be included in the Program agreements required by subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The qualifications for persons to participate in the Program, as required by subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The benefits authorized for Program participants, as required by subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The status of National Guard personnel assigned to duty in support of the Program under subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The conditions for the use of National Guard facilities and equipment to carry out the Program, as required by subsection (h).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The status of Program participants, as described in subsection (i).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The procedures to be used by the Secretary when communicating with States about the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1911</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 579</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–246, div. B, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="2000-07-13">July 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 577(a)–(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–140; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 596(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2651</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 594(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1935</ref>, 1936; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 594(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 593(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 519</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 510.</num>
<heading> Authorization for FireGuard Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may use members of the National Guard to carry out a program to aggregate, analyze, and assess multi-source remote sensing information for interagency partnerships in the detection and monitoring of wildfires, and to support any emergency response to such wildfires. Such a program shall be known as the “FireGuard Program”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts and Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with a qualified individual or entity for the performance of duties to supplement members of the National Guard in carrying out the FireGuard Program under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In association with a contract or cooperative agreement entered into under paragraph (1) with a qualified individual or entity, the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, in coordination with relevant State, local, and commercial entities, shall execute a memorandum of understanding with the qualified individual or entity, which shall clearly delineate the roles, responsibilities, functions, timelines, and end dates for the transition of the duties to be performed under the contract or cooperative agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “qualified individual or entity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any individual who possesses a requisite security clearance for handling classified remote sensing data for the purpose of wildfire detection and monitoring; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any corporation, firm, partnership, company, nonprofit, Federal agency or sub-agency, or State or local government, with contractors or employees who possess a requisite security clearance for handling such data.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 515(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 248</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title III, § 352(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>