<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 19B—</num>
<heading>WATER RESOURCES PLANNING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1962.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to meet the rapidly expanding demands for water throughout the Nation, it is hereby declared to be the policy of the Congress to encourage the conservation, development, and utilization of water and related land resources of the United States on a comprehensive and coordinated basis by the Federal Government, States, localities, and private enterprise with the cooperation of all affected Federal agencies, States, local governments, individuals, corporations, business enterprises, and others concerned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, § 2</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962–1.</num>
<heading> Effect on existing laws</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> to expand or diminish either Federal or State jurisdiction, responsibility, or rights in the field of water resources planning, development, or control; nor to displace, supersede, limit or modify any interstate compact or the jurisdiction or responsibility of any legally established joint or common agency of two or more States, or of two or more States and the Federal Government; nor to limit the authority of Congress to authorize and fund proj­ects;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> to change or otherwise affect the authority or responsibility of any Federal official in the discharge of the duties of his office except as required to carry out the provisions of this chapter with respect to the preparation and review of comprehensive regional or river basin plans and the formulation and evaluation of Federal water and related land resources projects;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> as superseding, modifying, or repealing existing laws applicable to the various Federal agencies which are authorized to develop or participate in the development of water and related land resources or to exercise licensing or regulatory functions in relation thereto, except as required to carry out the provisions of this chapter; nor to affect the jurisdiction, powers, or prerogatives of the International Joint Commission, United States and Canada, the Permanent Engineering Board and the United States Operating Entity or Entities established pursuant to the Columbia River Basin Treaty, signed at Washington, <date date="1961-01-17">January 17, 1961</date>, or the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> as authorizing any entity established or acting under the provisions hereof to study, plan, or recommend the transfer of waters between areas under the jurisdiction of more than one river basin commission or entity performing the function of a river basin commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962–2.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of objectives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the intent of Congress that the objectives of enhancing regional economic development, the quality of the total environment, including its protection and improvement, the well-being of the people of the United States, and the national economic development are the objectives to be included in federally financed water resource projects (including shore protection projects such as projects for beach nourishment, including the replacement of sand), and in the evaluation of benefits and cost attributable thereto, giving due consideration to the most feasible alternative means of accomplishing these objectives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–611, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 227(f)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962–3.</num>
<heading> Water resources principles and guidelines</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National water resources planning policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States that all water resources projects should reflect national priorities, encourage economic development, and protect the environment by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> seeking to maximize sustainable economic development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> seeking to avoid the unwise use of floodplains and flood-prone areas and minimizing adverse impacts and vulnerabilities in any case in which a floodplain or flood-prone area must be used; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> protecting and restoring the functions of natural systems and mitigating any unavoidable damage to natural systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principles and guidelines</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principles and guidelines defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “principles and guidelines” means the principles and guidelines contained in the document prepared by the Water Resources Council pursuant to <ref>section 1962a–2 of this title</ref>, entitled “Economic and Environmental Principles and Guidelines for Water and Related Land Resources Implementation Studies”, and dated <date date="1983-03-10">March 10, 1983</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, the Secretary shall issue revisions, consistent with paragraph (3), to the principles and guidelines for use by the Secretary in the formulation, evaluation, and implementation of water resources projects.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In developing revisions to the principles and guidelines under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall evaluate the consistency of the principles and guidelines with, and ensure that the principles and guidelines address, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The use of best available economic principles and analytical techniques, including techniques in risk and uncertainty analysis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The assessment and incorporation of public safety in the formulation of alternatives and recommended plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Assessment methods that reflect the value of projects for low-income communities and projects that use nonstructural approaches to water resources development and management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The assessment and evaluation of the interaction of a project with other water resources projects and programs within a region or watershed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The use of contemporary water resources paradigms, including integrated water resources management and adaptive management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Evaluation methods that ensure that water resources projects are justified by public benefits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and public participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the National Academy of Sciences, and the Council on Environmental Quality; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> solicit and consider public and expert comments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives copies of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the revisions to the principles and guidelines for use by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an explanation of the intent of each revision, how each revision is consistent with this section, and the probable impact of each revision on water resources projects carried out by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make the revisions to the principles and guidelines for use by the Secretary available to the public, including on the Internet.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the requirements of this subsection, the principles and guidelines as revised under this subsection shall apply to water resources projects carried out by the Secretary instead of the principles and guidelines for such projects in effect on the day before <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After the date of issuance of the revisions to the principles and guidelines, the revisions shall apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to all water resources projects carried out by the Secretary, other than projects for which the Secretary has commenced a feasibility study before the date of such issuance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at the request of a non-Federal interest, to a water resources project for which the Secretary has commenced a feasibility study before the date of such issuance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to the reevaluation or modification of a water resources project, other than a reevaluation or modification that has been commenced by the Secretary before the date of such issuance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Revisions to the principles and guidelines issued under paragraph (2) shall not affect the validity of any completed study of a water resources project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon completion of the revisions to the principles and guidelines for use by the Secretary, the Secretary shall make a recommendation to Congress as to the advisability of repealing subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 1962d–17 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2031</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962–4.</num>
<heading> Implementation of water resources principles and requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Secretary shall issue final agency-specific procedures necessary to implement the principles and requirements and the interagency guidelines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of future water resources development projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The procedures required by subsection (a) shall ensure that the Secretary, in the formulation of future water resources development projects—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> develops such projects in accordance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the guiding principles established by the principles and requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the national water resources planning policy established by <ref>section 1962–3(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fully identifies and analyzes national economic development benefits, regional economic development benefits, environmental quality benefits, and other societal effects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and update</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every 5 years, the Secretary shall review and, where appropriate, revise the procedures required by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public review, notice, and comment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In issuing, reviewing, and revising the procedures required by this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide notice to interested non-Federal stakeholders of the Secretary’s intent to revise the procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide opportunities for interested non-Federal stakeholders to engage with, and provide input and recommendations to, the Secretary on the revision of the procedures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> solicit and consider public and expert comments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “interagency guidelines” means the interagency guidelines contained in the document finalized by the Council on Environmental Quality pursuant to <ref>section 1962–3 of this title</ref> in December 2014, to implement the principles and requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principles and requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “principles and requirements” means the principles and requirements contained in the document prepared by the Council on Environmental Quality pursuant to <ref>section 1962–3 of this title</ref>, entitled “Principles and Requirements for Federal Investments in Water Resources”, and dated March 2013.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>WATER RESOURCES COUNCIL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1962a.</num>
<heading> Establishment; composition; other Federal agency participation; designation of Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established a Water Resources Council (hereinafter referred to as the “Council”) which shall be composed of the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Secretary of Energy. The Chairman of the Council shall request the heads of other Federal agencies to participate with the Council when matters affecting their responsibilities are considered by the Council. The Chairman of the Council shall be designated by the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–112, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-16">Oct. 16, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 578</ref>, 606, 607.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962a–1.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> maintain a continuing study and prepare an assessment biennially, or at such less frequent intervals as the Council may determine, of the adequacy of supplies of water necessary to meet the water requirements in each water resource region in the United States and the national interest therein; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> maintain a continuing study of the relation of regional or river basin plans and programs to the requirements of larger regions of the Nation and of the adequacy of administrative and statutory means for the coordination of the water and related land resources policies and programs of the several Federal agencies; it shall appraise the adequacy of existing and proposed policies and programs to meet such requirements; and it shall make recommendations to the President with respect to Federal policies and programs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962a–2.</num>
<heading> Principles, standards, and procedures for Federal projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment, consultation, revision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall establish, after such consultation with other interested entities, both Federal and non-Federal, as the Council may find appropriate, and with the approval of the President, principles, standards, and procedures for Federal participants in the preparation of comprehensive regional or river basin plans and for the formulation and evaluation of Federal water and related land resources projects. Such procedures may include provision for Council revision of plans for Federal projects intended to be proposed in any plan or revision thereof being prepared by a river basin planning commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic evaluation; primary criterion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall develop standards and criteria for economic evaluation of water resource projects. For the purpose of those standards and criteria, the primary direct navigation benefits of a water resource project are defined as the product of the savings to shippers using the waterway and the estimated traffic that would use the waterway. “Savings to shippers” means the difference between (1) the freight rates or charges prevailing at the time of the study for the movement by the alternative means, and (2) those which would be charged on the proposed waterway. Estimated traffic that would use the waterway will be based on those freight rates, taking into account projections of the economic growth of the area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–449, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962a–3.</num>
<heading> Review of river basin commission plans; report to President and Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon receipt of a plan or revision thereof from any river basin commission under the provisions of <ref>section 1962b–3(3) of this title</ref>, the Council shall review the plan or revision with special regard to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the efficacy of such plan or revision in achieving optimum use of the water and related land resources in the area involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the effect of the plan on the achievement of other programs for the development of agricultural, urban, energy, industrial, recreational, fish and wildlife, and other resources of the entire Nation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the contributions which such plan or revision will make in obtaining the Nation’s economic and social goals.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Based on such review the Council shall—</continuation>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> formulate such recommendations as it deems desirable in the national interest; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> transmit its recommendations, together with the plan or revision of the river basin commission and the views, comments, and recommendations with respect to such plan or revision submitted by any Federal agency, Governor, interstate commission, or United States section of an international commission, to the President for his review and transmittal to the Congress with his recommendations in regard to authorization of Federal projects.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962a–4.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings, proceedings, evidence, reports; office space; use of mails; personnel; consultants; motor vehicles; necessary expenses; other powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Council may: (1) hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, receive such evidence, and print or otherwise reproduce and distribute so much of its proceedings and reports thereon as it may deem advisable; (2) acquire, furnish, and equip such office space as is necessary; (3) use the United States mails in the same manner and upon the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States; (4) employ and fix the compensation of such personnel as it deems advisable, in accordance with the civil service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; (5) procure services as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, at rates not in excess of the daily equivalent of the rate prescribed for grade GS–18 under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> in the case of individual experts or consultants; (6) purchase, hire, operate, and maintain passenger motor vehicles; and (7) incur such necessary expenses and exercise such other powers as are consistent with and reasonably required to perform its functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oaths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any member of the Council is authorized to administer oaths when it is determined by a majority of the Council that testimony shall be taken or evidence received under oath.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records; public inspection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent permitted by law, all appropriate records and papers of the Council may be made available for public inspection during ordinary office hours.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information and personnel from other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request of the Council, the head of any Federal department or agency is authorized (1) to furnish to the Council such information as may be necessary for carrying out its functions and as may be available to or procurable by such department or agency, and (2) to detail to temporary duty with such Council on a reimbursable basis such personnel within his administrative jurisdiction as it may need or believe to be useful for carrying out its functions, each such detail to be without loss of seniority, pay, or other employee status.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility for personnel and funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall be responsible for (1) the appointment and supervision of personnel, (2) the assignment of duties and responsibilities among such personnel, and (3) the use and expenditures of funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–112, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-16">Oct. 16, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>RIVER BASIN COMMISSIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1962b.</num>
<heading> Creation of commissions; powers and duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President is authorized to declare the establishment of a river basin water and related land resources commission upon request therefor by the Council, or request addressed to the Council by a State within which all or part of the basin or basins concerned are located if the request by the Council or by a State (1) defines the area, river basin, or group of related river basins for which a commission is requested, (2) is made in writing by the Governor or in such manner as State law may provide, or by the Council, and (3) is concurred in by the Council and by not less than one-half of the States within which portions of the basin or basins concerned are located and, in the event the Upper Colorado River Basin is involved, by at least three of the four States of Colorado, New Mexico, Utah, and Wyoming or, in the event the Columbia River Basin is involved, by at least three of the four States of Idaho, Montana, Oregon, and Washington. Such concurrences shall be in writing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each such commission for an area, river basin, or group of river basins shall, to the extent consistent with <ref>section 1962–1 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the principal agency for the coordination of Federal, State, interstate, local and nongovernmental plans for the development of water and related land resources in its area, river basin, or group of river basins;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare and keep up to date, to the extent practicable, a comprehensive, coordinated, joint plan for Federal, State, interstate, local and nongovernmental development of water and related resources: <i>Provided</i>, That the plan shall include an evaluation of all reasonable alternative means of achieving optimum development of water and related land resources of the basin or basins, and it may be prepared in stages, including recommendations with respect to individual projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recommend long-range schedules of priorities for the collection and analysis of basic data and for investigation, planning, and construction of projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> foster and undertake such studies of water and related land resources problems in its area, river basin, or group of river basins as are necessary in the preparation of the plan described in clause (2) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962b–1.</num>
<heading> Membership of commissions; appointment of chairman</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each river basin commission shall be composed of members appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A chairman appointed by the President who shall also serve as chairman and coordinating officer of the Federal members of the commission and who shall represent the Federal Government in Federal-State relations on the commission and who shall not, during the period of his service on the commission, hold any other position as an officer or employee of the United States, except as a retired officer or retired civilian employee of the Federal Government;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> One member from each Federal department or independent agency determined by the President to have a substantial interest in the work to be undertaken by the commission, such member to be appointed by the head of such department or independent agency and to serve as the representative of such department or independent agency;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> One member from each State which lies wholly or partially within the area, river basin, or group of river basins for which the commission is established, and the appointment of each such member shall be made in accordance with the laws of the State which he represents. In the absence of governing provisions of State law, such State members shall be appointed and serve at the pleasure of the Governor;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> One member appointed by any interstate agency created by an interstate compact to which the consent of Congress has been given, and whose jurisdiction extends to the waters of the area, river basin, or group of river basins for which the river basin commission is created;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> When deemed appropriate by the President, one member, who shall be appointed by the President, from the United States section of any international commission created by a treaty to which the consent of the Senate has been given, and whose jurisdiction extends to the waters of the area, river basin, or group of river basins for which the river basin commission is established.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962b–2.</num>
<heading> Organization of commissions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of functions; transfer of property, assets, and records upon termination of commission; availability of studies, data, and other materials to participants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each river basin commission shall organize for the performance of its functions within ninety days after the President shall have declared the establishment of such commission, subject to the availability of funds for carrying on its work. A commission shall terminate upon decision of the Council or agreement of a majority of the States composing the commission. Upon such termination, all property, assets, and records of the commission shall thereafter be turned over to such agencies of the United States and the participating States as shall be appropriate in the circumstances: <i>Provided</i>, That studies, data, and other materials useful in water and related land resources planning to any of the participants shall be kept freely available to all such participants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vice chairman; State election; State representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">State members of each commission shall elect a vice chairman, who shall serve also as chairman and coordinating officer of the State members of the commission and who shall represent the State governments in Federal-State relations on the commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies; alternates for chairman and vice chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Vacancies in a commission shall not affect its powers but shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointments were made: <i>Provided</i>, That the chairman and vice chairman may designate alternates to act for them during temporary absences.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consensus of members on issues; opportunities for individual views; record of position of chairman and vice chairman; final authority on procedural questions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the work of the commission every reasonable endeavor shall be made to arrive at a consensus of all members on all issues; but failing this, full opportunity shall be afforded each member for the presentation and report of individual views: <i>Provided</i>, That at any time the commission fails to act by reason of absence of consensus, the position of the chairman, acting in behalf of the Federal members, and the vice chairman, acting upon instructions of the State members, shall be set forth in the record: <i>Provided further</i>, That the chairman, in consultation with the vice chairman, shall have the final authority, in the absence of an applicable by-law adopted by the commission or in the absence of a consensus, to fix the times and places for meetings, to set deadlines for the submission of annual and other reports, to establish subcommittees, and to decide such other procedural questions as may be necessary for the commission to perform its functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962b–3.</num>
<heading> Duties of commissions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each river basin commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> engage in such activities and make such studies and investigations as are necessary and desirable in carrying out the policy set forth in <ref>section 1962 of this title</ref> and in accomplishing the purposes set forth in <ref>section 1962b(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to the Council and the Governor of each participating State a report on its work at least once each year. Such report shall be transmitted through the President to the Congress. After such transmission, copies of any such report shall be sent to the heads of such Federal, State, interstate, and international agencies as the President or the Governors of the participating States may direct;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> submit to the Council for transmission to the President and by him to the Congress, and the Governors and the legislatures of the participating States a comprehensive, coordinated, joint plan, or any major portion thereof or necessary revisions thereof, for water and related land resources development in the area, river basin, or group of river basins for which such commission was established. Before the commission submits such a plan or major portion thereof or revision thereof to the Council, it shall transmit the proposed plan or revision to the head of each Federal department or agency, the Governor of each State, and each interstate agency, from which a member of the commission has been appointed, and to the head of the United States section of any international commission if the plan, portion or revision deals with a boundary water or a river crossing a boundary, or any tributary flowing into such boundary water or river, over which the international commission has jurisdiction or for which it has responsibility. Each such department and agency head, Governor, interstate agency, and United States section of an international commission shall have ninety days from the date of the receipt of the proposed plan, portion, or revision to report its views, comments, and recommendations to the commission. The commission may modify the plan, portion, or revision after considering the reports so submitted. The views, comments, and recommendations submitted by each Federal department or agency head, Governor, interstate agency, and United States section of an international commission shall be transmitted to the Council with the plan, portion, or revision; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> submit to the Council at the time of submitting such plan, any recommendations it may have for continuing the functions of the commission and for implementing the plan, including means of keeping the plan up to date.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962b–4.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings, proceedings, evidence, reports; office space; use of mails; personnel, consultants, and professional service contracts; personnel from other agencies; retirement and employee benefit system for personnel without coverage; motor vehicles; necessary expenses; other powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, each river basin commission may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, receive such evidence, and print or otherwise reproduce and distribute so much of its proceedings and reports thereon as it may deem advisable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acquire, furnish, and equip such office space as is necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use the United States mails in the same manner and upon the same conditions as departments and agencies of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> employ and compensate such personnel as it deems advisable, including consultants, at rates not in excess of the daily equivalent of the rate prescribed for grade GS–18 under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>, and retain and compensate such professional or technical service firms as it deems advisable on a contract basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> arrange for the services of personnel from any State or the United States, or any subdivision or agency thereof, or any intergovernmental agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> make arrangements, including contracts, with any participating government, except the United States or the District of Columbia, for inclusion in a suitable retirement and employee benefit system of such of its personnel as may not be eligible for or continuing in another governmental retirement or employee benefit system, or otherwise provide for such coverage of its personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> purchase, hire, operate, and maintain passenger motor vehicles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> incur such necessary expenses and exercise such other powers as are consistent with and reasonably required to perform its functions under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oaths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chairman of a river basin commission, or any member of such commission designated by the chairman thereof for the purpose, is authorized to administer oaths when it is determined by a majority of the commission that testimony shall be taken or evidence received under oath.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records; public inspection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent permitted by law, all appropriate records and papers of each river basin commission shall be made available for public inspection during ordinary office hours.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information and personnel from other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request of the chairman of any river basin commission, or any member or employee of such commission designated by the chairman thereof for the purpose, the head of any Federal department or agency is authorized (1) to furnish to such commission such information as may be necessary for carrying out its functions and as may be available to or procurable by such department or agency, and (2) to detail to temporary duty with such commission on a reimbursable basis such personnel within his administrative jurisdiction as it may need or believe to be useful for carrying out its functions, each such detail to be without loss of seniority, pay, or other employee status.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility for personnel and funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chairman of each river basin commission shall, with the concurrence of the vice chairman, appoint the personnel employed by such commission, and the chairman shall, in accordance with the general policies of such commission with respect to the work to be accomplished by it and the timing thereof, be responsible for (1) the supervision of personnel employed by such commission, (2) the assignment of duties and responsibilities among such personnel, and (3) the use and expenditure of funds available to such commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 249</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–112, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-16">Oct. 16, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962b–5.</num>
<heading> Compensation of members and chairmen</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional compensation prohibited to members appointed from Federal departments, agencies, and international commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any member of a river basin commission appointed pursuant to section 1962b–1(b) and (e) of this title shall receive no additional compensation by virtue of his membership on the commission, but shall continue to receive, from appropriations made for the agency from which he is appointed, the salary of his regular position when engaged in the performance of the duties vested in the commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of members from States and interstate agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of a commission, appointed pursuant to section 1962b–1(c) and (d) of this title, shall each receive such compensation as may be provided by the States or the interstate agency respectively, which they represent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The per annum compensation of the chairman of each river basin commission shall be determined by the President, but when employed on a full-time annual basis shall not exceed the maximum scheduled rate for grade GS–18 or when engaged in the performance of the commission’s duties on an intermittent basis such compensation shall be not more than $100 per day and shall not exceed $12,000 in any year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962b–6.</num>
<heading> Expenses of commissions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share; apportionment of remainder; annual budget; estimates of proposed Federal appropriations; advances against delayed State appropriations; credit to account in the Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each commission shall recommend what share of its expenses shall be borne by the Federal Government, but such share shall be subject to approval by the Council. The remainder of the commission’s expenses shall be otherwise apportioned as the commission may determine. Each commission shall prepare a budget annually and transmit it to the Council and the States. Estimates of proposed appropriations from the Federal Government shall be included in the budget estimates submitted by the Council under chapter 11 of title 31, and may include an amount for advance to a commission against State appropriations for which delay is anticipated by reason of later legislative sessions. All sums appropriated to or otherwise received by a commission shall be credited to the commission’s account in the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance, reception, utilization, and disposal of appropriations, donations, and grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A commission may accept for any of its purposes and functions appropriations, donations, and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services from any State or the United States or any subdivision or agency thereof, or intergovernmental agency, and may receive, utilize, and dispose of the same.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounts of receipts and disbursements; annual audit; inclusion in annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and disbursements. The accounts shall be audited at least annually in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified or licensed public accountants, certified or licensed by a regulatory authority of a State, and the report of the audit shall be included in and become a part of the annual report of the commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspection of accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The accounts of the commission shall be open at all reasonable times for inspection by representatives of the jurisdictions and agencies which make appropriations, donations, or grants to the commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE TO STATES FOR COMPREHENSIVE PLANNING GRANT AUTHORIZATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1962c.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations; coordination of related Federal planning assistance programs; utilization of Federal agencies administering programs contributing to water resources planning</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In recognition of the need for increased participation by the States in water and related land resources planning to be effective, there are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Council, $3,000,000 for fiscal year 1979 for grants to States to assist them in developing and participating in the development of comprehensive water and related land resources plans.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Council, with the approval of the President, shall prescribe such rules, establish such procedures, and make such arrangements and provisions relating to the performance of its functions under this subchapter, and the use of funds available therefor, as may be necessary in order to assure (1) coordination of the program authorized by this subchapter with related Federal planning assistance programs, including the program authorized under section 701 of the Housing Act of 1954 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003225">1</ref> and (2) appropriate utilization of other Federal agencies administering programs which may contribute to achieving the purpose of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–112, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-16">Oct. 16, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–404, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962c–1.</num>
<heading> Allotments to States: basis, population and land area determinations; payments to States: amount</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> From the sums appropriated pursuant to <ref>section 1962c of this title</ref> for any fiscal year the Council shall from time to time make allotments to the States, in accordance with its regulations, on the basis of (1) the population, (2) the land area, (3) the need for comprehensive water and related land resources planning programs, and (4) the financial need of the respective States. For the purposes of this section the population of the States shall be determined on the basis of the latest estimates available from the Department of Commerce and the land area of the States shall be determined on the basis of the official records of the United States Geological Survey.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> From each State’s allotment under this section for any fiscal year the Council shall pay to such State an amount which is not more than 50 per centum of the cost of carrying out its State program approved under <ref>section 1962c–2 of this title</ref>, including the cost of training personnel for carrying out such program and the cost of administering such program.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 251</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962c–2.</num>
<heading> State programs; approval by Council; submission; requirements; notice and hearing prior to disapproval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall approve any program for comprehensive water and related land resources planning which is submitted by a State, if such program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides for comprehensive planning with respect to intrastate or interstate water resources, or both, in such State to meet the needs for water and water-related activities taking into account prospective demands for all purposes served through or affected by water and related land resources development, with adequate provision for coordination with all Federal, State, and local agencies, and nongovernmental entities having responsibilities in affected fields;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides, where comprehensive statewide development planning is being carried on with or without assistance under section 701 of the Housing Act of 1954 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003226">1</ref> or under chapter 2003 of title 54, for full coordination between comprehensive water resources planning and other statewide planning programs and for assurances that such water resources planning will be in conformity with the general development policy in such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> designates a State agency (hereinafter referred to as the “State agency”) to administer the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provides that the State agency will make such reports in such form and containing such information as the Council from time to time reasonably requires to carry out its functions under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> sets forth the procedure to be followed in carrying out the State program and in administering such program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provides such accounting, budgeting, and other fiscal methods and procedures as are necessary for keeping appropriate accountability of the funds and for the proper and efficient administration of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Council shall not disapprove any program without first giving reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the State agency administering such program.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962c–3.</num>
<heading> Noncompliance; curtailing of payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the Council after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to a State agency finds that—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> the program submitted by such State and approved under <ref>section 1962c–2 of this title</ref> has been so changed that it no longer complies with a requirement of such section; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> in the administration of the program there is a failure to comply substantially with such a requirement,</content>
</subsection>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Council shall notify such agency that no further payments will be made to the State under this subchapter until it is satisfied that there will no longer be any such failure. Until the Council is so satisfied, it shall make no further payments to such State under this subchapter.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962c–4.</num>
<heading> Payments to States; computation of amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The method of computing and paying amounts pursuant to this subchapter shall be as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Council shall, prior to the beginning of each calendar quarter or other period prescribed by it, estimate the amount to be paid to each State under the provisions of this subchapter for such period, such estimate to be based on such records of the State and information furnished by it, and such other investigation, as the Council may find necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Council shall pay to the State, from the allotment available therefor, the amount so estimated by it for any period, reduced or increased, as the case may be, by any sum (not previously adjusted under this paragraph) by which it finds that its estimate of the amount to be paid such State for any prior period under this subchapter was greater or less than the amount which should have been paid to such State for such prior period under this subchapter. Such payments shall be made through the disbursing facilities of the Treasury Department, at such times and in such installments as the Council may determine.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962c–5.</num>
<heading> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter the term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands or Guam.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–285, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-05-12">May 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962c–6.</num>
<heading> Records; audit and examination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each recipient of a grant under this chapter shall keep such records as the Chairman of the Council shall prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition of the funds received under the grant, and the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which the grant was made and the amount and nature of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Council and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient of the grant that are pertinent to the determination that funds granted are used in accordance with this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations to the Water Resources Council</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Water Resources Council:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation for single river basin commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The sum of $2,886,000 for fiscal year 1979 for the Federal share of the expenses of administration and operation of river basin commissions, including salaries and expenses of the chairmen, but not including funds authorized by subsection (c) below: <i>Provided</i>, That not more than $750,000 annually shall be available under this subsection for any single river basin commission;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on the expenses of the Water Resources Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003227">1</ref> sum of $2,668,000 for fiscal year 1979 for the expenses of the Water Resources Council in administering this chapter, not including funds authorized by subsection (c) below;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on availability of funds for preparation of certain studies and for assessments and plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The sum of $3,179,900 for fiscal year 1979 for preparation of assessments, and for directing and coordinating the preparation of such river basin plans as the Council determines are necessary and desirable in carrying out the policy of this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That $828,900 shall be available under this subsection for preparation of the Columbia River Estuary Special Study: <i>Provided further</i>, That $308,000 shall be available under this subsection for preparation of the New England Port and Harbor Study and $135,000 shall be available for completion of the Hudson River Basin Level B Study: <i>Provided further</i>, That $150,000 shall be available under this subsection for completion of Case Studies of the Application of Cost Sharing Policy Options for Flood Plain Management in the Connecticut River Basin: <i>Provided further</i>, That not more than $2,500,000 shall be available under this subsection for the preparation of assessments: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Council may transfer funds authorized by this subsection to river basin commissions and to Federal and State agencies upon such terms and conditions as it determines are necessary and desirable to carry out the above functions in an economical, efficient, and timely manner, and that such commissions and agencies are hereby authorized to receive and expend such funds pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–547</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–27</ref>, <date date="1971-06-17">June 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–396</ref>, <date date="1972-08-20">Aug. 20, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–55</ref>, <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–112, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-16">Oct. 16, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–285, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-05-12">May 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–41, § 1</ref>, <date date="1977-06-06">June 6, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–404, § 1(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–1.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council is authorized to make such rules and regulations as it may deem necessary or appropriate for carrying out those provisions of this chapter which are administered by it.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–2.</num>
<heading> Delegation of functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council is authorized to delegate to any member or employee of the Council its administrative functions under <ref>section 1962a–4 of this title</ref> and the detailed administration of the grant program under subchapter III.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–3.</num>
<heading> Utilization of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council may, with the consent of the head of any other department or agency of the United States, utilize such officers and employees of such agency on a reimbursable basis as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–80, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–4.</num>
<heading> Northeastern United States water supply</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plans for Federal construction, operation, and maintenance of reservoir system within certain river basins and conveyance and purification facilities through cooperation of Secretary of the Army and government agencies; financial participation of States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress hereby recognizes that assuring adequate supplies of water for the great metropolitan centers of the United States has become a problem of such magnitude that the welfare and prosperity of this country require the Federal Government to assist in the solution of water supply problems. Therefore, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to cooperate with Federal, State, and local agencies in preparing plans in accordance with the Water Resources Planning Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1962</ref> et seq.] to meet the long-range water needs of the northeastern United States. This plan may provide for the construction, operation, and maintenance by the United States of (1) a system of major reservoirs to be located within those river basins of the northeastern United States which drain into the Chesapeake Bay, those that drain into the Atlantic Ocean north of the Chesapeake Bay, those that drain into Lake Ontario, and those that drain into the Saint Lawrence River, (2) major conveyance facilities by which water may be exchanged between these river basins to the extent found desirable in the national interest, and (3) major purification facilities. Such plans shall provide for appropriate financial participation by the States, political subdivisions thereof, and other local interests.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction, operation, and maintenance of reservoirs and conveyance and purification facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall construct, operate, and maintain those reservoirs, conveyance facilities, and purification facilities, which are recommended in the plan prepared in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, and which are specifically authorized by law enacted after <date date="1965-10-27">October 27, 1965</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservoirs as components of river basin and water supply plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each reservoir included in the plan authorized by this section shall be considered as a component of a comprehensive plan for the optimum development of the river basin in which it is situated, as well as a component of the plan established in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–298, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1965-10-27">Oct. 27, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5.</num>
<heading> Water resources development projects involving navigation, flood control, and shore protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction, operation, and maintenance; limitation on estimated Federal first cost of construction; Congressional committee approval of projects; reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain any water resource development project, including single and multiple purpose projects involving, but not limited to, navigation, flood control, and shore protection, if the estimated Federal first cost of constructing such project is less than $15,000,000. No appropriation shall be made to construct, operate, or maintain any such project if such project has not been approved by resolutions adopted by the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives, respectively. For the purpose of securing consideration of such approval the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report of such proposed project, including all relevant data and all costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local cooperation requirements based on certain estimated Federal first cost of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any water resource development project authorized to be constructed by this section shall be subject to the same requirements of local cooperation as it would be if the estimated Federal first cost of such project were $15,000,000 or more.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–298, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1965-10-27">Oct. 27, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1073</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 131</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5a.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement to States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Combination of reimbursement of installation costs and reduction in contributions; single project limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, may, when he determines it to be in the public interest, enter into agreements providing for reimbursement to States or political subdivisions thereof for work to be performed by such non-Federal public bodies at water resources development projects authorized for construction under the Secretary of the Army and the supervision of the Chief of Engineers. Such agreements may provide for reimbursement of installation costs incurred by such entities or an equivalent reduction in the contributions they would otherwise be required to make, or in appropriate cases, for a combination thereof. The amount of Federal reimbursement, including reductions in contributions, for a single project shall not exceed $5,000,000 or 1 percent of the total project cost, whichever is greater; except that the amount of actual Federal reimbursement, including reductions in contributions, for such project may not exceed $7,000,000 in any fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement provisions; termination of agreement for failure to commence work</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Agreements entered into pursuant to this section shall (1) fully describe the work to be accomplished by the non-Federal public body, and be accompanied by an engineering plan if necessary therefor; (2) specify the manner in which such work shall be carried out; (3) provide for necessary review of design and plans, and inspection of the work by the Chief of Engineers or his designee; (4) state the basis on which the amount of reimbursement shall be determined; (5) state that such reimbursement shall be dependent upon the appropriation of funds applicable thereto or funds available therefor, and shall not take precedence over other pending projects of higher priority for improvements; and (6) specify that reimbursement or credit for non-Federal installation expenditures shall apply only to work undertaken on Federal projects after project authorization and execution of the agreement, and does not apply retroactively to past non-Federal work. Each such agreement shall expire three years after the date on which it is executed if the work to be undertaken by the non-Federal public body has not commenced before the expiration of that period. The time allowed for completion of the work will be determined by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, and stated in the agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification of performance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No reimbursement shall be made, and no expenditure shall be credited, pursuant to this section, unless and until the Chief of Engineers or his designee, has certified that the work for which reimbursement or credit is requested has been performed in accordance with the agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Beach erosion control projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Reimbursement for work commenced by non-Federal public bodies no later than one year after <date date="1968-08-13">August 13, 1968</date>, to carry out or assist in carrying out projects for beach erosion control, may be made in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 426f of title 33</ref>. Reimbursement for such work may, as an alternative, be made in accordance with the provisions of this section, provided that agreement required herein shall have been executed prior to commencement of the work. Expenditures for projects for beach erosion control commenced by non-Federal public bodies subsequent to one year after <date date="1968-08-13">August 13, 1968</date>, may be reimbursed by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of construction for Federal assumption of responsibilities of non-Federal bodies or for Federal liability for unnecessary or inapplicable project work of such bodies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not be construed (1) as authorizing the United States to assume any responsibilities placed upon a non-Federal body by the conditions of project authorization, or (2) as committing the United States to reimburse non-Federal interests if the Federal project is not undertaken or is modified so as to make the work performed by the non-Federal Public body no longer applicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allotment limitation for any fiscal year; specific project reimbursement authorizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized to allot from any appropriations hereafter made for civil works, not to exceed $10,000,000 for any one fiscal year to carry out the provisions of this section. This limitation does not include specific project authorizations providing for reimbursement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–483, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1968-08-13">Aug. 13, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 747</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 913</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–676, § 12</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4025</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 224(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3697</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. C, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5b.</num>
<heading> Written agreement requirement for water resources projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation of non-Federal interest</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, the construction of any water resources project, or an acceptable separable element thereof, by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, or by a non-Federal interest where such interest will be reimbursed for such construction under any provision of law, shall not be commenced until each non-Federal interest has entered into a written partnership agreement with the Secretary (or, where appropriate, the district engineer for the district in which the project will be carried out) under which each party agrees to carry out its responsibilities and requirements for implementation or construction of the project or the appropriate element of the project, as the case may be; except that no such agreement shall be required if the Secretary determines that the administrative costs associated with negotiating, executing, or administering the agreement would exceed the amount of the contribution required from the non-Federal interest and are less than $25,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liquidated damages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A partnership agreement described in paragraph (1) may include a provision for liquidated damages in the event of a failure of one or more parties to perform.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligation of future appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any partnership agreement described in paragraph (1) and entered into by a State, or a body politic of the State which derives its powers from the State constitution, or a governmental entity created by the State legislature, the agreement may reflect that it does not obligate future appropriations for such performance and payment when obligating future appropriations would be inconsistent with constitutional or statutory limitations of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit for in-kind contributions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A partnership agreement described in paragraph (1) may provide with respect to a project that the Secretary shall credit toward the non-Federal share of the cost of the project, including a project implemented without specific authorization in law or a project under an environmental infrastructure assistance program, the value of in-kind contributions made by the non-Federal interest, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the costs of planning (including data collection), design, management, mitigation, construction, and construction services that are provided by the non-Federal interest for implementation of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the value of materials or services provided before execution of the partnership agreement, including efforts on constructed elements incorporated into the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the value of materials and services provided after execution of the partnership agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may credit an in-kind contribution under subparagraph (A) only if the Secretary determines that the material or service provided as an in-kind contribution is integral to the project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Work performed before partnership agreement</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">In any case in which the non-Federal interest is to receive credit under subparagraph (A) for the cost of construction carried out by the non-Federal interest before execution of a partnership agreement and that construction has not been carried out as of <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, the Secretary and the non-Federal interest shall enter into an agreement under which the non-Federal interest shall carry out such work and shall do so prior to the non-Federal interest initiating construction or issuing a written notice to proceed for the construction.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Construction that is carried out after the execution of an agreement to carry out work described in subclause (I) and any design activities that are required for that construction, even if the design activity is carried out prior to the execution of the agreement to carry out work, shall be eligible for credit.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Planning</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">In any case in which the non-Federal interest is to receive credit under subparagraph (A) for the cost of planning carried out by the non-Federal interest before execution of a feasibility cost-sharing agreement, the Secretary and the non-Federal interest shall enter into an agreement under which the non-Federal interest shall carry out such work and shall do so prior to the non-Federal interest initiating that planning.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Planning that is carried out by the non-Federal interest after the execution of an agreement to carry out work described in subclause (I) shall be eligible for credit.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Credit authorized under this paragraph for a project—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not exceed the non-Federal share of the cost of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not alter any other requirement that a non-Federal interest provide lands, easements, relocations, rights-of-way, or areas for disposal of dredged material for the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall not alter any requirement that a non-Federal interest pay a portion of the costs of construction of the project under sections 2211(a)(2) and 2213(a)(1)(A) of title 33; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> shall not exceed the actual and reasonable costs of the materials, services, or other things provided by the non-Federal interest, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis of costs and benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the evaluation of the costs and benefits of a project, the Secretary shall not consider construction carried out by a non-Federal interest under this subsection as part of the future without project condition.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of credit between separable elements of a project</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Credit for in-kind contributions provided by a non-Federal interest that are in excess of the non-Federal cost share for an authorized separable element of a project may be applied toward the non-Federal cost share for a different authorized separable element of the same project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of credit</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">To the extent that credit for in-kind contributions, as limited by subparagraph (D), and credit for required land, easements, rights-of-way, dredged material disposal areas, and relocations provided by the non-Federal interest exceed the non-Federal share of the cost of construction of a project other than a navigation project, the Secretary, subject to the availability of funds, shall enter into a reimbursement agreement with the non-Federal interest, which shall be in addition to a partnership agreement under subparagraph (A), to reimburse the difference to the non-Federal interest.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If appropriated funds are insufficient to cover the full cost of all requested reimbursement agreements under clause (i), the Secretary shall enter into reimbursement agreements in the order in which requests for such agreements are received.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(H)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">This paragraph shall apply to water resources projects authorized after <date date="1986-11-16">November 16, 1986</date>, including projects initiated after <date date="1986-11-16">November 16, 1986</date>, without specific authorization in law, and to water resources projects authorized prior to <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>, if correction of design deficiencies is necessary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization as addition to other authorizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The authority of the Secretary to provide credit for in-kind contributions pursuant to this paragraph shall be in addition to any other authorization to provide credit for in-kind contributions and shall not be construed as a limitation on such other authorization. The Secretary shall apply the provisions of this paragraph, in lieu of provisions under other crediting authority, only if so requested by the non-Federal interest.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of non-Federal interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The term “non-Federal interest” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a legally constituted public body (including an Indian tribe and a tribal organization (as those terms are defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>)) and an inter-tribal consortium (as defined in <ref>section 3202 of title 25</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a nonprofit entity with the consent of the affected local government,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">that has full authority and capability to perform the terms of its agreement and to pay damages, if necessary, in the event of failure to perform.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement; jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every agreement entered into pursuant to this section shall be enforcible in the appropriate district court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonperformance of terms of agreement by non-Federal interest; notice; reasonable opportunity for performance; performance by Chief of Engineers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After commencement of construction of a project, the Chief of Engineers may undertake performance of those items of cooperation necessary to the functioning of the project for its purposes, if he has first notified the non-Federal interest of its failure to perform the terms of its agreement and has given such interest a reasonable time after such notification to so perform.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, the Secretary shall issue policies and guidelines for partnership agreements that delegate to the district engineers, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the authority to approve any policy in a partnership agreement that has appeared in an agreement previously approved by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the authority to approve any policy in a partnership agreement the specific terms of which are dictated by law or by a final feasibility study, final environmental impact statement, or other final decision document for a water resources project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the authority to approve any partnership agreement that complies with the policies and guidelines issued by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the authority to sign any partnership agreement for any water resources project unless, within 30 days of the date of authorization of the project, the Secretary notifies the district engineer in which the project will be carried out that the Secretary wishes to retain the prerogative to sign the partnership agreement for that project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, and every year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of partnership agreements signed by district engineers and the number of partnership agreements signed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For any partnership agreement signed by the Secretary, an explanation of why delegation to the district engineer was not appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, the Chief of Engineers shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that each district engineer has made available to the public, including on the Internet, all partnership agreements entered into under this section within the preceding 10 years and all partnership agreements for water resources projects currently being carried out in that district; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make each partnership agreement entered into after <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, available to the public, including on the Internet, not later than 7 days after the date on which such agreement is entered into.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any project the construction of which was commenced before <date date="1972-01-01">January 1, 1972</date>, or to the assurances for future demands required by the Water Supply Act of 1958, as amended [<ref>43 U.S.C. 390b</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–611, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1831</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–222, § 4</ref>, <date date="1971-12-23">Dec. 23, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 799</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 912(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1064(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–541, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2000-12-11">Dec. 11, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2003(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1067</ref>, 1069; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1018(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1131</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1155(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3793</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1137</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5c.</num>
<heading> Non-Federal public bodies, installment construction payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual installments during period of construction in absence of other provision for extended repayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In connection with any water resource development project, heretofore, herein, or hereafter authorized to be undertaken by the Secretary of the Army, the construction of which has not been initiated as of <date date="1974-03-07">March 7, 1974</date>, where authorization requires that non-Federal public bodies make an agreed-upon cash contribution as part of their reimbursement to the Federal Government for construction costs, or a specific portion of the construction costs, and where there exists no other provision of law which would permit extended repayment for the construction costs or such specific portion of the construction costs involved, such non-Federal public bodies may make such repayment in annual installments during the period of construction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing; modification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of affected non-Federal public bodies, the Secretary of the Army is authorized to modify existing cost sharing agreements in order to effectuate the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–251, title I, § 40</ref>, <date date="1974-03-07">Mar. 7, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 23</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5d.</num>
<heading> Authorization of Secretary of the Army to contract with States and political subdivisions for increased law enforcement services during peak visitation periods; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to contract with States and their political subdivisions for the purpose of obtaining increased law enforcement services at water resources development projects under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army to meet needs during peak visitation periods.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 per fiscal year for each fiscal year beginning after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 120</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2924</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 920</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4193</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5e.</num>
<heading> Wetland areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of Secretary of the Army to plan and establish wetland areas; criteria for establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to plan and establish wetland areas as part of an authorized water resources development project under his jurisdiction. Establishment of any wetland area in connection with the dredging required for such a water resources development project may be undertaken in any case where the Chief of Engineers in his judgment finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> environmental, economic, and social benefits of the wetland area justifies the increased cost thereof above the cost required for alternative methods of disposing of dredged material for such project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the increased cost of such wetland area will not exceed $400,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there is reasonable evidence that the wetland area to be established will not be substantially altered or destroyed by natural or man-made causes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, submits to Congress a report on a water resources development project after <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, such report shall include, where appropriate, consideration of the establishment of wetland areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the computation of benefits and cost of any water resources development project the benefits of establishing of any wetland area shall be deemed to be at least equal to the cost of establishing such area. All costs of establishing a wetland area shall be borne by the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 150</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2931</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5f.</num>
<heading> Beach nourishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to provide periodic beach nourishment in the case of each water resources development project where such nourishment has been authorized for a limited period for such additional period as he determines necessary but in no event shall such additional period extend beyond the fiftieth year which begins after the date of initiation of construction of such project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Secretary shall, at the request of the non-Federal interest, carry out a study to determine the feasibility of extending the period of nourishment described in subsection (a) for a period not to exceed 50 additional years beyond the maximum period described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The additional years provided under paragraph (1) shall begin on the date of initiation of construction of congressionally authorized nourishment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan for reducing risk to people and property</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As part of the review described in subsection (b), the non-Federal interest shall submit to the Secretary a plan for reducing risk to people and property during the life of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of plan in recommendation to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall include the plan described in subsection (a) in the recommendations to Congress described in subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon completion of the review described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives any recommendations of the Secretary related to the review; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> include in the subsequent annual report to Congress required under <ref>section 2282d of title 33</ref>, any recommendations that require specific congressional authorization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, for any existing authorized water resources development project for which the maximum period for nourishment described in subsection (a) will expire within the 16-year period beginning on <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, that project shall remain eligible for nourishment for an additional 12 years after the expiration of such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 156</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2933</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 934</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4197</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1037(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1235</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1122(j)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1647</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1158</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3794</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8129(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–5g.</num>
<heading> Hydroelectric power resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study; plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized and directed to conduct a study of the most efficient methods of utilizing the hydroelectric power resources at water resource development projects under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army and to prepare a plan based upon the findings of such study. Such study shall include, but not be limited to, an analysis of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the physical potential for hydroelectric development, giving consideration to the economic, social, environmental and institutional factors which will affect the realization of physical potential;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the magnitude and regional distribution of needs for hydroelectric power;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the integration of hydroelectric power generation with generation from other types of generating facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> measures necessary to assure that generation from hydroelectric projects will efficiently contribute to meeting the national electric energy demands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the timing of hydroelectric development to properly coincide with changes in the demand for electric energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> conventional hydroelectric potential, both high head and low head projects utilizing run-of-rivers and possible advances in mechanical technology, and pumped storage hydroelectric potential at sites which evidence such potential;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the feasibility of adding or reallocating storage and modifying operation rules to increase power production at corps projects with existing hydroelectric installations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> measures deemed necessary or desirable to insure that the potential contribution of hydroelectric resources to the overall electric energy supply are realized to the maximum extent possible; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> any other pertinent factors necessary to evaluate the development and operation of hydroelectric projects of the Corps of Engineers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal of plan to Congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within three years after the date of the first appropriation of funds for the purpose of carrying out this section, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall transmit the plan prepared pursuant to subsection (a) with supporting studies and documentation, together with the recommendations of the Secretary and the Chief of Engineers on such plan, to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out subsections (a) and (b) of this section not to exceed $7,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Feasibility studies of specific hydroelectric power installations; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized with respect to previously authorized projects to undertake feasibility studies of specific hydroelectric power installations that are identified in the course of the study authorized by this section, as having high potential for contribution toward meeting regional power needs. There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection not to exceed $5,000,000 per fiscal year for each of the fiscal years 1978 and 1979.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 167</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–6.</num>
<heading> Feasibility studies; acceleration; advancement of costs by non-Federal sources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may accelerate feasibility studies authorized by law when and to the extent that the costs of such studies shall have been advanced by non-Federal sources.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–561, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 714</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–7.</num>
<heading> Delmarva Peninsula hydrologic study; duties of Secretary of the Interior</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized and directed to make a comprehensive study and investigation of the water resources of the Delmarva Peninsula with a view to determining the availability of fresh water supplies needed to meet the anticipated future water requirements of the Delmarva Peninsula area, and with a view to determining the most effective means from the standpoint of hydrologic feasibility of protecting and developing fresh water sources so as to insure, insofar as practicable, the availability of adequate water supplies in the future. In carrying out such study and investigation with respect to the Delmarva Peninsula, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> appraise the water use, requirements, and trends, and determine the availability of water in the streams and underground sources for the entire peninsula;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determine the depths, thicknesses, and permeabilities, the perennial yield, and the recharge characteristics of major aquifers, and the quality characteristics to be expected from each such major aquifer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> determine with respect to ground water resources the continuity and extent of important water-bearing formations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> determine the yield from stream systems under natural flow conditions and under varying degrees of storage and the amounts and quality of waters available from such systems during drought, flood, and intermediate conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> determine whether sea water has moved inland into heavily pumped coastal aquifers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> give special consideration to conditions which may invite the invasion of sea water into fresh-water supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> compile and make available to appropriate State and local officials any results of this study and investigation that would be appropriate for their use in long-range planning, development, and management of water supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> cooperate with State and local agencies for the purpose of using any information and data available to carry out the purposes of this study; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> consider such other matters as the Secretary may deem appropriate to the study and investigation herein authorized.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–618, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-10-04">Oct. 4, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–8.</num>
<heading> Reports on Delmarva Peninsula hydrologic study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the course of the study and investigation authorized by sections 1962d–7 to 1962d–11 of this title, the Secretary may submit to the President for transmission to the Congress such interim reports as the Secretary may consider desirable. The Secretary shall submit a final report to the President for transmission to the Congress not more than six years after <date date="1966-10-04">October 4, 1966</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–618, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-10-04">Oct. 4, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–9.</num>
<heading> Information from Federal agencies for Delmarva Peninsula study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to secure directly from any executive department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality of the Federal Government, information, suggestions, estimates, and statistics for the purpose of sections 1962d–7 to 1962d–11 of this title, and each department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality is authorized and directed to furnish such information, suggestions, estimates, and statistics, to the Secretary upon his or his designee’s request.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–618, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-10-04">Oct. 4, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–10.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with agencies on Delmarva Peninsula study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the study and investigation authorized by sections 1962d–7 to 1962d–11 of this title, the Secretary is authorized to cooperate with other Federal, State, and local agencies now engaged in comprehensive planning for water resource use and development in the Delmarva Peninsula area by making available to those agencies his findings and to cooperate with those agencies in the Northeastern United States Water Supply Study as authorized by <ref>section 1962d–4 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–618, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-10-04">Oct. 4, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 871</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–11.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriation for Delmarva Peninsula study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated the sum of $500,000 to carry out the provisions of sections 1962d–7 to 1962d–11 of this title: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in such sections shall prevent the expenditure of other funds appropriated to the United States Geological Survey for studies and activities performed under its general authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–618, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-10-04">Oct. 4, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–11a.</num>
<heading> Potomac River water diversion structure</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consent of Congress for construction; written agreement providing schedule for allocation among parties for withdrawal of waters</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the consent of Congress is granted under <ref>section 401 of title 33</ref> to the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission to construct a water diversion structure, with an elevation not to exceed one hundred and fifty-nine feet above sea level, from the north shore of the Potomac River at the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission water filtration plant to the north shore of Watkins Island.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The structure authorized by paragraph (1) of this subsection, may not be constructed until the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, and the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Virginia, the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission, and such other governmental authorities as the Secretary of the Army, the State of Maryland, and the Commonwealth of Virginia deem desirable signatories enter into a written agreement providing an enforceable schedule for allocation among the parties to such agreement for the withdrawal of the waters of that portion of the Potomac River located between Little Falls Dam and the farthest upstream limit of the pool of water behind the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Company rubble dam at Seneca, Maryland, during periods of low flow of such portion of such river.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of Secretary of the Army to enter written agreement; amendments or revisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to enter into the agreement referred to in subsection (a)(2) of this section and any amendment to or revision of such agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Riparian rights or other authority of Maryland, Virginia, political subdivisions; authority of District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as may be provided in the agreement referred to in subsection (a)(2) of this section, nothing in this section shall alter any riparian rights or other authority of the State of Maryland, or any political subdivision thereof, the Commonwealth of Virginia, or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia, or authority of the Corps of Engineers existing on <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, relative to the appropriation of water from, or the use of, the Potomac River.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 181</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–292, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–11b.</num>
<heading> Dalecarlia Reservoir; delivery of water to metropolitan Maryland; expenses; payments; purchase of water from State or local authorities in Maryland or Virginia</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary, on the recommendation of the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to permit the delivery of water from the District of Columbia water system at the Dalecarlia filtration plant, or at other points on the system, to any competent State or local authority in the Washington, District of Columbia, metropolitan area in Maryland. All of the expense of installing the connection or connections and appurtenances between the water supply systems and any subsequent changes therein shall be paid by the requesting entity, which shall also pay such charges for the use of the water as the Secretary may, from time to time in advance of delivery, determine to be reasonable. Payments shall be made at such time, and pursuant to such regulations, as the Secretary prescribes. The Secretary may revoke any permit for the use of water at any time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to purchase water from any State or local authority in Maryland or Virginia that has, at the time of purchase, completed a connection with the District of Columbia water system. The Secretary is authorized to pay such charges for the use of the water as the Secretary has agreed upon in advance of delivery.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4231</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1962d–12 to 1962d–14.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–58, title I, § 104(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–14a.</num>
<heading> Alaska hydroelectric power development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional findings and declaration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Congress finds that the expeditious development of hydroelectric power generating facilities in Alaska that are environmentally sound to assist the Nation in meeting existing and future energy demands is in the national interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Congress therefore declares that the expertise of the Chief of Engineers can and should be utilized for the benefit of local public bodies in the development of projects which yield 90 per centum or more of the benefits of the project are attributable to hydroelectric power generation when the project is fully operational.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of fund; composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To meet the goals of this section, there is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States an Alaska Hydroelectric Power Development Fund (hereafter referred to as the “fund”) to be and remain available for use by the Secretary of the Army (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) to make expenditures authorized by this section. The fund shall consist of (1) all receipts and collections by the Secretary of repayments in accordance with subsection (e) of this section and payments by non-Federal public authorities to the Secretary to finance the cost of construction of projects in accordance with subsection (f) of this section, and which the Secretary is hereby directed to deposit in the fund as they are received, and (2) any appropriations made by the Congress to the fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for deposit in the fund established by subsection (b) of this section the sum of $25,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments; deposits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Secretary determines that moneys in the fund are in excess of current needs, he may request the investment of such amounts as he deems advisable by the Secretary of the Treasury in direct, general obligations of, or obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by, the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> With the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary may deposit moneys of the fund in any Federal Reserve bank or other depository for funds of the United States, or in such other banks and financial institutions and under such terms and conditions as the Secretary and the Secretary of the Treasury may mutually agree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures for phase I design memorandum stage of advanced engineering and design; withholding of favorable report to Congress prior to repayment; expenditures from non-Federal funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make expenditures from the fund for the phase I design memorandum stage of advanced engineering and design for any project in Alaska that meets the requirements of subsection (a)(2) of this section, if appropriate non-Federal public authorities, approved by the Secretary, agree with the Secretary, in writing, to repay the Secretary for all the separable and joint costs of preparing such design memorandum, if such report is favorable. Following the completion of the phase I design memorandum stage of advanced engineering and design under this subsection, the Secretary shall not transmit any favorable report to Congress prior to being repaid in full by the appropriate non-Federal public authorities for the costs incurred during such phase I. The Secretary is also authorized to make expenditures from non-Federal funds deposited in the fund as an advance against construction costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to construct projects; expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In connection with water resources development projects which meet the criteria established by subsection (a)(2) of this section and which are to be constructed by the Secretary, acting through the Chief of Engineers, in accordance with an authorization by Congress and a contract between the non-Federal public authorities and the Secretary, pursuant to subsection (g)(1) of this section occurring on or subsequent to <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to construct such projects including activities for engineering and design land acquisition, site development, and off-site improvements necessary for the authorized construction by making expenditures from (1) the Fund established in subsection (b) of this section of funds deposited by non-Federal public authorities as payments for construction and (2) payments of non-Federal public authorities held by the Secretary as payment of construction costs for a project authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement with non-Federal public authorities and submittal to Congressional committees, payment of total non-Federal obligations; conditions of United States assumption of excess over costs fixed in agreement, payment subject to appropriations acts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Prior to initiating any construction work under the authorities of this section, the Secretary and the appropriate non-Federal public authorities shall agree in writing, and submit such agreement to the Committees on Environment and Public Works and on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committees on Public Works and Transportation and on Appropriations of the House of Representatives for review and reporting to the Congress for its consideration and approval that the appropriate non-Federal public authorities will pay the full anticipated costs of constructing the project at the time such costs are incurred, together with normal contingencies and related administrative expenses of the Secretary, and such payments shall be deposited in the fund or held by the Secretary for payment of obligations incurred by the Secretary on an authorized project under this section. The agreement shall provide for an initial determination of feasibility and compliance by the project with law. The total non-Federal obligation shall be paid on or prior to the date the Chief of Engineers has estimated by agreement, that the project concerned will be available for actual generation of all or a substantial portion of the authorized hydroelectric power of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In consideration of the obligations to be assumed by non-Federal public authorities under the provisions of this section and in recognition of the substantial investments which will be made by these authorities in reliance on the program established by this section, the United States shall assume the responsibility for paying for all costs over those fixed in the agreement with the non-Federal public authorities, if such costs are occasioned by acts of God, failure on the part of the Secretary, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to adhere to the agreed schedule of work or a failure of design: <i>Provided</i>, That payments by the Secretary of such costs shall be subject to appropriations acts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conveyance of title, rights, and interests of United States; Federal requirements, reservations, and provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed, pursuant to the agreement, to convey all title, rights, and interests of the United States to any project, its lands and water areas, and appurtenant facilities to the non-Federal public authorities which have agreed to assume ownership of the project and responsibility for its performance, operation, and maintenance, as well as necessary replacements in accordance with this section upon full payment by such non-Federal public authorities as required under subsection (g)(1) of this section. Such conveyance shall, pursuant to the agreement required by subsection (g) of this section, to the maximum extent possible, occur immediately upon the project’s availability for generation of all or a substantial portion of the authorized hydroelectric power of the project, and shall include such Federal requirements, reservations, and provisions for access rights to the project and its records as the Secretary finds advisable to complete any portion of project construction remaining at the time of conveyance and to assure that the project will be operated and maintained in a responsible and safe manner to accomplish, as nearly as may be possible, all of the authorized purposes of the project including, but not restricted to, hydroelectric power generation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall be cited as the “Alaska Hydroelectric Power Development Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 203</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2946</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–15.</num>
<heading> Protection of United States from liability for damages; exception of damages due to fault or negligence of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirement in any water resources development project under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army, that non-Federal interests hold and save the United States free from damages due to the construction, operation, and maintenance of the project, does not include damages due to the fault or negligence of the United States or its contractors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–251, title I, § 9</ref>, <date date="1974-03-07">Mar. 7, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 16</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–16.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive plans for development, utilization, and conservation of water and related resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal State cooperation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to cooperate with any State, group of States, non-Federal interest working with a State or group of States, local government, or regional coalition of governmental entities in the preparation of comprehensive plans for the development, utilization, and conservation of the water and related resources of drainage basins, watersheds, or ecosystems located within the boundaries of such State, interest, local government, or entity, including plans to comprehensively address water resources challenges, and to submit to Congress reports and recommendations with respect to appropriate Federal participation in carrying out such plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At the request of a governmental agency or non-Federal interest, the Secretary may provide technical assistance to such agency or non-Federal interest in managing water resources.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Technical assistance under this paragraph may include provision and integration of hydrologic, economic, and environmental data and analyses and title research for abandoned structures.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 4141 of title 10</ref>, in carrying out this subsection, the Secretary may work with an institution of higher education, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall prioritize the provision of assistance under this subsection to address both inland and coastal life safety risks.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purpose of recovering 50 percent of the total cost of providing assistance pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of the Army is authorized to establish appropriate fees, as determined by the Secretary, and to collect such fees from States and other non-Federal public bodies to whom assistance is provided under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contributed funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may accept and expend funds in excess of the fees established under paragraph (1) that are provided by a State or other non-Federal interest for assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In-kind services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The non-Federal contribution for preparation of a plan subject to the cost sharing program under this subsection may be made by the provision of services, materials, supplies, or other in-kind services necessary to prepare the plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit and use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Fees collected under this subsection shall be deposited into the account in the Treasury of the United States entitled, “Contributions and Advances, Rivers and Harbors, Corps of Engineers (8862)” and shall be available until expended to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal and State cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $30,000,000 annually to carry out subsection (a)(1), except that not more than $5,000,000 in Federal funds shall be expended in any one year in any one State. The Secretary may allow 2 or more States to combine all or a portion of the funds that the Secretary makes available to the States in carrying out subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 annually to carry out subsection (a)(2), of which not more than $2,000,000 annually may be used by the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with nonprofit organizations to provide assistance to rural and small communities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual submission of proposed activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Concurrent with the President’s submission to Congress of the President’s request for appropriations for the Civil Works Program for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report describing the individual activities proposed for funding under subsection (a)(1) for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “State” means the several States of the United States, Indian tribes, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribes and territories</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The cost-share for assistance under this section provided to Indian tribes, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands shall be as provided under <ref>section 2310 of title 33</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economically disadvantaged communities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (b)(1) and the limitation in <ref>section 2310 of title 33</ref>, as applicable pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary is authorized to waive the collection of fees for any local government to which assistance is provided under subsection (a) that the Secretary determines is an economically disadvantaged community, as defined by the Secretary under section 160 of the Water Resources Development Act of 2020 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 2201</ref> note) (including economically disadvantaged communities located in urban and rural areas).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–251, title I, § 22</ref>, <date date="1974-03-07">Mar. 7, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 20</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 168</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–597, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 921</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–640, title III, § 319</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–580, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1992-10-31">Oct. 31, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3697</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2013</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1075</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3015</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I</ref>, §§ 1128, 1129, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1159</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3795</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8119(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1127</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–17.</num>
<heading> Regional or river basin plans and Federal water and related land resources projects; preparation, formulation, and evaluation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest rate formula for discounting future benefits and cost computations; repeal of conflicting provisions and administrative actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The interest rate formula to be used in plan formulation and evaluation for discounting future benefits and computing costs by Federal officers, employees, departments, agencies, and instrumentalities in the preparation of comprehensive regional or river basin plans and the formulation and evaluation of Federal water and related land resources projects shall be the formula set forth in the “Policies, Standards, and Procedures in the Formulation, Evaluation, and Review of Plans for Use and Development of Water and Related Land Resources” approved by the President on <date date="1962-05-15">May 15, 1962</date>, and published as Senate Document 97 of the Eighty-seventh Congress on <date date="1962-05-29">May 29, 1962</date>, as amended by the regulation issued by the Water Resources Council and published in the Federal Register on <date date="1968-12-24">December 24, 1968</date> (33 F.R. 19170; 18 C.F.R. 704.39), until otherwise provided by a statute enacted after <date date="1974-03-07">March 7, 1974</date>. Every provision of law and every administrative action in conflict with this section is hereby repealed to the extent of such conflict.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest rate for prior authorized projects assured of non-Federal share of project costs; continuation of rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any project authorized before <date date="1969-01-03">January 3, 1969</date>, if the appropriate non-Federal interests have, prior to <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, given satisfactory assurances to pay the required non-Federal share of project costs, the discount rate to be used in the computation of benefits and costs for such project shall be the rate in effect immediately prior to <date date="1968-12-24">December 24, 1968</date>, and that rate shall continue to be used for such project until construction has been completed, unless otherwise provided by a statute enacted after <date date="1974-03-07">March 7, 1974</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water and related resources projects; Presidential study; scope of study; report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall make a full and complete investigation and study of principles and standards for planning and evaluating water and related resources projects. Such investigation and study shall include, but not be limited to, consideration of enhancing regional economic development, the quality of the total environment including its protection and improvement, the well-being of the people of the United States, and the national economic development, as objectives to be included in federally-financed water and related resources projects and in the evaluation of costs and benefits attributable to such projects, as intended in <ref>section 1962–2 of this title</ref>, the interest rate formula to be used in evaluating and discounting future benefits for such projects, and appropriate Federal and non-Federal cost sharing for such projects. He shall report the results of such investigation and study, together with his recommendations, to Congress not later than one year after funds are first appropriated to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–251, title I, § 80</ref>, <date date="1974-03-07">Mar. 7, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 34</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–18.</num>
<heading> Study of depletion of natural resources of regions of Colorado, Kansas, New Mexico, Oklahoma, Texas, and Nebraska utilizing Ogallala aquifer; plans; reports to Congress; authorization of appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to assure an adequate supply of food to the Nation and to promote the economic vitality of the High Plains Region, the Secretary of Commerce (hereinafter referred to in this section as the “Secretary”), acting through the Economic Development Administration, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, and appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies, and the private sector, is authorized and directed to study the depletion of the natural resources of those regions of the States of Colorado, Kansas, New Mexico, Oklahoma, Texas, and Nebraska presently utilizing the declining water resources of the Ogallala acquifer,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003228">1</ref> and to develop plans to increase water supplies in the area and report thereon to Congress, together with any recommendations for further congressional action. In formulating these plans, the Secretary is directed to consider all past and ongoing studies, plans, and work on depleted water resources in the region, and to examine the feasibility of various alternatives to provide adequate water supplies in the area including, but not limited to, the transfer of water from adjacent areas, such portion to be conducted by the Chief of Engineers to assure the continued economic growth and vitality of the region. The Secretary shall report on the costs of reasonably available options, the benefits of various options, and the costs of inaction. If water transfer is found to be a part of a reasonable solution, the Secretary, as part of his study, shall include a recommended plan for allocating and distributing water in an equitable fashion, taking into account existing water rights and the needs for future growth of all affected areas. An interim report, with recommendations, shall be transmitted to the Congress no later than <date date="1978-10-01">October 1, 1978</date>, and a final report, with recommendations, shall be transmitted to Congress not later than <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>. A sum of $6,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–587, § 193</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–19.</num>
<heading> Cooperation of Secretary of the Interior with State and local regulatory and law enforcement officials in enforcement of laws or ordinances in connection with Federal resource protection, etc., within Federal water resource development project; funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, in connection with Federal resource protection and the Federal administration of the use and occupancy of lands and waters within a water resource development project under his jurisdiction, is authorized to cooperate with the regulatory and law enforcement officials of any State or political subdivision thereof in the enforcement of the laws or ordinances of such State or political subdivision. Such cooperation may include the reimbursement of a State or its political subdivision for expenditures incurred in connection with such resource protection and administration. For purposes of complying with <ref>section 651 of title 2</ref>, the authorization provided under this section is subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–552, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–20.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on Great Lakes diversions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional findings and declarations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Great Lakes are a most important natural resource to the eight Great Lakes States and two Canadian provinces, providing water supply for domestic and industrial use, clean energy through hydropower production, an efficient transportation mode for moving products into and out of the Great Lakes region, and recreational uses for millions of United States and Canadian citizens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Great Lakes need to be carefully managed and protected to meet current and future needs within the Great Lakes basin and Canadian provinces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any new diversions of Great Lakes water for use outside of the Great Lakes basin will have significant economic and environmental impacts, adversely affecting the use of this resource by the Great Lakes States and Canadian provinces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> four of the Great Lakes are international waters and are defined as boundary waters in the Boundary Waters Treaty of 1909 between the United States and Canada, and as such any new diversion of Great Lakes water in the United States would affect the relations of the Government of the United States with the Government of Canada.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional declaration of purpose and policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is therefore declared to be the purpose and policy of the Congress in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to take immediate action to protect the limited quantity of water available from the Great Lakes system for use by the Great Lakes States and in accordance with the Boundary Waters Treaty of 1909;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage the Great Lakes States, in consultation with the Provinces of Ontario and Quebec, to develop and implement a mechanism that provides a common conservation standard embodying the principles of water conservation and resource improvement for making decisions concerning the withdrawal and use of water from the Great Lakes Basin;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to prohibit any diversion of Great Lakes water by any State, Federal agency, or private entity for use outside the Great Lakes basin unless such diversion is approved by the Governor of each of the Great Lakes States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to prohibit any Federal agency from undertaking any studies that would involve the transfer of Great Lakes water for any purpose for use outside the Great Lakes basin.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Great Lakes State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “Great Lakes State” means each of the States of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, Pennsylvania, New York, and Wisconsin.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval by Governors for diversion of water</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No water shall be diverted or exported from any portion of the Great Lakes within the United States, or from any tributary within the United States of any of the Great Lakes, for use outside the Great Lakes basin unless such diversion or export is approved by the Governor of each of the Great Lake <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003229">1</ref> States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of Governors for diversion studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No Federal agency may undertake any study, or expend any Federal funds to contract for any study, of the feasibility of diverting water from any portion of the Great Lakes within the United States, or from any tributary within the United States of any of the Great Lakes, for use outside the Great Lakes basin, unless such study or expenditure is approved by the Governor of each of the Great Lakes States. The prohibition of the preceding sentence shall not apply to any study or data collection effort performed by the Corps of Engineers or other Federal agency under the direction of the International Joint Commission in accordance with the Boundary Waters Treaty of 1909.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Previously authorized diversions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any diversion of water from any of the Great Lakes which is authorized on <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XI, § 1109</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4230</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–541, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2000-12-11">Dec. 11, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–21.</num>
<heading> John Glenn Great Lakes basin program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct a comprehensive study of the Great Lakes region to ensure the future use, management, and protection of water resources and related resources of the Great Lakes basin.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As expeditiously as possible, but not later than 3 years after <date date="1999-08-17">August 17, 1999</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report outlining a strategic plan for Corps of Engineers programs and proposed Corps of Engineers projects in the Great Lakes basin.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The plan shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> details of projects in the Great Lakes region relating to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> navigation improvements, maintenance, and operations for commercial and recreational vessels;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> environmental restoration activities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> water level maintenance activities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> technical and planning assistance to States and remedial action planning committees;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> sediment transport analysis, sediment management planning, and activities to support prevention of excess sediment loadings;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> flood damage reduction and shoreline erosion prevention; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> all other relevant activities of the Corps of Engineers; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an analysis of factors limiting use of programs and authorities of the Corps of Engineers in existence on <date date="1999-08-17">August 17, 1999</date>, in the Great Lakes basin, including the need for new or modified authorities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2000 through 2003.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes biohydrological information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inventory</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after <date date="1999-08-17">August 17, 1999</date>, the Secretary shall request each Federal agency that may possess information relevant to the Great Lakes biohydrological system to provide an inventory of all such information in the possession of the agency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relevant information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For the purpose of subparagraph (A), relevant information includes information on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ground and surface water hydrology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> natural and altered tributary dynamics;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> biological aspects of the system influenced by and influencing water quantity and water movement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> meteorological projections and the impacts of weather conditions on Great Lakes water levels; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> other Great Lakes biohydrological system data relevant to sustainable water use management.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 18 months after <date date="1999-08-17">August 17, 1999</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with the States, Indian tribes, and Federal agencies, and after requesting information from the provinces and the federal government of Canada, shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> compile the inventories of information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> analyze the information for consistency and gaps; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> submit to Congress, the International Joint Commission, and the Great Lakes States a report that includes recommendations on ways to improve the information base on the biohydrological dynamics of the Great Lakes ecosystem as a whole, so as to support environmentally sound decisions regarding diversions and consumptive uses of Great Lakes water.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The recommendations in the report under subparagraph (A) shall include recommendations relating to the resources and funds necessary for implementing improvement of the information base.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In developing the report under subparagraph (A), the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Transportation, and the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall consider and report on the status of the issues described and recommendations made in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Report of the International Joint Commission to the Governments of the United States and Canada under the 1977 reference issued in 1985; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the 1993 Report of the International Joint Commission to the Governments of Canada and the United States on Methods of Alleviating Adverse Consequences of Fluctuating Water Levels in the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Basin.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes recreational boating</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="1999-08-17">August 17, 1999</date>, the Secretary, using information and studies in existence on <date date="1999-08-17">August 17, 1999</date>, to the extent practicable, and in cooperation with the Great Lakes States, shall submit to Congress a report detailing the economic benefits of recreational boating in the Great Lakes basin, particularly at harbors benefiting from operation and maintenance projects of the Corps of Engineers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In undertaking activities under this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> encourage public participation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cooperate, and, as appropriate, collaborate, with Great Lakes States, tribal governments, and Canadian federal, provincial, and tribal governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Water use activities and policies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may provide technical assistance to the Great Lakes States to develop interstate guidelines to improve the consistency and efficiency of State-level water use activities and policies in the Great Lakes basin.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may seek and accept funds from non-Federal entities to be used to pay up to 25 percent of the cost of carrying out subsections (b), (c), (d), and (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In-kind contributions for study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The non-Federal interest may provide up to 100 percent of the non-Federal share required under subsection (f) in the form of in-kind services and materials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–53, title IV, § 455</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title IV, § 4001</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962d–22.</num>
<heading> Great Lakes fishery and ecosystem restoration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Great Lakes comprise a nationally and internationally significant fishery and ecosystem;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Great Lakes fishery and ecosystem should be developed and enhanced in a coordinated manner; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Great Lakes fishery and ecosystem provides a diversity of opportunities, experiences, and beneficial uses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lake</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Great Lake” means Lake Superior, Lake Michigan, Lake Huron (including Lake St. Clair), Lake Erie, and Lake Ontario (including the St. Lawrence River to the 45th parallel of latitude).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Great Lake” includes any connecting channel, historically connected tributary, and basin of a lake specified in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Great Lakes Commission” means the Great Lakes Commission established by the Great Lakes Basin Compact (<ref>82 Stat. 414</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes Fishery Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Great Lakes Fishery Commission” has the meaning given the term “Commission” in <ref>section 931 of title 16</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Great Lakes State” means each of the States of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, Pennsylvania, New York, and Wisconsin.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Great Lakes fishery and ecosystem restoration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support plan</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2000-12-11">December 11, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall develop a plan for activities of the Corps of Engineers that support the management of Great Lakes fisheries.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of existing documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the maximum extent practicable, the plan shall make use of and incorporate documents that relate to the Great Lakes and are in existence on <date date="2000-12-11">December 11, 2000</date>, such as lakewide management plans and remedial action plans.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall develop the plan in cooperation with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the signatories to the Joint Strategic Plan for Management of the Great Lakes Fisheries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other affected interests.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reconnaissance studies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Before planning, designing, or constructing a project under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall carry out a reconnaissance study—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to identify methods of restoring the fishery, ecosystem, and beneficial uses of the Great Lakes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to determine whether planning of a project under paragraph (3) should proceed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall plan, design, and construct projects to support the restoration of the fishery, ecosystem, and beneficial uses of the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall develop a program to evaluate the success of the projects carried out under paragraph (3) in meeting fishery and ecosystem restoration goals.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Evaluations under subparagraph (A) shall be conducted in consultation with the Great Lakes Fishery Commission and appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recreation features</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A project carried out pursuant to this subsection may include compatible recreation features as determined by the Secretary, except that the Federal costs of such features may not exceed 10 percent of the Federal ecosystem restoration costs of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement with the Great Lakes Commission or any other agency established to facilitate active State participation in management of the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to other Great Lakes activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No activity under this section shall affect the date of completion of any other activity relating to the Great Lakes that is authorized under other law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal share of the cost of development of the plan under subsection (c)(1) shall be 65 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project planning, design, construction, and evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except for reconnaissance studies, the Federal share of the cost of planning, design, construction, and evaluation of a project under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (c) shall be 65 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit for land, easements, and rights-of-way</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall credit the non-Federal interest for the value of any land, easement, right-of-way, dredged material disposal area, or relocation provided for carrying out a project under subsection (c)(3).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The non-Federal interest may provide up to 100 percent of the non-Federal share required under paragraphs (1) and (2) in the form of services, materials, supplies, or other in-kind contributions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation and maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The operation, maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, and replacement of projects carried out under this section shall be a non-Federal responsibility.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal interests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with <ref>section 1962d–5b of this title</ref>, for any project carried out under this section, a non-Federal interest may include a private interest and a nonprofit entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–541, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2000-12-11">Dec. 11, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–114, title V, § 5011</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–322, title I</ref>, §§ 1123, 1140, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1647</ref>, 1658.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>