<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 97—</num>
<heading>ACID PRECIPITATION PROGRAM AND CARBON DIOXIDE STUDY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ACID PRECIPITATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8901.</num>
<heading> Introductory provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional statement of findings and purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that acid precipitation resulting from other than natural sources—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> could contribute to the increasing pollution of natural and man-made water systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> could adversely affect agricultural and forest crops;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> could adversely affect fish and wildlife and natural ecosystems generally;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> could contribute to corrosion of metals, wood, paint, and masonry used in construction and ornamentation of buildings and public monuments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> could adversely affect public health and welfare; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> could affect areas distant from sources and thus involve issues of national and international policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress declares that it is the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to identify the causes and sources of acid precipitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to evaluate the environmental, social, and economic effects of acid precipitation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> based on the results of the research program established by this subchapter and to the extent consistent with existing law, to take action to the extent necessary and practicable (A) to limit or eliminate the identified emissions which are sources of acid precipitation, and (B) to remedy or otherwise ameliorate the harmful effects which may result from acid precipitation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Acid precipitation” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter the term “acid precipitation” means the wet or dry deposition from the atmosphere of acid chemical compounds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8902.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive ten-year program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation by Acid Precipitation Task Force; membership, etc., of Task Force</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is hereby established a comprehensive ten-year program to carry out the provisions of this subchapter; and to implement this program there shall be formed an Acid Precipitation Task Force (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Task Force”), of which the Secretary of Agriculture, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall be joint chairmen. The remaining membership of the Task Force shall consist of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one representative each from the Department of the Interior, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Energy, the Department of State, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Council on Environmental Quality, the National Science Foundation, and the Tennessee Valley Authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the director of the Argonne National Laboratory, the director of the Brookhaven National Laboratory, the director of the Oak Ridge National Laboratory, and the director of the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> four additional members to be appointed by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research management consortium; membership, responsibilities, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The four National Laboratories (referred to in subsection (a)(2)) shall constitute a research management consortium having the responsibilities described in <ref>section 8903(b)(13) of this title</ref> as well as the general responsibilities required by their representation on the Task Force. In carrying out these responsibilities the consortium shall report to, and act pursuant to direction from, the joint chairmen of the Task Force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director of research program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall serve as the director of the research program established by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 771</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8903.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive research plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation by Task Force for ten-year program; purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Task Force shall prepare a comprehensive research plan for the ten-year program (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “comprehensive plan”), setting forth a coordinated program (1) to identify the causes and effects of acid precipitation and (2) to identify actions to limit or ameliorate the harmful effects of acid precipitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The comprehensive plan shall include programs for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identifying the sources of atmospheric emissions contributing to acid precipitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establishing and operating a nationwide long-term monitoring network to detect and measure levels of acid precipitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> research in atmospheric physics and chemistry to facilitate understanding of the processes by which atmospheric emissions are transformed into acid precipitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> development and application of atmospheric transport models to enable prediction of long-range transport of substances causing acid precipitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> defining geographic areas of impact through deposition monitoring, identification of sensitive areas, and identification of areas at risk;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> broadening of impact data bases through collection of existing data on water and soil chemistry and through temporal trend analysis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> development of dose-response functions with respect to soils, soil organisms, aquatic and amphibious organisms, crop plants, and forest plants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> establishing and carrying out system studies with respect to plant physiology, aquatic ecosystems, soil chemistry systems, soil microbial systems, and forest ecosystems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> economic assessments of (A) the environmental impacts caused by acid precipitation on crops, forests, fisheries, and recreational and aesthetic resources and structures, and (B) alternative technologies to remedy or otherwise ameliorate the harmful effects which may result from acid precipitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> documenting all current Federal activities related to research on acid precipitation and ensuring that such activities are coordinated in ways that prevent needless duplication and waste of financial and technical resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> effecting cooperation in acid precipitation research and development programs, ongoing and planned, with the affected and contributing States and with other sovereign nations having a commonality of interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (f)(1), management by the Task Force of financial resources committed to Federal acid precipitation research and development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (f)(2), management of the technical aspects of Federal acid precipitation research and development programs, including but not limited to (A) the planning and management of research and development programs and projects, (B) the selection of contractors and grantees to carry out such programs and projects, and (C) the establishment of peer review procedures to assure the quality of research and development programs and their products; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> analyzing the information available regarding acid precipitation in order to formulate and present periodic recommendations to the Congress and the appropriate agencies about actions to be taken by these bodies to alleviate acid precipitation and its effects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures applicable</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The comprehensive plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be submitted in draft form to the Congress, and for public review, within six months after <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be available for public comment for a period of sixty days after its submission in draft form under paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be submitted in final form, incorporating such needed revisions as arise from comments received during the review period, to the President and the Congress within forty-five days after the close of the period allowed for comments on the draft comprehensive plan under paragraph (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall constitute the basis on which requests for authorizations and appropriations are to be made for the nine fiscal years following the fiscal year in which the comprehensive plan is submitted in final form under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Convening of Task Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Task Force shall convene as necessary, but no less than twice during each fiscal year of the ten-year period covered by the comprehensive plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of annual report to President and Congress by Task Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Task Force shall submit to the President and the Congress by January 15 of each year an annual report which shall detail the progress of the research program under this subchapter and which shall contain such recommendations as are developed under subsection (b)(14).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of other statutory provisions to Task Force or plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subsection (b)(12) shall not be construed as modifying, or as authorizing the Task Force or the comprehensive plan to modify, any provision of an appropriation Act (or any other provision of law relating to the use of appropriated funds) which specifies (A) the department or agency to which funds are appropriated, or (B) the obligations of such department or agency with respect to the use of such funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subsection (b)(13) shall not be construed as modifying, or as authorizing the Task Force or the comprehensive plan to modify, any provision of law (relating to or involving a department or agency) which specifies (A) procurement practices for the selection, award, or management of contracts or grants by such department or agency, or (B) program activities, limitations, obligations, or responsibilities of such department or agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 771</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8904.</num>
<heading> Implementation of comprehensive plan; new or existing regulatory authorities, etc., not granted or modified</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The comprehensive plan shall be carried out during the nine fiscal years following the fiscal year in which the comprehensive plan is submitted in its final form under <ref>section 8903(c)(3) of this title</ref>; and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be carried out in accord with, and meet the program objectives specified in, paragraphs (1) through (11) of <ref>section 8903(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be managed in accord with paragraphs (12) through (14) of such section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be funded by annual appropriations, subject to annual authorizations which shall be made for each fiscal year of the program (as provided in <ref>section 8905 of this title</ref>) after the submission of the Task Force progress report which under <ref>section 8903(e) of this title</ref> is required to be submitted by January 15 of the calendar year in which such fiscal year begins.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be deemed to grant any new regulatory authority or to limit, expand, or otherwise modify any regulatory authority under existing law, or to establish new criteria, standards, or requirements for regulation under existing law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8905.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For the purpose of establishing the Task Force and developing the comprehensive plan under <ref>section 8903 of this title</ref> there is authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for fiscal year 1981 the sum of $5,000,000 to remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Authorizations of appropriations for the nine fiscal years following the fiscal year in which the comprehensive plan is submitted in final form under <ref>section 8903(c)(3) of this title</ref>, for purposes of carrying out the comprehensive ten-year program established by <ref>section 8902(a) of this title</ref> and implementing the comprehensive plan under sections 8903 and 8904 of this title, shall be provided on an annual basis in authorization Acts hereafter enacted; but the total sum of dollars authorized for such purposes for such nine fiscal years shall not exceed $45,000,000 except as may be specifically provided by reference to this paragraph in the authorization Acts involved.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8906.</num>
<heading> Updated data base on acid content in precipitation; new monitoring site not required</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National Weather Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall maintain an updated data base describing the acid content in precipitation in the United States, using information from Federal acid precipitation monitoring sites.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such data shall be available to interested parties by Weather Service Forecast Offices in the National Weather Service, or through such other facilities or means as the Assistant Administrator for Weather Services, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall direct, for those areas of the United States where and at such time as such information is presently available, within 120 days after <date date="1988-11-17">November 17, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Where other Federal agencies collect such data in the course of carrying out their statutory missions, the heads of those agencies and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall arrange for the transfer of such data to the National Weather Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any Federal agency to establish any new acid precipitation monitoring site.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–685, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CARBON DIOXIDE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8911.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive study of projected impact on atmospheric levels of fossil fuel combustion, etc.</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementing agreement between Director of Office of Science and Technology and National Academy of Sciences; contents; conduct; status report by President respecting negotiations of Office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to carry out a comprehensive study of the projected impact, on the level of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere, of fossil fuel combustion, coal-conversion and related synthetic fuels activities authorized in this Act, and other sources. Such study should also include an assessment of the economic, physical, climatic, and social effects of such impacts. In conducting such study the Office and the Academy are encouraged to work with domestic and foreign governmental and non-governmental entities, and international entities, so as to develop an international, worldwide assessment of the problems involved and to suggest such original research on any aspect of such problems as the Academy deems necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President shall report to the Congress within six months after <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, regarding the status of the Office’s negotiations to implement the study required under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final report by Office and Academy; contents; prior clearance or review of work of Academy; recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A report including the major findings and recommendations resulting from the study required under this section shall be submitted to the Congress by the Office and the Academy not later than three years after <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>. The Academy contribution to such report shall not be subject to any prior clearance or review, nor shall any prior clearance or conditions be imposed on the Academy as part of the agreement made by the Office with the Academy under this section. Such report shall in any event include recommendations regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> how a long-term program of domestic and international research, monitoring, modeling, and assessment of the causes and effects of varying levels of atmospheric carbon dioxide should be structured, including comments by the Office on the interagency requirements of such a program and comments by the Secretary of State on the international agreements required to carry out such a program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> how the United States can best play a role in the development of such a long-term program on an international basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> what domestic resources should be made available to such a program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> how the ongoing United States Government carbon dioxide assessment program should be modified so as to be of increased utility in providing information and recommendations of the highest possible value to government policy makers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the need for periodic reports to the Congress in conjunction with any long-term program the Office and the Academy may recommend under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from other Federal agencies and departments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Director of the National Science Foundation shall furnish to the Office or the Academy upon request any information which the Office or the Academy determines to be necessary for purposes of conducting the study required by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate assessment by Office of interagency implementation requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall provide a separate assessment of the interagency requirements to implement a comprehensive program of the type described in the third sentence of subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title VII, § 711</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 774</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8912.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the expenses of carrying out the carbon dioxide study authorized by <ref>section 8911 of this title</ref> (as determined by the Office of Science and Technology Policy) there are authorized to be appropriated such sums, not exceeding $3,000,000 in the aggregate, as may be necessary. At least 80 percent of any amounts appropriated pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be provided to the National Academy of Sciences.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–294, title VII, § 712</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>