<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 102—</num>
<heading>MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9401.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> despite the significant progress that has been made in making community mental health services available and in improving residential mental health facilities since the original community mental health centers legislation was enacted in 1963, unserved and underserved populations remain and there are certain groups in the population, such as chronically mentally ill individuals, children and youth, elderly individuals, racial and ethnic minorities, women, poor persons, and persons in rural areas, which often lack access to adequate private and public mental health services and support services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the process of transferring or diverting chronically mentally ill individuals from unwarranted or inappropriate institutionalized settings to their home communities has frequently not been accompanied by a process of providing those individuals with the mental health and support services they need in community-based settings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the shift in emphasis from institutional care to community-based care has not always been accompanied by a process of affording training, retraining, and job placement for employees affected by institutional closure and conversion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the delivery of mental health and support services is typically uncoordinated within and among local, State, and Federal entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> mentally ill persons are often inadequately served by (A) programs of the Department of Health and Human Services such as medicare, medicaid, supplemental security income, and social services, and (B) programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of Labor, and other Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> health care systems often lack general health care personnel with adequate mental health care training and often lack mental health care personnel and consequently many individuals with some level of mental disorder do not receive appropriate mental health care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> present knowledge of methods to prevent mental illness through discovery and elimination of its causes and through early detection and treatment is too limited;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a comprehensive and coordinated array of appropriate private and public mental health and support services for all people in need within specific geographic areas, based upon a cooperative local-State-Federal partnership, remains the most effective and humane way to provide a majority of mentally ill individuals with mental health care and needed support; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> because of the rising demand for mental health services and the wide disparity in the distribution of psychiatrists, clinical psychologists, social workers, and psychiatric nurses, there is a shortage in the medical specialty of psychiatry and there are also shortages among the other health personnel who provide mental health services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–398, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1565</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9411.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9412.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes (in addition to the fifty States) the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “nonprofit”, as applied to any entity, means an entity which is owned and operated by one or more corporations or associations no part of the net earnings of which inures or may lawfully inure to the benefit of any private shareholder or person.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–398, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(f)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 9421 to 9423.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>GRANT PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 9431 to 9438.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS RESPECTING GRANT PROGRAMS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">State Mental Health Service Programs</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 9451, 9452.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Applications and Related Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 9461 to 9465.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Performance</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 9471 to 9473.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part D—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Enforcement</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9481.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part E—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Miscellaneous</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 9491 to 9493.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MENTAL HEALTH RIGHTS AND ADVOCACY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9501.</num>
<heading> Bill of Rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that each State should review and revise, if necessary, its laws to ensure that mental health patients receive the protection and services they require; and in making such review and revision should take into account the recommendations of the President’s Commission on Mental Health and the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A person admitted to a program or facility for the purpose of receiving mental health services should be accorded the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The right to appropriate treatment and related services in a setting and under conditions that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are the most supportive of such person’s personal liberty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> restrict such liberty only to the extent necessary consistent with such person’s treatment needs, applicable requirements of law, and applicable judicial orders.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The right to an individualized, written, treatment or service plan (such plan to be developed promptly after admission of such person), the right to treatment based on such plan, the right to periodic review and reassessment of treatment and related service needs, and the right to appropriate revision of such plan, including any revision necessary to provide a description of mental health services that may be needed after such person is discharged from such program or facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The right to ongoing participation, in a manner appropriate to such person’s capabilities, in the planning of mental health services to be provided such person (including the right to participate in the development and periodic revision of the plan described in subparagraph (B)), and, in connection with such participation, the right to be provided with a reasonable explanation, in terms and language appropriate to such person’s condition and ability to understand, of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such person’s general mental condition and, if such program or facility has provided a physical examination, such person’s general physical condition;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the objectives of treatment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the nature and significant possible adverse effects of recommended treatments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the reasons why a particular treatment is considered appropriate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the reasons why access to certain visitors may not be appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any appropriate and available alternative treatments, services, and types of providers of mental health services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The right not to receive a mode or course of treatment, established pursuant to the treatment plan, in the absence of such person’s informed, voluntary, written consent to such mode or course of treatment, except treatment—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> during an emergency situation if such treatment is pursuant to or documented contemporaneously by the written order of a responsible mental health professional; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as permitted under applicable law in the case of a person committed by a court to a treatment program or facility.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The right not to participate in experimentation in the absence of such person’s informed, voluntary, written consent, the right to appropriate protections in connection with such participation, including the right to a reasonable explanation of the procedure to be followed, the benefits to be expected, the relative advantages of alternative treatments, and the potential discomforts and risks, and the right and opportunity to revoke such consent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The right to freedom from restraint or seclusion, other than as a mode or course of treatment or restraint or seclusion during an emergency situation if such restraint or seclusion is pursuant to or documented contemporaneously by the written order of a responsible mental health professional.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The right to a humane treatment environment that affords reasonable protection from harm and appropriate privacy to such person with regard to personal needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The right to confidentiality of such person’s records.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> The right to access, upon request, to such person’s mental health care records, except such person may be refused access to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information in such records provided by a third party under assurance that such information shall remain confidential; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> specific material in such records if the health professional responsible for the mental health services concerned has made a determination in writing that such access would be detrimental to such person’s health, except that such material may be made available to a similarly licensed health professional selected by such person and such health professional may, in the exercise of professional judgment, provide such person with access to any or all parts of such material or otherwise disclose the information contained in such material to such person.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The right, in the case of a person admitted on a residential or inpatient care basis, to converse with others privately, to have convenient and reasonable access to the telephone and mails, and to see visitors during regularly scheduled hours, except that, if a mental health professional treating such person determines that denial of access to a particular visitor is necessary for treatment purposes, such mental health professional may, for a specific, limited, and reasonable period of time, deny such access if such mental health professional has ordered such denial in writing and such order has been incorporated in the treatment plan for such person. An order denying such access should include the reasons for such denial.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The right to be informed promptly at the time of admission and periodically thereafter, in language and terms appropriate to such person’s condition and ability to understand, of the rights described in this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> The right to assert grievances with respect to infringement of the rights described in this section, including the right to have such grievances considered in a fair, timely, and impartial grievance procedure provided for or by the program or facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subparagraph (J), the right of access to (including the opportunities and facilities for private communication with) any available—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> rights protection service within the program or facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> rights protection service within the State mental health system designed to be available to such person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> qualified advocate;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">for the purpose of receiving assistance to understand, exercise, and protect the rights described in this section and in other provisions of law.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> The right to exercise the rights described in this section without reprisal, including reprisal in the form of denial of any appropriate, available treatment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> The right to referral as appropriate to other providers of mental health services upon discharge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The rights described in this section should be in addition to and not in derogation of any other statutory or constitutional rights.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The rights to confidentiality of and access to records as provided in subparagraphs (H) and (I) of paragraph (1) should remain applicable to records pertaining to a person after such person’s discharge from a program or facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No otherwise eligible person should be denied admission to a program or facility for mental health services as a reprisal for the exercise of the rights described in this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section should—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> obligate an individual mental health or health professional to administer treatment contrary to such professional’s clinical judgment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> prevent any program or facility from discharging any person for whom the provision of appropriate treatment, consistent with the clinical judgment of the mental health professional primarily responsible for such person’s treatment, is or has become impossible as a result of such person’s refusal to consent to such treatment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> require a program or facility to admit any person who, while admitted on prior occasions to such program or facility, has repeatedly frustrated the purposes of such admissions by withholding consent to proposed treatment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> obligate a program or facility to provide treatment services to any person who is admitted to such program or facility solely for diagnostic or evaluative purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> In order to assist a person admitted to a program or facility in the exercise or protection of such person’s rights, such person’s attorney or legal representatives should have reasonable access to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the areas of the program or facility where such person has received treatment, resided, or had access; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> pursuant to the written authorization of such person, the records and information pertaining to such person’s diagnosis, treatment, and related services described in paragraph (1)(I).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Each program and facility should post a notice listing and describing, in language and terms appropriate to the ability of the persons to whom such notice is addressed to understand, the rights described in this section of all persons admitted to such program or facility. Each such notice should conform to the format and content for such notices, and should be posted in all appropriate locations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a person adjudicated by a court of competent jurisdiction as being incompetent to exercise the right to consent to treatment or experimentation described in subparagraph (D) or (E) of paragraph (1), or the right to confidentiality of or access to records described in subparagraph (H) or (I) of such paragraph, or to provide authorization as described in paragraph (3)(C)(iii), such right may be exercised or such authorization may be provided by the individual appointed by such court as such person’s guardian or representative for the purpose of exercising such right or such authorization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a person who lacks capacity to exercise the right to consent to treatment or experimentation under subparagraph (D) or (E) of paragraph (1), or the right to confidentiality of or access to records described in subparagraph (H) or (I) of such paragraph, or to provide authorization as described in paragraph (3)(C)(iii), because such person has not attained an age considered sufficiently advanced under State law to permit the exercise of such right or such authorization to be legally binding, such right may be exercised or such authorization may be provided on behalf of such person by a parent or legal guardian of such person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A) and (B), in the case of a person admitted to a program or facility for the purpose of receiving mental health services, no individual employed by or receiving any remuneration from such program or facility should act as such person’s guardian or representative.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–398, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9502.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>SEX OFFENSE PREVENTION AND CONTROL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9511.</num>
<heading> Grants for sex offense prevention and control</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of National Center for the Prevention and Control of Sex Offenses; functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the National Center for the Prevention and Control of Sex Offenses (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”), may, directly or by grant, carry out the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A continuing study of sex offenses, including a study and investigation of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of existing Federal, State, and local laws dealing with sex offenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the relationship, if any, between traditional legal and social attitudes toward sexual roles, sex offenses, and the formulation of laws dealing with rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the treatment of the victims of sex offenses by law enforcement agencies, hospitals or other medical institutions, prosecutors, and the courts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the causes of sex offenses, identifying to the degree possible—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> social conditions which encourage sexual attacks, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the motives of offenders, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the impact of a sex offense on the victim and family of the victim;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> sexual assaults in correctional institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the estimated actual incidence of forcible sex offenses as compared to the reported incidence of forcible sex offenses and the reasons for any difference between the two; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of existing private and local and State government educational, counseling, and other programs designed to prevent and control sex offenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The compilation, analysis, and publication of summaries of the continuing study conducted under paragraph (1) and the research and demonstration projects conducted under paragraph (5). The Secretary shall submit not later than <date date="1983-03-30">March 30, 1983</date>, to the Congress a summary of such study and projects together with a review of their effectiveness and recommendations where appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The development and maintenance of an information clearinghouse with regard to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the prevention and control of sex offenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the treatment and counseling of the victims of sex offenses and their families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the rehabilitation of offenders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The compilation and publication of training materials for personnel who are engaged or intend to engage in programs designed to prevent and control sex offense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Assistance to qualified public and nonprofit private entities in conducting research and demonstration projects concerning the prevention and control of sex offense, including projects (A) for the planning, development, implementation, and evaluation of alternative methods used in the prevention and control of sex offense, the treatment and counseling of the victims of sex offense and their families, and the rehabilitation of offenders; (B) for the application of such alternative methods; and (C) for the promotion of community awareness of the specific locations in which, and the specific social and other conditions under which sexual attacks are most likely to occur.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory committee; functions, membership, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall appoint an advisory committee to advise, consult with, and make recommendations to the Secretary on the implementation of subsection (a). The recommendations of the committee shall be submitted directly to the Secretary without review or revision by any person without the consent of the committee. The Secretary shall appoint to such committee persons who are particularly qualified to assist in carrying out the functions of the committee. A majority of the members of the committee shall be women. Members of the advisory committee shall receive compensation at rates, not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate in effect for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule, for each day (including traveltime) they are engaged in the performance of their duties as members of the advisory committee and, while so serving away from their homes or regular places of business, each member shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in Government service employed intermittently.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission and approval of application; form, manner and contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No grant may be made under subsection (a) unless an application therefor is submitted to and approved by the Secretary. The application shall be submitted in such form and manner and contain such information as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated $6,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, $1,500,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>, $1,500,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Sex offense” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the term “sex offense” includes statutory and attempted rape and any other criminal sexual assault (whether homosexual or heterosexual) which involves force or the threat of force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–398, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1602</ref>, 1603; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(f)(20)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 87(d)(3)</ref>–(7), <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–654, § 3(b)(3)</ref>–(7), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3663</ref>, 3664.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9512.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9521.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9522.</num>
<heading> Report on shelter and basic living needs of chronically mentally ill individuals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congressional committees by Secretaries of Health and Human Services and Housing and Urban Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall jointly submit a report to the Committees on Labor and Human Resources and Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, and the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives, relating to Federal efforts to respond to the shelter and basic living needs of chronically mentally ill individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of the extent to which chronically mentally ill individuals remain inappropriately housed in institutional facilities or have otherwise inadequate or inappropriate housing arrangements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an analysis of available permanent noninstitutional housing arrangements for the chronically mentally ill;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> an evaluation of ongoing permanent and demonstration programs, funded in whole or in part by Federal funds, which are designed to provide noninstitutional shelter and basic living services for the chronically mentally ill, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of each program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total number of individuals estimated to be eligible to participate in each program, the number of individuals served by each program, and an estimate of the total population each program expects to serve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the effectiveness of each program in the provision of shelter and basic living services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommendations of measures to encourage States to coordinate and link the provisions in State health plans which relate to mental health and, in particular, the shelter and basic living needs of chronically mentally ill individuals, with local and State housing plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> recommendations for Federal legislation relating to the provision of permanent residential noninstitutional housing arrangements and basic living services for chronically mentally ill individuals, including an estimate of the cost of such recommendations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any other recommendations for Federal initiatives which, in the judgment of the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, will lead to improved shelter and basic living services for chronically mentally ill individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted to the committees referred to in subsection (a) no later than <date date="1981-01-01">January 1, 1981</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–398, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1606</ref>; H. Res. 549, <date date="1980-03-25">Mar. 25, 1980</date>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9523.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 902(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 560</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>