<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 44—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3531.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress hereby declares that the general welfare and security of the Nation and the health and living standards of our people require, as a matter of national purpose, sound development of the Nation’s communities and metropolitan areas in which the vast majority of its people live and work.</p>
<p class="indent0">To carry out such purpose, and in recognition of the increasing importance of housing and urban development in our national life, the Congress finds that establishment of an executive department is desirable to achieve the best administration of the principal programs of the Federal Government which provide assistance for housing and for the development of the Nation’s communities; to assist the President in achieving maximum coordination of the various Federal activities which have a major effect upon urban community, suburban, or metropolitan development; to encourage the solution of problems of housing, urban development, and mass transportation through State, county, town, village, or other local and private action, including promotion of interstate, regional, and metropolitan cooperation; to encourage the maximum contributions that may be made by vigorous private homebuilding and mortgage lending industries to housing, urban development, and the national economy; and to provide for full and appropriate consideration, at the national level, of the needs and interests of the Nation’s communities and of the people who live and work in them.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 2</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3532.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Department</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation; appointment and supervision of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established at the seat of government an executive department to be known as the Department of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Department”). There shall be at the head of the Department a Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”), who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Department shall be administered under the supervision and direction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General duties of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, among his responsibilities, advise the President with respect to Federal programs and activities relating to housing and urban development; develop and recommend to the President policies for fostering the orderly growth and development of the Nation’s urban areas; exercise leadership at the direction of the President in coordinating Federal activities affecting housing and urban development; provide technical assistance and information, including a clearinghouse service to aid State, county, town, village, or other local governments in developing solutions to community and metropolitan development problems; consult and cooperate with State Governors and State agencies, including, when appropriate, holding informal public hearings, with respect to Federal and State programs for assisting communities in developing solutions to community and metropolitan development problems and for encouraging effective regional cooperation in the planning and conduct of community and metropolitan development programs and projects; encourage comprehensive planning by the State aud <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003321">1</ref> local governments with a view to coordinating Federal, State, and local urban and community development activities; encourage private enterprise to serve as large a part of the Nation’s total housing and urban development needs as it can and develop the fullest cooperation with private enterprise in achieving the objectives of the Department; and conduct continuing comprehensive studies, and make available findings, with respect to the problems of housing and urban development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial or limitation of benefits of departmental programs, functions, or activities on basis of population or corporate status of community</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to deny or limit the benefits of any program, function, or activity assigned to the Department by this chapter or any other Act to any community on the basis of its population or corporate status, except as may be expressly provided by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of housing and urban development programs in enterprise zones</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote the coordination of all programs under the jurisdiction of the Secretary that are carried on within an enterprise zone designated pursuant to <ref>section 11501 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expedite, to the greatest extent possible, the consideration of applications for programs referred to in paragraph (1) through the consolidation of forms or otherwise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide, whenever possible, for the consolidation of periodic reports required under programs referred to in paragraph (1) into one summary report submitted at such intervals as may be designated by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3533.</num>
<heading> Officers of Department</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deputy Secretary, Assistant Secretaries, and General Counsel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department a Deputy Secretary, 7 Assistant Secretaries, and a General Counsel, who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall perform such functions, powers, and duties as the Secretary shall prescribe from time to time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Public Affairs, who shall be appointed by the President and shall perform such functions, powers, and duties as the Secretary shall prescribe from time to time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Housing Commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department a Federal Housing Commissioner, who shall be one of the Assistant Secretaries, who shall head a Federal Housing Administration within the Department, who shall have such duties and powers as may be prescribed by the Secretary, and who shall administer, under the supervision and direction of the Secretary, departmental programs relating to the private mortgage market. The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that managers of Federal Housing Administration programs, at each level of the Department, shall be accountable for program operation, risk management, management of cash and other Federal assets, and program financing related to activities over which such managers have responsibility.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director of Urban Program Coordination; designation; powers and duties; studies of urban and community problems and recommendations for administration of Federal programs affecting such problems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department a Director of Urban Program Coordination, who shall be designated by the Secretary. He shall assist the Secretary in carrying out his responsibilities to the President with respect to achieving maximum coordination of the programs of the various departments and agencies of the Government which have a major impact on community development. In providing such assistance, the Director shall make such studies of urban and community problems as the Secretary shall request, and shall develop recommendations relating to the administration of Federal programs affecting such problems, particularly with respect to achieving effective cooperation among the Federal, State, and local agencies concerned. Subject to the direction of the Secretary, the Director shall, in carrying out his responsibilities, (1) establish and maintain close liaison with the Federal departments and agencies concerned and (2) consult with State, local, and regional officials, and consider their recommendations with respect to such programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistant to Secretary; designation; duty to provide information and advice to nonprofit project sponsors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Assistant to the Secretary, designated by the Secretary, who shall be responsible for providing information and advice to nonprofit organizations desiring to sponsor housing projects assisted under programs administered by the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Assistant for Indian and Alaska Native Programs; report to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department a Special Assistant for Indian and Alaska Native Programs, who shall be located in the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Public and Indian Housing. The Special Assistant for Indian and Alaska Native Programs shall be designated by the Secretary not later than 60 days after <date date="1977-10-12">October 12, 1977</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Special Assistant for Indian and Alaska Native Programs shall be appointed based solely on merit and shall be covered under the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The Special Assistant for Indian and Alaska Native Programs shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> administering, in coordination with the relevant office in the Department, the provision of housing assistance to Indian tribes or Indian housing authorities under each program of the Department that provides for such assistance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> administering the community development block grant program for Indian tribes under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.] and the provision of assistance to Indian tribes under such Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> directing, coordinating, and assisting in managing any regional offices of the Department that administer Indian programs to the extent of such programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> coordinating all programs of the Department relating to Indian and Alaska Native housing and community development.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall include in the annual report under <ref>section 3536 of this title</ref> a description of the extent of the housing needs for Indian families and community development needs of Indian tribes in the United States and the activities of the Department, and extent of such activities, in meeting such needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall, not later than December 1 of each year, submit to Congress an annual report which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of his actions during the current year and a projection of his activities during the succeeding years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> estimates of the cost of the projected activities for succeeding fiscal years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a statistical report on the conditions of Indian and Alaska Native housing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> recommendations for such legislative, administrative, and other actions, as he deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Housing Administration Comptroller</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department a Federal Housing Administration Comptroller, designated by the Secretary, who shall be responsible for overseeing the financial operations of the Federal Housing Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Housing Counseling</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established, in the Department, the Office of Housing Counseling.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established the position of Director of Housing Counseling. The Director shall be the head of the Office of Housing Counseling and shall be appointed by, and shall report to, the Secretary. Such position shall be a career-reserved position in the Senior Executive Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall have primary responsibility within the Department for all activities and matters relating to homeownership counseling and rental housing counseling, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> research, grant administration, public outreach, and policy development relating to such counseling; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> establishment, coordination, and administration of all regulations, requirements, standards, and performance measures under programs and laws administered by the Department that relate to housing counseling, homeownership counseling (including maintenance of homes), mortgage-related counseling (including home equity conversion mortgages and credit protection options to avoid foreclosure), and rental housing counseling, including the requirements, standards, and performance measures relating to housing counseling.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Director shall carry out the functions assigned to the Director and the Office under this section and any other provisions of law. Such functions shall include establishing rules necessary for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the counseling procedures under <ref>section 1701x(g)(1) of title 12</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> carrying out all other functions of the Secretary under <ref>section 1701x(g) of title 12</ref>, including the establishment, operation, and publication of the availability of the toll-free telephone number under paragraph (2) of such section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> contributing to the distribution of home buying information booklets pursuant to <ref>section 2604 of title 12</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> carrying out the certification program under <ref>section 1701x(e) of title 12</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> carrying out the assistance program under <ref>section 1701x(a)(4) of title 12</ref>, including criteria for selection of applications to receive assistance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> carrying out any functions regarding abusive, deceptive, or unscrupulous lending practices relating to residential mortgage loans that the Secretary considers appropriate, which shall include conducting the study under section 6 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003322">1</ref> of the Expand and Preserve Home Ownership Through Counseling Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> providing for operation of the advisory committee established under paragraph (4) of this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> collaborating with community-based organizations with expertise in the field of housing counseling; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> providing for the building of capacity to provide housing counseling services in areas that lack sufficient services, including underdeveloped areas that lack basic water and sewer systems, electricity services, and safe, sanitary housing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory committee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall appoint an advisory committee to provide advice regarding the carrying out of the functions of the Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Such advisory committee shall consist of not more than 12 individuals, and the membership of the committee shall equally represent the mortgage and real estate industry, including consumers and housing counseling agencies certified by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (D), each member of the advisory committee shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. Members may be reappointed at the discretion of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of initial appointees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As designated by the Secretary at the time of appointment, of the members first appointed to the advisory committee, 4 shall be appointed for a term of 1 year and 4 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of pay; travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Members of the advisory committee shall serve without pay, but shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory role only</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The advisory committee shall have no role in reviewing or awarding housing counseling grants.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of homeownership counseling</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the responsibilities of the Director, the Director shall ensure that homeownership counseling provided by, in connection with, or pursuant to any function, activity, or program of the Department addresses the entire process of homeownership, including the decision to purchase a home, the selection and purchase of a home, issues arising during or affecting the period of ownership of a home (including refinancing, default and foreclosure, and other financial decisions), and the sale or other disposition of a home.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Position</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be in the Office of the Secretary a Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs, who shall report directly to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs shall be appointed based solely on merit and shall be covered under the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensuring veterans have fair access to housing and homeless assistance under each program of the Department providing either such assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinating all programs and activities of the Department relating to veterans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> serving as a liaison for the Department with the Department of Veterans Affairs, including establishing and maintaining relationships with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> serving as a liaison for the Department, and establishing and maintaining relationships with the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness and officials of State, local, regional, and nongovernmental organizations concerned with veterans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> providing information and advice regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sponsoring housing projects for veterans assisted under programs administered by the Department; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assisting veterans in obtaining housing or homeless assistance under programs administered by the Department;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> coordinating with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in carrying out section 404 of the Housing Opportunity Through Modernization Act of 2016;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> collaborating with the Department of Veterans Affairs on making joint recommendations to the Congress, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on how to better coordinate and improve services to veterans under both Department of Housing and Urban Development and Department of Veteran Affairs veterans housing programs, including ways to improve the Independent Living Program of the Department of Veteran Affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> carrying out such other duties as may be assigned to the Special Assistant by the Secretary or by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 4</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title VIII, § 808(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–448, title XVII, § 1708(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 606</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title IX, § 917</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1816</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–383, title VIII, § 818(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–128, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–235, title I</ref>, §§ 121, 122, 140, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2021</ref>, 2030; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 112(a)(4)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, 104 Stat.1427, 1454; <ref>Pub. L. 101–576, title II, § 205(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3866</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title XIV, § 1442</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2163</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(g)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–201, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-29">July 29, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3533a.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3534.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Housing and Home Finance Agency, Federal Housing Administration, and Public Housing Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section, there are hereby transferred to and vested in the Secretary all of the functions, powers, and duties of the Housing and Home Finance Agency, of the Federal Housing Administration and the Public Housing Administration in that Agency, and of the heads and other officers and offices of said agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government National Mortgage Association</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Government National Mortgage Association, together with its functions, powers, and duties, is hereby transferred to the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Studies of organization of housing and urban development functions and programs and recommendations regarding transfer of such functions and programs to or from Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall undertake studies of the organization of housing and urban development functions and programs within the Federal Government, and he shall provide the Congress with the findings and conclusions of such studies, together with his recommendations regarding the transfer of such functions and programs to or from the Department. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, none of the functions of the Secretary of the Interior authorized under chapter 2003 of title 54 or other functions carried out by the Bureau of Outdoor Recreation shall be transferred from the Department of the Interior or in any way be limited geographically unless specifically provided for by reorganization plan pursuant to provisions of chapter 9 of title 5, or by statute.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 5</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–448, title VIII, § 807(c)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1352</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I, § 1161(f)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3535.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel, assets, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, or other funds held, used, arising from, or available or to be made available in connection with, the functions, powers, and duties transferred by <ref>section 3534 of this title</ref> are hereby transferred with such functions, powers, and duties, respectively.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 90–448, title VIII, § 807(d)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 544</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment, compensation, authority, and duties of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized, subject to the civil service and classification laws, to select, appoint, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, as shall be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter and to prescribe their authority and duties: <i>Provided</i>, That any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, the Secretary may fix the compensation for not more than six positions in the Department at the annual rate applicable to positions in level V of the Executive Schedule provided by subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of authority; rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may delegate any of his functions, powers, and duties to such officers and employees of the Department as he may designate, may authorize such successive redelegations of such functions, powers, and duties as he may deem desirable, and may make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out his functions, powers, and duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary employment of experts or consultants; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may obtain services as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, at rates for individuals not to exceed the per diem equivalent to the highest rate for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>. The Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts with private companies for the provision of such managerial support to the Federal Housing Administration as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, including but not limited to the management of insurance risk and the improvement of the delivery of mortgage insurance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Working capital fund; establishment; uses; appropriations; capitalization; reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish a working capital fund, to be available without fiscal year limitation, for expenses necessary for the maintenance and operation of such common administrative services as he shall find to be desirable in the interest of economy and efficiency in the Department, including such services as a central supply service for stationery and other supplies and equipment for which adequate stocks may be maintained to meet in whole or in part the requirements of the Department and its agencies; central messenger, mail, telephone, and other communications services; office space; central services for document reproduction and for graphics and visual aids; and a central library service. In addition to amounts appropriated to provide capital for said fund, which appropriations are hereby authorized, the fund shall be capitalized by transfer to it of such stock of supplies and equipment on hand or on order as the Secretary shall direct. Such fund shall be reimbursed from available funds of agencies and offices in the Department for which services are performed at rates which will return in full all expenses of operation, including reserves for accrued annual leave and for depreciation of equipment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall cause a seal of office to be made for the Department of such device as he shall approve, and judicial notice shall be taken of such seal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial transactions, finality; checking accounts for funds in Treasury; availability of funds for administrative expenses; consolidation of cash for banking and checking purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as such authority is otherwise expressly provided in any other Act administered by the Secretary, such financial transactions of the Secretary as the making of loans or grants (and vouchers approved by the Secretary in connection with such financial transactions) shall be final and conclusive upon all officers of the Government. Funds made available to the Secretary pursuant to any provision of law for such financial transactions shall be deposited in a checking account or accounts with the Treasury of the United States. Such funds and any receipts and assets obtained or held by the Secretary in connection with such financial transactions shall be available, in such amounts as may from year to year be authorized by the Congress, for the administrative expenses of the Secretary in connection with such financial transactions. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the Secretary may, with the approval of the Comptroller General, consolidate into one or more accounts for banking and checking purposes all cash obtained or held in connection with such financial transactions, including amounts appropriated, from whatever source derived.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreclosure of property; actions for protection and enforcement of rights; purchase of property; dealing with property after such acquisition; deprivation of State court civil and criminal jurisdiction; impairment of civil rights under State laws; application of <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>; annual payments in lieu of local property taxes; sale and exchanges of property; insurance; modification of interest, time for installment payment, and other terms; other covenants, conditions, and provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as such authority is otherwise expressly provided in any other Act administered by the Secretary, the Secretary is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> foreclose on any property or commence any action to protect or enforce any right conferred upon him by any law, contract, or other agreement, and bid for and purchase at any foreclosure or any other sale any property in connection with which he has made a loan or grant. In the event of any such acquisition, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of real property by the United States, complete, administer, remodel and convert, dispose of, lease, and otherwise deal with, such property: <i>Provided</i>, That any such acquisition of real property shall not deprive any State or political subdivision thereof of its civil or criminal jurisdiction in and over such property or impair the civil rights under the State or local laws of the inhabitants on such property: <i>Provided further</i>, That <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref> shall not apply to any contract for services or supplies on account of any property so acquired or owned if the amount of such contract does not exceed $2,500;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter into agreements to pay annual sums in lieu of taxes to any State or local taxing authority with respect to any real property so acquired or owned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sell or exchange at public or private sale, or lease, real or personal property, and sell or exchange any securities or obligations, upon such terms as he may fix;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> obtain insurance against loss in connection with property and other assets held;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consent to the modification, with respect to the rate of interest, time of payment of any installment of principal or interest, security, or any other term of any contract or agreement to which he is a party or which has been transferred to him; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> include in any contract or instrument such other covenants, conditions, or provisions as he may deem necessary, including any provisions relating to the authority or requirements under paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees and charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law the Secretary is authorized to establish fees and charges, chargeable against program beneficiaries and project participants, which shall be adequate to cover over the long run, costs of inspection, project review and financing service, audit by Federal or federally authorized auditors, and other beneficial rights, privileges, licenses, and services. Such fees and charges heretofore or hereafter collected shall be considered nonadministrative and shall remain available for operating expenses of the Department in providing similar services on a consolidated basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gifts and services, acceptance; taxable status of property; investments; disbursements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to accept and utilize voluntary and uncompensated services and accept, hold, administer, and utilize gifts and bequests of property, both real and personal, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Department. Gifts and bequests of money and the proceeds from sales of other property received as gifts or bequests shall be deposited in the Treasury in a separate fund and shall be disbursed upon order of the Secretary. Property accepted pursuant to this paragraph, and the proceeds thereof, shall be used as nearly as possible in accordance with the terms of the gift or bequest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purpose of Federal income, estate, and gift taxes, property accepted under paragraph (1) shall be considered as a gift or bequest to or for use of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Upon the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury may invest and reinvest in securities of the United States or in securities guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States any moneys contained in the fund provided for in paragraph (1). Income accruing from such securities and from any other property held by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be deposited to the credit of the fund and shall be disbursed upon order of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultants; appointment of advisory committees; compensation and travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to appoint, without regard to the civil service laws, such advisory committees as shall be appropriate for the purpose of consultation with and advice to the Department in performance of its functions. Members of such committees, other than those regularly employed by the Federal Government, while attending meetings of such committees or otherwise serving at the request of the Secretary, may be paid compensation at rates not exceeding those authorized for individuals under subsection (e) of this section, and while so serving away from their homes or regular places of business, may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Occupancy preference in rental housing for military personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever he shall determine that, because of location, or other considerations, any rental housing project assisted under title II of the National Housing Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1707</ref> et seq.] or title I of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965 could ordinarily be expected substantially to serve the family housing needs of lower income military personnel serving on active duty, the Secretary is authorized to provide for or approve such preference or priority of occupancy of such project by such military personnel as he shall determine is appropriate to assure that the project will serve their needs on a continuing basis notwithstanding the frequency with which individual members of such personnel may be transferred or reassigned to new duty stations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Day care center for children of employees of Department; establishment; fees and charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized by contract or otherwise to establish, equip, and operate a day care center facility or facilities, or to assist in establishing, equipping, and operating interagency day care facilities for the purpose of serving children who are members of households of employees of the Department. The Secretary is authorized to establish or provide for the establishment of appropriate fees and charges to be chargeable against the Department of Housing and Urban Development employees or others who are beneficiaries of services provided by any such day care center. In addition, limited start-up costs may be provided by the Secretary in an amount limited to 3 per centum of the first year’s operating budget, but not to exceed $3,500.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agenda of rules or regulations under development or review; transmittal to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives an agenda of all rules or regulations which are under development or review by the Department. Such an agenda shall be transmitted to such Committees within 30 days of <date date="1978-10-31">October 31, 1978</date>, and at least semi-annually thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any rule or regulation which is on any agenda submitted under paragraph (1) may not be published for comment prior to or during the 15-calendar day period beginning on the day after the date on which such agenda was transmitted. If within such period, either Committee notifies the Secretary in writing that it intends to review any rule or regulation or portion thereof which appears on the agenda, the Secretary shall submit to both Committees a copy of any such rule or regulation, in the form it is intended to be proposed, at least 15 calendar days prior to its being published for comment in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any rule or regulation which has not been published for comment before <date date="1978-10-31">October 31, 1978</date>, and which does not appear on an agenda submitted under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to both such Committees at least 15 calendar days prior to its being published for comment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No rule or regulation may become effective until after the expiration of the 30-calendar day period beginning on the day after the day on which such rule or regulation is published as final. Any regulation implementing any provision of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989 that authorizes the imposition of a civil money penalty may not become effective until after the expiration of a public comment period of not less than 60 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3) may be waived upon the written request of the Secretary, if agreed to by the Chairmen and Ranking Minority Members of both Committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content>, (6) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–235, title I, § 123(4)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2021</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall include with each rule or regulation required to be transmitted to the Committees under this subsection a detailed summary of all changes required by the Office of Management and Budget that prohibit, modify, postpone, or disapprove such rule or regulation in whole or part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-benefit analysis of field reorganizations; requirements, contents, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A plan for the reorganization of any regional, area, insuring, or other field office of the Department of Housing and Urban Development may take effect only upon the expiration of 90 days after publication in the Federal Register of a cost-benefit analysis of the effect of the plan on each office involved. Such cost-benefit analysis shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an estimate of cost savings supported by background information detailing the source and substantiating the amount of the savings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an estimate of the additional cost which will result from the reorganization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a study of the impact on the local economy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an estimate of the effect of the reorganization on the availability, accessibility, and quality of services provided for recipients of those services,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">where any of the above factors cannot be quantified, the Secretary shall provide a statement on the nature and extent of those factors in the cost-benefit analysis.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(q)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any waiver of regulations of the Department shall be in writing and shall specify the grounds for approving the waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may delegate authority to approve a waiver of a regulation only to an individual of Assistant Secretary rank or equivalent rank, who is authorized to issue the regulation to be waived.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall notify the public of all waivers of regulations approved by the Department. The notification shall be included in a notice in the Federal Register published not less than quarterly. Each notification shall cover the period beginning on the day after the last date covered by the prior notification, and shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify the project, activity, or undertaking involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describe the nature of the requirement that has been waived and specify the provision involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> specify the name and title of the official who granted the waiver request;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> include a brief description of the grounds for approval of the waiver; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> state how more information about the waiver and a copy of the request and the approval may be obtained.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Any waiver of a provision of a handbook of the Department shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be in writing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specify the grounds for approving the waiver; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be maintained in indexed form and made available for public inspection for not less than the 3-year period beginning on the date of the waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(r)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program evaluation and monitoring</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the programs listed in paragraph (2), amounts appropriated under this subsection shall be available to the Secretary for evaluating and monitoring of all such programs (including all aspects of the public housing and section 202 programs) and collecting and maintaining data for such purposes. The Secretary shall expend amounts made available under this subsection in accordance with the need and complexity of evaluating and monitoring each such program and collecting and maintaining data for such purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The programs subject to this subsection shall be the programs authorized under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> titles I [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437</ref> et seq.] and II <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003323">1</ref> of the United States Housing Act of 1937;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1701q</ref>];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> section 106 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1701x</ref>];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Fair Housing Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> title I [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.] and section 810 <sup>1</sup> of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> section 201 of the Housing and Community Development Amendments of 1978 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1715z–1a</ref>];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Congregate Housing Services Act of 1978 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 8001</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> section 222 of the Housing and Urban-Rural Recovery Act of 1983;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>section 3616a of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 11360</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> titles II [<ref>42 U.S.C. 12721</ref> et seq.], III, and IV and section 811 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 8013</ref>] of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In conducting evaluations and monitoring pursuant to the authority under this subsection, and collecting and maintaining data pursuant to the authority under this subsection, the Secretary shall determine any need for additional staff and funding relating to evaluating and monitoring the programs under paragraph (2) and collecting and maintaining data for such purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide for evaluation and monitoring under this subsection and collecting and maintaining data for such purposes directly or by grants, contracts, or interagency agreements. Not more than 50 percent of the amounts made available under paragraph (1) may be used for grants, contracts, or interagency agreements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any amounts not used for grants, contracts, or interagency agreements under subparagraph (A) shall be used in a manner that increases and strengthens the ability of the Department to monitor and evaluate the programs under paragraph (2) and to collect and maintain data for such purposes through officers and employees of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 1993 and fiscal year 1994. Such amounts shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(s)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations; allocations for staff and training</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, there is authorized to be appropriated for salaries and expenses to carry out the purposes of this section $988,000,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $1,029,496,000 for fiscal year 1994.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated by this section, $96,000,000 shall be available for each of the fiscal years 1993 and 1994, which amounts shall be used to provide staff in regional, field, or zone offices of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to review, process, approve, and service applications for mortgage insurance under title II of the National Housing Act [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1707</ref> et seq.] for housing consisting of 5 or more dwelling units.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, not less than $5,000,000 of such amount shall be available for each fiscal year exclusively for the purposes of providing ongoing training and capacity building for Department personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(t)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training regarding issues relating to grandparent-headed and relative-headed families</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that all personnel employed in field offices of the Department who have responsibilities for administering the housing assistance program under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437f</ref>) or the supportive housing program under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1701q</ref>), and an appropriate number of personnel in the headquarters office of the Department who have responsibilities for those programs, have received adequate training regarding how covered families (as that term is defined in section 202 of the LEGACY Act of 2003) can be served by existing affordable housing programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 7</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title VIII, § 808(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–448, title VIII, § 807(d)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title I, § 120(c)</ref>, title IX, §§ 905, 906, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1775</ref>, 1809, 1811; <ref>Pub. L. 94–375</ref>, §§ 17(d), 21, <date date="1976-08-03">Aug. 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1077</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–557, title III</ref>, §§ 316, 324, title IX, § 908, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2099</ref>, 2103, 2129; <ref>Pub. L. 96–399, title III, § 334(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-08">Oct. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–479, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title V, § 563(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1944</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–235, title I</ref>, §§ 106, 123, 124, 141, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2000</ref>, 2021, 2022, 2030; <ref>Pub. L. 101–625, title IX, § 954(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX</ref>, §§ 902(b), (c), 929, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3867</ref>, 3887; <ref>Pub. L. 103–233, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–400, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1675</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–186, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3535a.</num>
<heading> Working capital fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the United States Treasury, pursuant to <ref>section 3535(f) of this title</ref>, a working capital fund for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (referred to in this paragraph as the “Fund”): <i>Provided</i>, That amounts transferred to the Fund under this heading shall be available for Federal shared services used by offices and agencies of the Department, and for such portion of any office or agency’s printing, records management, space renovation, furniture, or supply services as the Secretary determines shall be derived from centralized sources made available by the Department to all offices and agencies and funded through the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That of the amounts made available in this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003324">1</ref> for salaries and expenses under the headings “Executive Offices”, “Administrative Support Offices”, “Program Office Salaries and Expenses”, and “Government National Mortgage Association”, the Secretary shall transfer to the Fund such amounts, to remain available until expended, as are necessary to fund services, specified in the first proviso, for which the appropriation would otherwise have been available, and may transfer not to exceed an additional $10,000,000, in aggregate, from all such appropriations, to be merged with the Fund and to remain available until expended for use for any office or agency: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts in the Fund shall be the only amounts available to each office or agency of the Department for the services, or portion of services, specified in the first proviso: <i>Provided further</i>, That with respect to the Fund, the authorities and conditions under this heading shall supplant the authorities and conditions provided under <ref>section 3535(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. L, title II</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3536.</num>
<heading> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after the end of each calendar year, make a report to the President for submission to the Congress on the activities of the Department during the preceding calendar year. The report required under this section shall include the reports required under paragraphs (2) and (6) of <ref>section 3608(e) of this title</ref>, the reports required under subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 4856 of this title</ref>, the report required under section 1701<i>o</i> of title 12, and the report required under <ref>section 3533(e)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 8</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–569, title XI, § 1103(e)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 3031</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3536a.</num>
<heading> Report on interagency family economic empowerment strategies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall submit a report to the Congress annually that describes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any interagency strategies of such Departments that are designed to improve family economic empowerment by linking housing assistance with essential supportive services, such as employment counseling and training, financial education and growth, childcare, transportation, meals, youth recreational activities, and other supportive services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any actions taken in the preceding year to carry out such strategies and the extent of progress achieved by such actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–201, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2016-07-29">July 29, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 812</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3537.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other evidence of the intent of Congress, it is hereby declared to be the intent of Congress that if any provision of this chapter, or the application thereof to any persons or circumstances, shall be adjudged by any court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, such judgment shall not affect, impair, or invalidate the remainder of this chapter or its application to other persons and circumstances, but shall be confined in its operation to the provision of this chapter, or the application thereof to the persons and circumstances, directly involved in the controversy in which such judgment shall have been rendered.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 10</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 671</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3537a.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of advance disclosure of funding decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During any selection process, no officer or employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall knowingly disclose any covered selection information regarding such selection, directly or indirectly, to any person other than a person authorized by the Secretary to receive such information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative remedies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary receives or obtains information providing a reasonable basis to believe that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a selection that has not been made, determine whether to terminate the selection process or take other appropriate actions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a selection that has been made, determine whether to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> void or rescind the selection, subject to review and determination on the record after opportunity for a hearing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> impose sanctions upon the violating applicant selected, subject to review and determination on the record after opportunity for a hearing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> permit the violating applicant selected to continue to participate in the program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> take any other actions that the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil money penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever any employee of the Department knowingly and materially violates the prohibition in subsection (a), the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on the employee in accordance with the provisions of this subsection. This penalty shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary takes other disciplinary actions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of the penalty, as determined by the Secretary, may not exceed $10,000 for each violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish standards and procedures governing the imposition of civil money penalties under this subsection. The standards and procedures—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall provide for the Secretary or other official of the Department to make the determination to impose a penalty or to use an administrative entity to make the determination;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall provide for the imposition of a penalty only after the employee has been given an opportunity for a hearing on the record; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> may provide for review of any determination or order, or interlocutory ruling, arising from a hearing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If no hearing is requested within 15 days of receipt of the notice of opportunity for hearing, the imposition of the penalty shall constitute a final and unappealable order. If the Secretary reviews the determination or order, the Secretary may affirm, modify, or reverse that determination or order. If the Secretary does not review the determination or order within 90 days of the issuance of the determination or order, the determination or order shall be final.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors in determining amount of penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In determining the amount of a penalty under paragraph (2), consideration shall be given to such factors as the gravity of the offense, any history of prior disclosures of information on pending funding decisions made after <date date="1989-12-15">December 15, 1989</date>, ability to pay the penalty, injury to the public, benefits received, deterrence of future violations, and such other factors as the Secretary may determine in regulations to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviewability of imposition of a penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary’s determination or order imposing a penalty under paragraph (1) shall not be subject to review, except as provided in paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review of agency determination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">After exhausting all administrative remedies established by the Secretary under paragraph (3)(A), an employee against whom the Secretary has imposed a civil money penalty under paragraph (1) may obtain a review of the penalty and such ancillary issues (such as any administrative sanctions under 24 C.F.R. part 25) as may be addressed in the notice of determination to impose a penalty under paragraph (3)(A)(i) in the appropriate court of appeals of the United States, by filing in such court, within 20 days after the entry of such order or determination, a written petition praying that the Secretary’s order or determination be modified or be set aside in whole or in part.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objections not raised in hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The court shall not consider any objection that was not raised in the hearing conducted pursuant to paragraph (3)(A) unless a demonstration is made of extraordinary circumstances causing the failure to raise the objection. If any party demonstrates to the satisfaction of the court that additional evidence not presented at such hearing is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to present such evidence at the hearing, the court shall remand the matter to the Secretary for consideration of such additional evidence.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The decisions, findings, and determinations of the Secretary shall be reviewed pursuant to <ref>section 706 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Order to pay penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any such review, the court shall have the power to order payment of the penalty imposed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action to collect penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any employee fails to comply with the Secretary’s determination or order imposing a civil money penalty under paragraph (1), after the determination or order is no longer subject to review as provided by paragraphs (3)(A) and (4), the Secretary may request the Attorney General of the United States to bring an action in an appropriate United States district court to obtain a monetary judgment against the employee and such other relief as may be available. The monetary judgment may, in the court’s discretion, include the attorneys’ fees and other expenses incurred by the United States in connection with the action. In an action under this subsection, the validity and appropriateness of the Secretary’s determination or order imposing the penalty shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Settlement by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit any civil money penalty which may be, or has been, imposed under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall deposit all civil money penalties collected under this subsection into miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever willfully violates subsection (a) by making a disclosure prohibited by subsection (a) to any applicant, or any officer, employee, representative, agent, or consultant of any applicant, shall be imprisoned not more than 5 years, or fined in accordance with title 18, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “applicant” means any applicant or candidate that is being considered for receiving assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “assistance” means any grant, loan, subsidy, guarantee, or other financial assistance under a program administered by the Secretary that provides by statute, regulation, or otherwise for the competitive distribution of such assistance. The term does not include any mortgage insurance provided under a program administered by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered selection information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered selection information” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any information that is contained in any application or request for assistance, or any information regarding the decision of the Secretary to make available assistance or other information that is determined by the Secretary to be information that is not generally available to the public (not including program requirements and timing of the decision to make assistance available); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any information that is required by statute, regulation, or order to be confidential.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowingly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “knowingly” means having actual knowledge of or acting with deliberate ignorance of or reckless disregard for the prohibitions under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “selection” means the determination of which applicants for assistance are to receive assistance under the program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “selection process” means the period with respect to a selection for assistance that begins with the development, preparation, and issuance of a solicitation or request for applications for the assistance and concludes with the selection of recipients of assistance, and includes the evaluation of applications.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary deems appropriate to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply only with respect to violations that occur on or after December, 15, 1989.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 12</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–235, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3537b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–65, § 11(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-19">Dec. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 701</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3537c.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of lump-sum payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In providing relocation assistance in connection with any program administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary may not make lump-sum payments to any displaced residential tenant, except where necessary to cover—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> moving expenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a downpayment on the purchase of a replacement residence, including a condominium unit or membership in a cooperative housing association; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any incidental expenses related to paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–174, § 14</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 922</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3538.</num>
<heading> Rescheduling and refinancing of Federal loans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development is authorized to refinance any note or other obligation which is held by him in connection with any loan made by the Department of Housing and Urban Development or its predecessor in interest, or which is included within the revolving fund for liquidating programs established by the Independent Offices Appropriation Act of 1955 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1701g–5</ref>], where he finds such refinancing necessary because of the loss, destruction, or damage (as a result of a major disaster) to property or facilities securing such obligations. The Secretary may authorize a suspension in the payment of principal and interest charges on, and an additional extension in the maturity of, any such loan for a period not to exceed five years if he determines that such action is necessary to avoid severe financial hardship.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–606, title II, § 236(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3539.</num>
<heading> Housing and Urban Development Disaster Assistance Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development is authorized to establish a fund and to transfer to such fund from appropriations or funds available to the Department of Housing and Urban Development, such amounts as may be necessary to provide disaster assistance for which the Secretary has been requested by the President to make resources available pursuant to the authority of the Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–383, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1972-08-14">Aug. 14, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 553</ref>; 1973 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 1, 3(a)(1), eff. <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, 38 F.R. 9579, <ref>87 Stat. 1089</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 11749, § 2(1), <date date="1973-12-10">Dec. 10, 1973</date>, 38 F.R. 34177; Ex. Ord. No. 12148, § 4–201, <date date="1979-07-20">July 20, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 43239; <ref>Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 109(s)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3539a.</num>
<heading> Department of Housing and Urban Development Nonrecurring Expenses Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Department of Housing and Urban Development Nonrecurring Expenses Fund” (the Fund): <i>Provided</i>, That unobligated balances of expired discretionary funds appropriated for this or any succeeding fiscal year from the General Fund of the Treasury to the Department of Housing and Urban Development by this or any other Act may be transferred (not later than the end of the fifth fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such funds are available for the purposes for which they were appropriated) into the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available until expended, in addition to such other funds as may be available for such purposes, for capital needs of the Department, including facilities infrastructure and information technology infrastructure, subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts in the Fund may be obligated only after the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations are notified at least 15 days in advance of the planned use of funds.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–42, div. F, title II, § 235</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3540.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title IV, § 420</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3541.</num>
<heading> Paperwork reduction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that various departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government with responsibilities involving housing and housing finance programs, require, approve, use or otherwise employ a variety of different forms as residential mortgages (or deeds of trust or similar security instruments) as notes secured by those mortgages, and for applications, appraisals and other purposes, and that such duplication of forms constitutes a paperwork burden that adds to the costs imposed on the Nation’s homeowners and home buyers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that unnecessary paperwork impairs the effectiveness of Federal housing and housing finance programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that both single-family and multi-family programs are affected; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that simplification of paperwork imposed by Federal housing and housing finance programs would contribute to achieving the Nation’s housing goals by reducing housing costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uniform legal and other forms for use by agencies in housing programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, consistent with provisions of law governing the conduct of housing programs, employ in their respective programs—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> uniform single-family and multi-family note and mortgage forms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a uniform application form for mortgage approval and commitment for mortgage insurance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a uniform form for computation of the monthly net effective income of applicants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a uniform property appraisal form;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a uniform settlement statement which shall satisfy the requirements of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 2601</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> such other consolidated or simplified forms, particularly those which solicit identical or nearly identical information from the same persons in the conduct of two or more such programs, the consolidation or simplification of which the Secretaries of Housing and Urban Development and Agriculture and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs mutually agree would contribute to a reduction in the paperwork and regulatory burden of such programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, consistent with provisions of law governing their respective programs, provide by regulation for the elimination of forms which solicit information which is already available from other available sources through indexing or other means of identifying such forms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each agency referred to in subsection (b) may employ riders, addenda, or similar forms of modification agreements to adapt such uniform forms to its respective programs and policies, consistent with the goals of minimizing the use and extent of such modification agreements and maximizing the suitability of such forms for the use of all participants, public and private.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination and reports by Director of Office of Management and Budget</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall coordinate and monitor the development and implementation by Federal departments and agencies of the efforts required by subsection (b) and shall report to the Congress on such development and implementation and with respect to any provisions of law which unnecessarily prevent such departments and agencies from carrying out the provisions of this section as part of each report required under <ref>Public Law 93–556</ref>. Such report shall include an estimate of the reduction of the level of paperwork burden hours of the affected agencies as allocated by the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–557, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–153, title III, § 328</ref>, <date date="1979-12-21">Dec. 21, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–479, title II, § 204(n)(4)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(q)(10)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3542.</num>
<heading> Public notice and comment regarding demonstration programs not expressly authorized in law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No demonstration program not expressly authorized in law may be commenced by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development until (1) a description of such demonstration program is published in the Federal Register, which description may be included in a notice of funding availability; and (2) there expires a period of sixty calendar days following the date of such publication, during which period the Secretary shall fully consider any public comments submitted with respect to such demonstration program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section may be considered to authorize the conducting of any demonstration program by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 470], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3543.</num>
<heading> Preventing fraud and abuse in Department of Housing and Urban Development programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure of social security account number</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a condition of initial or continuing eligibility for participation in any program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development involving loans, grants, interest or rental assistance of any kind, or mortgage or loan insurance, and to ensure that the level of benefits provided under such programs is proper, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may require that an applicant or participant (including members of the household of an applicant or participant) disclose his or her social security account number or employer identification number to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the terms “applicant” and “participant” shall have such meanings as the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development by regulation shall prescribe. Such terms shall not include persons whose involvement is only in their official capacity, such as State or local government officials or officers of lending institutions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title I, § 165</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3544.</num>
<heading> Preventing fraud and abuse in housing and urban development programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicant; participant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “applicant” and “participant” shall have such meanings as the Secretary by regulation shall prescribe, except that such terms shall include members of an applicant’s or participant’s household, and such terms shall not include persons whose involvement is only in their official capacity, such as State or local government officials and officers of lending institutions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public housing agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “public housing agency” means any agency described in section 3(b)(6) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(6)</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development” includes Indian housing programs assisted under title II <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003325">1</ref> of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicant and participant consent</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As a condition of initial or continuing eligibility for participation in any program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development involving initial and periodic review of an applicant’s or participant’s income, and to assure that the level of benefits provided under the program is correct, the Secretary may require that an applicant or participant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sign a consent form approved by the Secretary authorizing the Secretary, the public housing agency, or the owner responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits to request current or previous employers to verify salary and wage information pertinent to the applicant’s or participant’s eligibility or level of benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sign a consent form approved by the Secretary authorizing the Secretary or the public housing agency responsible for determining eligibility or level of benefits to request a State agency charged with the administration of the State unemployment law to release wage information with respect to such applicant or participant or information regarding whether such applicant or participant is receiving, has received, or has made application for, unemployment compensation, and the amount of any such compensation being received (or to be received) by such applicant or participant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sign a consent form approved by the Secretary authorizing the Secretary to request the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary of the Treasury to release information pursuant to section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 with respect to such applicant or participant for the sole purpose of the Secretary verifying income information pertinent to the applicant’s or participant’s eligibility or level of benefits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> only in the case of an applicant or participant that is a member of a family described in section 3(f)(2) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(f)(2)</ref>), sign an agreement under which the applicant or participant agrees to provide to the appropriate public housing agency, or the owner responsible for determining the participant’s eligibility or level of benefits, the information required under section 3(f)(1) of such Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(f)(1)</ref>] for the sole purpose of verifying income information pertinent to the applicant’s or participant’s eligibility or level of benefits, and comply with such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Except as provided in this subsection, this consent form shall not be used to request taxpayer return information protected by <ref>section 6103 of title 26</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to records</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicant and participant protections</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In order to protect applicants for, and recipients of, benefits under the programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development from the improper use of information obtained pursuant to the requirements of <ref>section 503(i) of this title</ref> from the State agency charged with the administration of the State unemployment compensation law, pursuant to section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>] from the applicant or participant, or pursuant to section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 from the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary of the Treasury, officers and employees of the Department of Housing and Urban Development and (in the case of information obtained pursuant to such section 503(i) or 3(d)(1) [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>]) representatives of public housing agencies may only use such information—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to verify an applicant’s or participant’s eligibility for or level of benefits; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an owner or public housing agency responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits, to inform such owner or public housing agency that an applicant’s or participant’s eligibility for or level of benefits is uncertain and to request such owner or public housing agency to verify such applicant’s or participant’s income information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> No Federal, State, or local agency, or public housing agency, or owner responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits receiving such information may terminate, deny, suspend, or reduce any benefits of an applicant or participant until such agency or owner has taken appropriate steps to independently verify information relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of the wages, other earnings or income, or unemployment compensation involved,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> whether such applicant or participant actually has (or had) access to such wages, other earnings or income, or benefits for his or her own use, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the period or periods when, or with respect to which, the applicant or participant actually received such wages, other earnings or income, or benefits.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Such applicant or participant shall be informed by the agency or owner of the findings made by the agency or owner on the basis of such verified information, and shall be given an opportunity to contest such findings, in the same manner as applies to other information and findings relating to eligibility factors under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any information concerning an applicant or participant pursuant to the authority contained in <ref>section 503(i) of this title</ref>, section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], or section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 without consent or agreement, as applicable, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section or under false pretenses, or any person who knowingly and willfully discloses any such information in any manner to any individual not entitled under any law to receive it, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000. The term “person” as used in this paragraph shall include an officer or employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, an officer or employee of any public housing agency, and any owner responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits (or employee thereof).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any applicant or participant affected by (i) a negligent or knowing disclosure of information referred to in this section, <ref>section 503(i) of this title</ref>, section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], or section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 about such person by an officer or employee of any public housing agency or owner (or employee thereof), which disclosure is not authorized by this section, such section 503(i), such section 3(d)(1) [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], such section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix), or any regulation implementing this section, such section 503(i), such section 3(d)(1) [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], or such section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix), or for which consent, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, has not been granted, or (ii) any other negligent or knowing action that is inconsistent with this section, such section 503(i), such section 3(d)(1) [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], such section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix), or any such implementing regulation may bring a civil action for damages and such other relief as may be appropriate against any officer or employee of any public housing agency or owner (or employee thereof) responsible for any such unauthorized action. The district court of the United States in the district in which the affected applicant or participant resides, in which such unauthorized action occurred, or in which the applicant or participant alleged to be responsible for any such unauthorized action resides, shall have jurisdiction in such matters. Appropriate relief that may be ordered by such district courts shall include reasonable attorney’s fees and other litigation costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the provisions of this section shall take effect on <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Optional early implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the initiative of a State or an agency of the State, and with the approval of the Secretary of Labor, the amendments made by subsection (c)(1) may be made effective in such State on any date before <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, which is more than 90 days after <date date="1988-11-07">November 7, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any State the legislature of which has not been in session for at least 30 calendar days (whether or not consecutive) between <date date="1988-11-07">November 7, 1988</date>, and <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, the amendments made by subsection (c)(1) shall take effect 30 calendar days after the first day on which such legislature is in session on or after <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions of release of information by third parties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An applicant or participant under any program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development may not be required or requested to consent to the release of information by third parties as a condition of initial or continuing eligibility for participation in the program unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the request for consent is made, and the information secured is maintained, in accordance with this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003326">2</ref> <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the consent that is requested is appropriately limited, with respect to time and information relevant and necessary to meet the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3259</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 903(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3867</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title III, § 3003</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 338</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 508(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–74, title II, § 214(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-20">Oct. 20, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3545.</num>
<heading> HUD accountability</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice regarding assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of notice of availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the availability of any assistance under any program or discretionary fund administered by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of application procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a description of the form and procedures by which application for the assistance may be made, and any deadlines relating to the award or allocation of the assistance. Such description shall be designed to help eligible applicants to apply for such assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of selection criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less than 30 days before any deadline by which applications or requests for assistance under any program or discretionary fund administered by the Secretary must be submitted, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the criteria by which selection for the assistance will be made. Subject to <ref>section 1439 of this title</ref>, such criteria shall include any objective measures of housing need, project merit, or efficient use of resources that the Secretary determines are appropriate and consistent with the statute under which the assistance is made available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Documentation of decisions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall award or allocate assistance only in response to a written application in a form approved in advance by the Secretary, except where other award or allocation procedures are specified in statute.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall ensure that documentation and other information regarding each application for assistance is sufficient to indicate the basis on which any award or allocation was made or denied. The preceding sentence shall apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any application for an award or allocation of assistance made by the Secretary to a State, unit of general local government, or other recipient of assistance, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any application for a subsequent award or allocation of such assistance by such State, unit of general local government or other recipient.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall notify the public of all funding decisions made by the Department. The Secretary shall require any State or unit of general local government to notify the public of the award or allocation of such funding to subsequent recipients. The notification shall include the following elements for each funding decision:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the name and address of each funding recipient;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the name or other means of identifying the project, activity, or undertaking for each funding recipient;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the dollar amount of the funding for each project, activity, or undertaking;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the citation to the statutory, regulatory, or other criteria under which the funding decision was made; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> such additional information as the Secretary deems appropriate for a clear and full understanding of the funding decision.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The notification referred to in clause (i) of this subsection shall be published as a Notice in the Federal Register at least quarterly.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “funding decision” means the decision of the Secretary to make available grants, loans, or any other form of financial assistance to an individual or to an entity, including (but not limited to) a State or local government or agency thereof (including a public housing agency), an Indian tribe, or a nonprofit organization, under any program administered by the Department that provides, by statute, regulation, or otherwise, for the competitive distribution of financial assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register at least annually informing the public of the allocation of assistance under <ref>section 1439(d)(1)(A) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that each application and all related documentation and other information referred to in subparagraph (B), including each letter of support, is readily available for public inspection for a period of not less than 5 years, beginning not less than 30 days following the date on which the award or allocation is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may waive the requirements of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) if the Secretary determines that the waiver is required for appropriate response to an emergency. Not less than 30 days after providing a waiver under the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the Secretary’s reasons for so doing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosures by applicants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall require the disclosure of information with respect to any application for assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department for a project application submitted to the Secretary or to any State or unit of general local government by any applicant who has received or, in the determination of the Secretary, can reasonably be expected to receive assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department in excess of $200,000 in the aggregate during any fiscal year or such lower amount as the Secretary may establish by regulation. Such information shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other government assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Information regarding any related assistance from the Federal Government, a State, or a unit of general local government, or any agency or instrumentality thereof, that is expected to be made available with respect to the project or activities for which the applicant is seeking assistance. Such related assistance shall include but not be limited to any loan, grant, guarantee, insurance, payment, rebate, subsidy, credit, tax benefit, or any other form of direct or indirect assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interested parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The name and pecuniary interest of any person who has a pecuniary interest in the project or activities for which the applicant is seeking assistance. Persons with a pecuniary interest in the project or activity shall include but not be limited to any developers, contractors, and consultants involved in the application for assistance or the planning, development, or implementation of the project or activity. For purposes of this paragraph, residency of an individual in housing for which assistance is being sought shall not, by itself, be considered a pecuniary interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expected sources and uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A report satisfactory to the Secretary of the expected sources and uses of funds that are to be made available for the project or activity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updating of disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the period when an application is pending or assistance is being provided, the applicant shall update the disclosure required under the previous subsection within 30 days of any substantial change.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall certify that assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department, as such term is defined in subsection (m), except that for purposes of this subsection such term shall not include any mortgage insurance provided pursuant to title II of the National Housing Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1707</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003327">1</ref> to any housing project shall not be more than is necessary to provide affordable housing after taking account of assistance described in subsection (b)(1). The Secretary shall adjust the amount of such assistance awarded or allocated to an applicant to compensate in whole or in part, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, for any changes reported under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative remedies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary receives or obtains information providing a reasonable basis to believe that a violation of subsection (b) or (c) has occurred, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a selection that has not been made, determine whether to terminate the selection process or take other appropriate actions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a selection that has been made, determine whether to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> void or rescind the selection, subject to review and determination on the record after opportunity for a hearing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> impose sanctions upon the violator, including debarment, subject to review and determination on the record after opportunity for a hearing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recapture any funds that have been disbursed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> permit the violating applicant selected to continue to participate in the program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> take any other actions that the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a descriptive statement of each determination made and action taken under this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil money penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever any person knowingly and materially violates any provision of subsection (b) or (c), the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on that person in accordance with the provisions of this section. This penalty shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty, and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary imposes other administrative sanctions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of the penalty, as determined by the Secretary, may not exceed $10,000 for each violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency procedures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish standards and procedures governing the imposition of civil money penalties under subsection (f). These standards and procedures—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall provide for the Secretary to make the determination to impose the penalty or to use an administrative entity to make the determination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide for the imposition of a penalty only after the person has been given an opportunity for a hearing on the record; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may provide for review by the Secretary of any determination or order, or interlocutory ruling, arising from a hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If no hearing is requested within 15 days of receipt of the notice of opportunity for hearing, the imposition of the penalty shall constitute a final and unappealable determination. If the Secretary reviews the determination or order, the Secretary may affirm, modify, or reverse that determination or order. If the Secretary does not review the determination or order, the determination or order shall be final.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors in determining amount of penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In determining the amount of a penalty under subsection (f), consideration shall be given to such factors as the gravity of the offense, ability to pay the penalty, injury to the public, benefits received, deterrence of future violations, and such other factors as the Secretary may determine in regulations to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviewability of imposition of a penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary’s determination or order imposing a penalty under subsection (f) shall not be subject to review, except as provided in subsection (h).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review of agency determination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After exhausting all administrative remedies established by the Secretary under subsection (g)(1), a person against whom the Secretary has imposed a civil money penalty under subsection (f) may obtain a review of the penalty and such ancillary issues as may be addressed in the notice of determination to impose a penalty under subsection (g)(1)(A) in the appropriate court of appeals of the United States, by filing in such court, within 20 days after the entry of such order or determination, a written petition praying that the order or determination of the Secretary be modified or be set aside in whole or in part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objections not raised in hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The court shall not consider any objection that was not raised in the hearing conducted pursuant to subsection (g)(1) unless a demonstration is made of extraordinary circumstances causing the failure to raise the objection. If any party demonstrates to the satisfaction of the court that additional evidence not presented at the hearing is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to present such evidence at the hearing, the court shall remand the matter to the Secretary for consideration of such additional evidence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The decisions, findings, and determinations of the Secretary shall be reviewed pursuant to <ref>section 706 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Order to pay penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any such review, the court shall have the power to order payment of the penalty imposed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action to collect penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any person fails to comply with the determination or order of the Secretary imposing a civil money penalty under subsection (f), after the determination or order is no longer subject to review as provided by subsections (g)(1) and (h), the Secretary may request the Attorney General of the United States to bring an action in an appropriate United States district court to obtain a monetary judgment against the person and such other relief as may be available. The monetary judgment may, in the court’s discretion, include the attorneys’ fees and other expenses incurred by the United States in connection with the action. In an action under this subsection, the validity and appropriateness of the Secretary’s determination or order imposing the penalty shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Settlement by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit any civil money penalty which may be, or has been, imposed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary deems appropriate to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall deposit all civil money penalties collected under this section into miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Department” means the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “person” means an individual (including a consultant, lobbyist, or lawyer), corporation, company, association, authority, firm, partnership, society, State, local government, or any other organization or group of people.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department” includes any contract, grant, loan, cooperative agreement, or other form of assistance, including the insurance or guarantee of a loan, mortgage, or pool of mortgages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “knowingly” means having actual knowledge of or acting with deliberate ignorance of or reckless disregard for the prohibitions under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on the date specified in regulations implementing this section that are issued by the Secretary after notice and public comment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–235, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title VIII, § 2834(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3545a.</num>
<heading> Notification of issuance of electronic notice of availability of assistance or funding to be competitively awarded for certain programs or discretionary funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall, for fiscal year 2014 and subsequent fiscal years, notify the public through the Federal Register and other means, as determined appropriate, of the issuance of a notice of the availability of assistance or notice of funding availability (NOFA) for any program or discretionary fund administered by the Secretary that is to be competitively awarded. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for fiscal year 2014 and subsequent fiscal years, the Secretary may make the NOFA available only on the Internet at the appropriate Government Web site or through other electronic media, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. L, title II, § 226</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 632</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3546.</num>
<heading> Use of domestic products</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition against fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person shall not intentionally affix a label bearing the inscription of “Made in America”, or any inscription with that meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States, if that product is not a domestic product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each submit, before <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>, a report to the Congress on procurements of products that are not domestic products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Domestic product” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “domestic product” means a product—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that is manufactured or produced in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at least 50 percent of the cost of the articles, materials, or supplies of which are mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 920</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3547.</num>
<heading> Special projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to assure that the policies of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.] and other provisions of law which further the purposes of such Act (as specified in regulations issued by the Secretary) are most effectively implemented in connection with the expenditure of funds for special projects appropriated under an appropriations Act for the Department of Housing and Urban Development, such as special projects under the head “Annual Contributions for Assisted Housing” in title II of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1993, and to assure to the public undiminished protection of the environment, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may, under such regulations, in lieu of the environmental protection procedures otherwise applicable, provide for the release of funds for particular special projects upon the request of recipients of special projects assistance, if the State or unit of general local government, as designated by the Secretary in accordance with regulations, assumes all of the responsibilities for environmental review, decisionmaking, and action pursuant to such Act, and such other provisions of law as the regulations of the Secretary specify, that would otherwise apply to the Secretary were the Secretary to undertake such special projects as Federal projects.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out this section only after consultation with the Council on Environmental Quality. Such regulations shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide for monitoring of the performance of environmental reviews under this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the discretion of the Secretary, provide for the provision or facilitation of training for such performance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> subject to the discretion of the Secretary, provide for suspension or termination by the Secretary of the assumption under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of State or unit of general local government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary’s duty under subparagraph (B) shall not be construed to limit any responsibility assumed by a State or unit of general local government with respect to any particular release of funds under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve the release of funds for projects subject to the procedures authorized by this section only if, not less than 15 days prior to such approval and prior to any commitment of funds to such projects, the recipient submits to the Secretary a request for such release, accompanied by a certification of the State or unit of general local government which meets the requirements of paragraph (3). The Secretary’s approval of any such certification shall be deemed to satisfy the Secretary’s responsibilities under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.] and such other provisions of law as the regulations of the Secretary specify insofar as those responsibilities relate to the releases of funds for special projects to be carried out pursuant thereto which are covered by such certification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A certification under the procedures authorized by this section shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be in a form acceptable to the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be executed by the chief executive officer or other officer of the State or unit of general local government who qualifies under regulations of the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> specify that the State or unit of general local government under this section has fully carried out its responsibilities as described under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> specify that the certifying officer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consents to assume the status of a responsible Federal official under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.] and each provision of law specified in regulations issued by the Secretary insofar as the provisions of such Act or other such provision of law apply pursuant to paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is authorized and consents on behalf of the State or unit of general local government and himself or herself to accept the jurisdiction of the Federal courts for the purpose of enforcement of the responsibilities as such an official.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval by States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In cases in which a unit of general local government carries out the responsibilities described in paragraph (1), the Secretary may permit the State to perform those actions of the Secretary described in paragraph (2) and the performance of such actions by the State, where permitted by the Secretary, shall be deemed to satisfy the Secretary’s responsibilities referred to in the second sentence of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–233, title III, § 305(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3548.</num>
<heading> Semiannual report on contracts and task orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit semi-annually to the Committees on Appropriations a list of all contracts and task orders issued under such contracts in excess of $250,000 which were entered into during the prior 6-month period by the Secretary, the Government National Mortgage Association, and the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight (or by any officer of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Government National Mortgage Association, or the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight acting in his or her capacity to represent the Secretary or these entities). Each listing shall identify the parties to the contract, the term and amount of the contract, and the subject matter and responsibilities of the parties to the contract.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–18, title II, § 10001</ref>, <date date="1997-06-12">June 12, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3549.</num>
<heading> Investigation of violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on and after <date date="2003-02-20">February 20, 2003</date>, the Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall, in consultation with the Budget Officer, have sole authority to investigate potential or actual violations under the Anti-Deficiency Act (<ref>31 U.S.C. 1341</ref> et seq.) and all other statutes and regulations related to the obligation and expenditure of funds made available in this, or any other Act; shall determine whether violations exist; and shall submit final reports on violations to the Secretary, the President, the Office of Management and Budget and the Congress in accordance with applicable statutes and Office of Management and Budget circulars.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. K, title II</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3550.</num>
<heading> Audit of Department financial statements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For this fiscal year and each fiscal year thereafter, subject to appropriations for that purpose, the Office of Inspector General shall procure and rely upon the services of an independent external auditor(s) to audit the financial statements of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, including the consolidated financial statement and the financial statements of the Federal Housing Administration and the Government National Mortgage Association.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. L, title II</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1891</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>