<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 127—</num>
<heading>COORDINATED SERVICES FOR CHILDREN, YOUTH, AND FAMILIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12301.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> children and youth are inherently the most valuable resource of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the welfare, protection, healthy development, and positive role of children and youth in society are essential to the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> children and youth deserve love, respect, and guidance, as well as good health, shelter, food, education, productive employment opportunities, and preparation for responsible participation in community life;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> children and youth have increasing opportunities to participate in the decisions that affect their lives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the family is the primary caregiver and source of social learning and must be supported and strengthened;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> when a family is unable to ensure the satisfaction of basic needs of children and youth it is the responsibility of society to assist such family; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> it is the joint and several responsibility of the Federal Government, each State, and the political subdivisions of each State to assist children and youth to secure, to the maximum extent practicable, equal opportunity to full and free access to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the best possible physical and mental health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adequate and safe physical shelter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a high level of educational opportunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> effective training, apprenticeships, opportunities for community service, and productive employment and participation in decisions affecting their lives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a wide range of civic, cultural, and recreational activities that recognize young Americans as resources and promote self-esteem and a stake in the communities of such Americans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> comprehensive community services that are efficient, coordinated, readily available, and involve families of young individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families, as established under <ref>section 12311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Council” means the Federal Council on Children, Youth, and Families, as established under <ref>section 12314(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “‘nonprofit”, as applied to any agency, institution, or organization, means an agency, institution, or organization that is, or is owned and operated by, one or more corporations or associations, no part of the net earnings of which may lawfully inure to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Young individual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “young individual” means any child or youth from birth to 21 years of age.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ESTABLISHMENT OF ADMINISTRATION AND AWARDING OF GRANTS FOR PROGRAMS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Administration on Children, Youth, and Families</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12311.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Administration on Children, Youth, and Families</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of Health and Human Services an Administration on Children, Youth, and Families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commissioner</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Administration on Children, Youth, and Families, as established under subsection (a), shall be headed by a Commissioner on Children, Youth, and Families.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint the Commissioner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 915</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12312.</num>
<heading> Functions of Commissioner</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the effective and visible advocate for children, youth, and families within the Department of Health and Human Services and with other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government by maintaining active review and commenting responsibilities, as appropriate, concerning Federal policies affecting young individuals, and the families of young individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> collect and disseminate information related to the problems of young individuals and the families of such individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assist the Secretary in appropriate matters pertaining to young individuals, and the families of such individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> administer the grants authorized under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop plans and conduct research in the field of young individuals, and the families of such individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> assist, to the maximum extent practicable, in the establishment and implementation of programs designed to meet the needs of young individuals for supportive services including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> health and mental health services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> housing and shelter assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> education and training services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> protective services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> foster care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> teen parenting support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> child care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> family support and preservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> teen pregnancy prevention and counseling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> counseling on the effects of violence in the communities of such individuals and their families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> recreational and volunteer opportunities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> comprehensive early childhood development;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance and consultation to States and the political subdivisions of such States with respect to programs for young individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> prepare, publish, and disseminate educational materials concerning the welfare of young individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> gather statistics concerning young individuals, and the families of such individuals, that other Federal agencies are not collecting;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable coordinate activities carried out or assisted by all departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government with respect to the collection, preparation, and dissemination of information relevant to young individuals and the families of such individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> stimulate more effective uses of existing resources and available services for young individuals and the families of such individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> develop basic policies and set priorities with respect to the development and operation of programs and activities conducted under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> convene conferences of authorities and officials of organizations, including Federal, State, and local agencies, and nonprofit private organizations, of programs for children, youth and their families for the development and implementation of policies related to the priorities and purposes of this chapter, including topics such as the establishment of a nationwide network of comprehensive, coordinated services and opportunities for such individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> conduct periodic evaluations of the programs and activities related to the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> develop, in coordination with other agencies, methods to ensure adequate training for personnel concerning children, youth and families and to ensure the adequate dissemination of such information to appropriate State and community agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Encouragement of volunteerism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In executing the duties and functions of the Administration under this subchapter and in carrying out the programs and activities authorized under this chapter, the Commissioner, in consultation with the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, shall take necessary steps to coordinate with and seek the advice of voluntary agencies and organizations that provide services related to the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 916</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1263</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–82, title IV, § 405</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12313.</num>
<heading> Federal agency consultations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner shall consult and cooperate with the heads of all appropriate Federal agencies or departments administering programs or services that are substantially related to the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent practicable, the Commissioner shall facilitate cooperation through the entering into of interagency agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 917</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12314.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12315.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Commissioner</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Commissioner is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide consultative services, technical assistance, and short-term training to the independent State bodies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct research and demonstrations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collect, prepare, publish, and disseminate special educational or informational materials, including reports of the projects for which funds are provided under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide staff and other technical assistance to the Council;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> evaluate the effectiveness of programs authorized under this subchapter and periodically publish analyses of the results of such evaluations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year, prepare and submit, to the President and the chairman of the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the chairman of the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, a report concerning the activities carried out under this subchapter and concerning such other activities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of services and facilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to agreements made between the Commissioner and the head of such agency or organization, in carrying out the duties referred to in subsection (a) the Commissioner may utilize the services and facilities of any agency of the Federal Government and of any other public or nonprofit agency or organizations.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004040">1</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commissioner may pay for such services and facilities, in advance or by way of reimbursement, as may be provided in such agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the aggregate amount appropriated to carry out this chapter in any fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve not more than 10 percent for salaries and expenses of the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families related to the administration of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 919</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Grants for State and Community Programs for Children, Youth, and Families</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12331.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this part to encourage and assist State and local agencies to coordinate resources, reduce barriers to services, and develop new capacities to ensure that State and community services designed to serve children, youth, and families are more effective and comprehensive.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 925</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1268</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12332.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this part:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community referral services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “community referral services” means services to assist families in obtaining community resources, including health care, mental health care, employability development and job training, and other social services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Core services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “core services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> educational and support services provided to assist parents in acquiring parenting skills, learning about child development, and responding appropriately to the behavior of their children; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the early developmental screening of children to assess any needs of such children and to identify specific types of support that may be provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> outreach services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> community referral services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> follow up services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Follow up services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “follow up services” means services provided to ensure that necessary services are received by families and are effective in meeting their needs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent State body</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “independent State body” means the entity established under <ref>section 12336 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “lead agency” means an existing State agency, or other public or nonprofit private entity designated by the chief executive officer of the State as the agency responsible for the development and implementation of local family resource and support programs. Such agency shall have demonstrated ability to work with other State and community based agencies, to provide training and technical assistance, and shall also have a commitment to parental participation in the design and administration of family resource and support programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “other services” and “other support services” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> child care, early childhood development and intervention programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> employability development services (including skill training);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> educational services, such as scholastic tutoring, literacy training, and General Educational Degree (GED) services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> nutritional education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> life management skills training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> peer counseling and crisis intervention, family violence counseling and referrals for such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> referral for substance abuse counseling and treatment referral; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> referral for primary health and mental health services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “outreach services” means services provided to ensure (through home visits or other methods) that parents are aware of and able to participate in family resource and support program activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 926</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1268</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12333.</num>
<heading> Establishment of programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner shall make grants—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in each State under <ref>section 12337 of this title</ref> to improve State planning and coordination of services, and under <ref>section 12338 of this title</ref> to expand supportive services, in order to promote the availability of developmental, preventive, and remedial services to children, youth and their families that are designed to ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adequate and safe physical shelter whether in their own homes or, if necessary, in out-of-home programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> high quality physical and mental health care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the enhancement of the development of children to ensure that children enter school prepared and ready to learn;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> highest quality educational opportunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> effective training and apprenticeships to increase the likelihood of employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> opportunities for community service and productive employment, and for participation by children and youth in decisions affecting the lives of such children and youth; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a wide range of civic, cultural, and recreational activities that recognize young individuals as resources and promote self-esteem and a sense of community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to States on a competitive basis under section 12339 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004041">1</ref> of this title to establish family resource programs (including family support centers) in order to enhance the ability of families to remain together and to thrive through the provision of community based services that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promote and build family and parenting skills;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote and assist families in the use of formal and informal family support services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> create a support network to strengthen and reinforce good parenting; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> are closely linked with, but not duplicative of, other community resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 927</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12334.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner shall administer programs under this part through the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this part, the Commissioner may request the technical assistance and cooperation of the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Labor, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Transportation, the Director of the Office of Community Services, and such other agencies and departments of the Federal Government as may be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 928</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12335.</num>
<heading> State plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief executive officer of a State, in order to be eligible for grants from an allotment under section 12337, 12338, or 12339 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004042">1</ref> of this title for any fiscal year, shall prepare and submit to the Commissioner a State plan for a 3-year period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revisions of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each chief executive officer of a State may make annual revisions of the State plan referred to in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief executive officer of a State shall include within the State plan of that State assurances as required under sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004043">2</ref> 12337, 12338, or 12339 <sup>1</sup> of this title, and a description of the proposed multi-year plans of the State for program development and implementation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type of application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State may apply for funds under one or more of the following categories:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 12337 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sections 12337 and 12338 of this title jointly; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> section 12339 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of each category, the State application and plan shall comply only with the requirements of the appropriate section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commissioner shall approve any State plan under sections 12337 and 12338 of this title that the Commissioner determines meets the requirements of such sections.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice and opportunity to correct deficiencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commissioner shall not make a final determination disapproving any State plan, modifying such plan, or declaring a State to be ineligible to receive funds under sections 12337 and 12338 of this title without previously affording such State reasonable notice and opportunity to correct deficiencies in its application.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 929</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12336.</num>
<heading> Independent State body</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State shall not be eligible to receive a grant from an allotment under section 12337 or 12338 of this title unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the chief executive officer of such State designates an independent State body that is composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cabinet level representatives from each agency of such State that has responsibilities for programs affecting young individuals who shall comprise a majority of the independent State body; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> individuals appointed from among—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> private nonprofit providers of services to young individuals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> advocacy and citizens groups concerned with young individuals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> committees of the legislature of such State that have responsibility for young individuals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> leaders who are young individuals, including such leaders who are recipients of services provided under this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> representatives of the business community;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> representatives of employees of providers of services to young individuals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> representatives of general purpose local government; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<chapeau> such staff as shall be necessary to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> develop a State plan to be submitted to the Commissioner for approval under <ref>section 12337 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> administer and monitor the State plan within such State;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> assist in the coordination of all State activities related to the purpose of the chapter;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> serve as an effective and visible advocate for young individuals by reviewing and commenting on all State plans, budgets, and policies that affect such individuals and the families of such individuals by providing technical assistance to any agency, organization, association, or individual representing the needs of young individuals; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the independent State body designated under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develops a system for the distribution within the State of funds received under sections 12337 and 12338 of this title by the chief executive officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submits a description of such system to the Commissioner for review and comment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> ensures that preference will be given in such distribution of funds to developing or supporting local service delivery systems that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide a range of services organized to tailor responses to needs rather than a predetermined array of services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are rooted in and part of the communities that such systems are designed to serve as measured by the degree to which public and private community leaders and young individuals participate in the planning of such systems; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> demonstrate an ability to develop systematic collaboration among service providers on behalf of children, youth and families, including joint planning, joint financing, joint service delivery, common intake and assessment, and other arrangements that promote more effective service systems for such individuals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner may approve a State plan in which the chief executive officer of the State designates as the independent State body an existing State entity that is comprised of the parties described in subsection (a) and that is authorized to conduct the same range of interagency planning and coordination activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 930</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12337.</num>
<heading> State coordination of services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner shall make grants under this section to States on a formula basis for the purpose of improving the coordination of services provided to children, youth, and families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the chief executive officer of a State shall prepare and submit to the Commissioner an application containing a plan providing assurances that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the independent State body is committed to interagency planning that results in statewide policies promoting systematic collaboration among agencies on behalf of young individuals as demonstrated by joint planning, joint financing, joint service delivery, common intake and assessment, and other arrangements that reduce barriers to services and promote more effective local service delivery systems for young individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> such plan will be based on needs as identified through an analysis of updated reports (such as “State of the Child” reports) prepared by the State, including detailed information gathered by the State, to the extent practicable, on young individuals and the families of such individuals concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> age, sex, race, and ethnicity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the residences of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the incidence of homelessness among such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the composition of families of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the economic situations of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the incidence of poverty among such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> experiences in the care of such individuals away from home;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the health of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> violence in the homes or communities of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the nature of the attachment of such individuals to school and work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> dropout rates of such individuals from school; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> the character of the communities in which such individuals reside;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the system to be used for the distribution of funds within the State will require that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each area have an equal opportunity to apply for or receive funds under this part; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the public be given an opportunity to express views concerning the development and administration of such plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the independent State body will provide an inventory of existing public and private services for children, youth and their families and will evaluate the need for supportive services within the State to address the purposes of this chapter and determine the extent to which existing public and private programs meet such need;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the independent State body will make such reports, in such form, and containing such information, as the Commissioner may require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> such fiscal control and fund accounting procedures will be adopted as may be necessary to ensure proper disbursement of, and accounting for, Federal funds paid under this part to the chief executive officer of the State, including any such funds paid to the recipients of a grant or contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the independent State body will conduct periodic evaluations of activities and projects carried out pursuant to this section and <ref>section 12338 of this title</ref> and will report the results and recommendations to the chief executive officer of the State and the State legislature;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the chief executive officer of the State will provide technical assistance or in-service training opportunities for personnel responsible for carrying out the purposes of this section and <ref>section 12338 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the chief executive officer of each State will provide for the implementation of the requirements of <ref>section 12338 of this title</ref>, relating to supportive services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of grants to States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 12340(g) of this title</ref>, the amounts made available to each State under <ref>section 12340(a) of this title</ref> may be used to make grants to a State to enable such State to pay such percentages as the independent State body of such State determines to be appropriate, of the cost of administering the State plan of such State including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the costs of the preparation of such plan and the provision of technical assistance to local areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the costs of the evaluation of activities carried out under such plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the costs of the collection of data and the carrying out of analyses related to the need for supportive services within the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the costs of the dissemination of information obtained under paragraph (3); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the costs of the provision of short-term training to personnel of public or nonprofit private agencies and organizations engaged in the operation of programs authorized by this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004044">1</ref> Supplement not supplant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts received by a State under this section and <ref>section 12338 of this title</ref> shall be used only to supplement, not to supplant, the amount of Federal, State, and local funds expended for the purposes for which grants are made under this section and <ref>section 12338 of this title</ref>. In no event shall such expenditures be used to satisfy the matching requirements of any other Federal program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to family resource and support program grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a State intends to apply for a grant under section 12339 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004045">2</ref> of this title to be used for the same calendar year as the grant under this section, such State shall include in the application for a grant under this section a description of plans for family resource and support programs and for the coordination of the use of all funds received under this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 931</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12338.</num>
<heading> Supportive services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner shall carry out a program for making grants to a State, that has designated an independent State body under <ref>section 12336 of this title</ref> and provided for coordinated services under <ref>section 12337 of this title</ref>, for distribution by the chief executive officer under a State plan approved under <ref>section 12337 of this title</ref> to demonstrate successful program approaches to fill service gaps identified through State planning and advocacy efforts for any of the areas specified in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The services eligible to be provided under subsection (a) are services—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that are designed to facilitate the provision of comprehensive community based services that are efficient, coordinated, and readily available through such activities as case planning, case management, intake and assessment, and information and referral; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> that serve any of the following purposes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide adequate and safe physical shelter to young individuals and the families of such individuals, especially in emergency circumstances;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide transitional living services to young individuals who are homeless;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enable young individuals to attain and maintain physical and mental well-being;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide health screening to detect or prevent illnesses, or both, that occur most frequently in young individuals as well as better treatment and counseling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> enhance the development of children to ensure that such children enter school prepared and ready to learn;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> promote the highest quality of educational opportunity, especially through drop-out prevention programs, remediation for young individuals who have dropped out of school, and vocational education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> provide effective training apprenticeships and employment opportunities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> promote participation in community service and civic, cultural, and recreational activities that value young individuals as resources and promote self-esteem and a stake in the community;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> promote the participation of young individuals in decisions concerning planning and managing the lives of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> encourage young individuals and the families of such individuals to use any community facilities and services that are available to such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> ensure that young individuals who are unable to live with the biological families of such individuals have a safe place to live until such individuals can return home or move into independent adult life; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> prevent the abuse, neglect, or exploitation of young individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 932</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1273</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12339.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–252, title IV, § 401(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 672</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12340.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriation and allotment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration on Children, Youth, and Families; State coordination; supportive services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out sections 12337 and 12338 of this title such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1995 through 1998.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of appropriation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Of the amount appropriated under paragraph (1) for any fiscal year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not more than 10 percent shall be available to carry out <ref>section 12315 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less than 90 percent shall be available to carry out sections 12337 and 12338 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allotment formula</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (4), from the amount available under paragraph (2)(B) for each fiscal year, a State shall be allotted an amount that bears the same ratio to the amount appropriated for such fiscal year as the population of the State that is under the age of 21 bears to the population of all States that is under the age of 21.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and subject to the availability of appropriations under paragraph (1), no State shall be allotted less than $300,000 under the formula established under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on allotment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), Guam, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall each be allotted not less than $75,000 under the formula established under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of age</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The number of individuals under the age of 21 in each State shall be determined by the Commissioner on the basis of the most recent data available to the Commissioner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of allotted funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the Commissioner determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any amount allotted to a State for a fiscal year under section 12337 or 12338 of this title will not be used by such State for carrying out the purpose for which such allotment was made; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a State has failed to qualify under the State plan required under <ref>section 12335 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Commissioner shall make such allotment available for carrying out such purposes to other participating States in a proportional manner based on the relative population of the State of individuals under the age of 21.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–252, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 673</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State shall not use in excess of 10 percent of a grant awarded under section 12338 or 12339 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004046">1</ref> of this title for administrative activities at the State level.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for Indians</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner shall use 1 percent of the amount appropriated under this section for each fiscal year to make allotments to Indian tribes and tribal organizations (such terms having the same meaning given to such terms in section 5304(b) and (c) <sup>1</sup> of title 25) that submit to the Commissioner a plan that meets criteria consistent with the provisions of this part and that comply with other requirements established by the Commissioner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants made under this subchapter may be used to pay not more than 80 percent of the cost of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the preparation, administration, and evaluation of State plans under <ref>section 12337 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development of comprehensive, efficient, coordinated supportive services under <ref>section 12338 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the development, expansion, and operation of local family support and resource programs under section 12339 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The remaining 20 percent of such cost shall be paid by the State with funds from non-Federal sources.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 934</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1277</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–252, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">National Clearinghouse</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12351.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fundamental changes in the demographics and economics of family life in the United States over the past 20 years have had a profound effect on children and their parents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> since 1966, the number of women working outside the home has increased by 92 percent and the number of two earner families has increased by over 50 percent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 61 percent of the children born today will live in a single-parent family before reaching the age of 20, with one out of every three single female heads of households living on income below the Federal poverty level;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> one out of every four children under the age of 6 in the United States currently lives below the Federal poverty level;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> over the past 10 years, parents have increasingly come together with other parents to organize family resource and support programs that promote healthy child development and increase parental competency, particularly families at risk; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Federal investment in promoting the development of family resource and support programs will reap long-term benefits for individual families and the nation as a whole.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this part <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004047">1</ref> to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> stimulate the development and expansion of family resource and support programs that are prevention oriented;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage early intervention of such programs with families to ameliorate problem situations before such situations become crises; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assist parents in enhancing their children’s development to ensure that their children enter school prepared and ready to learn.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 956</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1278</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12352.</num>
<heading> “Family resource and support programs” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this part, the term “family resource and support programs” means community-based services that offer sustained assistance to families at various stages in their development. Such services shall promote parental competencies and behaviors that will lead to the healthy and positive personal development of parents and children through—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provision of assistance to build family skills and assist parents in improving their capacities to be supportive and nurturing parents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the provision of assistance to families to enable such families to use other formal and informal resources and opportunities for assistance that are available within the communities of such families; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the creation of supportive networks to enhance the childrearing capacity of parents and assist in compensating for the increased social isolation and vulnerability of families.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 957</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1278</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12353.</num>
<heading> Establishment of National Center on Family Resource and Support Programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commissioner shall establish, through grant or contract, a national center for the collection and provision of programmatic information and technical assistance that relates to all types of family resource and support programs, to be known as the “National Center on Family Resource and Support Programs”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The national center established under subsection (a) shall serve as a national information and data clearinghouse, training, technical assistance, and material development source for family resource and support programs. Such center shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and maintain a system for disseminating information on all types of family resource and support programs and on the state of family resource and support program development, including information concerning the most effective model programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop and sponsor a variety of training institutes and curricula for family resource and support program staff;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify several programs representing the various types of family resource and support programs to develop technical assistance materials and activities to assist other agencies in establishing family resource and support programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop State-wide networks of family resource and support programs for the purpose of sharing and disseminating information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 958</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–252, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12354.</num>
<heading> Evaluation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commissioner shall, through grants or contracts awarded or entered into with independent auditors, conduct evaluations and related activities, of family resource and support programs, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluations of on-going programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> process evaluations focusing on implementation strategies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the development of simple evaluation models for use by local family resource and support programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 959</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12355.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out <ref>section 12353 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1995 through 1998.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out <ref>section 12354 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1995, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1996 through 1998.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 960</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–252, title IV, § 403(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>WHITE HOUSE CONFERENCE ON CHILDREN, YOUTH, AND FAMILIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12371.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> children and youth are inherently our most valuable resource and their welfare, protection, healthy development, and positive role in society are essential to the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> children and youth deserve love, respect, and guidance, as well as good health, shelter, food, education, productive work, and preparation for responsible participation in community life;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an increasing opportunity for children and youth to participate in the decisions that affect their lives is essential;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the family is the primary caregiver and the source of social learning which must be supported and strengthened, but when families are unable to ensure the satisfaction of the needs of children and youth, it is society’s responsibility to assist them;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> at a minimum, all children and youth need and deserve access to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the best possible physical and mental health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adequate and safe physical shelter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the highest quality of educational opportunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> effective training, apprenticeships, opportunities for community service, and productive employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the widest range of civic, cultural, and recreational activities which recognize young Americans as resources and promote self-esteem and a stake in their communities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> comprehensive community services which are efficient, coordinated, and readily available; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> genuine participation in decisions concerning the planning and managing of their lives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> there is a great need for a comprehensive national policy with respect to young individuals, designed to engage Federal, State, and local government agencies, youth organizations, and other voluntary organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Congress that the Federal Government should work jointly with the States and their citizens to develop recommendations and plans for action to meet the challenge and needs of young individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 982</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12372.</num>
<heading> Authority of President and Secretary; final report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calling of Conference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall call a White House Conference on Children, Youth, and Families in 1993 in order to develop recommendations for further action in the field of children, youth, and families which will further the policy set forth in <ref>section 12371(b) of this title</ref>. The Conference shall be planned and conducted under the direction of the Secretary in cooperation with the Commissioner and with the heads of such other Federal departments and agencies as are appropriate. Such assistance may include the assignment of personnel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of Conference</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the Conference shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase the public awareness of the value and needs of young individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to examine the well-being of young individuals as well as the problems which they face;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to describe the extent to which young individuals with identified needs do not receive services to meet such needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to determine the reasons why young individuals are not receiving needed services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to develop such specific and comprehensive recommendations for executive and legislative action as may be appropriate to improve the well-being of youth and their families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conference participants and delegates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In order to carry out the purposes of the Conference, the Conference shall bring together—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> representatives of Federal, State, and local governments, including representatives of the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> professionals who are working in the field of children, youth, and families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> representatives of the general public, particularly young individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of delegates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The delegates to attend the Conference shall be selected without regard to political affiliation or past partisan activity and shall, to the best of the appointing authority’s ability, be representative of the spectrum of thought in the field of children, youth, and families.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 983</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12373.</num>
<heading> Conference administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> request the cooperation and assistance of the heads of such other Federal departments and agencies as may be appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> furnish all reasonable assistance to State agencies administering programs related to children, youth and families, and to other appropriate organizations, to enable them to organize and conduct conferences in conjunction with the Conference;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prepare and make available for public comment a proposed agenda for the Conference which reflects, to the greatest extent possible, the major issues facing children, youth, and families consistent with subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> prepare and make available background materials which the Secretary deems necessary for the use of delegates to the Conference; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> engage such additional personnel as may be necessary to carry out this section without regard to provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in carrying out the Secretary’s responsibilities and functions under this section, ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the conferences under subsection (a)(2) will be conducted so as to ensure broad participation of young individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the proposed agenda for the Conference under subsection (a)(3) is published in the Federal Register not less than 180 days before the beginning of the Conference and the proposed agenda is open for public comment for a period of not less than 60 days;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the final agenda for the Conference, taking into consideration the comments received under paragraph (2), is published in the Federal Register and transmitted to the chief executive officers of the States not later than 30 days after the close of the public comment period provided for under paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the personnel engaged under subsection (a)(5) shall be fairly balanced in terms of points of views represented and shall be appointed without regard to political affiliation or previous partisan activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the recommendations of the Conference are not inappropriately influenced by any appointing authority or by any special interest, but will instead be the result of the independent judgment of the Conference; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, current and adequate statistical data (including decennial census data) and other information on the well-being of young individuals in the United States are readily available, in advance of the Conference, to the delegates of the Conference, together with such information as may be necessary to evaluate Federal programs and policies relating to children and youth. In carrying out this subparagraph, the Secretary may make grants to, and enter into contracts with, public agencies and nonprofit private organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 984</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12374.</num>
<heading> Conference committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to the Conference which shall include representatives from the Federal Council on Children, Youth, and Families, public agencies and nonprofit private organizations as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may establish such other committees, including technical committees, as may be necessary to assist in the planning, conducting, and reviewing of the Conference.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition of committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each committee established under this section shall be composed of professionals and public members, and shall include individuals from low-income families and from minority groups.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of any committee established under this section (other than any officers or employees of the Federal Government), while attending conferences or meetings of the committee or otherwise serving at the request of the Secretary, shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the Secretary, but not to exceed the daily rate payable for GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> (including travel time). While away from their homes or regular places of business, such members may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized under section 5703 of such title for persons employed intermittently in Federal Government service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 985</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12375.</num>
<heading> Report of Conference</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A proposed report of the Conference which shall include a statement of comprehensive coherent national policy on children, youth, and families together with recommendations for the implementation of such policy, shall be published and submitted to the chief executive officers of the States not later than 180 days following the date on which the Conference is adjourned. The findings and recommendations included in the published proposed report shall be available immediately to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response to proposed report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief executive officers of the States, after reviewing and soliciting recommendations and comments on the proposed report of the Conference, shall submit to the Secretary, not later than 180 days after receiving such report, their views and findings on the recommendations of the Conference.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after submission of the views and comments of the chief executive officers of the States, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> prepare a final report on the conference, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a statement of the policy and recommendations of the Conference;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the views and comments of the chief executive officers of the States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the recommendations of the Secretary, after taking into consideration the views and comments of such officers, for administrative and legislative action necessary to implement the recommendations of the Conference; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> publish and transmit such report to the President and the chairman of the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and chairman of the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 986</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12376.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Conference” means the 1993 White House Conference on Children, Youth, and Families; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “child”, “youth”, and “young individual” means <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004048">1</ref> an individual who is less than 21 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 987</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12377.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary, for each of the fiscal years 1993 and 1994, to carry out this subchapter. Sums appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on the date the Conference is adjourned. New spending authority or authority to enter into contracts as provided in this subchapter shall be effective only to the extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return of unexpended funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any funds remaining upon the expiration of the 1-year period referred to in subsection (a) shall be returned to the Treasury of the United States and credited as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 988</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>