<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 53—</num>
<heading>ADVISORY COMMISSION ON INTERGOVERNMENTAL RELATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4271.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a permanent bipartisan commission to be known as the Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4272.</num>
<heading> Declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Because the complexity of modern life intensifies the need in a federal form of government for the fullest cooperation and coordination of activities between the levels of government, and because population growth and scientific developments portend an increasingly complex society in future years, it is essential that an appropriate agency be established to give continuing attention to intergovernmental problems.</p>
<p class="indent0">It is intended that the Commission, in the performance of its duties, will—</p>
<p class="indent1">(1) bring together representatives of the Federal, State, and local governments for the consideration of common problems;</p>
<p class="indent1">(2) provide a forum for discussing the administration and coordination of Federal grant and other programs requiring intergovernmental cooperation;</p>
<p class="indent1">(3) give critical attention to the conditions and controls involved in the administration of Federal grant programs;</p>
<p class="indent1">(4) make available technical assistance to the executive and legislative branches of the Federal Government in the review of proposed legislation to determine its overall effect on the Federal system;</p>
<p class="indent1">(5) encourage discussion and study at an early stage of emerging public problems that are likely to require intergovernmental cooperation;</p>
<p class="indent1">(6) recommend, within the framework of the Constitution, the most desirable allocation of governmental functions, responsibilities, and revenues among the several levels of government; and</p>
<p class="indent1">(7) recommend methods of coordinating and simplifying tax laws and administrative practices to achieve a more orderly and less competitive fiscal relationship between the levels of government and to reduce the burden of compliance for taxpayers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 2</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4273.</num>
<heading> Membership of Commission; appointment of members; term</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number of members; appointment; qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall be composed of twenty-six members, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Six appointed by the President of the United States, three of whom shall be officers of the executive branch of the Government, and three private citizens, all of whom shall have had experience or familiarity with relations between the levels of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Three appointed by the President of the Senate, who shall be Members of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Three appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, who shall be Members of the House;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Four appointed by the President from a panel of at least eight Governors submitted by the Governors’ Conference;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Three appointed by the President from a panel of at least six members of State legislative bodies submitted by the board of managers of the Council of State Governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Four appointed by the President from a panel of at least eight mayors submitted jointly by the National League of Cities and the United States Conference of Mayors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Three appointed by the President from a panel of at least six elected county officers submitted by the National Association of Counties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Political and geographical composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members appointed from private life under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall be appointed without regard to political affiliation; of each class of members enumerated in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a), two shall be from the majority party of the respective houses; of each class of members enumerated in paragraphs (4), (5), (6), and (7) of subsection (a), not more than two shall be from any one political party; of each class of members enumerated in paragraphs (5), (6) and (7) of subsection (a), not more than one shall be from any one State; at least two of the appointees under paragraph (6) of subsection (a) shall be from cities under five hundred thousand population.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office; reappointment; period of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term of office of each member of the Commission shall be two years; members shall be eligible for reappointment; and, except as provided in <ref>section 4274(d) of this title</ref>, members shall serve until their successors are appointed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 3</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–733</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4274.</num>
<heading> Organization of Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall convene the Commission within ninety days following <date date="1959-09-24">September 24, 1959</date> at such time and place as he may designate for the Commission’s initial meeting.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman and Vice Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall designate a Chairman and a Vice Chairman from among members of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies in membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any vacancy in the membership of the Commission shall be filed in the same manner in which the original appointment was made; except that where the number of vacancies is fewer than the number of members specified in paragraphs (4), (5), (6), and (7) of <ref>section 4273(a) of this title</ref>, each panel of names submitted in accordance with the aforementioned paragraphs shall contain at least two names for each vacancy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of service in official position from which originally appointed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where any member ceases to serve in the official position from which originally appointed under <ref>section 4273(a) of this title</ref>, his place on the Commission shall be deemed to be vacant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Thirteen members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but two or more members shall constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting hearings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 4</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 705</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4275.</num>
<heading> Duties of Commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Commission—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to engage in such activities and to make such studies and investigations as are necessary or desirable in the accomplishment of the purposes set forth in <ref>section 4272 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to consider, on its own initiative, ways and means for fostering better relations between the levels of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to submit an annual report to the President and the Congress on or before January 31 of each year. The Commission may also submit such additional reports to the President, to the Congress or any committee of the Congress, and to any unit of government or organization as the Commission may deem appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 5</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 705</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4276.</num>
<heading> Powers and administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings; oaths and affirmations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission or, on the authorization of the Commission, any subcommittee or members thereof, may, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, hold such hearings, take such testimony, and sit and act at such times and places as the Commission deems advisable. Any member authorized by the Commission may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Commission or any subcommittee or members thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation by Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each department, agency, and instrumentality of the executive branch of the Government, including independent agencies, is authorized and directed to furnish to the Commission, upon request made by the Chairman or Vice Chairman, such information as the Commission deems necessary to carry out its functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall have power to appoint, fix the compensation of, and remove an executive director without regard to the civil service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5. Such appointment shall be made solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position and without regard to political affiliation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of other personnel; temporary and intermittent services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to such rules and regulations as may be adopted by the Commission, the Chairman, without regard to the civil service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, and without reference to political affiliation, shall have the power—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to appoint, fix the compensation of, and remove such other personnel as he deems necessary,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to procure temporary and intermittent services to the same extent as is authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> but at rates not to exceed $50 a day for individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of other laws to employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, persons in the employ of the Commission under subsections (c) and (d)(1) of this section shall be considered to be Federal employees for all purposes, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> chapter 87 of title 5,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> annual and sick leave, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> subchapter I of chapter 57 of this title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum compensation of employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No individual employed in the service of the Commission shall be paid compensation for such employment at a rate in excess of the highest rate provided for grade 18 under the General Schedule, except that the executive director of the Commission may be paid compensation at any rate not exceeding the rate prescribed for level V in the Executive Schedule of subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 6</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 306(e)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–733</ref>, §§ 3, 4, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4277.</num>
<heading> Compensation of members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Members of the Commission who are Members of Congress, officers of the executive branch of the Federal Government, Governors, or full-time salaries officers of city and county governments shall serve without compensation in addition to that received in their regular public employment, but shall be allowed necessary travel expenses (or, in the alternative, a per diem in lieu of subsistence and mileage not to exceed the rates prescribed in subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5), without regard to subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, the Standardized Government Travel Regulations, or <ref>section 5731(a) of title 5</ref>, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of duties vested in the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Unless prohibited by State or local law, members of the Commission, other than those to whom subsection (a) is applicable, shall receive compensation at the rate of $50 per day for each day they are engaged in the performance of their duties as members of the Commission and shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties as members of the Commission, as provided for in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 7</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–733, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4278.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 8</ref>, <date date="1959-09-24">Sept. 24, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4279.</num>
<heading> Receipt of funds; consideration by Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to receive funds through grants, contracts, and contributions from State and local governments and organizations thereof, and from nonprofit organizations. Such funds may be received and expended by the Commission only for purposes of this chapter. In making appropriations to the Commission the Congress shall consider the amount of any funds received by the Commission in addition to those funds appropriated to it by the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–380, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 89–733, § 6</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>