<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>LEAD-BASED PAINT POISONING PREVENTION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GRANTS FOR DETECTION AND TREATMENT OF LEAD-BASED PAINT POISONING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4801.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–626, title II, § 208(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3588</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>GRANTS FOR ELIMINATION OF LEAD-BASED PAINT POISONING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4811.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–626, title II, § 208(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3588</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL DEMONSTRATION AND RESEARCH PROGRAM: FEDERAL HOUSING ADMINISTRATION REQUIREMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4821.</num>
<heading> Development of program; consultation; nature of program; safe level of lead; report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall develop and carry out a demonstration and research program to determine the nature and extent of the problem of lead based paint poisoning in the United States, particularly in urban areas, including the methods by which the lead based paint hazard can most effectively be removed from interior surfaces, porches, and exterior surfaces of residential housing to which children may be exposed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Consumer Product Safety Commission shall conduct appropriate research on multiple layers of dried paint film, containing the various lead compounds commonly used, in order to ascertain the safe level of lead in residential paint products. No later than <date date="1974-12-31">December 31, 1974</date>, the Chairman shall submit to Congress a full and complete report of his findings and recommendations as developed pursuant to such programs, together with a statement of any legislation which should be enacted or any changes in existing law which should be made in order to carry out such recommendations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–695, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1971-01-13">Jan. 13, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 2079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–151, § 3</ref>, <date date="1973-11-09">Nov. 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4822.</num>
<heading> Requirements for housing receiving Federal assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elimination of hazards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall establish procedures to eliminate as far as practicable the hazards of lead based paint poisoning with respect to any existing housing which may present such hazards and which is covered by an application for mortgage insurance or housing assistance payments under a program administered by the Secretary or otherwise receives more than $5,000 in project-based assistance under a Federal housing program. Beginning on <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, such procedures shall apply to all such housing that constitutes target housing, as defined in <ref>section 4851b of this title</ref>, and shall provide for appropriate measures to conduct risk assessments, inspections, interim controls, and abatement of lead-based paint hazards. At a minimum, such procedures shall require—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the provision of lead hazard information pamphlets, developed pursuant to <ref>section 2686 of title 15</ref>, to purchasers and tenants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> periodic risk assessments and interim controls in accordance with a schedule determined by the Secretary, the initial risk assessment of each unit constructed prior to 1960 to be conducted not later than <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, and, for units constructed between 1960 and 1978—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not less than 25 percent shall be performed by <date date="1998-01-01">January 1, 1998</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not less than 50 percent shall be performed by <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the remainder shall be performed by <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> inspection for the presence of lead-based paint prior to federally-funded renovation or rehabilitation that is likely to disturb painted surfaces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> reduction of lead-based paint hazards in the course of rehabilitation projects receiving less than $25,000 per unit in Federal funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> abatement of lead-based paint hazards in the course of substantial rehabilitation projects receiving more than $25,000 per unit in Federal funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> where risk assessment, inspection, or reduction activities have been undertaken, the provision of notice to occupants describing the nature and scope of such activities and the actual risk assessment or inspection reports (including available information on the location of any remaining lead-based paint on a surface-by-surface basis); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> such other measures as the Secretary deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional measures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may establish such other procedures as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of federally owned housing</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pre-1960 target housing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Beginning on <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, procedures established under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall require the inspection and abatement of lead-based paint hazards in all federally owned target housing constructed prior to 1960.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Target housing constructed between 1960 and 1978</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Beginning on <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, procedures established under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall require an inspection for lead-based paint and lead-based paint hazards in all federally owned target housing constructed between 1960 and 1978. The results of such inspections shall be made available to prospective purchasers, identifying the presence of lead-based paint and lead-based paint hazards on a surface-by-surface basis. The Secretary shall have the discretion to waive the requirement of this subparagraph for housing in which a federally funded risk assessment, performed by a certified contractor, has determined no lead-based paint hazards are present.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent that subparagraphs (A) and (B) increase the cost to the Government of outstanding direct loan obligations or loan guarantee commitments, such activities shall be treated as modifications under <ref>section 661c(e) of title 2</ref> and shall be subject to the availability of appropriations. To the extent that paragraphs (A) and (B) impose additional costs to the Resolution Trust Corporation and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, its requirements shall be carried out only if appropriations are provided in advance in an appropriations Act. In the absence of appropriations sufficient to cover the costs of subparagraphs (A) and (B), these requirements shall not apply to the affected agency or agencies.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For the purposes of this subsection, the terms “inspection”, “abatement”, “lead-based paint hazard”, “federally owned housing”, “target housing”, “risk assessment”, and “certified contractor” have the same meaning given such terms in <ref>section 4851b of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the terms “risk assessment”, “inspection”, “interim control”, “abatement”, “reduction”, and “lead-based paint hazard” have the same meaning given such terms in <ref>section 4851b of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Measurement criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The procedures established by the Secretary under this section for the risk assessment, interim control, inspection, and abatement of lead-based paint hazards in housing covered by this section shall be based upon guidelines developed pursuant to <ref>section 4852c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspection requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall require the inspection of all intact and nonintact interior and exterior painted surfaces of housing subject to this section for lead-based paint using an approved x-ray fluorescence analyzer, atomic absorption spectroscopy, or comparable approved sampling or testing technique. A certified inspector or laboratory shall certify in writing the precise results of the inspection. If the results equal or exceed a level of 1.0 milligrams per centimeter squared or 0.5 percent by weight, the results shall be provided to any potential purchaser or tenant of the housing. The Secretary shall periodically review and reduce the level below 1.0 milligram per centimeter squared or 0.5 percent by weight to the extent that reliable technology makes feasible the detection of a lower level and medical evidence supports the imposition of a lower level. The requirements of this subsection shall apply as provided in subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abatement required</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transitional testing and abatement in public housing receiving modernization assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of public housing assisted with capital assistance provided under <ref>section 1437g of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall require the inspection described in subsection (c) for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a random sample of dwellings and common areas in all public housing projects assisted under such section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each dwelling in any public housing project in which there is a dwelling determined under subparagraph (A) to have lead-based paint hazards, except that the Secretary shall not require the inspection of each dwelling if the Secretary requires the abatement of the lead-based paint hazards for the surfaces of each dwelling in the public housing project that correspond to the surfaces in the sample determined to have such hazards under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall require the inspection of all housing subject to this paragraph in accordance with the modernization schedule. A public housing agency may elect to test for lead-based paint using atomic absorption spectroscopy and may elect to abate lead-based paint and dust containing lead under standards more stringent than that in subsection (c), including the abatement of lead-based paint and dust which exceeds the standard of lead permitted in paints by the Consumer Product Safety Commission under this chapter, and such abatement shall qualify for capital assistance provided under <ref>section 1437g of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall require abatement of lead-based paint and lead-based paint hazards in housing in which the test results equal or exceed the standard established by or under subsection (c). Final inspection and certification after abatement shall be made by a qualified inspector, industrial hygienist, or local public health official.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abatement demonstration program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abatement demonstration program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out the requirements of this subsection with respect to single-family and multifamily properties owned by the Department of Housing and Urban Development and public housing, the Secretary shall utilize a sufficient variety of abatement methods in a sufficient number of areas and circumstances to demonstrate their relative cost-effectiveness and their applicability to various types of housing. For purposes of the demonstration, a public housing agency may elect to test for lead-based paint using atomic absorption spectroscopy and may elect to abate lead-based paint and dust containing lead under standards more stringent than that in subsection (c), including the abatement of lead-based paint and dust which exceeds the standard of lead permitted in paints by the Consumer Product Safety Commission under this chapter, and such abatement shall qualify for assistance under section 1437<i>l</i> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003375">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 18 months after the effective date of the regulations issued to carry out this subsection, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress the findings and recommendations of the Secretary as a result of the demonstration program, including any recommendations of the Secretary for legislation to revise the requirements of this subsection. Based on the demonstration, the Secretary shall prepare and include in the report a comprehensive and workable plan for the cost-effective inspection and abatement of public housing in accordance with paragraph (3), including an estimate of the total cost of abatement in accordance with paragraph (3)(B). In preparing such report, the Secretary shall examine—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the most reliable technology available for detecting lead-based paint, including X-ray fluorescence and atomic absorption spectroscopy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the most efficient and cost-effective methods for abatement, including removal, containment, or encapsulation of the contaminated components, procedures which minimize the generation of dust (including the high efficiency vacuum removal of leaded dust), and procedures that provide for offsite disposal of the removed components, in compliance with all applicable regulatory standards and procedures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> safety considerations in testing, abatement, and worker protection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the overall accuracy and reliability of laboratory testing of physical samples, x-ray fluorescence machines, and other available testing procedures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> availability of qualified samplers and testers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> an estimate of the amount, characteristics, and regional distribution of housing in the United States that contains lead-based paint hazards at differing levels of contamination; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the merits of an interim containment protocol for public housing dwellings that are determined to have lead-based paint hazards but for which comprehensive improvement assistance under section 1437<i>l</i> <sup>1</sup> of this title is not available.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Testing and abatement of other public housing</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required inspection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall require the inspection described in subsection (c) for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a random sample of dwellings and common areas in all public housing that is not subject to paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each dwelling in any public housing project in which there is a dwelling determined under clause (i) to have lead-based paint hazards, except that the Secretary shall not require the inspection of each dwelling if the Secretary requires the abatement of the lead-based paint hazards for the surfaces of each dwelling in the public housing project that correspond to the surfaces in the sample determined to have such hazards under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall require the inspection of all housing subject to this paragraph prior to the expiration of 5 years after the report is required to be transmitted under paragraph (2)(B). The Secretary may prioritize, within such 5-year period, inspections on the basis of vacancy, age of housing, or projected modernization or rehabilitation. The Secretary shall require abatement and final inspection and certification of such housing in accordance with the last two sentences of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 9 months after completion of the demonstration required by paragraph (2), the Secretary shall, based on the demonstration, prepare and transmit to the Congress, a comprehensive and workable plan, including any recommendations for changes in legislation, for the prompt and cost effective inspection and abatement of privately owned single family and multifamily housing, including housing assisted under <ref>section 1437f of this title</ref>. After the expiration of the 9-month period referred to in the preceding sentence, the Secretary may not obligate or expend any funds or otherwise carry out activities related to any other policy development and research project until the report is transmitted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> housing for the elderly or persons with disabilities, or any 0-bedroom dwelling, except for any dwelling in such housing in which any child who is under age 6 resides or is expected to reside; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any project for which an application for insurance is submitted under section 1715v, 1715w, 1715z–6, or 1715z–7 of title 12.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out the provisions of this section utilizing available Federal funding sources. The Secretary shall use funds available under the Capital Fund under <ref>section 1437g of this title</ref> to carry out this section in public housing. The Secretary shall submit annually to the Congress an estimate of the funds required to carry out the provisions of this section with the reports required by paragraphs (2)(B) and (4).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interpretation of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may not be construed to affect the responsibilities of the Environmental Protection Agency with respect to the protection of the public health from hazards posed by lead-based paint.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–695, title III, § 302</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–151, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-09">Nov. 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 566</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title V, § 566(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1945</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title X, § 1088(a)</ref>–(f), (h), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3280–3282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title X</ref>, §§ 1012(a)–(d), 1013, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3904</ref>, 3905, 3907; <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 522(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. K, title II, § 237(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 788</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>PROHIBITION AGAINST FUTURE USE OF LEAD-BASED PAINT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4831.</num>
<heading> Use of lead-based paint</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition by Secretary of Health and Human Services in application to cooking, drinking, or eating utensils</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall take such steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the application of lead-based paint to any cooking utensil, drinking utensil, or eating utensil manufactured and distributed after <date date="1971-01-13">January 13, 1971</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition by Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of use in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by Federal Government or with Federal assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall take steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the use of lead-based paint in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by the Federal Government, or with Federal assistance in any form after <date date="1971-01-13">January 13, 1971</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition by Consumer Product Safety Commission in application to toys or furniture articles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Consumer Product Safety Commission shall take such steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the application of lead-based paint to any toy or furniture article.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–695, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1971-01-13">Jan. 13, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 2079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–151, § 5</ref>, <date date="1973-11-09">Nov. 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–317, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-23">June 23, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4841.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “State” means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “units of general local government” means (A) any city, county, township, town, borough, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State, (B) any combination of units of general local government in one or more States, (C) an Indian tribe, or (D) with respect to lead-based paint poisoning elimination activities in their urban areas, the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “lead-based paint” means any paint containing more than five-tenths of 1 per centum lead by weight (calculated as lead metal) in the total nonvolatile content of the paint, or the equivalent measure of lead in the dried film of paint already applied, or both.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Consumer Product Safety Commission shall, during the six-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of the National Health Promotion and Disease Prevention Act of 1976, determine, on the basis of available data and information and after providing opportunity for an oral hearing and considering recommendations of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (including those of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention) and of the National Academy of Sciences, whether or not a level of lead in paint which is greater than six one-hundredths of 1 per centum but not in excess of five-tenths of 1 per centum is safe. If the Commission determines, in accordance with the preceding sentence, that another level of lead is safe, the term “lead-based paint” means, with respect to paint which is manufactured after the expiration of the six-month period beginning on the date of the Commission’s determination, paint containing by weight (calculated as lead metal) in the total nonvolatile content of the paint more than the level of lead determined by the Commission to be safe or the equivalent measure of lead in the dried film of paint already applied, or both.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Unless the definition of the term “lead-based paint” has been established by a determination of the Consumer Product Safety Commission pursuant to clause (i) of this subparagraph, the term “lead-based paint” means, with respect to paint which is manufactured after the expiration of the twelve-month period beginning on such date of enactment, paint containing more than six one-hundredths of 1 per centum lead by weight (calculated as lead metal) in the total nonvolatile content of the paint, or the equivalent measure of lead in the dried film of paint already applied, or both.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–695, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1971-01-13">Jan. 13, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 2080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–151, § 6</ref>, <date date="1973-11-09">Nov. 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–317, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-23">June 23, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–531, title III, § 312(g)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3506</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4842.</num>
<heading> Consultation by Secretary with other departments and agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out their respective authorities under this chapter, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall each cooperate with and seek the advice of the heads of any other departments or agencies regarding any programs under their respective responsibilities which are related to, or would be affected by, such authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–695, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1971-01-13">Jan. 13, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 2080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–317, title II, § 204(d)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-23">June 23, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4843.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter $10,000,000 for the fiscal year 1976, $12,000,000 for the fiscal year 1977, and $14,000,000 for the fiscal year 1978.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any amounts appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended when so provided in appropriation Acts; and any amounts authorized for one fiscal year but not appropriated may be appropriated for the succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–695, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1971-01-13">Jan. 13, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 2080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–151, § 7(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="1973-11-09">Nov. 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–317, title II, § 204(e)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-23">June 23, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 4844, 4845.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 95–626, title II, § 208(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3588</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4846.</num>
<heading> State laws superseded, and null and void</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is hereby expressly declared that it is the intent of the Congress to supersede any and all laws of the States and units of local government insofar as they may now or hereafter provide for a requirement, prohibition, or standard relating to the lead content in paints or other similar surface-coating materials which differs from the provisions of this chapter or regulations issued pursuant to this chapter. Any law, regulation, or ordinance purporting to establish such different requirement, prohibition, or standard shall be null and void.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–695, title V, § 504</ref>, formerly § 506, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–151, § 7(e)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-09">Nov. 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 568</ref>; renumbered § 504, <ref>Pub. L. 95–626, title II, § 208(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3588</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>