<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 160—</num>
<heading>TREATMENT OF CERTAIN PAYMENTS IN EUGENICS COMPENSATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18501.</num>
<heading> Exclusion of payments from State eugenics compensation programs from consideration in determining eligibility for, or the amount of, Federal public benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, payments made under a State eugenics compensation program shall not be considered as income or resources in determining eligibility for, or the amount of, any Federal public benefit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal public benefit</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal public benefit” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any grant, contract, loan, professional license, or commercial license provided by an agency of the United States or by appropriated funds of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any retirement, welfare, health, disability, public or assisted housing, postsecondary education, food assistance, unemployment benefit, or any other similar benefit for which payments or assistance are provided to an individual, household, or family eligibility unit by an agency of the United States or by appropriated funds of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State eugenics compensation program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State eugenics compensation program” means a program established by State law that is intended to compensate individuals who were sterilized under the authority of the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–241, § 2</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 976</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>