<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 51—</num>
<heading>DESIGN AND CONSTRUCTION OF PUBLIC BUILDINGS TO ACCOMMODATE PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4151.</num>
<heading> “Building” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “building” means any building or facility (other than (A) a privately owned residential structure not leased by the Government for subsidized housing programs and (B) any building or facility on a military installation designed and constructed primarily for use by able bodied military personnel) the intended use for which either will require that such building or facility be accessible to the public, or may result in the employment or residence therein of physically handicapped persons, which building or facility is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to be constructed or altered by or on behalf of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to be leased in whole or in part by the United States after <date date="1968-08-12">August 12, 1968</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to be financed in whole or in part by a grant or a loan made by the United States after <date date="1968-08-12">August 12, 1968</date>, if such building or facility is subject to standards for design, construction, or alteration issued under authority of the law authorizing such grant or loan; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to be constructed under authority of the National Capital Transportation Act of 1960, the National Capital Transportation Act of 1965, or title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–480, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-08-12">Aug. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 718</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–205</ref>, <date date="1970-03-05">Mar. 5, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–541, title II, § 201(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4152.</num>
<heading> Standards for design, construction, and alteration of buildings; Administrator of General Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall prescribe standards for the design, construction, and alteration of buildings (other than residential structures subject to this chapter and buildings, structures, and facilities of the Department of Defense and of the United States Postal Service subject to this chapter) to insure whenever possible that physically handicapped persons will have ready access to, and use of, such buildings.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–480, § 2</ref>, <date date="1968-08-12">Aug. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–541, title II, § 201(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4153.</num>
<heading> Standards for design, construction, and alteration of buildings; Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall prescribe standards for the design, construction, and alteration of buildings which are residential structures subject to this chapter to insure whenever possible that physically handicapped persons will have ready access to, and use of, such buildings.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–480, § 3</ref>, <date date="1968-08-12">Aug. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–541, title II, § 201(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4154.</num>
<heading> Standards for design, construction, and alteration of buildings; Secretary of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall prescribe standards for the design, construction, and alteration of buildings, structures, and facilities of the Department of Defense subject to this chapter to insure whenever possible that physically handicapped persons will have ready access to, and use of, such buildings.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–480, § 4</ref>, <date date="1968-08-12">Aug. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–541, title II, § 201(4)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4154a.</num>
<heading> Standards for design, construction, and alteration of buildings; United States Postal Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Postal Service, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall prescribe such standards for the design, construction, and alteration of its buildings to insure whenever possible that physically handicapped persons will have ready access to, and use of, such buildings.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–480, § 4a</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–541, title II, § 201(5)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2508</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4155.</num>
<heading> Effective date of standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every building designed, constructed, or altered after the effective date of a standard issued under this chapter which is applicable to such building, shall be designed, constructed, or altered in accordance with such standard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–480, § 5</ref>, <date date="1968-08-12">Aug. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 719</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4156.</num>
<heading> Waiver and modification of standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services, with respect to standards issued under <ref>section 4152 of this title</ref>, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, with respect to standards issued under <ref>section 4153 of this title</ref>, and the Secretary of Defense with respect to standards issued under <ref>section 4154 of this title</ref>, and the United States Postal Service with respect to standards issued under <ref>section 4154a of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is authorized to modify or waive any such standard, on a case-by-case basis, upon application made by the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States concerned, and upon a determination by the Administrator or Secretary, as the case may be, that such modification or waiver is clearly necessary, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall establish a system of continuing surveys and investigations to insure compliance with such standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–480, § 6</ref>, <date date="1968-08-12">Aug. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–541, title II, § 201(6)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4157.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</chapter>