<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 62—</num>
<heading>INTERGOVERNMENTAL PERSONNEL PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4701.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress hereby finds and declares—</p>
<p class="indent0">That effective State and local governmental institutions are essential in the maintenance and development of the Federal system in an increasingly complex and interdependent society.</p>
<p class="indent0">That, since numerous governmental activities administered by the State and local governments are related to national purpose and are financed in part by Federal funds, a national interest exists in a high caliber of public service in State and local governments.</p>
<p class="indent0">That the quality of public service at all levels of government can be improved by the development of systems of personnel administration consistent with such merit principles as—</p>
<p class="indent1">(1) recruiting, selecting, and advancing employees on the basis of their relative ability, knowledge, and skills, including open consideration of qualified applicants for initial appointment;</p>
<p class="indent1">(2) providing equitable and adequate compensation;</p>
<p class="indent1">(3) training employees, as needed, to assure high-quality performance;</p>
<p class="indent1">(4) retaining employees on the basis of the adequacy of their performance, correcting inadequate performance, and separating employees whose inadequate performance cannot be corrected;</p>
<p class="indent1">(5) assuring fair treatment of applicants and employees in all aspects of personnel administration without regard to political affiliation, race, color, national origin, sex, or religious creed and with proper regard for their privacy and constitutional rights as citizens; and</p>
<p class="indent1">(6) assuring that employees are protected against coercion for partisan political purposes and are prohibited from using their official authority for the purpose of interfering with or affecting the result of an election or a nomination for office.</p>
<p class="indent0">That Federal financial and technical assistance to State and local governments for strengthening their personnel administration in a manner consistent with these principles is in the national interest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4702.</num>
<heading> Administration of authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorities provided by this chapter shall be administered in such manner as (1) to recognize fully the rights, powers, and responsibilities of State and local governments, and (2) to encourage innovation and allow for diversity on the part of State and local governments in the design, execution, and management of their own systems of personnel administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DEVELOPMENT OF POLICIES AND STANDARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 4711 to 4713.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>STRENGTHENING STATE AND LOCAL PERSONNEL ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4721.</num>
<heading> Declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to assist State and local governments to strengthen their staffs by improving their personnel administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1911</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4722.</num>
<heading> State government and statewide programs and grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of grants; executive certification; systems of personnel administration: innovation and diversity in design, execution, and management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management (hereinafter referred to as the “Office”) is authorized to make grants to a State for up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, for up to 50 per centum) of the costs of developing and carrying out programs or projects, on the certification of the Governor of that State that the programs or projects contained within the State’s application are consistent with the applicable principles set forth in clauses (1)–(6) of the third paragraph of <ref>section 4701 of this title</ref>, to strengthen personnel administration in that State government or in local governments of that State. The authority provided by this section shall be employed in such a manner as to encourage innovation and allow for diversity on the part of State and local governments in the design, execution, and management of their own systems of personnel administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application; time of making; information; terms and conditions; personnel administration improvement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An application for a grant shall be made at such time or times, and contain such information, as the Office may prescribe. The Office may make a grant under subsection (a) of this section only if the application therefor—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides for designation, by the Governor or chief executive authority, of the State office that will have primary authority and responsibility for the development and administration of the approved program or project at the State level;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides for the establishment of merit personnel administration where appropriate and the further improvement of existing systems based on merit principles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provides for specific personnel administration improvement needs of the State government and, to the extent appropriate, of the local governments in that State, including State personnel administration services for local governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provides assurance that the making of a Federal Government grant will not result in a reduction in relevant State or local government expenditures or the substitution of Federal funds for State or local funds previously made available for these purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> sets forth clear and practicable actions for the improvement of particular aspects of personnel administration such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishment of statewide personnel systems of general or special functional coverage to meet the needs of urban, suburban, or rural governmental jurisdictions that are not able to provide sound career services, opportunities for advancement, adequate retirement and leave systems, and other career inducements to well-qualified professional, administrative, and technical personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> making State grants to local governments to strengthen their staffs by improving their personnel administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assessment of State and local government needs for professional, administrative, and technical manpower, and the initiation of timely and appropriate action to meet such needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> strengthening one or more major areas of personnel administration, such as recruitment and selection, training and development, and pay administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> undertaking research and demonstration projects to develop and apply better personnel administration techniques, including both projects conducted by State and local government staffs and projects conducted by colleges or universities or other appropriate nonprofit organizations under grants or contracts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> strengthening the recruitment, selection, assignment, and development of handicapped persons, women, and members of disadvantaged groups whose capacities are not being utilized fully;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> training programs related directly to upgrading within the agency for nonprofessional employees who show promise of developing a capacity for assuming professional responsibility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> achieving the most effective use of scarce professional, administrative, and technical manpower; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> increasing intergovernmental cooperation in personnel administration, with respect to such matters as recruiting, examining, pay studies, training, education, personnel interchange, manpower utilization, and fringe benefits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1911</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4723.</num>
<heading> Local government programs and grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Population served; amount of grants; executive certification; State grant, conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office is authorized to make grants to a general local government, or a combination of general local governments, that serve a population of fifty thousand or more, for up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, for up to 50 per centum) of the costs of developing and carrying out programs or projects, on the certification of the mayor(s), or chief executive officer(s), of the general local government or combination of local governments that the programs or projects are consistent with the applicable principles set forth in clauses (1)–(6) of the third paragraph of <ref>section 4701 of this title</ref>, to strengthen the personnel administration of such governments. Such a grant may not be made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if, at the time of submission of an application, the State concerned has an approved plan which, with the agreement of the particular local government concerned, provides for strengthening one or more aspects of personnel administration in that local government, unless the local government concerned has problems which are not met by the previously approved plan and for which, with the agreement of the State government concerned with respect to those aspects of personnel administration covered in the approved plan, it is submitting an application; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> after the State concerned has a statewide plan which has been developed by an appropriate State agency designated or established pursuant to State law which provides such agency with adequate authority, administrative organization, and staffing to develop and administer such a statewide plan, and to provide technical assistance and other appropriate support in carrying out the local components of the plan, and which provides procedures insuring adequate involvement of officials of affected local governments in the development and administration of such a statewide plan, unless the local government concerned has special, unique, or urgent problems which are not met by the approved statewide plan and for which it submits an application for funds to be distributed under <ref>section 4766(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Upon the request of a Governor or chief executive authority, a grant to a general local government or combination of such governments in that State may not be made during a period not to exceed ninety days commencing with the date provided in <ref>section 4772 of this title</ref>, or the date on which official regulations for this chapter are promulgated, whichever date is later: <i>Provided</i>, That the request of the Governor or chief executive authority indicates that he is developing a plan under (1) above, or during a period not to exceed one hundred and eighty days commencing with the date provided in <ref>section 4772 of this title</ref>, or the date on which official regulations for this chapter are promulgated, whichever date is later, provided the request of the Governor or chief executive authority indicates that he is developing a statewide plan under (2) above.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application; time of making; information; terms and conditions; waiver; development costs; population served</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An application for a grant from a general local government or a combination of general local governments shall be made at such time or times and shall contain such information as the Office may prescribe. The Office may make a grant under subsection (a) of this section only if the application therefor meets requirements similar to those established in <ref>section 4722(b) of this title</ref> for a State application for a grant, unless any such requirement is specifically waived by the Office, and the requirements of subsection (c) of this section. Such a grant may cover the costs of developing the program or project covered by the application. The Office may make grants to general local governments, or combinations of such governments, that serve a population of less than fifty thousand, if it finds that such grants will help meet essential needs in programs or projects of national interest and will assist general local governments experiencing special problems in personnel administration related to such programs or projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gubernatorial review of application; disapproval explanation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An application to be submitted to the Office under subsection (b) of this section shall first be submitted by the general local government or combination of such governments to the Governor for review, comments, and recommendations. The Governor may refer the application to the State office designated under <ref>section 4722(b)(1) of this title</ref> for review. Comments and recommendations (if any) made as a result of the review, and a statement by the general local government or combination of such governments that it has considered the comments and recommendations of the Governor shall accompany the application to the Office. The application need not be accompanied by the comments and recommendations of the Governor if the general local government or combination of such governments certifies to the Office that the application has been before the Governor for review and comment for a period of sixty days without comment by the Governor. An explanation in writing shall be sent to the Governor of a State by the Office whenever the Office does not concur with recommendations of the Governor in approving any local government applications.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1912</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4724.</num>
<heading> Intergovernmental cooperation in recruiting and examining activities; potential employees, certification; payments for costs; credits to appropriation or fund for payment of expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office may join, on a shared-costs basis, with State and local governments in cooperative recruiting and examining activities under such procedures and regulations as may jointly be agreed upon.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Office also may, on the written request of a State or local government and under such procedures as may be jointly agreed upon, certify to such governments from appropriate Federal registers the names of potential employees. The State or local government making the request shall pay the Office for the costs, as determined by the Office, of performing the service, and such payments shall be credited to the appropriation or fund from which the expenses were or are to be paid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1914</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4725.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance; waiver of payments for costs; credits to appropriation or fund for payment of expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office may furnish technical advice and assistance, on request, to State and general local governments seeking to improve their systems of personnel administration. The Office may waive, in whole or in part, payments from such governments for the costs of furnishing such assistance. All such payments shall be credited to the appropriation or fund from which the expenses were or are to be paid.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1914</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan. No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4726.</num>
<heading> Coordination of Federal programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office, after consultation with other agencies concerned, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate the personnel administration support and technical assistance given to State and local governments and the support given State programs or projects to strengthen local government personnel administration, including the furnishing of needed personnel administration services and technical assistance, under authority of this chapter with any such support given under other Federal programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make such arrangements, including the collection, maintenance, and dissemination of data on grants for strengthening State and local government personnel administration and on grants to States for furnishing needed personnel administration services and technical assistance to local governments, as needed to avoid duplication and insure consistent administration of related Federal activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1914</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4727.</num>
<heading> Interstate compacts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The consent of the Congress is hereby given to any two or more States to enter into compacts or other agreements, not in conflict with any law of the United States, for cooperative efforts and mutual assistance (including the establishment of appropriate agencies) in connection with the development and administration of personnel and training programs for employees and officials of State and local governments.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4728.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prescription of personnel standards on a merit basis</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are hereby transferred to the Office all functions, powers, and duties of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture under section 10(e)(2) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 of 1964 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2019(e)(2)</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003374">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Labor under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1933-06-06">June 6, 1933</date>, as amended (<ref>29 U.S.C. 49</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 503(a)(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Health and Human Services under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sections 2674(a)(6) and 2684(a)(6) of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 3023(a)(6) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sections 246(a)(2)(F) and (d)(2)(F) and 291d(a)(8) of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> sections 302(a)(5)(A), 602(a)(5)(A), 705(a)(3)(A), 1202(a)(5)(A), 1352(a)(5)(A), 1382(a)(5)(A), and 1396a(a)(4)(A) of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other department, agency, office, or officer (other than the President) under any other provision of law or regulation applicable to a program of grant-in-aid that specifically requires the establishment and maintenance of personnel standards on a merit basis with respect to the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">insofar as the functions, powers, and duties relate to the prescription of personnel standards on a merit basis.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards for systems of personnel administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with regulations of the Office of Personnel Management, Federal agencies may require as a condition of participation in assistance programs, systems of personnel administration consistent with personnel standards prescribed by the Office for positions engaged in carrying out such programs. The standards shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> include the merit principles in <ref>section 4701 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be prescribed in such a manner as to minimize Federal intervention in State and local personnel administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers and duties of Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide consultation and technical advice and assistance to State and local governments to aid them in complying with standards prescribed by the Office under subsection (a) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise Federal agencies administering programs of grants or financial assistance as to the application of required personnel administration standards, and recommend and coordinate the taking of such actions by the Federal agencies as the Office considers will most effectively carry out the purpose of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel, property, records, and funds; time of transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">So much of the personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds of any Federal agency employed, used, held, available, or to be made available in connection with the functions, powers, and duties vested in the Office by this section as the Director of the Management and Budget shall determine shall be transferred to the Office at such time or times as the Director shall direct.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification or supersedure of personnel standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Personnel standards prescribed by Federal agencies under laws and regulations referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall continue in effect until modified or superseded by standards prescribed by the Office under subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Systems of personnel administration; innovation and diversity in design, execution, and management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any standards or regulations established pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be such as to encourage innovation and allow for diversity on the part of State and local governments in the design, execution, and management of their own individual systems of personnel administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interpretation of certain provisions; limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section or in section 4722 or 4723 of this title shall be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> authorize any agency or official of the Federal Government to exercise any authority, direction, or control over the selection, assignment, advancement, retention, compensation, or other personnel action with respect to any individual State or local employee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> authorize the application of personnel standards on a merit basis to the teaching personnel of educational institutions or school systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prevent participation by employees or employee organizations in the formulation of policies and procedures affecting the conditions of their employment, subject to the laws and ordinances of the State or local government concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> require or request any State or local government employee to disclose his race, religion, or national origin, or the race, religion, or national origin, of any of his forebears;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> require or request any State or local government employee, or any person applying for employment as a State or local government employee, to submit to any interrogation or examination or to take any psychological test or any polygraph test which is designed to elicit from him information concerning his personal relationship with any person connected with him by blood or marriage, or concerning his religious beliefs or practices, or concerning his attitude or conduct with respect to sexual matters; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> require or request any State or local government employee to participate in any way in any activities or undertakings unless such activities or undertakings are related to the performance of official duties to which he is or may be assigned or to the development of skills, knowledge, or abilities which qualify him for the performance of such duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants-in-aid; abolition of certain requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective one year after <date date="1978-10-13">October 13, 1978</date>, all statutory personnel requirements established as a condition of the receipt of Federal grants-in-aid by State and local governments are hereby abolished, except—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> requirements prescribed under laws and regulations referred to in subsection (a) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requirements that generally prohibit discrimination in employment or require equal employment opportunity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> chapter 15 of title 5, relating to political activities of certain State and local employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, § 602(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1188</ref>, 1189; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(C)</ref>, (2)(CC), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1096</ref>, 1097; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(C), (2)(CC), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1859.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>TRAINING AND DEVELOPING STATE AND LOCAL EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4741.</num>
<heading> Declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to strengthen the training and development of State and local government employees and officials, particularly in professional, administrative, and technical fields.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1916</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4742.</num>
<heading> Admission to Federal employee training programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local government officers and employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with such conditions as may be prescribed by the head of the Federal agency concerned, a Federal agency may admit State and local government employees and officials to agency training programs established for Federal professional, administrative, or technical personnel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of payments for training costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Federal agencies may waive, in whole or in part, payments from, or on behalf of, State and local governments for the costs of training provided under this section. Payments received by the Federal agency concerned for training under this section shall be credited to the appropriation or fund used for paying the training costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial costs; reimbursement of other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office may use appropriations authorized by this chapter to pay the initial additional developmental or overhead costs that are incurred by reason of admittance of State and local government employees to Federal training courses and to reimburse other Federal agencies for such costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1916</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4743.</num>
<heading> Grants to State and local governments for training</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of grants; executive certification; use restrictions; uses for non-Federal share; personnel training and education programs: innovation and diversity in development and execution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If in its judgment training is not adequately provided for under grant-in-aid or other statutes, the Office is authorized to make grants to State and general local governments for up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, for up to 50 per centum) of the costs of developing and carrying out programs, on the certification of the Governor of that State, or the mayor or chief executive officer of the general local government, that the programs are consistent with the applicable principles set forth in clauses (1)–(6) of the third paragraph of <ref>section 4701 of this title</ref>, to train and educate their professional, administrative, and technical employees and officials. Such grants may not be used to cover costs of full-time graduate-level study, provided for in <ref>section 4745 of this title</ref>, or the costs of the construction or acquisition of training facilities. The State and local government share of the cost of developing and carrying out training and education plans and programs may include, but shall not consist solely of, the reasonable value of facilities and of supervisory and other personal services made available by such governments. The authority provided by this section shall be employed in such a manner as to encourage innovation and allow for diversity on the part of State and local governments in developing and carrying out training and education programs for their personnel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application; time of making; information; terms and conditions; waiver; development costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An application for a grant from a State or general local government shall be made at such time or times, and shall contain such information, as the Office may prescribe. The Office may make a grant under subsection (a) of this section, only if the application therefor meets requirements established by this subsection unless any requirement is specifically waived by the Office. Such grant to a State, or to a general local government under subsection (c) of this section, may cover the costs of developing the program covered by the application. The program covered by the application shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for designation, by the Governor or chief executive authority, of the State office that will have primary authority and responsibility for the development and administration of the program at the State level;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide, to the extent feasible, for coordination with relevant training available under or supported by other Federal Government programs or grants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for training needs of the State government and of local governments in that State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide, to the extent feasible, for intergovernmental cooperation in employee training matters, especially within metropolitan or regional areas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide assurance that the making of a Federal Government grant will not result in a reduction in relevant State or local government expenditures or the substitution of Federal funds for State or local funds previously made available for these purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Population served; amount of grants; executive certification; State grant, conditions; terms and conditions; waiver</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A grant authorized by subsection (a) of this section may be made to a general local government, or a combination of such governments, that serve a population of fifty thousand or more, for up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, for up to 50 per centum) of the costs of developing and carrying out programs or projects, on the certification of the mayor(s), or chief executive officer(s), of the general local government or combination of local governments that the programs or projects are consistent with the applicable principles set forth in clauses (1)–(6) of the third paragraph of <ref>section 4701 of this title</ref> to train and educate their professional, administrative, and technical employees and officials. Such a grant may not be made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if, at the time of submission of an application, the State concerned has an approved plan which, with the agreement of the particular local government concerned, provides for strengthening one or more aspects of training in that local government, unless the local government concerned has problems which are not met by the previously approved plan and for which, with the agreement of the State government concerned with respect to those aspects of training covered in the approved plan, it is submitting an application; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> after the State concerned has a statewide plan which has been developed by an appropriate State agency designated or established pursuant to State law which provides such agency with adequate authority, administrative organization, and staffing to develop and administer such a statewide plan, and to provide technical assistance and other appropriate support in carrying out the local components of the plan, and which provides procedures insuring adequate involvement of officials of affected local governments in the development and administration of such a statewide plan, unless the local government concerned has special, unique, or urgent problems which are not met by the approved statewide plan and for which it submits an application for funds to be distributed under <ref>section 4766(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Upon the request of a Governor or chief executive authority, a grant to a general local government or combination of such governments in that State may not be made during a period not to exceed ninety days commencing with the date provided in <ref>section 4772 of this title</ref>, or the date on which official regulations for this chapter are promulgated, whichever date is later: <i>Provided</i>, That the request of the Governor or chief executive authority indicates that he is developing a plan under (1) above, or during a period not to exceed one hundred and eighty days commencing with the date provided in <ref>section 4772 of this title</ref>, or the date on which official regulations for this chapter are promulgated, whichever date is later, provided the request of the Governor or chief executive authority indicates that he is developing a statewide plan under (2) above. To be approved, an application for a grant under this subsection must meet requirements similar to those established in subsection (b) of this section for State applications, unless any such requirement is specifically waived by the Office, and the requirements of subsection (d) of this section. The Office may make grants to general local governments, or combinations of such governments that serve a population of less than fifty thousand if it finds that such grants will help meet essential needs in programs or projects of national interest and will assist general local governments experiencing special needs for personnel training and education related to such programs or projects.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gubernatorial review of application; disapproval explanation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An application to be submitted to the Office under subsection (c) of this section shall first be submitted by the general local government or combination of such governments to the Governor for review, comments, and recommendations. The Governor may refer the application to the State office designated under subsection (b)(1) of this section for review. Comments and recommendations (if any) made as a result of the review and a statement by the general local government or combination of such governments that it has considered the comments and recommendations of the Governor shall accompany the application to the Office. The application need not be accompanied by the comments and recommendations of the Governor if the general local government or combination of such governments certifies to the Office that the application has been before the Governor for review and comment for a period of sixty days without comment by the Governor. An explanation in writing shall be sent to the Governor of a State by the Office whenever the Office does not concur with recommendations of the Governor in approving any local government applications.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1917</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4744.</num>
<heading> Grants to other organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of grants; conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office is authorized to make grants to other organizations to pay up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, up to 50 per centum) of the costs of providing training to professional, administrative, or technical employees and officials of State or local governments if the Office—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> finds that State or local governments have requested the proposed program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determines that the capability to provide such training does not exist, or is not readily available, within the Federal or the State or local governments requesting such program or within associations of State or local governments, or if such capability does exist that such government or association is not disposed to provide such training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> approves the program as meeting such requirements as may be prescribed by the Office in its regulations pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Other organization” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this section “other organization” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a national, regional, statewide, areawide, or metropolitan organization, representing member State or local governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an association of State or local public officials; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a nonprofit organization one of whose principal functions is to offer professional advisory, research, development, educational or related services to governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1919</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4745.</num>
<heading> Government Service Fellowships</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diverse payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office is authorized to make grants to State and general local governments to support programs approved by the Office for providing Government Service Fellowships for State and local government personnel. The grants may cover—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the necessary costs of the fellowship recipient’s books, travel, and transportation, and such related expenses as may be authorized by the Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reimbursement to the State or local government for not to exceed one-fourth of the salary of each fellow during the period of the fellowship; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> payment to the educational institutions involved of such amounts as the Office determines to be consistent with prevailing practices under comparable federally supported programs for each fellow, less any amount charged the fellow for tuition and nonrefundable fees and deposits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of fellowships; eligibility criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Fellowships awarded under this section may not exceed two years of full-time graduate-level study for professional, administrative, and technical employees. The regulations of the Office shall include eligibility criteria for the selection of fellowship recipients by State and local governments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of fellows; continuation of salary and employment benefits; public service plans upon completion of study: outline of plans in application for grant</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The State or local government concerned shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> select the individual recipients of the fellowships;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during the period of the fellowship, continue the full salary of the recipient and normal employment benefits such as credit for seniority, leave accrual, retirement, and insurance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make appropriate plans for the utilization and continuation in public service of employees completing fellowships and outline such plans in the application for the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1919</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4746.</num>
<heading> Coordination of Federal programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office, after consultation with other agencies concerned, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe regulations concerning administration of training for employees and officials of State and local governments provided for in this subchapter, including requirements for coordination of and reasonable consistency in such training programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate the training support given to State and local governments under authority of this chapter with training support given such governments under other Federal programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make such arrangements, including the collection and maintenance of data on training grants and programs, as may be necessary to avoid duplication of programs providing for training and to insure consistent administration of related Federal training activities, with particular regard to title IX of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1920</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4761.</num>
<heading> Declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to provide for the general administration of subchapters I, II, III, and IV of this chapter (hereinafter referred to as “this chapter”), and to provide for the establishment of certain advisory committees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4762.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Office” means the Office of Personnel Management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Federal agency” means an executive department, military department, independent establishment, or agency in the executive branch of the Government of the United States, including Government owned or controlled corporations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and a territory or possession of the United States, and includes interstate and Federal-interstate agencies but does not include the governments of the political subdivisions of a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “local government” means a city, town, county, or other subdivision or district of a State, including agencies, instrumentalities, and authorities of any of the foregoing and any combination of such units or combination of such units and a State. A “general local government” means a city, town, county, or comparable general-purpose political subdivision of a State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the population requirements of sections 4723(a) and 4743(c) of this title, a “local government” and a “general local government” also mean the recognized governing body of an Indian tribe, band, pueblo, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village, as defined in the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>85 Stat. 688</ref>) [<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], which performs substantial governmental functions. The requirements of sections 4723(c) and 4743(d) of this title, relating to reviews by the Governor of a State, do not apply to grant applications from the governing body of an Indian tribe, although nothing in this chapter is intended to discourage or prohibit voluntary communication and cooperation between Indian tribes and State and local governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1925</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–638, title I, § 104(d)</ref>, formerly § 105(d), <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2208</ref>, renumbered § 104(d), <ref>Pub. L. 100–472, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-05">Oct. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1189</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4763.</num>
<heading> General administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration by Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless otherwise specifically provided, the Office shall administer this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advice and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall furnish such advice and assistance to State and local governments as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations and standards; contracts: modification, covenants, conditions, and provisions; utilization of other agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the performance of, and with respect to, the functions, powers, and duties vested in it by this chapter, the Office may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue such standards and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consent to the modification of any contract entered into pursuant to this chapter, such consent being subject to any specific limitations of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include in any contract made pursuant to this chapter such covenants, conditions, or provisions as it deems necessary to assure that the purposes of this chapter will be achieved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> utilize the services and facilities of any Federal agency, any State or local government, and any other public or nonprofit agency or institution, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, in accordance with agreements between the Office and the head thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information: collection and availability; research and evaluation; administration report; coordination of Federal programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the performance of, and with respect to the functions, powers, and duties vested in it by this chapter, the Office—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may collect information from time to time with respect to State and local government training programs and personnel administration improvement programs and projects under this chapter, and make such information available to interested groups, organizations, or agencies, public or private;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may conduct such research and make such evaluation as needed for the efficient administration of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall include in its annual report a report of the administration of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall make such arrangements as may be necessary to avoid duplication of programs providing for training and to insure consistent administration of the related Federal training activities, with particular regard to title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter are not a limitation on existing authorities under other statutes but are in addition to any such authorities, unless otherwise specifically provided in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1926</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4764.</num>
<heading> Reporting and recordkeeping requirements for State or local governments and other organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A State or local government office designated to administer a program or project under this chapter shall make reports and evaluations in such form, at such times, and containing such information concerning the status and application of Federal funds and the operation of the approved program or project as the Office may require, and shall keep and make available such records as may be required by the Office for the verification of such reports and evaluations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An organization which receives a training grant under <ref>section 4744 of this title</ref> shall make reports and evaluations in such form, at such times, and containing such information concerning the status and application of Federal grant funds and the operation of the training program as the Office may require, and shall keep and make available such records as may be required by the Office for the verification of such reports and evaluations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1926</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4765.</num>
<heading> Review and audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office, the head of the Federal agency concerned, and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access, for the purpose of audit and examination, to any books, documents, papers, and records of a grant recipient that are pertinent to the grant received.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1927</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4766.</num>
<heading> Distribution of grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local government allocations; equitable distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall allocate 20 per centum of the total amount available for grants under this chapter in such manner as will most nearly provide an equitable distribution of the grants among States and between State and local governments, taking into consideration such factors as the size of the population, number of employees affected, the urgency of the programs or projects, the need for funds to carry out the purposes of this chapter, and the potential of the governmental jurisdictions concerned to use the funds most effectively.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Weighted formula; minimum allocation; reallocation; “State” defined</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office shall allocate 80 per centum of the total amount available for grants under this chapter among the States on a weighted formula taking into consideration such factors as the size of population and the number of State and local government employees affected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount allocated for each State under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be further allocated by the Office to meet the needs of both the State government and the local governments within the State on a weighted formula taking into consideration such factors as the number of State and local government employees and the amount of State and local government expenditures. The Office shall determine the categories of employees and expenditures to be included or excluded, as the case may be, in the number of employees and amount of expenditures. The minimum allocation for meeting needs of local governments in each State (other than the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands) shall be 50 per centum of the amount allocated for the State under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The amount of any allocation under paragraph (2) of this subsection which the Office determines, on the basis of information available to it, will not be used to meet needs for which allocated shall be available for use to meet the needs of the State government or local governments in that State, as the case may be, on such date or dates as the Office may fix.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The amount allocated for any State under paragraph (1) of this subsection which the Office determines, on the basis of information available to it, will not be used shall be available for reallocation by the Office from time to time, on such date or dates as it may fix, among other States with respect to which such a determination has not been made, in accordance with the formula set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection, but with such amount for any of such other States being reduced to the extent it exceeds the sum the Office estimates said State needs and will be able to use; and the total of such reductions shall be similarly reallocated among the States whose proportionate amounts were not so reduced.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this subsection, “State” means the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, the total of the payments from the appropriations for any fiscal year under this chapter made with respect to programs or projects in any one State may not exceed an amount equal to 12½ per centum of such appropriation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1189</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4767.</num>
<heading> Termination of grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the Office, after giving reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the State or general local government concerned, finds—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that a program or project has been so changed that it no longer complies with the provisions of this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that in the operation of the program or project there is a failure to comply substantially with any such provision;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Office shall notify the State or general local government of its findings and no further payments may be made to such government by the Office until it is satisfied that such noncompliance has been, or will promptly be, corrected. However, the Office may authorize the continuance of payments to those projects approved under this chapter which are not involved in the noncompliance.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1928</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4768.</num>
<heading> Advisory committees; appointment; compensation and travel expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office may appoint, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, such advisory committee or committees as it may determine to be necessary to facilitate the administration of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Members of advisory committees who are not regular full-time employees of the United States, while serving on the business of the committees including traveltime may receive compensation at rates not exceeding the daily rate for GS–18; and while so serving away from their homes or regular places of business may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for individuals in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 508</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1928</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4769.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated, without fiscal year limitation, such sums as may be necessary to carry out the programs authorized by this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4770.</num>
<heading> Limitations on availability of funds for cost sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Federal funds made available to State or local governments under other programs may not be used by the State or local government for cost-sharing purposes under grant provisions of this chapter, except that Federal funds of a program financed wholly by Federal funds may be used to pay a pro-rata share of such cost sharing. State or local government funds used for cost sharing on other federally assisted programs may not be used for cost sharing under grant provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4771.</num>
<heading> Method of payment; installments; advances or reimbursement; adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments under this chapter may be made in installments, and in advance or by way of reimbursement, as the Office may determine, with necessary adjustments on account of overpayments or underpayments.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1929</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4772.</num>
<heading> Effective date of grant provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Grant provisions of this chapter shall become effective one hundred and eighty days following <date date="1971-01-05">January 5, 1971</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 513</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>