<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 104—</num>
<heading>NUCLEAR SAFETY RESEARCH, DEVELOPMENT, AND DEMONSTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9701.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> nuclear energy is one of the two major energy sources available for electric energy production in the United States during the balance of the twentieth century;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> continued development of nuclear power is dependent upon maintaining an extremely high level of safety in the operation of nuclear plants, and on public recognition that these facilities do not constitute a significant threat to human health or safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> it is the responsibility of utilities, as owners and operators of nuclear powerplants, to assure that such plants are designed and operated safely and reliably; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a proper role of the Federal Government in assuring nuclear powerplant safety, in addition to its regulatory function, is the conduct of a research, development, and demonstration program to provide important scientific and technical information which can contribute to sound design and safe operation of these plants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> It is declared to be the policy of the United States and the purpose of this chapter to establish a research, development, and demonstration program for developing practical improvements in the generic safety of nuclear powerplants during the next five years, beginning in the fiscal year 1981. The objectives of such program shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to reduce the likelihood and severity of potentially serious nuclear powerplant accidents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to reduce the likelihood of disrupting the population in the vicinity of nuclear powerplants as the result of nuclear powerplant accidents.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as preventing the Secretary from undertaking projects or activities, in addition to those specified in this chapter, which appropriately further the purpose and objectives set forth in this subsection. Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the Secretary to assume responsibility for the management, cleanup or repair of any commercial nuclear powerplant. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as limiting the authority of the Secretary under any other law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Government agency” means any department, agency, commission, or independent establishment in the executive branch of the Federal Government, or any corporation, wholly or partly owned by the United States, which is an instrumentality of the United States, or any board, bureau, division, service, office, officer, authority, administration, or other establishment in the executive branch of the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Commission” means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Advisory Committee” means the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards established by <ref>section 2039 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9703.</num>
<heading> Research, development, and demonstration program; establishment; purposes; implementation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall establish a research, development, and demonstration program to carry out the purpose of this chapter. As part of such program, the Secretary shall at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> refine further the assessment of risk factors associated with the generic design and operation of nuclear powerplants to determine the degree and consequences of propagation of failures of systems, subsystems, and components, including consideration of the interaction between the primary and secondary systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop potentially cost-beneficial changes in the generic design and operation of nuclear powerplants that can (A) significantly reduce the risks from unintentional release of radioactive material from the various engineered barriers of nuclear powerplants and (B) reduce the radiation exposure to workers during plant operation and maintenance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop potentially cost-beneficial generic methods and designs that will significantly improve the performance of operators of nuclear powerplants under routine, abnormal, and accident conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identify the effect of total or partial automation of generic plant systems on reactor safety, operation, reliability, economics, and operator performance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> conduct further experimental investigations under abnormal operational and postulated accident conditions primarily for light water reactors to determine the consequences of such conditions. These investigations shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fuel failure at higher than standard burn-up levels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fuel-cladding interactions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fuel and cladding interactions with coolant under various temperatures and pressures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> thermohydraulic behavior in the reactor core;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> mechanisms to suppress and control the generation of hydrogen gas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> improved instrumentation for monitoring reactor cores;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> engineered-barrier failure modes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> fission product release and transport from failed fuel;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide for the examination and analysis of any nuclear powerplant fuel, component, or system which the Secretary deems to offer significant benefit in safety analysis and which is made available to the Secretary for a nominal cost, such as $1: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the Secretary shall accept only the number of samples of such fuel, component, or system necessary to carry out such examination and analysis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> identify the aptitudes, training, and manning levels which are necessary to assure reliable operator performance under normal, abnormal, and emergency conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out the generic safety research, development, and demonstration program established under this chapter, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall coordinate with the Commission and, to the extent necessary, enter into a new memorandum of understanding or revise existing memoranda for the purpose of eliminating unnecessary duplication and avoiding programmatic conflict with any reactor safety research program of the Commission, including the Improved Safety Systems Research program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall, to the extent practical, coordinate his activities with such other Government agencies, foreign governments, and industry as he deems appropriate to utilize their expertise, to minimize duplication of effort, and to ensure that information useful for improved concepts applicable to nuclear powerplant safety can be applied in a timely manner. The Secretary may enter into agreements and memoranda of understanding to accomplish these ends, but no such agreement shall have the effect of delaying the development and implementation of programs authorized under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall utilize, to the extent feasible, underutilized federally owned research reactors and facilities, along with the associated personnel, to maintain existing capabilities and to ensure that the research is generic in nature; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall make such recommendations as are practical to minimize the complexity of nuclear powerplant systems, including secondary systems, and operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9704.</num>
<heading> National reactor engineering simulator feasibility study</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultative requirements; purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Commission and the Advisory Committee, shall initiate a study of the need for and feasibility of establishing a reactor engineering simulator facility at a national laboratory, for the primary purpose of fostering research in generic design improvements and simplifications through the simulation of the performance of various types of light water reactors under a wide variety of abnormal conditions and postulated accident conditions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of relevant factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In performing the study, the Secretary shall consider relevant factors including, but not limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the potential advantages that would accrue from the establishment of such a facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the extent to which such a facility would further the generic safety research and development program established by this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the extent to which such a facility can be established by nongovernmental entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the opportunities for cost sharing by nongovernmental entities in the construction and operation of such a facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the importance of such a facility in emergencies to limit the extent of any future nuclear powerplant excursions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the potential for international cooperation in the establishment and operation of such a facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the appropriate national laboratory for siting such a facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, by <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, submit to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report characterizing the study and the resulting conclusions and recommendations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 5</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9705.</num>
<heading> Federal Nuclear Operations Corps’ study</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation and coordination requirements; purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in cooperation with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, shall initiate a study as to the sufficiency of efforts in the United States to provide specially trained professionals to operate the controls of nuclear powerplants and other facilities in the back-end of the nuclear fuel cycle. In carrying out the study, the Secretary shall coordinate his activities with the ongoing programs of the utility industry and other Federal governmental agencies for obtaining high standards of operator performance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In conducting the study the Secretary shall assess the desirability and feasibility of creating a Federal Corps of such professionals to inspect and supervise such operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The assessment shall consider the establishment of an academy to train Corps professionals in all aspects of nuclear technology, nuclear operations, nuclear regulatory and related law, and health science.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The assessment shall include the appropriate organizational approach for the establishment of a Federal Corps within the executive branch.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall complete the study within one year after <date date="1980-12-22">December 22, 1980</date>, and shall submit a report along with his recommendations to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3332</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9706.</num>
<heading> Dissemination of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall assure that full and complete safety-related information resulting from any project or other activity conducted under this chapter is made available in a timely manner to appropriate committees of Congress, Federal, State, and local authorities, relevant segments of private industry, the scientific community, and the public.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 7</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3332</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9707.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive program management plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation; scope; consultative requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed to prepare a comprehensive program management plan for the conduct of research, development, and demonstration activities under this chapter consistent with the provisions of <ref>section 9703 of this title</ref>. In the preparation of such plan, the Secretary shall consult with the Commission and the Advisory Committee and with the heads of such other Government agencies and such public and private organizations as he deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmission to Congressional committees; revisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit the comprehensive program management plan along with any comments by the Commission on the plan to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate within twelve months after <date date="1980-12-22">December 22, 1980</date>. Revisions to the plan shall be transmitted to such committees whenever deemed appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 8</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1051</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9708.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this chapter such sums as may be authorized by legislation hereafter enacted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–567, § 9</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3333</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>