<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 117—</num>
<heading>ENCOURAGING GOOD FAITH PROFESSIONAL REVIEW ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11101.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The increasing occurrence of medical malpractice and the need to improve the quality of medical care have become nationwide problems that warrant greater efforts than those that can be undertaken by any individual State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There is a national need to restrict the ability of incompetent physicians to move from State to State without disclosure or discovery of the physician’s previous damaging or incompetent performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This nationwide problem can be remedied through effective professional peer review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The threat of private money damage liability under Federal laws, including treble damage liability under Federal antitrust law, unreasonably discourages physicians from participating in effective professional peer review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> There is an overriding national need to provide incentive and protection for physicians engaging in effective professional peer review.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3784</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PROMOTION OF PROFESSIONAL REVIEW ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11111.</num>
<heading> Professional review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on damages for professional review actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a professional review action (as defined in <ref>section 11151(9) of this title</ref>) of a professional review body meets all the standards specified in <ref>section 11112(a) of this title</ref>, except as provided in subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the professional review body,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any person acting as a member or staff to the body,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any person under a contract or other formal agreement with the body, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any person who participates with or assists the body with respect to the action,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall not be liable in damages under any law of the United States or of any State (or political subdivision thereof) with respect to the action. The preceding sentence shall not apply to damages under any law of the United States or any State relating to the civil rights of any person or persons, including the Civil Rights Act of 1964, <ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e</ref>, et seq. and the Civil Rights Acts, <ref>42 U.S.C. 1981</ref>, et seq. Nothing in this paragraph shall prevent the United States or any Attorney General of a State from bringing an action, including an action under <ref>section 15c of title 15</ref>, where such an action is otherwise authorized.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection for those providing information to professional review bodies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no person (whether as a witness or otherwise) providing information to a professional review body regarding the competence or professional conduct of a physician shall be held, by reason of having provided such information, to be liable in damages under any law of the United States or of any State (or political subdivision thereof) unless such information is false and the person providing it knew that such information was false.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary has reason to believe that a health care entity has failed to report information in accordance with <ref>section 11133(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall conduct an investigation. If, after providing notice of noncompliance, an opportunity to correct the noncompliance, and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary determines that a health care entity has failed substantially to report information in accordance with <ref>section 11133(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall publish the name of the entity in the Federal Register. The protections of subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to an entity the name of which is published in the Federal Register under the previous sentence with respect to professional review actions of the entity commenced during the 3-year period beginning 30 days after the date of publication of the name.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment under State laws</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Professional review actions taken on or after <date date="1989-10-14">October 14, 1989</date></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsection (a) shall apply to State laws in a State only for professional review actions commenced on or after <date date="1989-10-14">October 14, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State early opt-in</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subsection (a) shall apply to State laws in a State for actions commenced before <date date="1989-10-14">October 14, 1989</date>, if the State by legislation elects such treatment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of election</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An election under State law is not effective, for purposes of,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003987">1</ref> for actions commenced before the effective date of the State law, which may not be earlier than the date of the enactment of that law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–177, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6103(e)(6)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11112.</num>
<heading> Standards for professional review actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of the protection set forth in <ref>section 11111(a) of this title</ref>, a professional review action must be taken—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the reasonable belief that the action was in the furtherance of quality health care,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> after a reasonable effort to obtain the facts of the matter,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> after adequate notice and hearing procedures are afforded to the physician involved or after such other procedures as are fair to the physician under the circumstances, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the reasonable belief that the action was warranted by the facts known after such reasonable effort to obtain facts and after meeting the requirement of paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">A professional review action shall be presumed to have met the preceding standards necessary for the protection set out in <ref>section 11111(a) of this title</ref> unless the presumption is rebutted by a preponderance of the evidence.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adequate notice and hearing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A health care entity is deemed to have met the adequate notice and hearing requirement of subsection (a)(3) with respect to a physician if the following conditions are met (or are waived voluntarily by the physician):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of proposed action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The physician has been given notice stating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that a professional review action has been proposed to be taken against the physician,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reasons for the proposed action,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that the physician has the right to request a hearing on the proposed action,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any time limit (of not less than 30 days) within which to request such a hearing, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a summary of the rights in the hearing under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of hearing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a hearing is requested on a timely basis under paragraph (1)(B), the physician involved must be given notice stating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the place, time, and date, of the hearing, which date shall not be less than 30 days after the date of the notice, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a list of the witnesses (if any) expected to testify at the hearing on behalf of the professional review body.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conduct of hearing and notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a hearing is requested on a timely basis under paragraph (1)(B)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> subject to subparagraph (B), the hearing shall be held (as determined by the health care entity)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> before an arbitrator mutually acceptable to the physician and the health care entity,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> before a hearing officer who is appointed by the entity and who is not in direct economic competition with the physician involved, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> before a panel of individuals who are appointed by the entity and are not in direct economic competition with the physician involved;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the right to the hearing may be forfeited if the physician fails, without good cause, to appear;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> in the hearing the physician involved has the right—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to representation by an attorney or other person of the physician’s choice,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to have a record made of the proceedings, copies of which may be obtained by the physician upon payment of any reasonable charges associated with the preparation thereof,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to call, examine, and cross-examine witnesses,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to present evidence determined to be relevant by the hearing officer, regardless of its admissibility in a court of law, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> to submit a written statement at the close of the hearing; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> upon completion of the hearing, the physician involved has the right—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to receive the written recommendation of the arbitrator, officer, or panel, including a statement of the basis for the recommendations, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to receive a written decision of the health care entity, including a statement of the basis for the decision.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">A professional review body’s failure to meet the conditions described in this subsection shall not, in itself, constitute failure to meet the standards of subsection (a)(3).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adequate procedures in investigations or health emergencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of <ref>section 11111(a) of this title</ref>, nothing in this section shall be construed as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> requiring the procedures referred to in subsection (a)(3)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> where there is no adverse professional review action taken, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a suspension or restriction of clinical privileges, for a period of not longer than 14 days, during which an investigation is being conducted to determine the need for a professional review action; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> precluding an immediate suspension or restriction of clinical privileges, subject to subsequent notice and hearing or other adequate procedures, where the failure to take such an action may result in an imminent danger to the health of any individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3785</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11113.</num>
<heading> Payment of reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs in defense of suit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any suit brought against a defendant, to the extent that a defendant has met the standards set forth under <ref>section 11112(a) of this title</ref> and the defendant substantially prevails, the court shall, at the conclusion of the action, award to a substantially prevailing party defending against any such claim the cost of the suit attributable to such claim, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, if the claim, or the claimant’s conduct during the litigation of the claim, was frivolous, unreasonable, without foundation, or in bad faith. For the purposes of this section, a defendant shall not be considered to have substantially prevailed when the plaintiff obtains an award for damages or permanent injunctive or declaratory relief.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3787</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11114.</num>
<heading> Guidelines of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may establish, after notice and opportunity for comment, such voluntary guidelines as may assist the professional review bodies in meeting the standards described in <ref>section 11112(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3787</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11115.</num>
<heading> Construction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as specifically provided in this subchapter, nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as changing the liabilities or immunities under law or as preempting or overriding any State law which provides incentives, immunities, or protection for those engaged in a professional review action that is in addition to or greater than that provided by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of clinical privileges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as requiring health care entities to provide clinical privileges to any or all classes or types of physicians or other licensed health care practitioners.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of nurses and other practitioners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as affecting, or modifying any provision of Federal or State law, with respect to activities of professional review bodies regarding nurses, other licensed health care practitioners, or other health professionals who are not physicians.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of patient malpractice claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as affecting in any manner the rights and remedies afforded patients under any provision of Federal or State law to seek redress for any harm or injury suffered as a result of negligent treatment or care by any physician, health care practitioner, or health care entity, or as limiting any defenses or immunities available to any physician, health care practitioner, or health care entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3787</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–177, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6103(e)(6)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>REPORTING OF INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11131.</num>
<heading> Requiring reports on medical malpractice payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each entity (including an insurance company) which makes payment under a policy of insurance, self-insurance, or otherwise in settlement (or partial settlement) of, or in satisfaction of a judgment in, a medical malpractice action or claim shall report, in accordance with <ref>section 11134 of this title</ref>, information respecting the payment and circumstances thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be reported</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The information to be reported under subsection (a) includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name of any physician or licensed health care practitioner for whose benefit the payment is made,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of the payment,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the name (if known) of any hospital with which the physician or practitioner is affiliated or associated,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a description of the acts or omissions and injuries or illnesses upon which the action or claim was based, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> such other information as the Secretary determines is required for appropriate interpretation of information reported under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions for failure to report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any entity that fails to report information on a payment required to be reported under this section shall be subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $10,000 for each such payment involved. Such penalty shall be imposed and collected in the same manner as civil money penalties under subsection (a) of <ref>section 1320a–7a of this title</ref> are imposed and collected under that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on treatment of small payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall study and report to Congress, not later than two years after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, on whether information respecting small payments should continue to be required to be reported under subsection (a) and whether information respecting all claims made concerning a medical malpractice action should be required to be reported under such subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3788</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11132.</num>
<heading> Reporting of sanctions taken by Boards of Medical Examiners</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions subject to reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each Board of Medical Examiners—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which revokes or suspends (or otherwise restricts) a physician’s license or censures, reprimands, or places on probation a physician, for reasons relating to the physician’s professional competence or professional conduct, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to which a physician’s license is surrendered,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall report, in accordance with <ref>section 11134 of this title</ref>, the information described in paragraph (2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be reported</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The information to be reported under paragraph (1) is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of the physician involved,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the acts or omissions or other reasons (if known) for the revocation, suspension, or surrender of license, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such other information respecting the circumstances of the action or surrender as the Secretary deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, after notice of noncompliance and providing opportunity to correct noncompliance, the Secretary determines that a Board of Medical Examiners has failed to report information in accordance with subsection (a), the Secretary shall designate another qualified entity for the reporting of information under <ref>section 11133 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 422</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11133.</num>
<heading> Reporting of certain professional review actions taken by health care entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting by health care entities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On physicians</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each health care entity which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> takes a professional review action that adversely affects the clinical privileges of a physician for a period longer than 30 days;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> accepts the surrender of clinical privileges of a physician—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> while the physician is under an investigation by the entity relating to possible incompetence or improper professional conduct, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in return for not conducting such an investigation or proceeding; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of such an entity which is a professional society, takes a professional review action which adversely affects the membership of a physician in the society,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall report to the Board of Medical Examiners, in accordance with <ref>section 11134(a) of this title</ref>, the information described in paragraph (3).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permissive reporting on other licensed health care practitioners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A health care entity may report to the Board of Medical Examiners, in accordance with <ref>section 11134(a) of this title</ref>, the information described in paragraph (3) in the case of a licensed health care practitioner who is not a physician, if the entity would be required to report such information under paragraph (1) with respect to the practitioner if the practitioner were a physician.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be reported</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The information to be reported under this subsection is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of the physician or practitioner involved,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the acts or omissions or other reasons for the action or, if known, for the surrender, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such other information respecting the circumstances of the action or surrender as the Secretary deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting by Board of Medical Examiners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Board of Medical Examiners shall report, in accordance with <ref>section 11134 of this title</ref>, the information reported to it under subsection (a) and known instances of a health care entity’s failure to report information under subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Health care entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A health care entity that fails substantially to meet the requirement of subsection (a)(1) shall lose the protections of <ref>section 11111(a)(1) of this title</ref> if the Secretary publishes the name of the entity under <ref>section 11111(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of Medical Examiners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, after notice of noncompliance and providing an opportunity to correct noncompliance, the Secretary determines that a Board of Medical Examiners has failed to report information in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary shall designate another qualified entity for the reporting of information under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> References to Board of Medical Examiners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any reference in this subchapter to a Board of Medical Examiners includes, in the case of a Board in a State that fails to meet the reporting requirements of <ref>section 11132(a) of this title</ref> or subsection (b), a reference to such other qualified entity as the Secretary designates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 423</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11134.</num>
<heading> Form of reporting</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing and form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The information required to be reported under sections 11131, 11132(a), and 11133 of this title shall be reported regularly (but not less often than monthly) and in such form and manner as the Secretary prescribes. Such information shall first be required to be reported on a date (not later than one year after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>) specified by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To whom reported</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The information required to be reported under sections 11131, 11132(a), and 11133(b) of this title shall be reported to the Secretary, or, in the Secretary’s discretion, to an appropriate private or public agency which has made suitable arrangements with the Secretary with respect to receipt, storage, protection of confidentiality, and dissemination of the information under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting to State licensing boards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Malpractice payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Information required to be reported under <ref>section 11131 of this title</ref> shall also be reported to the appropriate State licensing board (or boards) in the State in which the medical malpractice claim arose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting to other licensing boards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Information required to be reported under <ref>section 11133(b) of this title</ref> shall also be reported to the appropriate State licensing board in the State in which the health care entity is located if it is not otherwise reported to such board under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 424</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11135.</num>
<heading> Duty of hospitals to obtain information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the duty of each hospital to request from the Secretary (or the agency designated under <ref>section 11134(b) of this title</ref>), on and after the date information is first required to be reported under <ref>section 11134(a) of this title</ref>)— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003988">1</ref></chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at the time a physician or licensed health care practitioner applies to be on the medical staff (courtesy or otherwise) of, or for clinical privileges at, the hospital, information reported under this subchapter concerning the physician or practitioner, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> once every 2 years information reported under this subchapter concerning any physician or such practitioner who is on the medical staff (courtesy or otherwise) of, or has been granted clinical privileges at, the hospital.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">A hospital may request such information at other times.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to obtain information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to a medical malpractice action, a hospital which does not request information respecting a physician or practitioner as required under subsection (a) is presumed to have knowledge of any information reported under this subchapter to the Secretary with respect to the physician or practitioner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reliance on information provided</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each hospital may rely upon information provided to the hospital under this chapter and shall not be held liable for such reliance in the absence of the hospital’s knowledge that the information provided was false.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 425</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11136.</num>
<heading> Disclosure and correction of information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to the information reported to the Secretary (or the agency designated under <ref>section 11134(b) of this title</ref>) under this subchapter respecting a physician or other licensed health care practitioner, the Secretary shall, by regulation, provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disclosure of the information, upon request, to the physician or practitioner, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procedures in the case of disputed accuracy of the information.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 426</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3791</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11137.</num>
<heading> Miscellaneous provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Providing licensing boards and other health care entities with access to information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary (or the agency designated under <ref>section 11134(b) of this title</ref>) shall, upon request, provide information reported under this subchapter with respect to a physician or other licensed health care practitioner to State licensing boards, to hospitals, and to other health care entities (including health maintenance organizations) that have entered (or may be entering) into an employment or affiliation relationship with the physician or practitioner or to which the physician or practitioner has applied for clinical privileges or appointment to the medical staff.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Information reported under this subchapter is considered confidential and shall not be disclosed (other than to the physician or practitioner involved) except with respect to professional review activity, as necessary to carry out subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 11135 of this title</ref> (as specified in regulations by the Secretary), or in accordance with regulations of the Secretary promulgated pursuant to subsection (a). Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the disclosure of such information by a party which is otherwise authorized, under applicable State law, to make such disclosure. Information reported under this subchapter that is in a form that does not permit the identification of any particular health care entity, physician, other health care practitioner, or patient shall not be considered confidential. The Secretary (or the agency designated under <ref>section 11134(b) of this title</ref>), on application by any person, shall prepare such information in such form and shall disclose such information in such form.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty for violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $10,000 for each such violation involved. Such penalty shall be imposed and collected in the same manner as civil money penalties under subsection (a) of <ref>section 1320a–7a of this title</ref> are imposed and collected under that section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (1), information provided under <ref>section 11135 of this title</ref> and subsection (a) is intended to be used solely with respect to activities in the furtherance of the quality of health care.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may establish or approve reasonable fees for the disclosure of information under this section or <ref>section 11136 of this title</ref>. The amount of such a fee may not exceed the costs of processing the requests for disclosure and of providing such information. Such fees shall be available to the Secretary (or, in the Secretary’s discretion, to the agency designated under <ref>section 11134(b) of this title</ref>) to cover such costs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief from liability for reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person or entity (including the agency designated under <ref>section 11134(b) of this title</ref>) shall be held liable in any civil action with respect to any report made under this subchapter (including information provided under subsection (a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003989">1</ref> without knowledge of the falsity of the information contained in the report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interpretation of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In interpreting information reported under this subchapter, a payment in settlement of a medical malpractice action or claim shall not be construed as creating a presumption that medical malpractice has occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 427</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–177, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1007</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>DEFINITIONS AND REPORTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11151.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “adversely affecting” includes reducing, restricting, suspending, revoking, denying, or failing to renew clinical privileges or membership in a health care entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Board of Medical Examiners” includes a body comparable to such a Board (as determined by the State) with responsibility for the licensing of physicians and also includes a subdivision of such a Board or body.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “clinical privileges” includes privileges, membership on the medical staff, and the other circumstances pertaining to the furnishing of medical care under which a physician or other licensed health care practitioner is permitted to furnish such care by a health care entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “health care entity” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a hospital that is licensed to provide health care services by the State in which it is located,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an entity (including a health maintenance organization or group medical practice) that provides health care services and that follows a formal peer review process for the purpose of furthering quality health care (as determined under regulations of the Secretary), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> subject to subparagraph (B), a professional society (or committee thereof) of physicians or other licensed health care practitioners that follows a formal peer review process for the purpose of furthering quality health care (as determined under regulations of the Secretary).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “health care entity” does not include a professional society (or committee thereof) if, within the previous 5 years, the society has been found by the Federal Trade Commission or any court to have engaged in any anti-competitive practice which had the effect of restricting the practice of licensed health care practitioners.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “hospital” means an entity described in paragraphs (1) and (7) of <ref>section 1395x(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The terms “licensed health care practitioner” and “practitioner” mean, with respect to a State, an individual (other than a physician) who is licensed or otherwise authorized by the State to provide health care services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “medical malpractice action or claim” means a written claim or demand for payment based on a health care provider’s furnishing (or failure to furnish) health care services, and includes the filing of a cause of action, based on the law of tort, brought in any court of any State or the United States seeking monetary damages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “physician” means a doctor of medicine or osteopathy or a doctor of dental surgery or medical dentistry legally authorized to practice medicine and surgery or dentistry by a State (or any individual who, without authority holds himself or herself out to be so authorized).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> The term “professional review action” means an action or recommendation of a professional review body which is taken or made in the conduct of professional review activity, which is based on the competence or professional conduct of an individual physician (which conduct affects or could affect adversely the health or welfare of a patient or patients), and which affects (or may affect) adversely the clinical privileges, or membership in a professional society, of the physician. Such term includes a formal decision of a professional review body not to take an action or make a recommendation described in the previous sentence and also includes professional review activities relating to a professional review action. In this chapter, an action is not considered to be based on the competence or professional conduct of a physician if the action is primarily based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the physician’s association, or lack of association, with a professional society or association,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the physician’s fees or the physician’s advertising or engaging in other competitive acts intended to solicit or retain business,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the physician’s participation in prepaid group health plans, salaried employment, or any other manner of delivering health services whether on a fee-for-service or other basis,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a physician’s association with, supervision of, delegation of authority to, support for, training of, or participation in a private group practice with, a member or members of a particular class of health care practitioner or professional, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other matter that does not relate to the competence or professional conduct of a physician.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> The term “professional review activity” means an activity of a health care entity with respect to an individual physician—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to determine whether the physician may have clinical privileges with respect to, or membership in, the entity,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to determine the scope or conditions of such privileges or membership, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to change or modify such privileges or membership.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The term “professional review body” means a health care entity and the governing body or any committee of a health care entity which conducts professional review activity, and includes any committee of the medical staff of such an entity when assisting the governing body in a professional review activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The term “State” means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The term “State licensing board” means, with respect to a physician or health care provider in a State, the agency of the State which is primarily responsible for the licensing of the physician or provider to furnish health care services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 431</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3792</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11152.</num>
<heading> Reports and memoranda of understanding</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall report to Congress, annually during the three years after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, on the implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memoranda of understanding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall seek to enter into memoranda of understanding with the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of Veterans’ Affairs to apply the provisions of subchapter II of this chapter to hospitals and other facilities and health care providers under the jurisdiction of the Secretary or Administrator, respectively. The Secretary shall report to Congress, not later than two years after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, on any such memoranda and on the cooperation among such officials in establishing such memoranda.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memorandum of understanding with Drug Enforcement Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Administrator of Drug Enforcement relating to providing for the reporting by the Administrator to the Secretary of information respecting physicians and other practitioners whose registration to dispense controlled substances has been suspended or revoked under <ref>section 824 of title 21</ref>. The Secretary shall report to Congress, not later than two years after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, on any such memorandum and on the cooperation between the Secretary and the Administrator in establishing such a memorandum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>