<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 18—</num>
<heading>YOUTH MEDALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1921.</num>
<heading> Establishment of medals for bravery; rules and regulations; conditions governing awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Justice be, and it is, authorized and directed to promulgate rules and regulations establishing a medal; the method of selecting such recipient thereof so that an award shall be made to any child residing in the United States, who is eighteen years old or under, who has exhibited exceptional courage, extraordinary decision, presence of mind, and unusual swiftness of action, regardless of his or her own personal safety, in an effort to save or successfully saving the life or lives of any person or persons whose life or lives were in actual imminent danger.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 520, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1922.</num>
<heading> Establishment of medals for character and service; condition governing awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Justice shall also honor by an appropriate medal such American boy or girl citizens, eighteen years old or under, who, in the opinion of the said Department of Justice, shall have achieved outstanding or unusual recognition for character and service during any given year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 520, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1923.</num>
<heading> Names of medals; presentation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The medal to be awarded for bravery or valor as defined in <ref>section 1921 of this title</ref> shall be known as the Young American Medal for Bravery, while the medal for outstanding character and service as defined in <ref>section 1922 of this title</ref> shall be known as the Young American Medal for Service, and such medals shall be presented personally by the President of the United States for and on behalf, and in the name of the President and the Congress of the United States of America.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 520, § 3</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1924.</num>
<heading> Certificate of commendation accompanying awards; limitation on number of yearly awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Accompanying such medals designated in this chapter there shall be an appropriate certificate of commendation presented to the recipient or recipients stating (a) the circumstances under which the act of bravery was performed, and (b) citing the outstanding recognition for character and service: <i>Provided</i>, That there shall not be awarded in any one calendar year in excess of four such medals, to wit, two for bravery and two for character and service, as herein authorized.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 520, § 4</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1925.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1926.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall also be the duty of the Department of Justice to list in its annual budget request the sum of money necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter, which sum is authorized in a sum not to exceed $5,000 per annum.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 520, § 6</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>