<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 113—</num>
<heading>STATE JUSTICE INSTITUTE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Board” means the Board of Directors of the Institute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Director” means the Executive Director of the Institute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Governor” means the Chief Executive Officer of a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “Institute” means the State Justice Institute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “recipient” means any grantee, contractor, or recipient of financial assistance under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “Supreme Court” means the highest appellate court within a State unless, for the purposes of this chapter, a constitutionally or legislatively established judicial council acts in place of that court; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> “domestic violence” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any action that constitutes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> attempting to cause or intentionally, knowingly, or recklessly causing bodily injury or physical illness;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> rape, sexual assault, or causing involuntary deviate sexual intercourse;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> placing by physical menace another in fear of imminent serious bodily injury; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the infliction of false imprisonment;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">if such action is taken by one of 2 spouses, former spouses, or sexual or intimate partners against the other spouse, former spouse, or partner and the 2 of whom share biological parenthood of, have adopted, are legal custodians of, or are stepparents of a minor child; or</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> physically or sexually abusing such minor child if such abuse is inflicted by either of such spouses, former spouses, or partners.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3336</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–528, § 1</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10702.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Institute; duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; purpose; incorporation; powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a private nonprofit corporation which shall be known as the State Justice Institute. The purpose of the Institute shall be to further the development and adoption of improved judicial administration in State courts in the United States. The Institute may be incorporated in any State pursuant to <ref>section 10703(a)(6) of this title</ref>. To the extent consistent with the provisions of this chapter, the Institute may exercise the powers conferred upon a nonprofit corporation by the laws of the State in which it is incorporated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Institute shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> direct a national program of assistance designed to assure each person ready access to a fair and effective system of justice by providing funds to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State courts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> national organizations which support and are supported by State courts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other nonprofit organization that will support and achieve the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> foster coordination and cooperation with the Federal judiciary in areas of mutual concern;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote recognition of the importance of the separation of powers doctrine to an independent judiciary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage education for judges and support personnel of State court systems through national and State organizations, including universities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duplication of functions; responsibility of State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute shall not duplicate functions adequately performed by existing nonprofit organizations and shall promote, on the part of agencies of State judicial administration, responsibility for the success and effectiveness of State court improvement programs supported by Federal funding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of offices in State of incorporation; agent for receipt of service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute shall maintain its principal offices in the State in which it is incorporated and shall maintain therein a designated agent to accept service of process for the Institute. Notice to or service upon the agent shall be deemed notice to or service upon the Institute.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax status of Institute and programs assisted thereby</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute, and any program assisted by the Institute, shall be eligible to be treated as an organization described in <ref>section 170(c)(2)(B) of title 26</ref> and as an organization described in <ref>section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> which is exempt from taxation under <ref>section 501(a) of title 26</ref>. If such treatments are conferred in accordance with the provisions of title 26, the Institute, and programs assisted by the Institute, shall be subject to all provisions of title 26 relevant to the conduct of organizations exempt from taxation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules, regulations, etc.; notice and comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute shall afford notice and reasonable opportunity for comment to interested parties prior to issuing rules, regulations, guidelines, and instructions under this chapter, and it shall publish in the Federal Register all rules, regulations, guidelines, and instructions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3336</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7321(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4466</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4652</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–528, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10703.</num>
<heading> Board of Directors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Institute shall be supervised by a Board of Directors, consisting of eleven voting members to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Board shall have both judicial and nonjudicial members, and shall, to the extent practicable, have a membership representing a variety of backgrounds and reflecting participation and interest in the administration of justice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Board shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> six judges, to be appointed in the manner provided in paragraph (3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one State court administrator, to be appointed in the manner provided in paragraph (3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> four members from the public sector, no more than two of whom shall be of the same political party, to be appointed in the manner provided in paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President shall appoint six judges and one State court administrator from a list of candidates submitted to the President by the Conference of Chief Justices. The Conference of Chief Justices shall submit a list of at least fourteen individuals, including judges and State court administrators, whom the Conference considers best qualified to serve on the Board. Whenever the term of any of the members of the Board described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) terminates and that member is not to be reappointed to a new term, and whenever a vacancy otherwise occurs among those members, the President shall appoint a new member from a list of three qualified individuals submitted to the President by the Conference of Chief Justices. The President may reject any list of individuals submitted by the Conference under this paragraph and, if such a list is so rejected, the President shall request the Conference to submit to him another list of qualified individuals. Prior to consulting with or submitting a list to the President, the Conference of Chief Justices shall obtain and consider the recommendations of all interested organizations and individuals concerned with the administration of justice and the objectives of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In addition to those members appointed under paragraph (3), the President shall appoint four members from the public sector to serve on the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The President shall make the initial appointments of members of the Board under this subsection within ninety days after <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>. In the case of any other appointment of a member, the President shall make the appointment not later than ninety days after the previous term expires or the vacancy occurs, as the case may be. The Conference of Chief Justices shall submit lists of candidates under paragraph (3) in a timely manner so that the appointments can be made within the time periods specified in this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The initial members of the Board of Directors shall be the incorporators of the Institute and shall determine the State in which the Institute is to be incorporated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term of each voting member of the Board shall be three years. Each member of the Board shall continue to serve until the successor to such member has been appointed and qualified.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Five of the members first appointed by the President shall serve for a term of two years. Any member appointed to serve an unexpired term which has arisen by virtue of the death, disability, retirement, or resignation of a member shall be appointed only for such unexpired term, but shall be eligible for reappointment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term of initial members shall commence from the date of the first meeting of the Board, and the term of each member other than an initial member shall commence from the date of termination of the preceding term.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reappointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No member shall be reappointed to more than two consecutive terms immediately following such member’s initial term.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation; reimbursement for expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Board shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status of members of Board as officers and employees of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Board shall not, by reason of such membership, be considered officers or employees of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting rights of Board members; quorum; action of Board on concurrence of majority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of the Board shall be entitled to one vote. A simple majority of the membership shall constitute a quorum for the conduct of business. The Board shall act upon the concurrence of a simple majority of the membership present and voting.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman; initial selection and term of office; subsequent annual election</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall select from among the voting members of the Board a chairman, the first of whom shall serve for a term of three years. Thereafter, the Board shall annually elect a chairman from among its voting members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grounds for removal of members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of the Board may be removed by a vote of seven members for malfeasance in office, persistent neglect of, or inability to discharge duties, or for any offense involving moral turpitude, but for no other cause.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarterly meetings of Board; special meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regular meetings of the Board shall be held quarterly. Special meetings shall be held from time to time upon the call of the chairman, acting at his own discretion or pursuant to the petition of any seven members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Open meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All meetings of the Board, any executive committee of the Board (on any occasion on which that committee has been delegated the authority to act on behalf of the Board), and any council established in connection with this chapter, shall be open and subject to the requirements and provisions of <ref>section 552b of title 5</ref> relating to open meetings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties and functions of Board</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In its direction and supervision of the activities of the Institute, the Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish policies and develop such programs for the Institute that will further the achievement of its purpose and performance of its functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish policy and funding priorities and issue rules, regulations, guidelines, and instructions pursuant to such priorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> appoint and fix the duties of the Executive Director of the Institute, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board and shall be a nonvoting ex officio member of the Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> present to other Government departments, agencies, and instrumentalities whose programs or activities relate to the administration of justice in the State judiciaries of the United States, the recommendations of the Institute for the improvement of such programs or activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consider and recommend to both public and private agencies aspects of the operation of the State courts of the United States considered worthy of special study; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> award grants and enter into cooperative agreements or contracts pursuant to <ref>section 10705(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–372, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10704.</num>
<heading> Officers and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Director; appointment and removal of employees; political tests or qualifications prohibited</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director, subject to general policies established by the Board, shall supervise the activities of persons employed by the Institute and may appoint and remove such employees as he determines necessary to carry out the purposes of the Institute. The Director shall be responsible for the executive and administrative operations of the Institute, and shall perform such duties as are delegated to such Director by the Board and the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No political test or political qualification shall be used in selecting, appointing, promoting, or taking any other personnel action with respect to any officer, agent, or employee of the Institute, or in selecting or monitoring any grantee, contractor, person, or entity receiving financial assistance under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Officers and employees of the Institute shall be compensated at rates determined by the Board, but not in excess of the rate of level V of the Executive Schedule specified in <ref>section 5316 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status of Institute as department, agency, or instrumentality of Federal Government; authority of Office of Management and Budget</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, the Institute shall not be considered a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This chapter does not limit the authority of the Office of Management and Budget to review and submit comments upon the Institute’s annual budget request at the time it is transmitted to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Institute may purchase goods and services from the General Services Administration in order to carry out its functions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status of officers and employees of Institute as officers and employees of United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), officers and employees of the Institute shall not be considered officers or employees of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Officers and employees of the Institute shall be considered officers and employees of the United States solely for the purposes of the following provisions of title 5: Subchapter I of chapter 81 (relating to compensation for work injuries); chapters 83 and 84 (relating to civil service retirement); chapter 87 (relating to life insurance); and chapter 89 (relating to health insurance), notwithstanding section 8914 of such title. The Institute shall make contributions under the provisions referred to in this subsection at the same rates applicable to agencies of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Freedom of information requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute and its officers and employees shall be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref> relating to freedom of information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3339</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7321(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4466</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–372, § 3(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10705.</num>
<heading> Grants and contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Institute; purposes of grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Institute is authorized to award grants and enter into cooperative agreements or contracts, in a manner consistent with subsection (b), in order to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct research, demonstrations, or special projects pertaining to the purposes described in this chapter, and provide technical assistance and training in support of tests, demonstrations, and special projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> serve as a clearinghouse and information center, where not otherwise adequately provided, for the preparation, publication, and dissemination of information regarding State judicial systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> participate in joint projects with other agencies, including the Federal Judicial Center, with respect to the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> evaluate, when appropriate, the programs and projects carried out under this chapter to determine their impact upon the quality of criminal, civil, and juvenile justice and the extent to which they have met or failed to meet the purposes and policies of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> encourage and assist in the furtherance of judicial education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> encourage, assist, and serve in a consulting capacity to State and local justice system agencies in the development, maintenance, and coordination of criminal, civil, and juvenile justice programs and services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> be responsible for the certification of national programs that are intended to aid and improve State judicial systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority in making awards; alternative recipients; approval of applications; receipt and administration of funds; accountability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Institute is empowered to award grants and enter into cooperative agreements or contracts as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Institute may award grants to or enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> State and local courts and their agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> national nonprofit organizations controlled by, operating in conjunction with, and serving the judicial branches of State governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> national nonprofit organizations for the education and training of judges and support personnel of the judicial branch of State governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Institute may, if the objective can better be served thereby, award grants to or enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> other nonprofit organizations with expertise in judicial administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> institutions of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> individuals, partnerships, firms, or corporations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> private agencies with expertise in judicial administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Upon application by an appropriate State or local agency or institution and if the arrangements to be made by such agency or institution will provide services which could not be provided adequately through nongovernmental arrangements, the Institute may award a grant or enter into a cooperative agreement or contract with a unit of State or local government other than a court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Institute may enter into contracts with Federal agencies to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Each application for funding by a State or local court shall be approved, consistent with State law, by the State’s supreme court, or its designated agency or council, which shall receive, administer, and be accountable for all funds awarded by the Institute to such courts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permissible uses of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds available pursuant to grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts awarded under this section may be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assist State and local court systems in establishing appropriate procedures for the selection and removal of judges and other court personnel and in determining appropriate levels of compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support education and training programs for judges and other court personnel, for the performance of their general duties and for specialized functions, and to support national and regional conferences and seminars for the dissemination of information on new developments and innovative techniques;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to conduct research on alternative means for using judicial and nonjudicial personnel in court decisionmaking activities, to implement demonstration programs to test innovative approaches, and to conduct evaluations of their effectiveness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to support studies of the appropriateness of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003969">1</ref> efficacy of court organization and financing structures in particular States, and to enable States to implement plans for improved court organization and finance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to support State court planning and budgeting staffs and to provide technical assistance in resource allocation and service forecasting techniques;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to support studies of the adequacy of court management systems in State and local courts and to implement and evaluate innovative responses to problems of record management, data processing, court personnel management, reporting and transcription of court proceedings, and juror utilization and management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to collect and compile statistical data and other information on the work of the courts and on the work of other agencies which relate to and affect the work of courts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to conduct studies of the causes of trial and appellate court delay in resolving cases, and to establish and evaluate experimental programs for reducing case processing time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to develop and test methods for measuring the performance of judges and courts and to conduct experiments in the use of such measures to improve the functioning of such judges and courts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to support studies of court rules and procedures, discovery devices, and evidentiary standards, to identify problems with the operation of such rules, procedures, devices, and standards, to devise alternative approaches to better reconcile the requirements of due process with the need for swift and certain justice, and to test the utility of those alternative approaches;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> to support studies of the outcomes of cases in selected subject matter areas to identify instances in which the substance of justice meted out by the courts diverges from public expectations of fairness, consistency, or equity, to propose alternative approaches to the resolving of cases in problem areas, and to test and evaluate those alternatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> to support programs to increase court responsiveness to the needs of citizens through citizen education, improvement of court treatment of witnesses, victims, and jurors, and development of procedures for obtaining and using measures of public satisfaction with court processes to improve court performance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> to test and evaluate experimental approaches to providing increased citizen access to justice, including processes which reduce the cost of litigating common grievances and alternative techniques and mechanisms for resolving disputes between citizens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<chapeau> conduct <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003970">2</ref> not more than 5 projects at an aggregate cost of not to exceed $600,000—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to investigate, and carry out research regarding State judicial decisions relating to child custody litigation involving domestic violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to develop training curricula to assist State courts to develop an understanding of, and appropriate responses to, child custody litigation involving domestic violence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to disseminate the results of the investigation and research carried out under subparagraph (A), and the curricula developed under subparagraph (B), to State courts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> to carry out such other programs, consistent with the purposes of this chapter, as may be deemed appropriate by the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching fund requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute shall incorporate in any grant, cooperative agreement, or contract awarded under this section in which a State or local court (or other unit of State or local government) is the recipient, the requirement that the recipient provide a match, from private or public sources, not less than 50 per centum of the total cost of such grant, cooperative agreement, or contract, except that such requirement may be waived in exceptionally rare circumstances upon the approval of the chief justice of the highest court of the State and a majority of the Board of Directors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance monitoring and evaluation by Institute</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute shall monitor and evaluate, or provide for independent evaluations of, programs supported in whole or in part under this chapter to ensure that the provisions of this chapter, the bylaws of the Institute, and the applicable rules, regulations, and guidelines promulgated pursuant to this chapter, are carried out.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent study of financial and technical assistance programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute shall provide for an independent study of the financial and technical assistance programs under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7321(b)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4466</ref>, 4467; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title VI</ref>, §§ 603, 604, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–528</ref>, §§ 2, 3(2), <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3461</ref>, 3462; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title VIII</ref>, §§ 802, 803(b), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4515</ref>, 4516.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10706.</num>
<heading> Limitations on grants and contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Institute</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">With respect to grants made and contracts or cooperative agreements entered into under this chapter, the Institute shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that no funds made available to recipients by the Institute shall be used at any time, directly or indirectly, to influence the issuance, amendment, or revocation of any Executive order or similar promulgation by any Federal, State, or local agency, or to undertake to influence the passage or defeat of any legislation or constitutional amendment by the Congress of the United States, or by any State or local legislative body, or any State proposal by initiative petition, or of any referendum, unless a governmental agency, legislative body, a committee, or a member thereof—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requests personnel of the recipients to testify, draft, or review measures or to make representations to such agency, body, committee, or member; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is considering a measure directly affecting the activities under this chapter of the recipient or the Institute; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure all personnel engaged in grant, cooperative agreement or contract assistance activities supported in whole or part by the Institute refrain, while so engaged, from any partisan political activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds for training programs for advocacy of nonjudicial public policies or encouraging nonjudicial political activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No funds made available by the Institute under this chapter, either by grant, cooperative agreement, or contract, may be used to support or conduct training programs for the purpose of advocating particular nonjudicial public policies or encouraging nonjudicial political activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority coextensive with appropriation Acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorization to enter into cooperative agreements, contracts or any other obligation under this chapter shall be effective only to the extent, and in such amounts, as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited uses of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To ensure that funds made available under this chapter are used to supplement and improve the operation of State courts, rather than to support basic court services, funds shall not be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to supplant State or local funds currently supporting a program or activity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to construct court facilities or structures, except to remodel existing facilities to demonstrate new architectural or technological techniques, or to provide temporary facilities for new personnel or for personnel involved in a demonstration or experimental program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10707.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on activities of the Institute</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Litigation; interference with independence of State judiciary; funding of State judicial system activities other than pursuant to this chapter; legislative lobbying</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Institute shall not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> participate in litigation unless the Institute or a recipient of the Institute is a party, and shall not participate on behalf of any client other than itself;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> interfere with the independent nature of any State judicial system or allow financial assistance to be used for the funding of regular judicial and administrative activities of any State judicial system other than pursuant to the terms of any grant, cooperative agreement, or contract with the Institute, consistent with the requirements of this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> undertake to influence the passage or defeat of any legislation by the Congress of the United States or by any State or local legislative body, except that personnel of the Institute may testify or make other appropriate communication—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> when formally requested to do so by a legislative body, committee, or a member thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in connection with legislation or appropriations directly affecting the activities of the Institute; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in connection with legislation or appropriations dealing with improvements in the State judiciary, consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of shares of stock; declaration of dividends; compensation for services; reimbursement for expenses; political activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Institute shall have no power to issue any shares of stock, or to declare or pay any dividends.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No part of the income or assets of the Institute shall enure to the benefit of any director, officer, or employee, except as reasonable compensation for services or reimbursement for expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Neither the Institute nor any recipient shall contribute or make available Institute funds or program personnel or equipment to any political party or association, or the campaign of any candidate for public or party office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Institute shall not contribute or make available Institute funds or program personnel or equipment for use in advocating or opposing any ballot measure, initiative, or referendum.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of Institute with political activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Officers and employees of the Institute or of recipients shall not at any time intentionally identify the Institute or the recipient with any partisan or nonpartisan political activity associated with a political party or association, or the campaign of any candidate for public or party office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3343</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10708.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Institute shall prescribe procedures to ensure that financial assistance under this chapter shall not be suspended unless the grantee, contractor, person, or entity receiving financial assistance under this chapter has been given reasonable notice and opportunity to show cause why such actions should not be taken.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided by Federal law other than this chapter, no officer or employee of the Institute, and no recipient of assistance under this chapter, may use or reveal any research or statistical information furnished under this chapter by any person and identifiable to any specific private person for any purpose other than the purpose for which the information was obtained in accordance with this chapter. Such information and copies thereof shall be immune from legal process, and shall not, without the consent of the person furnishing such information, be admitted as evidence or used for any purpose in any action, suit, or other judicial, legislative, or administrative proceedings.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3344</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10709.</num>
<heading> Presidential coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may, to the extent not inconsistent with any other applicable law, direct that appropriate support functions of the Federal Government may be made available to the Institute in carrying out its functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10710.</num>
<heading> Records and reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute is authorized to require such reports as it deems necessary from any recipient with respect to activities carried out pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Institute is authorized to prescribe the keeping of records with respect to funds provided by any grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this chapter and shall have access to such records at all reasonable times for the purpose of ensuring compliance with such grant, cooperative agreement, or contract or the terms and conditions upon which financial assistance was provided.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of copies of reports to recipients; maintenance in principal office of Institute; availability for public inspection; furnishing of copies to interested parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Copies of all reports pertinent to the evaluation, inspection, or monitoring of any recipient shall be submitted on a timely basis to such recipient, and shall be maintained in the principal office of the Institute for a period of at least five years after such evaluation, inspection, or monitoring. Such reports shall be available for public inspection during regular business hours, and copies shall be furnished, upon request, to interested parties upon payment of such reasonable fees as the Institute may establish.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Federal funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Non-Federal funds received by the Institute, and funds received for projects funded in part by the Institute or by any recipient from a source other than the Institute, shall be accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Federal funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10711.</num>
<heading> Audits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time and place of audits; standards; availability of books, accounts, facilities, etc., to auditors; filing of report and availability for public inspection</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The accounts of the Institute shall be audited annually. Such audits shall be conducted in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants who are certified by a regulatory authority of the jurisdiction in which the audit is undertaken.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The audits shall be conducted at the place or places where the accounts of the Institute are normally kept. All books, accounts, financial records, reports, files, and other papers or property belonging to or in use by the Institute and necessary to facilitate the audits shall be made available to the person or persons conducting the audits. The full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances and securities held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians shall be afforded to any such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The report of the annual audit shall be filed with the Government Accountability Office and shall be available for public inspection during business hours at the principal office of the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional audits; requirements; reports and recommendations to Congress and Attorney General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In addition to the annual audit, the financial transactions of the Institute for any fiscal year during which Federal funds are available to finance any portion of its operations may be audited by the Government Accountability Office in accordance with such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any such audit shall be conducted at the place or places where accounts of the Institute are normally kept. The representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, financial records, reports, files, and other papers or property belonging to or in use by the Institute and necessary to facilitate the audit. The full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances and securities held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians shall be afforded to such representatives. All such books, accounts, financial records, reports, files, and other papers or property of the Institute shall remain in the possession and custody of the Institute throughout the period beginning on the date such possession or custody commences and ending three years after such date, but the Government Accountability Office may require the retention of such books, accounts, financial records, reports, files, and other papers or property for a longer period under <ref>section 3523(c) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A report of such audit shall be made by the Comptroller General to the Congress and to the Attorney General, together with such recommendations with respect thereto as the Comptroller General deems advisable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual audits by Institute or recipients; reports; submission of copies to Comptroller General; inspection of books, accounts, etc.; availability of audit reports for public inspection</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Institute shall conduct, or require each recipient to provide for, an annual fiscal audit. The report of each such audit shall be maintained for a period of at least five years at the principal office of the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Institute shall submit to the Comptroller General of the United States copies of such reports, and the Comptroller General may, in addition, inspect the books, accounts, financial records, files, and other papers or property belonging to or in use by such grantee, contractor, person, or entity, which relate to the disposition or use of funds received from the Institute. Such audit reports shall be available for public inspection during regular business hours, at the principal office of the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3345</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10712.</num>
<heading> Report by Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Federal Judicial Center, shall transmit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the effectiveness of the Institute in carrying out the duties specified in <ref>section 10702(b) of this title</ref>. Such report shall include an assessment of the cost effectiveness of the program as a whole and, to the extent practicable, of individual grants, an assessment of whether the restrictions and limitations specified in sections 10706 and 10707 of this title have been respected, and such recommendations as the Attorney General, in consultation with the Federal Judicial Center, deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–179, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-05-20">May 20, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10713.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the purposes of this chapter, $7,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005, 2006, 2007, and 2008. Amounts appropriated for each such year are to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7321(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4466</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–162, title V</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1028</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4515</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–372, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>