<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 115—</num>
<heading>CHILD DEVELOPMENT ASSOCIATE SCHOLARSHIP ASSISTANCE PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10901.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary to make grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make a grant for any fiscal year to any State receiving a grant under title XX of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1397</ref> et seq.] for such fiscal year to enable such State to award scholarships to eligible individuals within the State who are candidates for the Child Development Associate credential.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–425, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 976</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10902.</num>
<heading> Application for grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State desiring to participate in the grant program established by this chapter shall submit an application to the Secretary in such form as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of applications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State’s application shall contain appropriate assurances that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> scholarship assistance made available with funds provided under this chapter will be awarded—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> only to eligible individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on the basis of the financial need of such individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in amounts sufficient to cover the cost of application, assessment, and credentialing (including, at the option of the State, any training necessary for credentialing) for the Child Development Associate credential for such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not more than 35 percent of the funds received under this chapter by a State may be used to provide scholarship assistance under paragraph (1) to cover the cost of training described in paragraph (1)(C); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not more than 10 percent of the funds received by the State under this chapter will be used for the costs of administering the program established in such State to award such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equitable distribution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making grants under this chapter, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> distribute such grants equitably among States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the needs of rural and urban areas are appropriately addressed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–425, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 976</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10903.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “eligible individual” means a candidate for the Child Development Associate credential whose income does not exceed the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003979">1</ref> 130 percent of the lower living standard income level,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003980">2</ref> by more than 50 percent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “lower living standard income level” means that income level (adjusted for regional, metropolitan, urban, and rural differences and family size) determined annually by the Secretary of Labor and based on the most recent lower living family budget issued by the Secretary of Labor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and Palau.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–425, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 976</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10904.</num>
<heading> Annual report by States; contents; manner of payments pursuant to grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State receiving grants under this chapter shall annually submit to the Secretary information on the number of eligible individuals assisted under the grant program, and their positions and salaries before and after receiving the Child Development Associate credential.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments pursuant to grants made under this chapter may be made in installments, and in advance or by way of reimbursement, with necessary adjustments on account of overpayments or underpayments, as the Secretary may determine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–425, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 977</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10905.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 1995.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–425, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 977</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–501, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–252, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>