<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 159—</num>
<heading>SPACE EXPLORATION, TECHNOLOGY, AND SCIENCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18301.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States human space flight program has, since the first Mercury flight on <date date="1961-05-05">May 5, 1961</date>, been a source of pride and inspiration for the Nation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The establishment of and commitment to human exploration goals is essential for providing the necessary long term focus and programmatic consistency and robustness of the United States civilian space program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The National Aeronautics and Space Administration is and should remain a multi-mission agency with a balanced and robust set of core missions in science, aeronautics, and human space flight and exploration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the 50 years since the establishment of NASA, the arena of space has evolved substantially. As the uses and users of space continue to expand, the issues and operations in the regions closest to Earth have become increasingly complex, with a growing number of overlaps between civil, commercial and national security activities. These developments present opportunities and challenges to the space activities of NASA and the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The extraordinary challenges of achieving access to space both motivated and accelerated the development of technologies and industrial capabilities that have had widespread applications which have contributed to the technological excellence of the United States. It is essential to tie space activity to human challenges ranging from enhancing the influence, relationships, security, economic development, and commerce of the United States to improving the overall human condition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> It is essential to the economic well-being of the United States that the aerospace industrial capacity, highly skilled workforce, and embedded expertise remain engaged in demanding, challenging, and exciting efforts that ensure United States leadership in space exploration and related activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Crewmembers provide the essential component to ensure the return on investment from and the growth and safe operation of the ISS. The Russian Soyuz vehicle has allowed continued human presence on the ISS for United States crewmembers with its ability to serve as both a routine and backup capability for crew delivery, rescue, and return. With the impending retirement of the Space Shuttle, the United States will find itself with no national crew delivery and return system. Without any other system, the United States and all the ISS partners will have no redundant system for human access to and from the ISS. It is therefore essential that a United States capability be developed as soon as possible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Existing and emerging United States commercial launch capabilities and emerging launch capabilities offer the potential for providing crew support assets. New capabilities for human crew access to the ISS should be developed in a manner that ensures ISS mission assurance and safety. Commercial services offer the potential to broaden the availability and access to space at lower costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> While commercial transportation systems have the promise to contribute valuable services, it is in the United States national interest to maintain a government operated space transportation system for crew and cargo delivery to space.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Congress restates its commitment, expressed in the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2005 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004347">1</ref> (<ref>Public Law 109–155</ref>) and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2008 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004347">1</ref> (<ref>Public Law 110–422</ref>), to the development of commercially developed launch and delivery systems to the ISS for crew and cargo missions. Congress reaffirms that NASA shall make use of United States commercially provided ISS crew transfer and crew rescue services to the maximum extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> It is critical to identify an appropriate combination of NASA and related United States Government programs, while providing a framework that allows partnering, leveraging and stimulation of the existing and emerging commercial and international efforts in both near Earth space and the regions beyond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The designation of the United States segment of the ISS as a National Laboratory, as provided by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2005 <sup>1</sup> and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2008,<sup>1</sup> provides an opportunity for multiple United States Government agencies, university-based researchers, research organizations, and others to utilize the unique environment of microgravity for fundamental scientific research and potential economic development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> For some potential replacement elements necessary for ISS sustainability, the Space Shuttle may represent the only vehicle, existing or planned, capable of carrying those elements to the ISS in the near term. Additional or alternative transportation capabilities must be identified as contingency delivery options, and accompanied by an independent analysis of projected availability of such capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The United States must develop, as rapidly as possible, replacement vehicles capable of providing both human and cargo launch capability to low-Earth orbit and to destinations beyond low-Earth orbit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> There is a need for national space and export control policies that protect the national security of the United States while also enabling the United States and its aerospace industry to undertake cooperative programs in science and human space flight in an effective and efficient manner and to compete effectively in the global market place.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Science <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004348">1</ref> of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cis-lunar space</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cis-lunar space” means the region of space from the Earth out to and including the region around the surface of the Moon.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deep space</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “deep space” means the region of space beyond cis-lunar space.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> ISS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “ISS” means the International Space Station.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NASA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “NASA” means the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Near-Earth space</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “near-Earth space” means the region of space that includes low-Earth orbit and extends out to and includes geo-synchronous orbit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NOAA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “NOAA” means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> OSTP</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “OSTP” means the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Space Launch System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Space Launch System” means the follow-on government-owned civil launch system developed, managed, and operated by NASA to serve as a key component to expand human presence beyond low-Earth orbit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>POLICY, GOALS, AND OBJECTIVES FOR HUMAN SPACE FLIGHT AND EXPLORATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18311.</num>
<heading> United States human space flight policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of non-United States human space flight transportation services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Federal Government may not acquire human space flight transportation services from a foreign entity unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no United States Government-operated human space flight capability is available;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> no United States commercial provider is available; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> it is a qualified foreign entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial provider</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “commercial provider” means any person providing human space flight transportation services, primary control of which is held by persons other than the Federal Government, a State or local government, or a foreign government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified foreign entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified foreign entity” means a foreign entity that is in compliance with all applicable safety standards and is not prohibited from providing space transportation services under other law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States commercial provider</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “United States commercial provider” means a commercial provider, organized under the laws of the United States or of a State, that is more than 50 percent owned by United States nationals.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arrangements with foreign entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the Administrator from negotiating or entering into human space flight transportation arrangements with foreign entities to ensure safety of flight and continued ISS operations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States human space flight capabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress reaffirms the policy stated in <ref>section 70501(a) of title 51</ref>, that the United States shall maintain an uninterrupted capability for human space flight and operations in low-Earth orbit, and beyond, as an essential instrument of national security and of the capacity to ensure continued United States participation and leadership in the exploration and utilization of space.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2811</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title III, § 302(d)</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 25</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18312.</num>
<heading> Goals and objectives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Long-term goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The long-term goals of the human space flight and exploration efforts of NASA shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to expand permanent human presence beyond low-Earth orbit and to do so, where practical, in a manner involving international, academic, and industry partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> crewed missions and progress toward achieving the goal in paragraph (1) to enable the potential for subsequent human exploration and the extension of human presence throughout the solar system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to enable a capability to extend human presence, including potential human habitation on another celestial body and a thriving space economy in the 21st Century.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004349">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Key objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The key objectives of the United States for human expansion into space shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to sustain the capability for long-duration presence in low-Earth orbit, initially through continuation of the ISS and full utilization of the United States segment of the ISS as a National Laboratory, and through assisting and enabling an expanded commercial presence in, and access to, low-Earth orbit, as elements of a low-Earth orbit infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to determine if humans can live in an extended manner in space with decreasing reliance on Earth, starting with utilization of low-Earth orbit infrastructure, to identify potential roles that space resources such as energy and materials may play, to meet national and global needs and challenges, such as potential cataclysmic threats, and to explore the viability of and lay the foundation for sustainable economic activities in space;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to maximize the role that human exploration of space can play in advancing overall knowledge of the universe, supporting United States national and economic security and the United States global competitive posture, and inspiring young people in their educational pursuits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to build upon the cooperative and mutually beneficial framework established by the ISS partnership agreements and experience in developing and undertaking programs and meeting objectives designed to realize the goal of human space flight set forth in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to achieve human exploration of Mars and beyond through the prioritization of those technologies and capabilities best suited for such a mission in accordance with the stepping stone approach to exploration under <ref>section 70504 of title 51</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title IV</ref>, §§ 411, 412, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 33</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18313.</num>
<heading> Assurance of core capabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the ISS, technology developments, the current Space Shuttle program, and follow-on transportation systems authorized by this chapter form the foundation of initial capabilities for missions beyond low-Earth orbit to a variety of lunar and Lagrangian orbital locations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> these initial missions and related capabilities should be utilized to provide operational experience, technology development, and the placement and assured use of in-space infrastructure and in-space servicing of existing and future assets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress regarding human space flight capability assurance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the Administrator shall proceed with the utilization of the ISS, technology development, and follow-on transportation systems (including the Space Launch System, multi-purpose crew vehicle, and commercial crew and cargo transportation capabilities) under subchapters II and III of this chapter in a manner that ensures—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that these capabilities remain inherently complementary and interrelated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a balance of the development, sustainment, and use of each of these capabilities, which are of critical importance to the viability and sustainability of the U.S. space program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that resources required to support the timely and sustainable development of these capabilities authorized in either subchapter II or subchapter III of this chapter are not derived from a reduction in resources for the capabilities authorized in the other subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in subsection (b) shall apply to or affect any capability authorized by any other subchapter of this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004350">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–273, § 2</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title IV, § 416(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 34</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EXPANSION OF HUMAN SPACE FLIGHT BEYOND THE INTERNATIONAL SPACE STATION AND LOW-EARTH ORBIT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18321.</num>
<heading> Human space flight beyond low-Earth orbit</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The extension of the human presence from low-Earth orbit to other regions of space beyond low-Earth orbit will enable missions to the surface of the Moon and missions to deep space destinations such as near-Earth asteroids and Mars.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The regions of cis-lunar space are accessible to other national and commercial launch capabilities, and such access raises a host of national security concerns and economic implications that international human space endeavors can help to address.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The ability to support human missions in regions beyond low-Earth orbit and on the surface of the Moon can also drive developments in emerging areas of space infrastructure and technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Developments in space infrastructure and technology can stimulate and enable increased space applications, such as in-space servicing, propellant resupply and transfer, and in situ resource utilization, and open opportunities for additional users of space, whether national, commercial, or international.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A long term objective for human exploration of space should be the eventual international exploration of Mars.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Future international missions beyond low-Earth orbit should be designed to incorporate capability development and availability, affordability, and international contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Human space flight and future exploration beyond low-Earth orbit should be based around a pay-as-you-go approach. Requirements in new launch and crew systems authorized in this chapter should be scaled to the minimum necessary to meet the core national mission capability needed to conduct cis-lunar missions. These initial missions, along with the development of new technologies and in-space capabilities can form the foundation for missions to other destinations. These initial missions also should provide operational experience prior to the further human expansion into space.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on international collaboration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the following assets and capabilities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any effort by NASA to expand and ensure effective international collaboration on the ISS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The efforts of NASA, including its approach and progress, in defining near-term, cis-lunar space human missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NASA contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In preparing the report required by paragraph (1), the Administrator shall assume that NASA will contribute to the efforts described in that paragraph the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A Space Launch System.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A multi-purpose crew vehicle.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Such other technology elements the Administrator may consider appropriate, and which the Administrator shall specifically identify in the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2813</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18322.</num>
<heading> Space Launch System as follow-on launch vehicle to the Space Shuttle</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States that NASA develop a Space Launch System as a follow-on to the Space Shuttle that can access cis-lunar space and the regions of space beyond low-Earth orbit in order to enable the United States to participate in global efforts to access and develop this increasingly strategic region.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of development</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall, as soon as practicable after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, initiate development of a Space Launch System meeting the minimum capabilities requirements specified in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of current contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to limit NASA’s termination liability costs and support critical capabilities, the Administrator shall, to the extent practicable, extend or modify existing vehicle development and associated contracts necessary to meet the requirements in paragraph (1), including contracts for ground testing of solid rocket motors, if necessary, to ensure their availability for development of the Space Launch System.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum capability requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Space Launch System developed pursuant to subsection (b) shall be designed to have, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The initial capability of the core elements, without an upper stage, of lifting payloads weighing between 70 tons and 100 tons into low-Earth orbit in preparation for transit for missions beyond low-Earth orbit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The capability to carry an integrated upper Earth departure stage bringing the total lift capability of the Space Launch System to 130 tons or more.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The capability to lift the multipurpose crew vehicle.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The capability to serve as a backup system for supplying and supporting ISS cargo requirements or crew delivery requirements not otherwise met by available commercial or partner-supplied vehicles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Space Launch System shall be designed from inception as a fully-integrated vehicle capable of carrying a total payload of 130 tons or more into low-Earth orbit in preparation for transit for missions beyond low-Earth orbit. The Space Launch System shall, to the extent practicable, incorporate capabilities for evolutionary growth to carry heavier payloads. Developmental work and testing of the core elements and the upper stage should proceed in parallel subject to appropriations. Priority should be placed on the core elements with the goal for operational capability for the core elements not later than <date date="2016-12-31">December 31, 2016</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transition needs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall ensure critical skills and capabilities are retained, modified, and developed, as appropriate, in areas related to solid and liquid engines, large diameter fuel tanks, rocket propulsion, and other ground test capabilities for an effective transition to the follow-on Space Launch System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The capacity for efficient and timely evolution, including the incorporation of new technologies, competition of sub-elements, and commercial operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18323.</num>
<heading> Multi-purpose crew vehicle</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of development</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall continue the development of a multi-purpose crew vehicle to be available as soon as practicable, and no later than for use with the Space Launch System. The vehicle shall continue to advance development of the human safety features, designs, and systems in the Orion project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Goal for operational capability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It shall be the goal to achieve full operational capability for the transportation vehicle developed pursuant to this subsection by not later than <date date="2016-12-31">December 31, 2016</date>. For purposes of meeting such goal, the Administrator may undertake a test of the transportation vehicle at the ISS before that date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum capability requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The multi-purpose crew vehicle developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall be designed to have, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The capability to serve as the primary crew vehicle for missions beyond low-Earth orbit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The capability to conduct regular in-space operations, such as rendezvous, docking, and extra-vehicular activities, in conjunction with payloads delivered by the Space Launch System developed pursuant to <ref>section 18322 of this title</ref>, or other vehicles, in preparation for missions beyond low-Earth orbit or servicing of assets described in <ref>section 18383 of this title</ref>, or other assets in cis-lunar space.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The capability to provide an alternative means of delivery of crew and cargo to the ISS, in the event other vehicles, whether commercial vehicles or partner-supplied vehicles, are unable to perform that function.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The capacity for efficient and timely evolution, including the incorporation of new technologies, competition of sub-elements, and commercial operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18324.</num>
<heading> Utilization of existing workforce and assets in development of Space Launch System and multi-purpose crew vehicle</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing the Space Launch System pursuant to <ref>section 18322 of this title</ref> and the multi-purpose crew vehicle pursuant to <ref>section 18323 of this title</ref>, the Administrator shall, to the extent practicable utilize—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> existing contracts, investments, workforce, industrial base, and capabilities from the Space Shuttle and Orion and Ares 1 projects, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> space-suit development activities for application to, and coordinated development of, a multi-purpose crew vehicle suit and associated life-support requirements with potential development of standard NASA-certified suit and life support systems for use in alternative commercially-developed crew transportation systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Space Shuttle-derived components and Ares 1 components that use existing United States propulsion systems, including liquid fuel engines, external tank or tank-related capability, and solid rocket motor engines; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> associated testing facilities, either in being or under construction as of <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discharge of requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In meeting the requirements of subsection (a), the Administrator—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall, to the extent practicable, utilize ground-based manufacturing capability, ground testing activities, launch and operations infrastructure, and workforce expertise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall, to the extent practicable, minimize the modification and development of ground infrastructure and maximize the utilization of existing software, vehicle, and mission operations processes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall complete construction and activation of the A–3 test stand with a completion goal of <date date="2013-09-30">September 30, 2013</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may procure, develop, and flight test applicable components; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> shall take appropriate actions to ensure timely and cost-effective development of the Space Launch System and the multi-purpose crew vehicle, including the use of a procurement approach that incorporates adequate and effective oversight, the facilitation of contractor efficiencies, and the stream-lining of contract and procurement requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18325.</num>
<heading> NASA launch support and infrastructure modernization program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall carry out a program the primary purpose of which is to prepare infrastructure at the Kennedy Space Center that is needed to enable processing and launch of the Space Launch System. Vehicle interfaces and other ground processing and payload integration areas should be simplified to minimize overall costs, enhance safety, and complement the purpose of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The program required by this section shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> investments to improve civil and national security operations at the Kennedy Space Center, to enhance the overall capabilities of the Center, and to reduce the long term cost of operations and maintenance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> measures to provide multi-vehicle support, improvements in payload processing, and partnering at the Kennedy Space Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such other measures, including investments to improve launch infrastructure at NASA flight facilities scheduled to launch cargo to the ISS under the commercial orbital transportation services program as the Administrator may consider appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on NASA launch support and infrastructure modernization program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the plan for the implementation of the NASA launch support and infrastructure modernization program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required by this subsection shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the ground infrastructure plan tied to the Space Launch System and potential ground investment activities at other NASA centers related to supporting the development of the Space Launch System;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of proposed initiatives intended to be conducted jointly or in cooperation with Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, Florida, or other installations or components of the United States Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of plans to use funds authorized to be appropriated by this chapter to improve non-NASA facilities, which plans shall include a business plan outlining the nature and scope of investments planned by other parties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2817</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18326.</num>
<heading> Development of technologies and in-space capabilities for beyond near-Earth space missions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development authorized</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator may initiate activities to develop the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Technologies identified as necessary elements of missions beyond low-Earth orbit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In-space capabilities such as refueling and storage technology, orbital transfer stages, innovative in-space propulsion technology, communications, and data management that facilitate a broad range of users (including military and commercial) and applications defining the architecture and design of such missions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Spacesuit development and associated life support technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Flagship missions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing technologies and capabilities under subsection (a), the Administrator may make investments—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in space technologies such as advanced propulsion, propellant depots, in situ resource utilization, and robotic payloads or capabilities that enable human missions beyond low-Earth orbit ultimately leading to Mars;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in a space-based transfer vehicle including these technologies with an ability to conduct space-based operations that provide capabilities—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to integrate with the Space Launch System and other space-based systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide opportunities for in-space servicing of and delivery to multiple space-based platforms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to facilitate international efforts to expand human presence to deep space destinations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in advanced life support technologies and capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in technologies and capabilities relating to in-space power, propulsion, and energy systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in technologies and capabilities relating to in-space propellant transfer and storage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> in technologies and capabilities relating to in situ resource utilization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> in expanded research to understand the greatest biological impediments to human deep space missions, especially the radiation challenge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of ISS as testbed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may utilize the ISS as a testbed for any technology or capability developed under subsection (a) in a manner consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall coordinate development of technologies and capabilities under this section through an overall agency technology approach, as authorized by section 905 of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18327.</num>
<heading> Report requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 90 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, or upon completion of reference designs for the Space Launch System and Multi-purpose Crew Vehicle authorized by this chapter, whichever occurs first, the Administrator shall provide a detailed report to the appropriate committees of Congress that provides an overall description of the reference vehicle design, the assumptions, description, data, and analysis of the systems trades and resolution process, justification of trade decisions, the design factors which implement the essential system and vehicle capability requirements established by this chapter, the explanation and justification of any deviations from those requirements, the plan for utilization of existing contracts, civil service and contract workforce, supporting infrastructure utilization and modifications, and procurement strategy to expedite development activities through modification of existing contract vehicles, and the schedule of design and development milestones and related schedules leading to the accomplishment of operational goals established by this chapter. The Administrator shall provide an update of this report as part of the President’s annual Budget Request.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>DEVELOPMENT AND USE OF COMMERCIAL CREW AND CARGO TRANSPORTATION CAPABILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18341.</num>
<heading> Commercial Cargo Development program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall continue to support the existing Commercial Resupply Services program, aimed at enabling the commercial space industry in support of NASA to develop reliable means of launching cargo and supplies to the ISS throughout the duration of the facility’s operation. The Administrator may apply funds towards the reduction of risk to the timely start of these services, specifically—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> efforts to conduct a flight test;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accelerate development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop the ground infrastructure needed for commercial cargo capability.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2820</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title III, § 302(f)</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18342.</num>
<heading> Requirements applicable to development of commercial crew transportation capabilities and services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FY 2011 contracts and procurement agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Administrator may not execute a contract or procurement agreement with respect to follow-on commercial crew services during fiscal year 2011.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Administrator may execute a contract or procurement agreement with respect to follow-on commercial crew services during fiscal year 2011 if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the requirements of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (b) are met; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total amount involved for all such contracts and procurement agreements executed during fiscal year 2011 does not exceed $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2011.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator may, beginning in fiscal year 2012 through the duration of the program, support follow-on commercially-developed crew transportation systems dependent upon the completion of each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Human rating requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator shall develop and make available to the public detailed human rating processes and requirements to guide the design of commercially-developed crew transportation capabilities, which requirements shall be at least equivalent to proven requirements for crew transportation in use as of <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial market assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an assessment, conducted, in coordination with the Federal Aviation Administration’s Office of Commercial Space Transportation, for purposes of this paragraph, of the potential non-Government market for commercially-developed crew and cargo transportation systems and capabilities, including an assessment of the activities associated with potential private sector utilization of the ISS research and technology development capabilities and other potential activities in low-Earth orbit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement system review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall review current Government procurement and acquisition practices and processes, including agreement authorities under the National Aeronautics and Space Act of 1958,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004351">1</ref> to determine the most cost-effective means of procuring commercial crew transportation capabilities and related services in a manner that ensures appropriate accountability, transparency, and maximum efficiency in the procurement of such capabilities and services, which review shall include an identification of proposed measures to address risk management and means of indemnification of commercial providers of such capabilities and services, and measures for quality control, safety oversight, and the application of Federal oversight processes within the jurisdiction of other Federal agencies. A description of the proposed procurement process and justification of the proposed procurement for its selection shall be included in any proposed initiation of procurement activity for commercially-developed crew transportation capabilities and services and shall be subject to review by the appropriate committees of Congress before the initiation of any competitive process to procure such capabilities or services. In support of the review by such committees, the Comptroller General shall undertake an assessment of the proposed procurement process and provide a report to the appropriate committees of Congress within 90 days after the date on which the Administrator provides the description and justification to such committees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of government-supplied capabilities and infrastructure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In evaluating any proposed development activity for commercially-developed crew or cargo launch capabilities, the Administrator shall identify the anticipated contribution of government personnel, expertise, technologies, and infrastructure to be utilized in support of design, development, or operations of such capabilities. This assessment shall include a clear delineation of the full requirements for the commercial crew service (including the contingency for crew rescue). The Administrator shall include details and associated costs of such support as part of any proposed development initiative for the procurement of commercially-developed crew or cargo launch capabilities or services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Flight demonstration and readiness requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall establish appropriate milestones and minimum performance objectives to be achieved before authority is granted to proceed to the procurement of commercially-developed crew transportation capabilities or systems. The guidelines shall include a procedure to provide independent assurance of flight safety and flight readiness before the authorization of United States government personnel to participate as crew onboard any commercial launch vehicle developed pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial crew rescue capabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provision of a commercial capability to provide ISS crew services shall include crew rescue requirements, and shall be undertaken through the procurement process initiated in conformance with this section. In the event such development is initiated, the Administrator shall make available any relevant government-owned intellectual property deriving from the development of a multi-purpose crew vehicle authorized by this chapter to commercial entities involved with such crew rescue capability development which shall be relevant to the design of a crew rescue capability. In addition, the Administrator shall seek to ensure that contracts for development of the multi-purpose crew vehicle contain provisions for the licensing of relevant intellectual property to participating commercial providers of any crew rescue capability development undertaken pursuant to this section. If one or more contractors involved with development of the multi-purpose crew vehicle seek to compete in development of a commercial crew service with crew rescue capability, separate legislative authority must be enacted to enable the Administrator to provide funding for any modifications of the multi-purpose crew vehicle necessary to fulfill the ISS crew rescue function.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>CONTINUATION, SUPPORT, AND EVOLUTION OF THE INTERNATIONAL SPACE STATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18351.</num>
<heading> Continuation of the International Space Station</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the policy of the United States, in consultation with its international partners in the ISS program, to support full and complete utilization of the ISS through at least <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NASA action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In furtherance of the policy set forth in subsection (a), NASA shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pursue international, commercial, and intragovernmental means to maximize ISS logistics supply, maintenance, and operational capabilities, reduce risks to ISS systems sustainability, and offset and minimize United States operations costs relating to the ISS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> utilize, to the extent practicable, the ISS for the development of capabilities and technologies needed for the future of human space exploration beyond low-Earth orbit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> utilize, if practical and cost effective, the ISS for Science Mission Directorate missions in low-Earth orbit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 114(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10815(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18352.</num>
<heading> Maximum utilization of the International Space Station</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With assembly of the ISS complete, NASA shall take steps to maximize the productivity and use of the ISS with respect to scientific and technological research and development, advancement of space exploration, and international collaboration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NASA actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), NASA shall, at a minimum, undertake the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Innovative use of U.S. segment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States segment of the ISS, which has been designated as a National Laboratory, shall be developed, managed and utilized in a manner that enables the effective and innovative use of such facility, as provided in <ref>section 18354 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The ISS shall continue to be utilized as a key component of international efforts to build missions and capabilities that further the development of a human presence beyond near-Earth space and advance United States security and economic goals. The Administrator shall actively seek ways to encourage and enable the use of ISS capabilities to support these efforts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic collaboration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The operations, management, and utilization of the ISS shall be conducted in a manner that provides opportunities for collaboration with other research programs and objectives of the United States Government in cooperation with commercial suppliers, users, and developers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18353.</num>
<heading> Maintenance of the United States segment and assurance of continued operations of the International Space Station</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall take all actions necessary to ensure the safe and effective operation, maintenance, and maximum utilization of the United States segment of the ISS through at least <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vehicle and component review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall, as soon as is practicable after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, carry out a comprehensive assessment of the essential modules, operational systems and components, structural elements, and permanent scientific equipment on board or planned for delivery and installation aboard the ISS, including both United States and international partner elements, for purposes of identifying the spare or replacement modules, systems and components, elements, and equipment that are required to ensure complete, effective, and safe functioning and full scientific utilization of the ISS through <date date="2020-09-30">September 30, 2020</date>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004352">1</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the assessment, the Administrator shall assemble any existing data, and provide for the development of any data or analysis not currently available, that is necessary for purposes of the assessment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on assessment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the assessment required by subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The report required by this paragraph shall include, at minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the spare or replacement modules, systems and components, elements, and equipment identified pursuant to the assessment that are currently produced, in inventory, or on order, a description of the state of their readiness, and a schedule for their delivery to the ISS (including the planned transportation means for such delivery), including for each such module, system or component, element, or equipment a description of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> its specifications, including size, weight, and necessary configuration for launch and delivery to the ISS;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> its function;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> its location; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> its criticality for ISS system integrity.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the spare or replacement modules, systems and components, elements, and equipment identified pursuant to the assessment that are not currently produced, in inventory, or on order, including for each such module, system or component, element, or equipment a description of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> its specifications, including size, weight, and necessary configuration for launch and delivery to the ISS;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> its function;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> its location;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> its criticality for ISS system integrity; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> the anticipated cost and schedule for its design, procurement, manufacture, and delivery to the ISS.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A detailed summary of the delivery schedule and associated delivery vehicle requirements necessary to transport all spare and replacement elements considered essential for the ongoing and sustained functionality of all critical systems of the ISS, both in and of themselves and as an element of an integrated, mutually dependent essential capability, including an assessment of the current schedule for delivery, the availability of delivery vehicles to meet that schedule, and the likelihood of meeting that schedule through such vehicles.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> GAO report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after the submittal to Congress under paragraph (1) of the assessment required by subsection (b), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the assessment. The report shall set forth an evaluation of the assessment by the Comptroller General, including an evaluation of the accuracy and level of confidence in the findings of the assessment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with GAO</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Administrator shall provide for the monitoring and participation of the Comptroller General in the assessment in a manner that permits the Comptroller General to prepare and submit the report required by subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of research facilities and capabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Utilization of research facilities and capabilities aboard the ISS (other than exploration-related research and technology development facilities and capabilities, and associated ground support and logistics), shall be planned, managed, and supported as provided in <ref>section 18354 of this title</ref>. Exploration-related research and technology development facilities, capabilities, and associated ground support and logistics shall be planned, managed, and supported by the appropriate NASA organizations and officials in a manner that does not interfere with other activities under <ref>section 18354 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Space Shuttle mission to ISS</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Space Shuttle mission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall fly the Launch-On-Need Shuttle mission currently designated in the Shuttle Flight Manifest dated <date date="2010-02-28">February 28, 2010</date>, to the ISS in fiscal year 2011, but no earlier than <date date="2011-06-01">June 1, 2011</date>, unless required earlier by an operations contingency, and pending the results of the assessment required by paragraph (2) and the determination under paragraph (3)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of safe means of return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall provide for an assessment by the NASA Engineering and Safety Center of the procedures and plans developed to ensure the safety of the Space Shuttle crew, and alternative means of return, in the event the Space Shuttle is damaged or otherwise unable to return safely to Earth.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule and payload</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The determination of the schedule and payload for the mission authorized by paragraph (1) shall take into account the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The supply and logistics delivery requirements of the ISS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The findings of the study required by paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts authorized to be appropriated by section 101(2)(B) <sup>1</sup> shall be available for the mission authorized by paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Space Shuttle manifest flight assurance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall take all actions necessary to preserve Space Shuttle launch capability through fiscal year 2011 in a manner that enables the launch, at a minimum, of missions and primary payloads in the Shuttle flight manifest as of <date date="2010-02-28">February 28, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation of contractor support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator may not terminate any contract that provides the system transitions necessary for shuttle-derived hardware to be used on either the multi-purpose crew vehicle described in <ref>section 18323 of this title</ref> or the Space Launch System described in <ref>section 18322 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 114(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10815(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18354.</num>
<heading> Management of the ISS national laboratory</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreement with not-for-profit entity for management of national laboratory</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall provide initial financial assistance and enter into a cooperative agreement with an appropriate organization that is exempt from taxation under <ref>section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> to manage the activities of the ISS national laboratory in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The organization with which the Administrator enters into the cooperative agreement shall develop the capabilities to implement research and development projects utilizing the ISS national laboratory and to otherwise manage the activities of the ISS national laboratory.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on other activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The cooperative agreement shall require the organization entering into the agreement to engage exclusively in activities relating to the management of the ISS national laboratory and activities that promote its long term research and development mission as required by this section, without any other organizational objectives or responsibilities on behalf of the organization or any parent organization or other entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NASA liaison</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall designate an official or employee of the Space Operations Mission Directorate of NASA to act as liaison between NASA and the organization with which the Administrator enters into a cooperative agreement under subsection (a) with regard to the management of the ISS national laboratory.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with liaison</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The cooperative agreement shall require the organization entering into the agreement to carry out its responsibilities under the agreement in cooperation and consultation with the official or employee designated under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Planning and coordination of ISS national laboratory research activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall provide initial financial assistance to the organization with which the Administrator enters into a cooperative agreement under subsection (a), in order for the organization to initiate the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Planning and coordination of the ISS national laboratory research activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Development and implementation of guidelines, selection criteria, and flight support requirements for non-NASA scientific utilization of ISS research capabilities and facilities available in United States-owned modules of the ISS or in partner-owned facilities of the ISS allocated to United States utilization by international agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Interaction with and integration of the International Space Station National Laboratory Advisory Committee established under <ref>section 70906 of title 51</ref> with the governance of the organization, and review recommendations provided by that Committee regarding agreements with non-NASA departments and agencies of the United States Government, academic institutions and consortia, and commercial entities leading to the utilization of the ISS national laboratory facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Coordination of transportation requirements in support of the ISS national laboratory research and development objectives, including provision for delivery of instruments, logistics support, and related experiment materials, and provision for return to Earth of collected samples, materials, and scientific instruments in need of replacement or upgrade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Cooperation with NASA, other departments and agencies of the United States Government, the States, and commercial entities in ensuring the enhancement and sustained operations of non-exploration-related research payload ground support facilities for the ISS, including the Space Life Sciences Laboratory, the Space Station Processing Facility and Payload Operations Integration Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Development and implementation of scientific outreach and education activities designed to ensure effective utilization of ISS research capabilities including the conduct of scientific assemblies, conferences, and other fora for the presentation of research findings, methods, and mechanisms for the dissemination of non-restricted research findings and the development of educational programs, course supplements, interaction with educational programs at all grade levels, including student-focused research opportunities for conduct of research in the ISS national laboratory facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Such other matters relating to the utilization of the ISS national laboratory facilities for research and development as the Administrator may consider appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research capacity allocation and integration of research payloads</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of ISS research capacity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The ISS national laboratory managed experiments shall be guaranteed access to, and utilization of, not less than 50 percent of the United States research capacity allocation, including power, cold stowage, and requisite crew time onboard the ISS through at least <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>. Access to the ISS research capacity includes provision for the adequate upmass and downmass capabilities to utilize the ISS research capacity, as available. The Administrator may allocate additional capacity to the ISS national laboratory should such capacity be in excess of NASA research requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional research capabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any NASA research plan is determined to require research capacity onboard the ISS beyond the percentage allocated under paragraph (1), such research plan shall be prepared in the form of a requested research opportunity to be submitted to the process established under this section for the consideration of proposed research within the capacity allocated to the ISS national laboratory. A proposal for such a research plan may include the establishment of partnerships with non-NASA institutions eligible to propose research to be conducted within the ISS national laboratory capacity. Until at least <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>, the official or employee designated under subsection (b) may grant an exception to this requirement in the case of a proposed experiment considered essential for purposes of preparing for exploration beyond low-Earth orbit, as determined by joint agreement between the organization with which the Administrator enters into a cooperative agreement under subsection (a) and the official or employee designated under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research priorities and enhanced capacity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The organization with which the Administrator enters into the cooperative agreement shall consider recommendations of the National Academies Decadal Survey on Biological and Physical Sciences in Space in establishing research priorities and in developing proposed enhancements of research capacity and opportunities for the ISS national laboratory.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility for research payload</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">NASA shall retain its roles and responsibilities in providing research payload physical, analytical, and operations integration during pre-flight, post-flight, transportation, and orbital phases essential to ensure safe and effective flight readiness and vehicle integration of research activities approved and prioritized by the organization with which the Administrator enters into the cooperative agreement and the official or employee designated under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 114(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10815(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>SPACE SHUTTLE RETIREMENT AND TRANSITION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18361.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress on the Space Shuttle program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Space Shuttle program represents a national asset consisting of critical skills and capabilities, including the ability to lift large payloads into space and return them to Earth.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Space Shuttle has carried more than 355 people from 16 nations into space.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Space Shuttle has projected the best of American values around the world, and Space Shuttle crews have sparked the imagination and dreams of the world’s youth and young at heart.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> it is essential that the retirement of the Space Shuttle and the transition to new human space flight capabilities be done in a manner that builds upon the legacy of this national asset; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> it is imperative for the United States to retain the skills and the industrial capability to provide a follow-on Space Launch System that is primarily designed for missions beyond near-Earth space, while offering some potential for supplanting shuttle delivery capabilities to low-Earth orbit, particularly in support of ISS requirements, if necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18362.</num>
<heading> Retirement of Space Shuttle orbiters and transition of Space Shuttle program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall retire the Space Shuttle orbiters pursuant to a schedule established by the Administrator and in a manner consistent with provisions of this chapter regarding potential requirements for contingency utilization of Space Shuttle orbiters for ISS requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of workforce and assets in follow-on Space Launch System</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of vehicle assets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall, to the maximum extent practicable, utilize workforce, assets, and infrastructure of the Space Shuttle program in efforts relating to the initiation of a follow-on Space Launch System developed pursuant to <ref>section 18322 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other assets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to the workforce, assets, and infrastructure not utilized as described in paragraph (1), the Administrator shall work closely with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government, and the private sector, to divest unneeded assets and to assist displaced workers with retraining and other placement efforts. Amounts authorized to be appropriated by section 101(2)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004353">1</ref> shall be available for activities pursuant to this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18363.</num>
<heading> Disposition of orbiter vehicles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the termination of the Space Shuttle program as provided in <ref>section 18362 of this title</ref>, the Administrator shall decommission any remaining Space Shuttle orbiter vehicles according to established safety and historic preservation procedures prior to their designation as surplus government property. The orbiter vehicles shall be made available and located for display and maintenance through a competitive procedure established pursuant to the disposition plan developed under section 613(a) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2008 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 17761(a)</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004354">1</ref> with priority consideration given to eligible applicants meeting all conditions of that plan which would provide for the display and maintenance of orbiters at locations with the best potential value to the public, including where the location of the orbiters can advance educational opportunities in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics disciplines, and with an historical relationship with either the launch, flight operations, or processing of the Space Shuttle orbiters or the retrieval of NASA manned space vehicles, or significant contributions to human space flight. The Smithsonian Institution, which, as of <date date="2001-10-11">October 11, 2001</date>, houses the Space Shuttle Enterprise, shall determine any new location for the Enterprise.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Display and maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The orbiter vehicles made available under subsection (a) shall be displayed and maintained through agreements and procedures established pursuant to section 613(a) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2008 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 17761(a)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to NASA such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section. The amounts authorized to be appropriated by this subsection shall be in addition to any amounts authorized to be appropriated by title I, and may be requested by the President as supplemental requirements, if needed, in the appropriate fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>EARTH SCIENCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18371.</num>
<heading> Interagency collaboration implementation approach</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of OSTP shall establish a mechanism to ensure greater coordination of the research, operations, and activities relating to civilian Earth observation of those Agencies, including NASA, that have active programs that either contribute directly or indirectly to these areas. This mechanism should include the development of a strategic implementation plan that is updated at least every 3 years, and includes a process for external independent advisory input. This plan should include a description of the responsibilities of the various Agency roles in Earth observations, recommended cost-sharing and procurement arrangements between Agencies and other entities, including international arrangements, and a plan for ensuring the provision of sustained, long term space-based climate observations. The Director shall provide a report to Congress within 90 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, on the implementation plan for this mechanism.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18372.</num>
<heading> Transitioning experimental research to operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall coordinate with the Administrator of NOAA and the Director of the United States Geological Survey to establish a formal mechanism that plans, coordinates, and supports the transitioning of NASA research findings, assets, and capabilities to NOAA operations and United States Geological Survey operations. In defining this mechanism, NASA should consider the establishment of a formal or informal Interagency Transition Office. The Administrator of NASA shall provide an implementation plan for this mechanism to Congress within 90 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18373.</num>
<heading> Decadal Survey missions implementation for Earth observation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall undertake to implement, as appropriate, missions identified in the National Research Council’s Earth Science Decadal Survey within the scope of the funds authorized for the Earth Science Mission Directorate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18374.</num>
<heading> Instrument test-beds and venture class missions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall pursue innovative ways to fly instrument-level payloads for early demonstration or as co-manifested payloads. The Congress encourages the use of the ISS as an accessible platform for the conduct of such activities. Additionally, in order to address the cost and schedule challenges associated with large flight systems, NASA should pursue smaller systems where practicable and warranted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>SPACE SCIENCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18381.</num>
<heading> Technology development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that the Science Mission Directorate maintains a long term technology development program for space and Earth science. This effort should be coordinated with an overall Agency technology investment approach, as authorized in section 905 of this Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18382.</num>
<heading> Suborbital research activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report of the National Academy of Sciences, Revitalizing NASA’s Suborbital Program: Advancing Science, Driving Innovation and Developing Workforce, found that suborbital science missions were absolutely critical to building an aerospace workforce capable of meeting the needs of current and future human and robotic space exploration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall designate an officer or employee of the Science Mission Directorate to act as the responsible official for all Suborbital Research in the Science Mission Directorate. The designee shall be responsible for the development of short- and long term strategic plans for maintaining, renewing and extending suborbital facilities and capabilities, monitoring progress towards goals in the plans, and be responsible for integration of suborbital activities and workforce development within the agency, thereby ensuring the long term recognition of their combined value to the directorate, to NASA, and to the Nation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Suborbital Research Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish a Suborbital Research Program within the Science Mission Directorate that shall include the use of sounding rockets, aircraft, high altitude balloons, suborbital reusable launch vehicles, and commercial launch vehicles to advance science and train the next generation of scientists and engineers in systems engineering and systems integration which are vital to maintaining critical skills in the aerospace workforce. The program shall integrate existing suborbital research programs with orbital missions at the discretion of the designated officer or employee and shall emphasize the participation of undergraduate and graduate students and post-doctoral researchers when formulating announcements of opportunity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall report to the appropriate committees of Congress on the number and type of suborbital missions conducted in each fiscal year and the number of undergraduate and graduate students participating in the missions. The report shall be made annually for each fiscal year under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18383.</num>
<heading> In-space servicing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall continue to take all necessary steps to ensure that provisions are made for in-space or human servicing and repair of all future observatory-class scientific spacecraft intended to be deployed in Earth-orbit or at a Lagrangian point to the extent practicable and appropriate. The Administrator should ensure that agency investments and future capabilities for space technology, robotics, and human space flight take the ability to service and repair these spacecraft into account, where appropriate, and incorporate such capabilities into design and operational plans.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18384.</num>
<heading> Decadal results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">NASA shall take into account the current decadal surveys from the National Academies’ Space Studies Board when submitting the President’s budget request to the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18385.</num>
<heading> On-going restoration of radioisotope thermoelectric generator material production</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States has led the world in the scientific exploration of space for nearly 50 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Missions such as Viking, Voyager, Cassini, and New Horizons have greatly expanded knowledge of our solar system and planetary characteristics and evolution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Radioisotope power systems are the only available power sources for deep space missions making it possible to travel to such distant destinations as Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Pluto, and beyond and maintain operational control and systems viability for extended mission durations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Current radioisotope power systems supplies and production will not fully support NASA missions planned even in the next decade and, without a new domestic production capability, the United States will no longer have the means to explore the majority of the solar system by the end of this decade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Continuing to rely on Russia or other foreign sources for radioisotope power system fuel production is not a secure option.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Reestablishing domestic production will require a long lead-time. Thus, meeting future space exploration mission needs requires that a restart project begin at the earliest opportunity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, pursue a joint approach beginning in fiscal year 2011 towards restarting and sustaining the domestic production of radioisotope thermoelectric generator material for deep space and other science and exploration missions. Funds authorized by this chapter for NASA shall be made available under a reimbursable agreement with the Department of Energy for the purpose of reestablishing facilities to produce fuel required for radioisotope thermoelectric generators to enable future missions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 120 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy shall submit a joint report to the appropriate committees of Congress on coordinated agreements, planned implementation, and anticipated schedule, production quantities, and mission applications under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18386.</num>
<heading> Collaboration with ESMD and SOMD on robotic missions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that the Exploration Systems Mission Directorate and the Space Operations Mission Directorate coordinate with the Science Mission Directorate on an overall approach and plan for interagency and international collaboration on robotic missions that are NASA or internationally developed, including lunar, Lagrangian, near-Earth orbit, and Mars spacecraft, such as the International Lunar Network. Within 90 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator shall provide a plan to the appropriate committees of Congress for implementation of the collaborative approach required by this section. The Administrator may not cancel or initiate any Exploration Systems Mission Directorate or Science Mission Directorate robotic project before the plan is submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18387.</num>
<heading> Near-Earth object survey and policy with respect to threats posed</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy reaffirmation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress reaffirms the policy set forth in <ref>section 20102(g) of title 51</ref> relating to surveying near-Earth asteroids and comets.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the OSTP shall implement, before <date date="2012-09-30">September 30, 2012</date>, a policy for notifying Federal agencies and relevant emergency response institutions of an impending near-Earth object threat if near-term public safety is at risk, and assign a Federal agency or agencies to be responsible for protecting the United States and working with the international community on such threats.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18388.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–181, § 2(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-21">Oct. 21, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 892</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>AERONAUTICS AND SPACE TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18401.</num>
<heading> Aeronautics research goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator should ensure that NASA maintains a strong aeronautics research portfolio ranging from fundamental research through systems research with specific research goals, including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Airspace capacity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">NASA’s Aeronautics Research Mission Directorate shall address research needs of the Next Generation Air Transportation System, including the ability of the National Airspace System to handle up to 3 times the current travel demand by 2025.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Environmental sustainability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Directorate shall consider and pursue concepts to reduce noise, emissions, and fuel consumption while maintaining high safety standards and shall pursue research related to alternative fuels.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aviation safety</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Directorate shall proactively address safety challenges with new and current air vehicles and with operations in the Nation’s current and future air transportation system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18402.</num>
<heading> Research collaboration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall continue to coordinate with the Secretary of Defense, through the National Partnership for Aeronautics Testing, to develop and implement joint plans for those elements of the Nation’s research, development, testing, and engineering infrastructure that are of common interest and use.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Aviation Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall continue to coordinate with, and work closely with, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, under the framework of the Senior Policy Council, in development of the Next Generation Air Transportation Program. The Administrator shall encourage the Council to explore areas for greater collaboration, including areas where NASA can help to accelerate the development and demonstration of NextGen technologies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18403.</num>
<heading> Goal for Agency space technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is critical that NASA maintain an Agency space technology base that helps align mission directorate investments and supports long term needs to complement mission-directorate funded research and support, where appropriate, multiple users, building upon its Innovative Partnerships Program and other partnering approaches.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18404.</num>
<heading> National space technology policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President or the President’s designee, in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, shall develop a national policy to guide the space technology development programs of the United States through 2020. The policy shall include national goals for technology development and shall describe the role and responsibilities of each Federal agency that will carry out the policy. In developing the policy, the President or the President’s designee shall utilize external studies that have been conducted on the state of United States technology development and have suggested policies to ensure continued competitiveness.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> At a minimum, the national space technology development policy shall describe for NASA—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the priority areas of research for technology investment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the basis on which and the process by which priorities for ensuing fiscal years will be selected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the facilities and personnel needed to carry out the technology development program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the budget assumptions on which the policy is based, which for fiscal years 2011, 2012, and 2013 shall be the authorized level for NASA’s technology program authorized by this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The policy shall be based on the premise that the Federal Government has an established interest in conducting research and development programs that help preserve the role of the United States as a global leader in space technologies and their application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In developing the national space technology development policy, the President or the President’s designee shall consider, and include a discussion in the report required by subsection (c), of the following issues:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The extent to which NASA should focus on long term, high-risk research or more incremental technology development, and the expected impact of that decision on the United States economy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The extent to which NASA should address military and commercial needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> How NASA will coordinate its technology program with other Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The extent to which NASA will conduct research in-house, fund university research, and collaborate on industry research and the expected impact of that mix of funding on the supply of United States workers for industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the development of the national space technology development policy, the President or the President’s designee shall consult widely with academic and industry experts and with other Federal agencies. The Administrator may enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to help develop the policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the President shall transmit a report setting forth national space technology policy to the appropriate committees of Congress and to the Senate Committee on Appropriations and the House of Representatives Committee on Appropriations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the President transmits the report required by paragraph (1) to the Congress, the Administrator shall transmit a report to the same committees describing how NASA will carry out the policy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18405.</num>
<heading> Commercial Reusable Suborbital Research Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report of the National Academy of Sciences, Revitalizing NASA’s Suborbital Program: Advancing Science, Driving Innovation and Developing Workforce, found that suborbital science missions were absolutely critical to building an aerospace workforce capable of meeting the needs of current and future human and robotic space exploration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall designate an officer or employee of the Space Technology Program to act as the responsible official for the Commercial Reusable Suborbital Research Program in the Space Technology Program. The designee shall be responsible for the development of short- and long term strategic plans for maintaining, renewing and extending suborbital facilities and capabilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish a Commercial Reusable Suborbital Research Program within the Space Technology Program that shall fund the development of payloads for scientific research, technology development, and education, and shall provide flight opportunities for those payloads to microgravity environments and suborbital altitudes. The Commercial Reusable Suborbital Research Program may fund engineering and integration demonstrations, proofs of concept, or educational experiments for commercial reusable vehicle flights. The program shall endeavor to work with NASA’s Mission Directorates to help achieve NASA’s research, technology, and education goals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall submit a report annually to the appropriate committees of Congress describing progress in carrying out the Commercial Reusable Suborbital Research program, including the number and type of suborbital missions planned in each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2013 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title IX, § 907</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IX—</num>
<heading>EDUCATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18421.</num>
<heading> Study of potential commercial orbital platform program impact on science, technology, engineering, and mathematics</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A fundamental and unique capability of NASA is in stimulating science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education in the United States. In ensuring maximum use of that capability, the Administrator shall carry out a study to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify the benefits of and lessons learned from ongoing and previous NASA orbital student programs including, at a minimum, the Get Away Special (GAS) and Earth Knowledge Acquired by Middle School Students (EarthKAM) programs, on science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assess the potential impacts on science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education of a program that would facilitate the development of scientific and educational payloads involving United States students and educators and the flights of those payloads on commercially available orbital platforms, when available and operational, with the goal of providing frequent and regular payload launches;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify NASA expertise, such as NASA science, engineering, payload development, and payload operations, that could be made available to facilitate a science, technology, engineering, and mathematics program using commercial orbital platforms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identify the issues that would need to be addressed before NASA could properly assess the merits and feasibility of the program described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title X, § 1003</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2838</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER X—</num>
<heading>RE-SCOPING AND REVITALIZING INSTITUTIONAL CAPABILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18431.</num>
<heading> Workforce stabilization and critical skills preservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Prior to receipt by the Congress of the study, recommendations, and implementation strategy developed pursuant to section 1103,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004355">1</ref> none of the funds authorized for use under this Act may be used to transfer the functions, missions, or activities, and associated civil service and contractor positions, from any NASA facility without authorization by the Congress to implement the proposed strategy. The Administrator shall preserve the critical skills and competencies in place at NASA centers prior to <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, in order to facilitate timely implementation of the requirements of this chapter and to minimize disruption to the workforce. The Administrator may not implement any reduction-in-force or other involuntary separations of permanent, non-Senior-Executive-Service, civil servant employees before <date date="2013-09-30">September 30, 2013</date>, except for cause on charges of misconduct, delinquency, or inefficiency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER XI—</num>
<heading>OTHER MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 18441.</num>
<heading> National and international orbital debris mitigation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A national and international effort is needed to develop a coordinated approach towards the prevention, negation, and removal of orbital debris.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The guidelines issued by the Inter-Agency Space Debris Coordination Committee provide a consensus understanding of 10 national space agencies (including NASA) plus the European Space Agency on the necessity of mitigating the creation of space debris and measures for doing so. NASA’s participation on the Committee should be robust, and NASA should urge other space-relevant Federal agencies (including the Departments of State, Defense, and Commerce) to work to ensure that their counterpart agencies in foreign governments are aware of these national commitments and the importance in which the United States holds them.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Key components of such an approach should include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a process for debris prevention through agreements regarding spacecraft design, operations, and end-of-life disposition plans to minimize orbiting vehicles or elements which are nonfunctional;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the development of a robust Space Situational Awareness network that can identify potential collisions and provide sufficient trajectory and orbital data to enable avoidance maneuvers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the interagency development of an overall strategy for review by the President, with recommendations for proposed international collaborative efforts to address this challenge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International discussion</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator shall, in consultation with such other departments and agencies of the Federal Government as the Administrator considers appropriate, continue and strengthen discussions with the representatives of other space-faring countries, within the Inter-Agency Space Debris Coordination Committee and elsewhere, to deal with this orbital debris mitigation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of carrying out this subsection, the Director of OSTP, in coordination with the Director of the National Security Council and using the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology coordinating mechanism, shall develop an overall strategy for review by the President, with recommendations for proposed international collaborative efforts to address this challenge.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title XII, § 1202</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18442.</num>
<heading> Reports on program and cost assessment and control assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The adherence of NASA to program cost and schedule targets and discipline across NASA programs remains a concern.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The James Webb Space Telescope has exceeded its cost estimate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In 2007 the Government Accountability Office issued a report on NASA’s high risk acquisition performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In response, NASA prepared a corrective action plan two years ago.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, and not later than April 30 of each year thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the implementation during the preceding year for the corrective action plan referred to in subsection (a)(4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each report under this subsection shall set forth, for the year covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of each NASA program that has exceeded its cost baseline by 15 percent or more or is more than 2 years behind its projected development schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For each program specified under subparagraph (A), a plan for such decrease in scope or requirements, or other measures, to be undertaken to control cost and schedule, including any cost monitoring or corrective actions undertaken pursuant to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2005 (<ref>Public Law 109–155</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004356">1</ref> and the amendments made by that Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title XII, § 1203</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18443.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for service of individual currently serving as Administrator of NASA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The individual serving in the position of Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration as of <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, comes from civilian life and is therefore eligible to serve in such position, in conformance with <ref>section 20111 of title 51</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18444.</num>
<heading> Counterfeit parts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall plan, develop, and implement a program, in coordination with other Federal agencies, to detect, track, catalog, and reduce the number of counterfeit electronic parts in the NASA supply chain.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the program, the Administrator shall establish—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> counterfeit part identification training for all employees that procure, process, distribute, and install electronic parts that will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> teach employees how to identify counterfeit parts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> educate employees on procedures to follow if they suspect a part is counterfeit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> regularly update employees on new threats, identification techniques, and reporting requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> integrate industry associations, manufacturers, suppliers, and other Federal agencies, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an internal database to track all suspected and confirmed counterfeit electronic parts that will maintain, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> companies and individuals known and suspected of selling counterfeit parts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> parts known and suspected of being counterfeit, including lot and date codes, part numbers, and part images;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> countries of origin;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> sources of reporting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> United States Customs seizures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Government-Industry Data Exchange Program reports and other public or private sector database notifications; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a mechanism to report all information on suspected and confirmed counterfeit electronic parts to law enforcement agencies, industry associations, and other databases, and to issue bulletins to industry on counterfeit electronic parts and related counterfeit activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of procurement and acquisition policy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In establishing the program, the Administrator shall amend existing acquisition and procurement policy to purchase electronic parts from trusted or approved manufacturers. To determine trusted or approved manufacturers, the Administrator shall establish a list, assessed and adjusted at least annually, and create criteria for manufacturers to meet in order to be placed onto the list.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The criteria may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> authentication or encryption codes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> embedded security markings in parts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> unique, harder to copy labels and markings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identifying distinct lot and serial codes on external packaging;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> radio frequency identification embedded into high-value parts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> physical destruction of all defective, damaged, and sub-standard parts that are by-products of the manufacturing process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> testing certifications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> maintenance of procedures for handling any counterfeit parts that slip through;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> maintenance of secure facilities to prevent unauthorized access to proprietary information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> maintenance of product return, buy back, and inventory control practices that limit counterfeiting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within one year after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, the Administrator shall report on the progress of implementing this section to the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title XII, § 1206</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18445.</num>
<heading> Information security</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring risk</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Update on system implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2010-10-11">October 11, 2010</date>, and on a biennial basis thereafter, the chief information officer of NASA, in coordination with other national security agencies, shall provide to the appropriate committees of Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an update on efforts to implement a system to provide dynamic, comprehensive, real-time information regarding risk of unauthorized remote, proximity, and insider use or access, for all information infrastructure under the responsibility of the chief information officer, and mission-related networks, including contractor networks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of whether the system has demonstrably and quantifiably reduced network risk compared to alternative methods of measuring security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the progress that each center and facility has made toward implementing the system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing assessments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The assessments required of the Inspector General under section 3545 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004357">1</ref> of title 44 shall evaluate the effectiveness of the system described in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information security awareness and education</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In consultation with the Department of Education, other national security agencies, and other agency directorates, the chief information officer shall institute an information security awareness and education program for all operators and users of NASA information infrastructure, with the goal of reducing unauthorized remote, proximity, and insider use or access.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The program shall include, at a minimum, ongoing classified and unclassified threat-based briefings, and automated exercises and examinations that simulate common attack techniques.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> All agency employees and contractors engaged in the operation or use of agency information infrastructure shall participate in the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Access to NASA information infrastructure shall only be granted to operators and users who regularly satisfy the requirements of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The chief human capital officer of NASA, in consultation with the chief information officer, shall create a system to reward operators and users of agency information infrastructure for continuous high achievement in the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information infrastructure defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “information infrastructure” means the underlying framework that information systems and assets rely on to process, transmit, receive, or store information electronically, including programmable electronic devices and communications networks and any associated hardware, software, or data.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–267, title XII, § 1207</ref>, <date date="2010-10-11">Oct. 11, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2844</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>