<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 109A—</num>
<heading>MEMBRANE PROCESSES RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10341.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there is an increasing threat of impairment to the quantity and quality of the Nation’s water resources due to, among other things, growing national needs, recurring drought in the Western States, point and nonpoint source pollution, and saltwater intrusion into existing groundwater supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> many communities in the United States have water supplies containing high salinity levels or contaminants which pose health risks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Nation needs to develop economical processes to treat existing water supplies that are contaminated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> it is necessary to provide for research into new techniques to reclaim waste water and to convert saline and other contaminated waters to a quality suitable for municipal, industrial, agricultural, recreational, and other beneficial uses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> there is very little Federal funding being applied to basic research in the field of treatment of contaminated water through membrane processes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the treatment of contaminated water through membrane processes will solve a wide variety of water treatment problems, including compliance with the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [<ref>33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.] and the Safe Drinking Water Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 300f</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–490, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10342.</num>
<heading> Research program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall establish a basic research program on membranes and membrane processes. Such program may be carried out through awarding grants, entering into contracts or cooperative agreements, or direct research.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–490, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10343.</num>
<heading> Goals of research program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The goals of the research program established under <ref>section 10342 of this title</ref> shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the development of membranes resistant to degradation, bacterial or otherwise, thereby extending the life of such membranes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development of membranes useful for the efficient and cost effective treatment of contaminated water; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the development of innovative technologies for membrane processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–490, § 4</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10344.</num>
<heading> Coordination with other research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The research program established under <ref>section 10342 of this title</ref> shall be carried out in coordination with any other related Federal research efforts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–490, § 5</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10345.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation, from sums otherwise authorized to be appropriated, $2,500,000 for fiscal year 1993, for carrying out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–490, § 6</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>