<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 98—</num>
<heading>OCEAN THERMAL ENERGY CONVERSION RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9001.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the supply of nonrenewable fuels in the United States is slowly being depleted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> alternative sources of energy must be developed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ocean thermal energy is a renewable energy resource that can make a significant contribution to the energy needs of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the technology base for ocean thermal energy conversion has improved over the past two years, and has consequently lowered the technical risk involved in constructing moderate-sized pilot plants with an electrical generating capacity of about ten to forty megawatts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> while the Federal ocean thermal energy conversion program has grown in size and scope over the past several years, it is in the national interest to accelerate efforts to commercialize ocean thermal energy conversion by building pilot and demonstration facilities and to begin planning for the commercial demonstration of ocean thermal energy conversion technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a strong and innovative domestic industry committed to the commercialization of ocean thermal energy conversion must be established, and many competent domestic industrial groups are already involved in ocean thermal energy conversion research and development activity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> consistent with the findings of the Domestic Policy Review on Solar Energy, ocean thermal energy conversion energy can potentially contribute at least one-tenth of quad of energy per year by the year 2000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Therefore, the purpose of this chapter is to accelerate ocean thermal energy conversion technology development to provide a technical base for meeting the following goals:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> demonstration by 1986 of at least one hundred megawatts of electrical capacity or energy product equivalent from ocean thermal energy conversion systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> demonstration by 1989 of at least five hundred megawatts of electrical capacity or energy product equivalent from ocean thermal energy conversion systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> achievement in the mid-1990’s, for the gulf coast region of the continental United States and for islands in the United States, its possessions and its territories, an average cost of electricity or energy product equivalent produced by installed ocean thermal energy conversion systems that is competitive with conventional energy sources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish as a national goal ten thousand megawatts of electrical capacity or energy product equivalent from ocean thermal energy conversion systems by the year 1999.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9002.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive program management plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized and directed to prepare a comprehensive program management plan for the conduct under this chapter of research, development, and demonstration activities consistent with the provisions of sections 9003, 9004, and 9005 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the preparation of such plan, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Administrator of the Maritime Administration, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the heads of such other Federal agencies and such public and private organizations as he deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal of plan to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit the comprehensive program management plan to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate within nine months after <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requisite provisions of plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The detailed description of the comprehensive plan under this section shall include, but need not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the anticipated research, development, and demonstration objectives to be achieved by the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the program strategies and technology application and market development plans, including detailed milestone goals to be achieved during the next fiscal year for all major activities and projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a five-year implementation schedule for program elements with associated budget and program management resources requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a detailed description of the functional organization of the program management including identification of permanent test facilities and of a lead center responsible for technology support and project management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the estimated relative financial contributions of the Federal Government and non-Federal participants in the pilot and demonstration projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> supporting research needed to solve problems which may inhibit or limit development of ocean thermal energy conversion systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> an analysis of the environmental, economic, and societal impacts of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1051(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9003.</num>
<heading> Research and development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall initiate research or accelerate existing research in areas in which the lack of knowledge limits development of ocean thermal energy conversion systems in order to achieve the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluations, tests, and dissemination of information, data, and materials</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct evaluations, arrange for tests, and disseminate to developers information, data, and materials necessary to support the design efforts undertaken pursuant to <ref>section 9004 of this title</ref>. Specific technical areas to be addressed shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> interface requirements between the platform and cold water pipe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cold water pipe deployment techniques;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> heat exchangers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> control system simulation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> stationkeeping requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> energy delivery systems, such as electric cable or energy product transport.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of new or improved technologies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, for the purpose of performing his responsibilities pursuant to this chapter, solicit proposals and evaluate any reasonable new or improved technology, a description of which is submitted to the Secretary in writing, which could lead or contribute to the development of ocean thermal energy conversion system technology.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9004.</num>
<heading> Pilot and demonstration plants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to initiate a program to design, construct, and operate well instrumented ocean thermal energy conversion facilities of sufficient size to demonstrate the technical feasibility and potential economic feasibility of utilizing the various forms of ocean thermal energy conversion to displace nonrenewable fuels. To achieve the goals of this section and to facilitate development of a strong industrial basis for the application of ocean thermal energy conversion system technology, at least two independent parallel demonstration projects shall be competitively selected.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstration program goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The specific goals of the demonstration program shall include at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the demonstration of ocean thermal energy conversion technical feasibility through multiple pilot and demonstration plants with a combined capacity of at least one hundred megawatts of electrical capacity or energy product equivalent by the year 1986;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the delivery of baseload electricity to utilities located on land or the production of commercially attractive quantities of energy product; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the continuous operation of each pilot and demonstration facility for a sufficient period of time to collect and analyze system performance and reliability data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing any financial assistance under this section, the Secretary shall (1) give full consideration to those projects which will provide energy to United States offshore States, its territories, and its possessions and (2) seek satisfactory cost-sharing arrangements when he deems such arrangements to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 5</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9005.</num>
<heading> Technology application</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technology application and market development plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Administrator of the Maritime Administration, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the Technical Panel established under <ref>section 9007 of this title</ref>, prepare a comprehensive technology application and market development plan that will permit realization of the ten-thousand-megawatt national goal by the year 1999. Such plans shall include at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an assessment of those Government actions required to achieve a two-hundred- to four-hundred-megawatt electrical-commercial demonstration of ocean thermal energy conversion systems in time to have industry meet the goal contained in <ref>section 9001(b)(2) of this title</ref> including a listing of those financial, property, and patent right packages most likely to lead to early commercial demonstration at minimum cost to the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of further Government actions required to permit expansion of the domestic ocean thermal energy conversion industry to meet the goal contained in <ref>section 9001(b)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an analysis of further Government actions necessary to aid the industry in minimizing and removing any legal and institutional barriers such as the designation of a lead agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an assessment of the necessary Government actions to assist in eliminating economic uncertainties through financial incentives, such as loan guarantees, price supports, or other inducements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal of plan to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit such comprehensive technology application and market development plan to the Congress within three years after <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, and update the plan on an annual basis thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Respondent proposals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As part of the competitive procurement initiative for design and construction of the pilot and demonstration projects authorized in <ref>section 9009(c) of this title</ref>, each respondent shall include in its proposal (1) a plan leading to a full-scale, first-of-a-kind facility based on a proposed demonstration system; and (2) the financial and other contributions the respondent will make toward meeting the national goals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9006.</num>
<heading> Program selection criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in fulfilling his responsibilities under this chapter, select program activities and set priorities which are consistent with the following criteria:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> realization of energy production costs for ocean thermal energy conversion systems that are competitive with costs from conventional energy production systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encouragement of projects for which contributions to project costs are forthcoming from private, industrial, utility, or governmental entities for the purpose of sharing with the Federal Government the costs of purchasing and installing ocean thermal energy conversion systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promotion of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities for coastal areas, islands, and isolated military institutions which are vulnerable to interruption in the fossil fuel supply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> preference for and priority to persons and domestic firms whose base of operations is in the United States as will assure that the program under this chapter promotes the development of a United States domestic technology for ocean thermal energy conversion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> preference for proposals for pilot and demonstration projects in which the respondents certify their intent to become an integral part of the industrial infrastructure necessary to meet the goals of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 7</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9007.</num>
<heading> Technical Panel of Energy Research Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Technical Panel of the Energy Research Advisory Board shall be established to advise the Board on the conduct of the ocean thermal energy conversion program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Technical Panel shall be comprised of such representatives from domestic industry, universities, Government laboratories, financial, environmental and other organizations as the Chairman of the Energy Research Advisory Board deems appropriate based on his assessment of the technical and other qualifications of such representative.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the Technical Panel need not be members of the full Energy Research Advisory Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with laws and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The activities of the Technical Panel shall be in compliance with any laws and regulations guiding the activities of technical and fact-finding groups reporting to the Energy Research Advisory Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Technical Panel shall review and may make recommendations on the following items, among others:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implementation and conduct of the programs established by this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> definition of ocean thermal energy conversion system performance requirements for various user applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> economic, technological, and environmental consequences of the deployment of ocean thermal energy conversion systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Technical Panel shall submit to the Energy Research Advisory Board on at least an annual basis a written report of its findings and recommendations with regard to the program. Such report, shall include at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the Panel’s activities for the preceding year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment and evaluation of the status of the programs mandated by this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> comments on and recommendations for improvements in the comprehensive program management plan required under <ref>section 9002 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submittal of report to Secretary of Energy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After consideration of the Technical Panel report, the Energy Research Advisory Board shall submit such report, together with any comments such Board deems appropriate, to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation by agency heads</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The heads of the departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the executive branch of the Federal Government shall cooperate with the Technical Panel in carrying out the requirements of this section and shall furnish to the Technical Panel such information as the Technical Panel deems necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff, funds, and other support from Secretary of Energy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide sufficient staff, funds, and other support as necessary to enable the Technical Panel to carry out the functions described in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 8</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9008.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “ocean thermal energy conversion” means a method of converting part of the heat from the Sun which is stored in the surface layers of a body of water into electrical energy or energy product equivalent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “energy product equivalent” means an energy carrier including, but not limited to, ammonia, hydrogen, or molten salts or an energy-intensive commodity, including, but not limited to, electrometals, fresh water, or nutrients for aquaculture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 9</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 946</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9009.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is hereby authorized to be appropriated to carry out the purposes of this chapter the sum of $20,000,000 for operating expenses for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, in addition to any amounts authorized to be appropriated in the fiscal year 1981 Authorization Act pursuant to <ref>section 7270 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There is hereby authorized to be appropriated to carry out the purposes of this chapter the sum of $60,000,000 for operating expenses for the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Funds are hereby authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 1981 to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 9004 of this title</ref> for plant and capital equipment as follows:<p class="indent0">Project 81–ES–1, ocean thermal energy conversion demonstration plants with a combined capacity of at least one hundred megawatts electrical or the energy product equivalent, sites to be determined, conceptual and preliminary design activities only $5,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Funds are hereby authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 1982 to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 9004 of this title</ref> for plant and capital equipment as follows:<p class="indent0">Project 81–ES–1, ocean thermal energy conversion demonstration plants with a combined capacity of at least one hundred megawatts electrical or the energy product equivalent, sites to be determined, conceptual and preliminary design activities only $25,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–310, § 10</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 946</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>