<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 38—</num>
<heading>PUBLIC WORKS AND ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3121.</num>
<heading> Findings and declarations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there continue to be areas of the United States experiencing chronic high unemployment, underemployment, outmigration, and low per capita incomes, as well as areas facing sudden and severe economic dislocations because of structural economic changes, changing trade patterns, certain Federal actions (including environmental requirements that result in the removal of economic activities from a locality), and natural disasters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> economic growth in the States, cities, and rural areas of the United States is produced by expanding economic opportunities, expanding free enterprise through trade, developing and strengthening public infrastructure, and creating a climate for job creation and business development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the goal of Federal economic development programs is to raise the standard of living for all citizens and increase the wealth and overall rate of growth of the economy by encouraging communities to develop a more competitive and diversified economic base by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> creating an environment that promotes economic activity by improving and expanding public infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promoting job creation through increased innovation, productivity, and entrepreneurship; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> empowering local and regional communities experiencing chronic high unemployment and low per capita income to develop private sector business and attract increased private sector capital investment;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> while economic development is an inherently local process, the Federal Government should work in partnership with public and private State, regional, tribal, and local organizations to maximize the impact of existing resources and enable regions, communities, and citizens to participate more fully in the American dream and national prosperity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in order to avoid duplication of effort and achieve meaningful, long-lasting results, Federal, State, tribal, and local economic development activities should have a clear focus, improved coordination, a comprehensive approach, and simplified and consistent requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Federal economic development efforts will be more effective if the efforts are coordinated with, and build upon, the trade, workforce investment, transportation, and technology programs of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declarations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to promote a strong and growing economy throughout the United States, Congress declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assistance under this chapter should be made available to both rural- and urban-distressed communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> local communities should work in partnership with neighboring communities, the States, Indian tribes, and the Federal Government to increase the capacity of the local communities to develop and implement comprehensive economic development strategies to alleviate economic distress and enhance competitiveness in the global economy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whether suffering from long-term distress or a sudden dislocation, distressed communities should be encouraged to support entrepreneurship to take advantage of the development opportunities afforded by technological innovation and expanding newly opened global markets; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assistance under this chapter should be made available to promote the productive reuse of abandoned industrial facilities and the redevelopment of brownfields.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, § 2</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3598</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1757</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3122.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Blue economy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “blue economy” means the sustainable use of marine, lake, or other aquatic resources in support of economic development objectives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capacity building</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “capacity building” includes all activities associated with early stage community-based project formation and conceptualization, prior to project predevelopment activity, including grants to local community organizations for planning participation, community outreach and engagement activities, research, and mentorship support to move projects from formation and conceptualization to project predevelopment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive economic development strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “comprehensive economic development strategy” means a comprehensive economic development strategy approved by the Secretary under <ref>section 3162 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Department” means the Department of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic development district</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “economic development district” means any area in the United States that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is composed of areas described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref> and, to the extent determined appropriate by the Secretary, neighboring counties or communities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has been designated by the Secretary as an economic development district under <ref>section 3171 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “economic development district” includes any economic development district designated by the Secretary under <ref>section 3173 of this title</ref> (as in effect on the day before the effective date of the Economic Development Administration Reform Act of 1998).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible recipient</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible recipient” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an economic development district;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a city or other political subdivision of a State, including a special purpose unit of a State or local government engaged in economic or infrastructure development activities, or a consortium of political subdivisions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> an institution of higher education or a consortium of institutions of higher education;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a public or private nonprofit organization or association acting in cooperation with officials of a political subdivision of a State;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> an economic development organization; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> a public-private partnership for public infrastructure.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training, research, and technical assistance grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of grants under <ref>section 3147 of this title</ref>, the term “eligible recipient” also includes private individuals and for-profit organizations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal agency” means a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “grant” includes a cooperative agreement (within the meaning of chapter 63 of title 31).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or Regional Corporation (as defined in or established under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.)), that is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outdoor recreation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “outdoor recreation” means all recreational activities, and the economic drivers of those activities, that occur in nature-based environments outdoors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project predevelopment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “project predevelopment” means a measure required to be completed before the initiation of a project, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> planning and community asset mapping;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> technical assistance and organizational development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> feasibility and market studies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> demonstration projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other predevelopment activities determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional Commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Regional Commission” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Appalachian Regional Commission established by <ref>section 14301(a) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Delta Regional Authority established by <ref>section 2009aa–1(a)(1) of title 7</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Denali Commission established by section 303(a) of the Denali Commission Act of 1998 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3121</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 105–277</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Great Lakes Authority established by <ref>section 15301(a)(4) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Mid-Atlantic Regional Commission established by <ref>section 15301(a)(5) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Northern Border Regional Commission established by <ref>section 15301(a)(3) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Northern Great Plains Regional Authority established by <ref>section 2009bb–1(a)(1) of title 7</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Southeast Crescent Regional Commission established by <ref>section 15301(a)(1) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The Southern New England Regional Commission established by <ref>section 15301(a)(6) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The Southwest Border Regional Commission established by <ref>section 15301(a)(2) of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel and tourism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “travel and tourism” means any economic activity that primarily serves to encourage recreational or business travel in or to the United States, including activities relating to public or nonprofit entertainment venues in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States” means all of the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> University center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “university center” means an institution of higher education or a consortium of institutions of higher education established under <ref>section 3147(c)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, § 3</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3599</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2211(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3123.</num>
<heading> Discrimination on basis of sex prohibited in federally assisted programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person in the United States shall, on the ground of sex, be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination under any program or activity receiving Federal financial assistance under the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 3121</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–65, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1971-08-05">Aug. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 168</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT PARTNERSHIPS COOPERATION AND COORDINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3131.</num>
<heading> Establishment of economic development partnerships</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing assistance under this subchapter, the Secretary shall cooperate with States and other entities to ensure that, consistent with national objectives, Federal programs are compatible with and further the objectives of State, regional, and local economic development plans and comprehensive economic development strategies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may provide such technical assistance to States, political subdivisions of States, sub-State regional organizations (including organizations that cross State boundaries), multi-State regional organizations, and nonprofit organizations as the Secretary determines is appropriate to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> alleviate economic distress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage and support public-private partnerships for the formation and improvement of economic development strategies that sustain and promote economic development across the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote investment in infrastructure and technological capacity to keep pace with the changing global economy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intergovernmental review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to ensure that appropriate State and local government agencies have been given a reasonable opportunity to review and comment on proposed projects under this subchapter that the Secretary determines may have a significant direct impact on the economy of the area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may enter into a cooperation agreement with any 2 or more States, or an organization of any 2 or more States, in support of effective economic development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each cooperation agreement shall provide for suitable participation by other governmental and nongovernmental entities that are representative of significant interests in and perspectives on economic development in an area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title I, § 101</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3600</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1759</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3132.</num>
<heading> Cooperation of Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with applicable laws and subject to the availability of appropriations, each Federal agency shall exercise its powers, duties and functions, and shall cooperate with the Secretary, in such manner as will assist the Secretary in carrying out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title I, § 102</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3133.</num>
<heading> Coordination</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate activities relating to the preparation and implementation of comprehensive economic development strategies under this chapter with Federal agencies carrying out other Federal programs, States, economic development districts, Indian tribes, and other appropriate planning and development organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out subsection (a), or for any other purpose relating to economic development activities, the Secretary may convene meetings with Federal agencies, State and local governments, economic development districts, Indian tribes, and other appropriate planning and development organizations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional commissions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In addition to meetings described in paragraph (1), not later than 1 year after <date date="2025-01-04">January 4, 2025</date>, and not less frequently than every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall convene a meeting with the Regional Commissions in furtherance of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attendees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The attendees for a meeting convened under this paragraph shall consist of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development, serving as Chair;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Federal Cochairpersons of the Regional Commissions, or their designees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the State Cochairpersons of the Regional Commissions, or their designees.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The purposes of a meeting convened under this paragraph shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to enhance coordination between the Economic Development Administration and the Regional Commissions in carrying out economic development programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to reduce duplication of efforts by the Economic Development Administration and the Regional Commissions in carrying out economic development programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to develop best practices and strategies for fostering regional economic development; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other purposes as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Where applicable and pursuant to subparagraph (C), not later than 1 year after a meeting under this paragraph, the Secretary shall prepare and make publicly available a report detailing, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the planned actions by the Economic Development Administration and the Regional Commissions to enhance coordination or reduce duplication of efforts and a timeline for implementing those actions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any best practices and strategies developed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title I, § 103</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3601</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2212</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>GRANTS FOR PUBLIC WORKS AND ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3141.</num>
<heading> Grants for public works and economic development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquisition or development of land and improvements for use for a public works, public service, or development facility or for the improvement of waste management and recycling systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acquisition, design and engineering, construction, rehabilitation, alteration, expansion, increasing the resilience <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003314">1</ref> or improvement of such a facility, including related machinery and equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for grant</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may make a grant under this section only if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the project for which the grant is applied for will, directly or indirectly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve the opportunities, in the area where the project is or will be located, for the successful establishment, expansion, or retention,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003315">2</ref> of industrial or commercial plants or facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assist in the creation of additional long-term employment opportunities in the area; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> primarily benefit the long-term unemployed and underemployed and members of low-income families;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the project for which the grant is applied for will fulfill a pressing need of the area, or a part of the area, in which the project is or will be located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the area for which the project is to be carried out has a comprehensive economic development strategy and the project is consistent with the strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In awarding grants under subsection (a) and subject to the criteria in subsection (b), the Secretary may also consider the extent to which a project would—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> lead to economic diversification in the area, or a part of the area, in which the project is or will be located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> address and mitigate economic impacts from extreme weather events, including development of resilient infrastructure, products, and processes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> benefit highly rural communities without adequate tax revenues to invest in long-term or costly infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> increase access to high-speed broadband;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> support outdoor recreation to spur economic development, with a focus on rural communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> promote job creation or retention relative to the population of the impacted region with outsized significance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> promote travel and tourism; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> promote blue economy activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum assistance for each State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 15 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section may be expended in any 1 State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3601</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2213(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3142.</num>
<heading> Base closings and realignments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may provide to an eligible recipient any assistance available under this subchapter for a project to be carried out on a military or Department of Energy installation that is closed or scheduled for closure or realignment without requiring that the eligible recipient have title to the property or a leasehold interest in the property for any specified term.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 202</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3602</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3143.</num>
<heading> Grants for planning and grants for administrative expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants to pay the costs of economic development planning and the administrative expenses of organizations that carry out the planning.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Planning process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Planning assisted under this subchapter shall be a continuous process involving public officials and private citizens in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> analyzing local economies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> defining economic development goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> determining project opportunities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> formulating and implementing an economic development program that includes systematic efforts to reduce unemployment and increase incomes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of planning assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Planning assistance under this subchapter shall be used in conjunction with any other available Federal planning assistance to ensure adequate and effective planning and economical use of funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Administrative expenses that may be paid with a grant under this section include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> expenses related to carrying out the planning process described in subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expenses related to project predevelopment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> expenses related to updating economic development plans to align with other applicable State, regional, or local planning efforts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> expenses related to hiring professional staff to assist communities in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> project predevelopment and implementing projects and priorities included in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a comprehensive economic development strategy; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an economic development planning grant;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identifying and using other Federal, State, and Tribal economic development programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> leveraging private and philanthropic investment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> preparing economic recovery plans in response to disasters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> carrying out economic development and predevelopment activities in accordance with professional economic development best practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any State plan developed with assistance under this section shall be developed, to the maximum extent practicable, cooperatively by the State, political subdivisions of the State, and the economic development districts located wholly or partially in the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive economic development strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As a condition of receipt of assistance for a State plan under this subsection, the State shall have or develop a comprehensive economic development strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before providing assistance for a State plan under this section, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which the State will consider local and economic development district plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive planning process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any overall State economic development planning assisted under this section shall be a part of a comprehensive planning process that shall consider the provision of public works to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promote economic development and opportunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> foster effective transportation access;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enhance and protect the environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assist in carrying out the workforce investment strategy of a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> promote the use of technology in economic development, including access to high-speed telecommunications (including broadband);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> address and mitigate economic impacts of extreme weather; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> balance resources through the sound management of physical development.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State that receives assistance for the development of a plan under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary an annual report on the planning process assisted under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3602</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2214</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3144.</num>
<heading> Cost sharing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), the Federal share of the cost of any project carried out under this subchapter shall not exceed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 60 percent; plus</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an additional percent that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not exceed 30 percent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is based on the relative needs of the area in which the project will be located, as determined in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In determining the amount of the non-Federal share of the cost of a project, the Secretary may provide credit toward the non-Federal share for all contributions both in cash and in-kind, fairly evaluated, including contributions of space, equipment, assumptions of debt, and services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional Commission funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funds contributed by a Regional Commission for a project under this subchapter may be considered to be part of the non-Federal share of the costs of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increase in Federal share</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a grant to an Indian tribe for a project under this subchapter, the Secretary may increase the Federal share above the percentage specified in subsection (a) up to 100 percent of the cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain States, political subdivisions, and nonprofit organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a grant to a State, or a political subdivision of a State, that the Secretary determines has exhausted the effective taxing and borrowing capacity of the State or political subdivision or can otherwise document that no local matching funds are reasonably obtainable, or in the case of a grant to a nonprofit organization that the Secretary determines has exhausted the effective borrowing capacity of the nonprofit organization, the Secretary may increase the Federal share above the percentage specified in subsection (a) up to 100 percent of the cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training, research, and technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a grant provided under section 3143 or 3147 of this title, the Secretary may increase the Federal share above the percentage specified in subsection (a) up to 100 percent of the cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Small communities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a grant to a political subdivision of a State (as described in <ref>section 3122(6)(A)(iv) of this title</ref>) that has a population of fewer than 10,000 residents and meets 1 or more of the eligibility criteria described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary may increase the Federal share under paragraph (1) up to 100 percent of the total cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3603</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2215</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3145.</num>
<heading> Supplementary grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of designated Federal grant program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “designated Federal grant program” means any Federal grant program that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides assistance in the construction or equipping of public works, public service, or development facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary designates as eligible for an allocation of funds under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> assists projects that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> eligible for assistance under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consistent with a comprehensive economic development strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplementary grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c), in order to assist eligible recipients in taking advantage of designated Federal grant programs, on the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make a supplementary grant for a project for which the recipient is eligible but for which the recipient cannot provide the required non-Federal share because of the economic situation of the recipient.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements applicable to supplementary grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of supplementary grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The share of the project cost supported by a supplementary grant under this section may not exceed the applicable Federal share under <ref>section 3144 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of supplementary grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall make supplementary grants by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the payment of funds made available under this chapter to the heads of the Federal agencies responsible for carrying out the applicable Federal programs; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the award of funds under this chapter, which will be combined with funds transferred from other Federal agencies in projects administered by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share limitations specified in other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any requirement as to the amount or source of non-Federal funds that may be applicable to a Federal program, funds provided under this section may be used to increase the Federal share for specific projects under the program that are carried out in areas described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref> above the Federal share of the cost of the project authorized by the law governing the program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 205</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3603</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3146.</num>
<heading> Regulations on relative needs and allocations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In promulgating rules, regulations, and procedures for assistance under this subchapter, the Secretary shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the relative needs of eligible areas are given adequate consideration by the Secretary, as determined based on, among other relevant factors—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the severity of the rates of unemployment in the eligible areas and the duration of the unemployment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the per capita income levels, the labor force participation rate, and the extent of underemployment in eligible areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the outmigration of population from eligible areas and the extent to which the outmigration is causing economic injury in the eligible areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> allocations of assistance under this subchapter are prioritized to ensure that the level of economic distress of an area, rather than a preference for a geographic area or a specific type of economic distress, is the primary factor in allocating the assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> rural and urban economically distressed areas are not harmed by the establishment or implementation by the Secretary of a private sector leveraging goal for a project under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any private sector leveraging goal established by the Secretary does not prohibit or discourage grant applicants under this subchapter from public works in, or economic development of, rural or urban economically distressed areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the relevant Committees of Congress are notified prior to making any changes to any private sector leveraging goal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> grants made under this subchapter promote job creation and retention and will have a high probability of meeting or exceeding applicable performance requirements established in connection with the grants.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 206</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3604</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1761</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2216</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3147.</num>
<heading> Grants for training, research, and technical assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants for training, research, and technical assistance, including grants for program evaluation and economic impact analyses, that would be useful in alleviating or preventing conditions of excessive unemployment or underemployment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Grants under paragraph (1) may be used for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> project planning, project predevelopment, and feasibility studies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> demonstrations of innovative activities or strategic economic development investments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> management and operational assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> establishment of university centers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> establishment of business outreach centers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> studies evaluating the needs of, and development potential for, economic growth of areas that the Secretary determines have substantial need for the assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> studies that evaluate the effectiveness of coordinating projects funded under this chapter with projects funded under other Acts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> assessment, marketing, and establishment of business clusters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> other activities determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a project assisted under this section that is national or regional in scope, the Secretary may waive the provision in <ref>section 3122(6)(A)(vi) of this title</ref> requiring a nonprofit organization or association to act in cooperation with officials of a political subdivision of a State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methods of provision of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In providing research and technical assistance under this section, the Secretary, in addition to making grants under subsection (a), may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide research and technical assistance through officers or employees of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pay funds made available to carry out this section to Federal agencies; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> employ private individuals, partnerships, businesses, corporations, or appropriate institutions under contracts entered into for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> University centers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with subsection (a)(2)(D), the Secretary may make grants to institutions of higher education to serve as university centers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographic coverage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that the network of university centers established under this subsection provides services in each State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To the maximum extent practicable, a university center established under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collaborate with other university centers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> collaborate with economic development districts and other relevant Federal economic development technical assistance and service providers to provide expertise and technical assistance to develop, implement, and support comprehensive economic development strategies and other economic development planning at the local, regional, and State levels, with a focus on innovation, entrepreneurship, workforce development, and regional economic development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance, business development, and technology transfer services to businesses in the area served by the university center;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> establish partnerships with 1 or more commercialization intermediaries that are public or nonprofit technology transfer organizations eligible to receive a grant under <ref>section 1862s–9 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> promote local and regional capacity building; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> provide to communities and regions assistance relating to data collection and analysis and other research relating to economic conditions and vulnerabilities that can inform economic development and adjustment strategies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In making grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the significant role of regional public universities in supporting economic development in distressed communities through the planning and the implementation of economic development projects and initiatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the location of the university center in or near a distressed community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 207</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3604</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1761</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II</ref>, §§ 2211(b), 2217, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3178</ref>, 3181.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3148.</num>
<heading> Investment priorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), for a project to be eligible for assistance under this subchapter, the project shall be consistent with 1 or more of the following investment priorities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Critical infrastructure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Economic development planning or implementation projects that support development of public facilities, including basic public infrastructure, transportation infrastructure, or telecommunications infrastructure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Workforce</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Economic development planning or implementation projects that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> support job skills training to meet the hiring needs of the area in which the project is to be carried out and that result in well-paying jobs; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise promote labor force participation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Innovation and entrepreneurship</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Economic development planning or implementation projects that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> support the development of innovation and entrepreneurship-related infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote business development and lending; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> foster the commercialization of new technologies that are creating technology-driven businesses and high-skilled, well-paying jobs of the future.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic recovery resilience</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Economic development planning or implementation projects that enhance the ability of an area to withstand and recover from adverse short-term or long-term changes in economic conditions, including effects from industry contractions or economic impacts from natural disasters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manufacturing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Economic development planning or implementation projects that encourage job creation, business expansion, technology and capital upgrades, and productivity growth in manufacturing, including efforts that contribute to the competitiveness and growth of domestic suppliers or the domestic production of innovative, high-value products and production technologies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary plans to use an investment priority that is not described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a written notification that explains the basis for using that investment priority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section waives any other requirement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 208</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2218</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3182</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3149.</num>
<heading> Grants for economic adjustment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants for development of public facilities, public services, business development (including funding of a revolving loan fund), planning, technical assistance, training, and any other assistance to alleviate long-term economic deterioration and sudden and severe economic dislocation and further the economic adjustment objectives of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may provide assistance under this section only if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the project will help the area to meet a special need arising from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> actual or threatened severe unemployment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> economic adjustment problems resulting from severe changes in economic conditions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the area for which a project is to be carried out has a comprehensive economic development strategy and the project is consistent with the strategy, except that this paragraph shall not apply to planning projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Particular community assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Assistance under this section may include assistance provided for activities identified by communities, the economies of which are injured by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> military base closures or realignments, defense contractor reductions in force, or Department of Energy defense-related funding reductions, for help in diversifying their economies through projects to be carried out on Federal Government installations or elsewhere in the communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disasters or emergencies, in areas with respect to which a major disaster or emergency has been declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.), for post-disaster economic recovery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> international trade, for help in economic restructuring of the communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> fishery failures, in areas with respect to which a determination that there is a commercial fishery failure has been made under <ref>section 1861a(a) of title 16</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the loss of manufacturing, travel and tourism, natural resource-based, blue economy, or agricultural jobs, for reinvesting in and diversifying the economies of the communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> economic dislocation in the steel industry due to the closure of a steel plant, primary steel economy contraction events (including temporary layoffs and shifts to part-time work), or job losses in the steel industry or associated with the departure or contraction of the steel industry, for help in economic restructuring of the communities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> limited water for industrial consumption in areas impacted by decreased water supplies due to drought or extreme heat.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to coal communities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coal economy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “coal economy” means the complete supply chain of coal-reliant industries, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> coal mining;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> coal-fired power plants;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> transportation or logistics; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> manufacturing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contraction event</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “contraction event” means the closure of a facility or a reduction in activity relating to a coal-reliant industry, including an industry described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants for projects in areas adversely impacted by a contraction event in the coal economy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall determine the eligibility of an area based on whether the eligible recipient can reasonably demonstrate that the area—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has been adversely impacted by a contraction event in the coal economy within the previous 25 years; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> will be adversely impacted by a contraction event in the coal economy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No regulation or other policy of the Secretary may limit the eligibility of an eligible recipient for a grant under this subsection based on the date of a contraction event except as provided in subparagraph (A)(i).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstrating adverse impact</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For the purposes of this paragraph, an eligible recipient may demonstrate an adverse impact by demonstrating—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a loss in employment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a reduction in tax revenue; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any other factor, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to nuclear host communities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Commission” means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community advisory board</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “community advisory board” means a community committee or other advisory organization that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> primarily focuses on the economic impacts of decommissioning activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> aims to foster communication and information exchange between a licensee planning for and involved in decommissioning activities and members of the community that decommissioning activities may affect.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decommission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “decommission” has the meaning given the term in section 50.2 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licensee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “licensee” has the meaning given the term in section 50.2 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nuclear host community</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “nuclear host community” means an eligible recipient that has been economically impacted, or reasonably demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that it will be economically impacted, by a nuclear power plant licensed by the Commission that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is not co-located with an operating nuclear power plant;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is at a site with spent nuclear fuel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> as of <date date="2025-01-04">January 4, 2025</date>—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> has ceased operations; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has provided a written notification to the Commission that it will cease operations.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to assist with economic development in nuclear host communities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to fund community advisory boards in nuclear host communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out this subsection, to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall implement the recommendations described in the report submitted to Congress under section 108 of the Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act (<ref>Public Law 115–439</ref>; <ref>132 Stat. 5577</ref>) entitled “Best Practices for Establishment and Operation of Local Community Advisory Boards Associated with Decommissioning Activities at Nuclear Power Plants”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a methodology to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, geographic diversity among grant recipients under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special provisions relating to revolving loan fund grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to maintain the proper operation and financial integrity of revolving loan funds established by recipients with assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Efficient administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the request of a grantee, amend and consolidate grant agreements governing revolving loan funds to provide flexibility with respect to lending areas and borrower criteria;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assign or transfer assets of a revolving loan fund to third party for the purpose of liquidation, and the third party may retain assets of the fund to defray costs related to liquidation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take such actions as are appropriate to enable revolving loan fund operators to sell or securitize loans (except that the actions may not include issuance of a Federal guaranty by the Secretary).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An action taken by the Secretary under this subsection with respect to a revolving loan fund shall not constitute a new obligation if all grant funds associated with the original grant award have been disbursed to the recipient.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation of securities laws</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Not treated as exempted securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No securities issued pursuant to paragraph (2)(C) shall be treated as exempted securities for purposes of the Securities Act of 1933 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 77a</ref> et seq.) or the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.), unless exempted by rule or regulation of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (A), no provision of this subsection or any regulation promulgated by the Secretary under this subsection supersedes or otherwise affects the application of the securities laws (as the term is defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</ref>)) or the rules, regulations, or orders of the Securities and Exchange Commission or a self-regulatory organization under that Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disaster mitigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing assistance pursuant to subsection (c)(2), if appropriate and as applicable, the Secretary may encourage hazard mitigation in assistance provided pursuant to such subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 209</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3605</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1762</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1217(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3451</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2219</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3150.</num>
<heading> Changed project circumstances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any case in which a grant (including a supplementary grant described in <ref>section 3145 of this title</ref>) has been made by the Secretary under this subchapter (or made under this chapter, as in effect on the day before the effective date of the Economic Development Administration Reform Act of 1998) for a project, and, after the grant has been made but before completion of the project, the purpose or scope of the project that was the basis of the grant is modified, the Secretary may approve, subject (except for a grant for which funds were obligated in fiscal year 1995) to the availability of appropriations, the use of grant funds for the modified project if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the modified project meets the requirements of this subchapter and is consistent with the comprehensive economic development strategy submitted as part of the application for the grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the modifications are necessary to enhance economic development in the area for which the project is being carried out.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 210</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3151.</num>
<heading> Use of funds in projects constructed under projected cost</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of a grant to a recipient for a construction project under section 3141 or 3149 of this title, if the Secretary determines, before closeout of the project, that the cost of the project, based on the designs and specifications that were the basis of the grant, has decreased because of decreases in costs, the Secretary may approve, without further appropriation, the use of the excess funds (or a portion of the excess funds) by the recipient—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase the Federal share of the cost of a project under this title to the maximum percentage allowable under <ref>section 3144 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to improve the project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other uses of excess funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amount of excess funds remaining after application of subsection (a) may be used by the Secretary for providing assistance under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transferred funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of excess funds described in subsection (a) in projects using funds transferred from other Federal agencies pursuant to <ref>section 3214 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use the funds in accordance with subsection (a), with the approval of the originating agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> return the funds to the originating agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 211</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3606</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1763</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1501(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2041</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3152.</num>
<heading> Reports by recipients</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each recipient of assistance under this subchapter shall submit reports to the Secretary at such intervals and in such manner as the Secretary shall require by regulation, except that no report shall be required to be submitted more than 10 years after the date of closeout of the assistance award.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each report shall contain an evaluation of the effectiveness of the economic assistance provided under this subchapter in meeting the need that the assistance was designed to address and in meeting the objectives of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 212</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3153.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of funds for attorney’s and consultant’s fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assistance made available under this subchapter shall not be used directly or indirectly for an attorney’s or consultant’s fee incurred in connection with obtaining grants and contracts under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 213</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3607</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154.</num>
<heading> Special impact areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the application of an eligible recipient that is determined by the Secretary to be unable to comply with the requirements of <ref>section 3162 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, the requirements of <ref>section 3162 of this title</ref> and designate the area represented by the recipient as a special impact area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may make a designation under subsection (a) only after determining that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the project will fulfill a pressing need of the area; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the project will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be useful in alleviating or preventing conditions of excessive unemployment or underemployment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assist in providing useful employment opportunities for the unemployed or underemployed residents in the area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the time of the designation under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a written notice of the designation, including a justification for the designation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 214</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1763</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154a.</num>
<heading> Performance awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make a performance award in connection with a grant made, on or after <date date="2004-10-27">October 27, 2004</date>, to an eligible recipient for a project under section 3141 or 3149 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance measures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to establish performance measures for making performance awards under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In promulgating regulations under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the inclusion of performance measures that assess—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether the recipient meets or exceeds scheduling goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the recipient meets or exceeds job creation goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> amounts of private sector capital investments leveraged; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of awards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall base the amount of a performance award made under subsection (a) in connection with a grant on the extent to which a recipient meets or exceeds performance measures established in connection with the grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of a performance award may not exceed 10 percent of the amount of the grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A recipient of a performance award under subsection (a) may use the award for any eligible purpose under this chapter, in accordance with <ref>section 3212 of this title</ref> and such regulations as the Secretary may promulgate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3144 of this title</ref>, the funds of a performance award may be used to pay up to 100 percent of the cost of an eligible project or activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment in meeting non-Federal share requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of meeting the non-Federal share requirements under this, or any other, Act the funds of a performance award shall be treated as funds from a non-Federal source.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making performance awards under subsection (a), the Secretary shall establish such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall use any amounts made available for economic development assistance programs to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall include information regarding performance awards made under this section in the annual report required under <ref>section 3213 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by Comptroller General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Comptroller General shall regularly review the implementation of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2004-10-27">October 27, 2004</date>, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the findings of the Comptroller on implementation of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 215</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 210(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1764</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154b.</num>
<heading> Planning performance awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make a planning performance award in connection with a grant made, on or after <date date="2004-10-27">October 27, 2004</date>, to an eligible recipient for a project under this subchapter located in an economic development district.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may make a planning performance award to an eligible recipient under subsection (a) in connection with a grant for a project if the Secretary determines before closeout of the project that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the recipient actively participated in the economic development activities of the economic development district in which the project is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the project is consistent with the comprehensive economic development strategy of the district;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the recipient worked with Federal, State, and local economic development entities throughout the development of the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the project was completed in accordance with the comprehensive economic development strategy of the district.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of a planning performance award made under subsection (a) in connection with a grant may not exceed 5 percent of the amount of the grant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A recipient of a planning performance award under subsection (a) shall use the award to increase the Federal share of the cost of a project under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3144 of this title</ref>, the funds of a planning performance award may be used to pay up to 100 percent of the cost of a project under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall use any amounts made available for economic development assistance programs to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 216</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154c.</num>
<heading> Direct expenditure or redistribution by recipient</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), a recipient of a grant under section 3141, 3143, or 3147 of this title may directly expend the grant funds or may redistribute the funds in the form of a subgrant to other eligible recipients to fund required components of the scope of work approved for the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A recipient may not redistribute grant funds received under section 3141 or 3143 of this title to a for-profit entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (d), a recipient of a grant under <ref>section 3149 of this title</ref> may directly expend the grant funds or may redistribute the funds to public and private entities in the form of a grant, loan, loan guarantee, payment to reduce interest on a loan guarantee, or other appropriate assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under subsection (c), a recipient may not provide any grant to a private for-profit entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 217</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 212(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1766</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154d.</num>
<heading> Renewable energy program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of renewable energy site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “renewable energy site” means a brownfield site that is redeveloped through the incorporation of 1 or more renewable energy technologies, including solar, wind, geothermal, ocean, and emerging, but proven, renewable energy technologies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make a grant for a project for the development of a renewable energy site if the Secretary determines that the project will—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use 1 or more renewable energy technologies described in subsection (a), to develop abandoned or contaminated sites for commercial use; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improve the commercial and economic opportunities in the area in which the project is located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent that any portion of a grant awarded under subsection (b) involves remediation, the remediation shall be subject to <ref>section 3222 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 218</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title II, § 213(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1766</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2220</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154e.</num>
<heading> Workforce training grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants to support the development and expansion of innovative workforce training programs through sectoral partnerships leading to quality jobs and the acquisition of equipment or construction of facilities to support workforce development activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds from a grant under this section may be used for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquisition or development of land and improvements to house workforce training activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acquisition, design and engineering, construction, rehabilitation, alteration, expansion, or improvement of such a facility, including related equipment and machinery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> acquisition of machinery or equipment to support workforce training activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> planning, technical assistance, and training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> sector partnerships development, program design, and program implementation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an eligible recipient that is a State, subject to subsection (c), a State program to support individual trainees for employment in critical industries with high demand and vacancies necessary for further economic development of the applicable State that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requires significant post-secondary training; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not require a post-secondary degree.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State grant pilot program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may award grants to States for the purpose described in subsection (b)(6).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, the Chief Executive of a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, which shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A method for identifying critical industry sectors driving in-State economic growth that face staffing challenges for in-demand jobs and careers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A governance structure for the implementation of the program established by the State, including defined roles for the consortia of agencies of such State, at a minimum, to include the State departments of economic development, labor, and education, or the State departments or agencies with jurisdiction over those matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A strategy for recruiting participants from at least 1 community that meets 1 or more of the criteria described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A plan for how the State will develop a tracking system for eligible programs, participant enrollment, participant outcomes, and an application portal for individual participants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall award not more than 1 grant under this subsection to any State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A grant under this subsection may be used for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> necessary costs to carry out the matters described in this subsection, including tuition and stipends for individuals that receive funds under the program established by the applicable State, subject to the requirements described in paragraph (6); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> program implementation, planning, technical assistance, or training.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3144 of this title</ref>, the Federal share of the cost of any award carried out with a grant made under this subsection shall not exceed 70 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participant amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State shall ensure that grant funds provided under this subsection to each individual that receives funds under the program established by the applicable State is the lesser of the following amounts:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In a case in which the individual is also eligible for a Federal Pell Grant under <ref>section 1070a of title 20</ref> for enrollment at the applicable training program for any award year of the training program, $11,000 minus the amount of the awarded Federal Pell Grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> For an individual not described in paragraph (1), the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $11,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the total cost of the training program in which the individual is enrolled, including tuition, fees, career navigation services, textbook costs, expenses related to assessments and exams for certification or licensure, equipment costs, and wage stipends (in the case of a training program that is an earn-and-learn program).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority provided under this subsection shall expire on <date date="2029-09-30">September 30, 2029</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate the development of new workforce development models with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 219</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2221</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3186</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154f.</num>
<heading> Congressional notification requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a project described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives notice, in accordance with subsection (c), of the award of a grant for the project not less than 3 business days before notifying an eligible recipient of their selection for that award.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A project referred to in subsection (a) is a project that the Secretary has selected to receive a grant administered by the Economic Development Administration in an amount not less than $100,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A notification under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name of the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the name of the applicant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the region in which the project is to be carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the State in which the project is to be carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the 1 or more counties or political subdivisions in which the project is to be carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the number of jobs expected to be created or retained as a result of the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the estimated date of completion of the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the amount of the grant awarded;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> a description of the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> any additional information, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make a notification under subsection (a) publicly available not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary provides the notice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 220</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2222</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3187</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154g.</num>
<heading> High-speed broadband deployment initiative</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Broadband project</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “broadband project” means, for the purposes of providing, extending, expanding, or improving high-speed broadband service to further the goals of this chapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> planning, technical assistance, or training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the acquisition or development of land; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the acquisition, design and engineering, construction, rehabilitation, alteration, expansion, or improvement of facilities, including related machinery, equipment, contractual rights, and intangible property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible recipient</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “eligible recipient” means an eligible recipient.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible recipient” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a public-private partnership; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a consortium formed for the purpose of providing, extending, expanding, or improving high-speed broadband service between 1 or more eligible recipients and 1 or more for-profit organizations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High-speed broadband</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “high-speed broadband” means the provision of 2-way data transmission with sufficient downstream and upstream speeds to end users to permit effective participation in the economy and to support economic growth, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Broadband projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants under this subchapter for broadband projects, which shall be subject to the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In reviewing applications submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall take into consideration geographic diversity of grants provided, including consideration of underserved markets, in addition to data requested in paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data requested</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In reviewing an application submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall request from the Federal Communications Commission, the Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Appalachian Regional Commission data on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the level and extent of broadband service that exists in the area proposed to be served; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the level and extent of broadband service that will be deployed in the area proposed to be served pursuant to another Federal program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest in real or personal property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For any broadband project carried out by an eligible recipient that is a public-private partnership or consortium, the Secretary shall require that title to any real or personal property acquired or improved with grant funds, or if the recipient will not acquire title, another possessory interest acceptable to the Secretary, be vested in a public partner or eligible nonprofit organization or association for the useful life of the project, after which title may be transferred to any member of the public-private partnership or consortium in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no person or entity shall be disqualified from competing to provide goods or services related to a broadband project on the basis that the person or entity participated in the development of the broadband project or in the drafting of specifications, requirements, statements of work, or similar documents related to the goods or services to be provided.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Broadband project property</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may permit a recipient of a grant for a broadband project to grant an option to acquire real or personal property (including contractual rights and intangible property) related to that project to a third party on such terms as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, subject to the condition that the option may only be exercised after the Secretary releases the Federal interest in the property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The grant or exercise of an option described in subparagraph (A) shall not constitute a redistribution of grant funds under <ref>section 3154c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In determining the amount of the non-Federal share of the cost of a broadband project, the Secretary may provide credit toward the non-Federal share for the present value of allowable contributions over the useful life of the broadband project, subject to the condition that the Secretary may require such assurances of the value of the rights and of the commitment of the rights as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 221</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2223</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3188</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3154h.</num>
<heading> Critical Supply Chain Site Development grant program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants under the “Critical Supply Chain Site Development grant program” (referred to in this section as the “grant program”) to carry out site development or expansion projects for the purpose of making the site ready for manufacturing projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In providing a grant to an eligible recipient under the grant program, the Secretary may consider whether—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the proposed improvements to the site will improve economic conditions for rural areas, Tribal communities, or areas that meet 1 or more of the criteria described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the project is consistent with regional economic development plans, which may include a comprehensive economic development strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the eligible recipient has initiatives to prioritize job training and workforce development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the project supports industries determined by the Secretary to be of strategic importance to the national or economic security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In awarding grants to eligible recipients under the grant program, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible recipients that propose to carry out a project that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has State, local, private, or nonprofit funds being contributed to assist with site development efforts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the site development or expansion project is carried out, will result in a demonstrated interest in the site by commercial entities or other entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A grant provided under the grant program may be used for the following activities relating to the development or expansion of a site:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Investments in site utility readiness, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> construction of on-site utility infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> construction of last-mile infrastructure, including road infrastructure, water infrastructure, power infrastructure, broadband infrastructure, and other physical last-mile infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> site grading; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other activities to extend public utilities or services to a site, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Investments in site readiness, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> land assembly;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> environmental reviews;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> zoning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> design;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> engineering; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> permitting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Investments in workforce development and sustainability programs, including job training and retraining programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Investments to ensure that disadvantaged communities have access to on-site jobs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), in awarding grants under the grant program, the Secretary shall not require an eligible recipient to demonstrate that a private company or investment has selected the site for development or expansion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safeguards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In awarding grants under the grant program, the Secretary shall include necessary safeguards to ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the site development is fully completed within a reasonable timeframe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the eligible recipient has sufficiently demonstrated private sector interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title II, § 222</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2224</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ELIGIBILITY; COMPREHENSIVE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT STRATEGIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3161.</num>
<heading> Eligibility of areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For a project to be eligible for assistance under section 3141 or 3149 of this title, the project shall be located in an area that, on the date of submission of the application, meets 1 or more of the following criteria:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low per capita income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The area has a per capita income of 80 percent or less of the national average.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unemployment rate above national average</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The area has an unemployment rate that is, for the most recent 24-month period for which data are available, at least 1 percent greater than the national average unemployment rate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unemployment, underemployment, or economic adjustment problems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The area is an area that the Secretary determines has experienced or is about to experience a special need arising from actual or threatened severe unemployment, underemployment, or economic adjustment problems resulting from severe short-term or long-term changes in economic conditions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Low median household income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The area has a median household income of 80 percent or less of the national average.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Workforce participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The area has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a labor force participation rate of 90 percent or less of the national average; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a prime-age employment gap of 5 percent or more.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expected economic dislocation and distress from energy industry transitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The area is an area that is expected to experience actual or threatened severe unemployment or economic adjustment problems resulting from severe short-term or long-term changes in economic conditions from energy industries that are experiencing accelerated contraction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Political boundaries of areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An area that meets 1 or more of the criteria of subsection (a), including a small area of poverty or high unemployment within a larger community in less economic distress, shall be eligible for assistance under section 3141 or 3149 of this title without regard to political or other subdivisions or boundaries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Documentation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A determination of eligibility under subsection (a) shall be supported by the most recent Federal data available (including data available from the Bureau of Economic Analysis, the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the Census Bureau, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, or any other Federal source determined by the Secretary to be appropriate), or, if no recent Federal data is available, by the most recent data available through the government of the State in which the area is located.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The documentation shall be accepted by the Secretary unless the Secretary determines that the documentation is inaccurate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prior designations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any designation of a redevelopment area made before the effective date of the Economic Development Administration Reform Act of 1998 shall not be effective after that effective date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transparency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent the Secretary includes neighboring counties and communities in an economic development district in accordance with subsection (a)(3), the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available online, a notification describing the justification for such inclusion and detailing the economic indicators of such neighboring counties and communities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title III, § 301</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3607</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2225</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3162.</num>
<heading> Comprehensive economic development strategies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may provide assistance under section 3141 or 3149 of this title (except for planning assistance under <ref>section 3149 of this title</ref>) to an eligible recipient for a project only if the eligible recipient submits to the Secretary, as part of an application for the assistance—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an identification of the economic development problems to be addressed using the assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an identification of the past, present, and projected future economic development investments in the area receiving the assistance and public and private participants and sources of funding for the investments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a comprehensive economic development strategy for addressing the economic problems identified under paragraph (1) in a manner that promotes economic development and opportunity, fosters effective transportation access, maximizes effective development and use of the workforce consistent with any applicable State or local workforce investment strategy, promotes the use of technology in economic development (including access to high-speed telecommunications), enhances and protects the environment, including to mitigate and adapt to the economic impacts of extreme weather, and balances resources through sound management of development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of how the strategy will solve the problems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of comprehensive economic development strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve a comprehensive economic development strategy that meets the requirements of subsection (a) to the satisfaction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of other plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may accept as a comprehensive economic development strategy a satisfactory plan developed under another federally supported program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing strategy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the maximum extent practicable, a plan submitted under this paragraph shall be consistent and coordinated with any existing comprehensive economic development strategy for the area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to grants awarded under <ref>section 3147 of this title</ref> or grants awarded under <ref>section 3149(c)(2) of this title</ref> for areas to which more than one comprehensive economic development strategy may apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title III, § 302</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3608</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2226</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT DISTRICTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3171.</num>
<heading> Designation of economic development districts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order that economic development projects of broad geographic significance may be planned and carried out, the Secretary may designate appropriate economic development districts in the United States, with the concurrence of the States in which the districts will be wholly or partially located, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the proposed district is of sufficient size or population, and contains sufficient resources, to foster economic development on a scale involving more than a single area described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the proposed district contains at least 1 area described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the proposed district has a comprehensive economic development strategy that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contains a specific program for intra-district cooperation, self-help, and public investment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is approved by each affected State and by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may, under regulations promulgated by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> invite the States to determine boundaries for proposed economic development districts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> cooperate with the States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in sponsoring and assisting district economic planning and economic development groups; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in assisting the district groups in formulating comprehensive economic development strategies for districts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage participation by appropriate local government entities in the economic development districts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title IV, § 401</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3172.</num>
<heading> Termination or modification of economic development districts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, by regulation, promulgate standards for the termination or modification of the designation of economic development districts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title IV, § 402</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3173.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1767</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3174.</num>
<heading> Provision of comprehensive economic development strategies to Regional Commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any part of an economic development district is in a region covered by 1 or more of the Regional Commissions, the economic development district shall ensure that a copy of the comprehensive economic development strategy of the district is provided to the affected Regional Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title IV, § 404</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3609</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3175.</num>
<heading> Assistance to parts of economic development districts not in eligible areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3161 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may provide such assistance as is available under this chapter for a project in a part of an economic development district that is not in an area described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref>, if the project will be of a substantial direct benefit to an area described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref> that is located in the district.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title IV, § 405</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3191.</num>
<heading> Assistant Secretary for Economic Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out this chapter through an Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development, to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development shall be compensated at the rate payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development shall carry out such duties as the Secretary shall require and shall serve as the administrator of the Economic Development Administration of the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 501</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3192.</num>
<heading> Economic development information clearinghouse</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> maintain a central information clearinghouse on the Internet with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information on economic development, economic adjustment, disaster recovery, defense conversion, and trade adjustment programs and activities of the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> links to State economic development organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> links to other appropriate economic development resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist potential and actual applicants for economic development, economic adjustment, disaster recovery, defense conversion, and trade adjustment assistance under Federal and State laws in locating and applying for the assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assist areas described in <ref>section 3161(a) of this title</ref> and other areas by providing to interested persons, communities, industries, and businesses in the areas any technical information, market research, or other forms of assistance, information, or advice that would be useful in alleviating or preventing conditions of excessive unemployment or underemployment in the areas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> obtain appropriate information from other Federal agencies needed to carry out the duties under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 502</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3193.</num>
<heading> Consultation with other persons and agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation on problems relating to employment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may consult with any persons, including representatives of labor, management, agriculture, and government, who can assist in addressing the problems of area and regional unemployment or underemployment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation on administration of chapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may provide for such consultation with interested Federal agencies as the Secretary determines to be appropriate in the performance of the duties of the Secretary under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 503</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3194.</num>
<heading> Administration, operation, and maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve Federal assistance under this chapter only if the Secretary is satisfied that the project for which Federal assistance is granted will be properly and efficiently administered, operated, and maintained.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 504</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3195.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3196.</num>
<heading> Performance evaluations of grant recipients</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of each university center and each economic development district that receives grant assistance under this chapter (each referred to in this section as a “grantee”) to assess the grantee’s performance and contribution toward retention and creation of employment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of evaluations of university centers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of the evaluations of university centers under subsection (a) shall be to determine which university centers are performing well and are worthy of continued grant assistance under this chapter, and which should not receive continued assistance, so that university centers that have not previously received assistance may receive assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of evaluations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Evaluations under subsection (a) shall be conducted on a continuing basis so that each grantee is evaluated within 3 years after the first award of assistance to the grantee, and at least once every 3 years thereafter, so long as the grantee receives the assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish criteria for use in conducting evaluations under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation criteria for university centers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The criteria for evaluation of a university center shall, at a minimum, provide for an assessment of the center’s contribution to providing technical assistance, conducting applied research, program performance, and disseminating results of the activities of the center.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation criteria for economic development districts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The criteria for evaluation of an economic development district shall, at a minimum, provide for an assessment of management standards, financial accountability, and program performance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peer review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In conducting an evaluation of a university center or economic development district under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide for the participation of at least 1 other university center or economic development district, as appropriate, on a cost-reimbursement basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 506</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3611</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3197.</num>
<heading> Notification of reorganization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 30 days before the date of any reorganization of the offices, programs, or activities of the Economic Development Administration, the Secretary shall provide notification of the reorganization to the Committee on Environment and Public Works and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 507</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3198.</num>
<heading> Office of Tribal Economic Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Economic Development Administration an Office of Tribal Economic Development (referred to in this section as the “Office”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of the Office shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to coordinate all Tribal economic development activities carried out by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to help Tribal communities access economic development assistance programs, including the assistance provided under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to coordinate Tribal economic development strategies and efforts with other Federal agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to be a participant in any negotiated rulemakings or consultations relating to, or having an impact on, projects, programs, or funding that benefit Tribal communities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal economic development strategy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2025-01-04">January 4, 2025</date>, the Office shall initiate a Tribal consultation process to develop, and not less frequently than every 3 years thereafter, update, a strategic plan for Tribal economic development for the Economic Development Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2025-01-04">January 4, 2025</date>, and not less frequently than every 3 years thereafter, the Office shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate the strategic plan for Tribal economic development developed under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a publicly facing website to help provide a comprehensive, single source of information for Indian tribes, Tribal leaders, Tribal businesses, and citizens in Tribal communities to better understand and access programs that support economic development in Tribal communities, including the economic development programs administered by Federal agencies or departments other than the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dedicated staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that the Office has sufficient staff to carry out all outreach activities under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 508</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2227</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3199.</num>
<heading> Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish an Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to direct and implement the post-disaster economic recovery responsibilities of the Economic Development Administration pursuant to subsections (c)(2) and (e) of <ref>section 3149 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 3233 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to direct and implement economic recovery and enhanced resilience support function activities as directed under the National Disaster Recovery Framework; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> support long-term economic recovery in communities in which a major disaster or emergency has been declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.), or otherwise impacted by an event of national significance, as determined by the Secretary, through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> convening and deploying an economic development assessment team;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> hosting or attending convenings related to identification of additional Federal, State, local, and philanthropic entities and resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> exploring potential flexibilities related to existing awards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provision of technical assistance through staff or contractual resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other activities determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment authorities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized to appoint such temporary personnel as may be necessary to carry out the responsibilities of the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conversion of employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding chapter 33 of title 5, or any other provision of law relating to the examination, certification, and appointment of individuals in the competitive service, a temporary employee appointed under this subsection may be selected by the Secretary for a permanent appointment in the competitive service in the Economic Development Administration under internal competitive promotion procedures if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the employee has served continuously for at least 2 years under 1 or more appointments under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the employee’s performance has been at an acceptable level of performance throughout the period or periods referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status upon conversion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An individual converted under this subsection shall become a career-conditional employee, unless the employee has already completed the service requirements for career tenure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For any fiscal year during which the Secretary exercises the authority under this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that describes the use of that authority including, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of employees hired under the authority during the fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the positions and grades for which employees were hired;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of employees converted to career-conditional;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a description of how the Secretary assessed employee performance to determine the eligibility of the employee for conversion under paragraph (2)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the number of employees who were hired under that authority as temporary employees who have met the continuous service requirements described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2) but not the performance requirements described in subparagraph (B) of that paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the number of employees who were hired under that authority who have separated from the Economic Development Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection waives any requirement relating to qualifications of applicants for positions in the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority provided by this subsection shall expire on <date date="2029-09-30">September 30, 2029</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disaster team</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As soon as practicable after <date date="2025-01-04">January 4, 2025</date>, the Secretary shall establish a disaster team (referred to in this section as the “disaster team”) for the deployment of individuals to carry out responsibilities of the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience after a major disaster or emergency has been declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.) and the Department has been activated by the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of staff</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">As soon as practicable after <date date="2025-01-04">January 4, 2025</date>, the Secretary shall designate to serve on the disaster team—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> employees of the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> employees of the Department who are not employees of the Economic Development Administration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies, employees of those agencies, as appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capabilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In designating individuals under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that the disaster team includes a sufficient quantity of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> individuals who are capable of deploying rapidly and efficiently to respond to major disasters and emergencies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> highly trained full-time employees who will lead and manage the disaster team.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that appropriate and ongoing training is provided to members of the disaster team to ensure that the members are adequately trained regarding the programs and policies of the Economic Development Administration relating to post-disaster economic recovery efforts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out this section, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use, with or without reimbursement, any service, equipment, personnel, or facility of any Federal agency with the explicit support of that agency, to the extent such use does not impair or conflict with the authority of the President or the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.) to direct Federal agencies in any major disaster or emergency declared under that Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide members of the disaster team with travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of services for, or relating to, the disaster team.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2026-07-01">July 1, 2026</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the activities of the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience and any disaster teams established pursuant to subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number and details of the disasters in which the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience and permanent and temporary personnel, including disaster teams, were involved and deployed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the locations and length of any deployments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of personnel deployed, broken down by category, including permanent and temporary personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a breakdown of expenses, with or without reimbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 509</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2228</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3200.</num>
<heading> Technical Assistance Liaisons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Regional Director of a regional office of the Economic Development Administration may designate a staff member to act as a “Technical Assistance Liaison” for any State served by the regional office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Role</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A Technical Assistance Liaison shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> work in coordination with an Economic Development Representative to provide technical assistance, in addition to technical assistance under <ref>section 3147 of this title</ref>, to eligible recipients that are underresourced communities, as determined by the Technical Assistance Liaison, that submit applications for assistance under subchapter II; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at the request of an eligible recipient that submitted an application for assistance under subchapter II, provide technical feedback on unsuccessful grant applications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with an eligible recipient for the purpose of providing technical assistance to eligible recipients that are underresourced communities that have submitted or may submit an application for assistance under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 510</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2229</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3211.</num>
<heading> Powers of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the duties of the Secretary under this chapter, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt, alter, and use a seal, which shall be judicially noticed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subject to the civil service and classification laws, select, employ, appoint, and fix the compensation of such personnel as are necessary to carry out this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, and take such testimony, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> request directly, from any Federal agency, board, commission, office, or independent establishment, such information, suggestions, estimates, and statistics as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this chapter (and each Federal agency, board, commission, office, or independent establishment may provide such information, suggestions, estimates, and statistics directly to the Secretary);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> under regulations promulgated by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assign or sell at public or private sale, or otherwise dispose of for cash or credit, in the Secretary’s discretion and on such terms and conditions and for such consideration as the Secretary determines to be reasonable, any evidence of debt, contract, claim, personal property, or security assigned to or held by the Secretary in connection with assistance provided under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> collect or compromise all obligations assigned to or held by the Secretary in connection with that assistance until such time as the obligations are referred to the Attorney General for suit or collection;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> deal with, complete, renovate, improve, modernize, insure, rent, or sell for cash or credit, on such terms and conditions and for such consideration as the Secretary determines to be reasonable, any real or personal property conveyed to or otherwise acquired by the Secretary in connection with assistance provided under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> pursue to final collection, by means of compromise or other administrative action, before referral to the Attorney General, all claims against third parties assigned to the Secretary in connection with assistance provided under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> acquire, in any lawful manner, any property (real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible), to the extent appropriate in connection with assistance provided under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> in addition to any powers, functions, privileges, and immunities otherwise vested in the Secretary, take any action, including the procurement of the services of attorneys by contract, determined by the Secretary to be necessary or desirable in making, purchasing, servicing, compromising, modifying, liquidating, or otherwise administratively dealing with assets held in connection with financial assistance provided under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> employ experts and consultants or organizations as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> except that contracts for such employment may be renewed annually;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compensate individuals so employed, including compensation for travel time; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> allow individuals so employed, while away from their homes or regular places of business, travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons employed intermittently in the Federal Government service;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> establish performance measures for grants and other assistance provided under this chapter, and use the performance measures to evaluate the economic impact of economic development assistance programs under this chapter, which establishment and use of performance measures shall be provided by the Secretary through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> officers or employees of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the employment of persons under contracts entered into for such purposes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> grants to persons, using funds made available to carry out this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> conduct environmental reviews and incur necessary expenses to evaluate and monitor the environmental impact of economic development assistance provided and proposed to be provided under this chapter, including expenses associated with the representation and defense of the actions of the Secretary relating to the environmental impact of the assistance, using any funds made available to carry out <ref>section 3147 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> sue and be sued in any court of record of a State having general jurisdiction or in any United States district court, except that no attachment, injunction, garnishment, or other similar process, mesne or final, shall be issued against the Secretary or the property of the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> establish such rules, regulations, and procedures as the Secretary considers appropriate for carrying out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deficiency judgments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority under subsection (a)(7) to pursue claims shall include the authority to obtain deficiency judgments or otherwise pursue claims relating to mortgages assigned to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of certain other requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 6101 of title 41</ref> shall not apply to any contract of hazard insurance or to any purchase or contract for services or supplies on account of property obtained by the Secretary as a result of assistance provided under this chapter if the premium for the insurance or the amount of the services or supplies does not exceed $1,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property interests</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The powers of the Secretary under this section, relating to property acquired by the Secretary in connection with assistance provided under this chapter, shall extend to property interests of the Secretary relating to projects approved under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> title I of the Public Works Employment Act of 1976 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6701</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> title II of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Community Emergency Drought Relief Act of 1977 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5184</ref> note; <ref>Public Law 95–31</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary may release, in whole or in part, any real property interest, or tangible personal property interest, in connection with a grant after the date that is 20 years after the date on which the grant was awarded.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain releases</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">On written request from a recipient of a grant under section 3149(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003316">1</ref> of this title, the Secretary shall release, in accordance with this subparagraph, any Federal interest in connection with the grant, if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the request is made not less than 7 years after the final disbursement of the original grant;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the recipient has complied with the terms and conditions of the grant to the satisfaction of the Secretary;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> any proceeds realized from the grant will be used for 1 or more activities that continue to carry out the economic development purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the recipient includes in the written request a description of how the recipient will use the proceeds of the grant in accordance with subclause (III).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Except as provided in subclause (II), the Secretary shall complete all closeout actions for the grant by not later than 180 days after receipt and acceptance of the written request under clause (i).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Secretary may extend a deadline under subclause (I) by an additional 180 days if the Secretary determines the extension to be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3"><ref>Section 3212 of this title</ref> shall continue to apply to a project assisted with a grant under section 3149(d) <sup>1</sup> of this title regardless of whether the Secretary releases a Federal interest under clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers of conveyance and execution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The power to convey and to execute, in the name of the Secretary, deeds of conveyance, deeds of release, assignments and satisfactions of mortgages, and any other written instrument relating to real or personal property or any interest in such property acquired by the Secretary under this chapter may be exercised by the Secretary, or by any officer or agent appointed by the Secretary for that purpose, without the execution of any express delegation of power or power of attorney.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 601</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3611</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–192, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 978</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3212.</num>
<heading> Maintenance of standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors on projects assisted by the Secretary under this chapter shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of chapter 31 of title 40. The Secretary shall not extend any financial assistance under this chapter for such a project without first obtaining adequate assurance that these labor standards will be maintained upon the construction work. The Secretary of Labor shall have, with respect to the labor standards specified in this provision, the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (15 F.R. 3176; <ref>64 Stat. 1267</ref>), and <ref>section 3145 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 602</ref>, formerly title VII, § 712, <date date="1965-08-26">Aug. 26, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–567, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1855</ref>; renumbered title VI, § 602, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3213.</num>
<heading> Annual report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>, and July 1 of each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a comprehensive and detailed annual report on the activities of the Secretary under this chapter during the most recently completed fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report required under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> include a list of all grant recipients by State, including the projected private sector dollar to Federal dollar investment ratio for each grant recipient;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> include a discussion of any private sector leveraging goal with respect to grants awarded to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> rural areas and urban economically distressed areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> highly distressed areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> after the completion of a project, include the realized private sector dollar to Federal dollar investment ratio for the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> include a list of all of the grants provided by the Economic Development Administration for projects located in, or that primarily benefit, rural areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an explanation of the process used to determine how each project referred to in subparagraph (A) would benefit a rural area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a certification that each project referred to in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is located in a rural area; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> will primarily benefit a rural area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As part of the annual report to Congress of the Economic Development Administration, the Secretary shall include a report on project completions and close outs for construction awards that includes the following information on individual construction projects:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The award date of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The completion date of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The close out date of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The total amount of the project, including non-Federal cost share and funding from other sources, including a breakdown by source.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The number of jobs anticipated to be created or retained as a result of the investment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the date of the submission of the report under subsection (c), the Secretary shall make the report under subsection (c) publicly available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional reporting requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To ensure that projects are meeting expected timelines, not later than 1 year after <date date="2025-01-04">January 4, 2025</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> includes an analysis of Economic Development Administration construction project timeline estimates and actual project durations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describes the frequency with which project timelines are delayed and the sources of those delays, including cases in which a project scope or schedule requires an award amendment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 603</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3614</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2230</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3214.</num>
<heading> Delegation of functions and transfer of funds among Federal agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of functions to other Federal agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> delegate to the heads of other Federal agencies such functions, powers, and duties of the Secretary under this chapter as the Secretary determines to be appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> authorize the redelegation of the functions, powers, and duties by the heads of the agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds to other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter may be transferred between Federal agencies, if the funds are used for the purposes for which the funds are specifically authorized and appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds from other Federal agencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), for the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary may accept transfers of funds from other Federal agencies if the funds are used for the purposes for which (and in accordance with the terms under which) the funds are specifically authorized and appropriated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The transferred funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall remain available until expended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may, to the extent necessary to carry out this chapter, be transferred to and merged by the Secretary with the appropriations for salaries and expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 604</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3215.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False statements; security overvaluation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person that makes any statement that the person knows to be false, or willfully overvalues any security, for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> obtaining for the person or for any applicant any financial assistance under this chapter or any extension of the assistance by renewal, deferment, or action, or by any other means, or the acceptance, release, or substitution of security for the assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> influencing in any manner the action of the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> obtaining money, property, or any thing of value, under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Embezzlement and fraud-related crimes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person that is connected in any capacity with the Secretary in the administration of this chapter and that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> embezzles, abstracts, purloins, or willfully misapplies any funds, securities, or other thing of value, that is pledged or otherwise entrusted to the person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> with intent to defraud the Secretary or any other person or entity, or to deceive any officer, auditor, or examiner—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> makes any false entry in any book, report, or statement of or to the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> without being duly authorized, draws any order or issue, puts forth, or assigns any note, debenture, bond, or other obligation, or draft, bill of exchange, mortgage, judgment, or decree thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with intent to defraud, participates or shares in or receives directly or indirectly any money, profit, property, or benefit through any transaction, loan, grant, commission, contract, or any other act of the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> gives any unauthorized information concerning any future action or plan of the Secretary that might affect the value of securities, or having such knowledge invests or speculates, directly or indirectly, in the securities or property of any company or corporation receiving loans, grants, or other assistance from the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 605</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3216.</num>
<heading> Employment of expediters and administrative employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Assistance shall not be provided by the Secretary under this chapter to any business unless the owners, partners, or officers of the business—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> certify to the Secretary the names of any attorneys, agents, and other persons engaged by or on behalf of the business for the purpose of expediting applications made to the Secretary for assistance of any kind, under this chapter, and the fees paid or to be paid to the person for expediting the applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> execute an agreement binding the business, for the 2-year period beginning on the date on which the assistance is provided by the Secretary to the business, to refrain from employing, offering any office or employment to, or retaining for professional services, any person who, on the date on which the assistance or any part of the assistance was provided, or within the 1-year period ending on that date—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> served as an officer, attorney, agent, or employee of the Department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> occupied a position or engaged in activities that the Secretary determines involved discretion with respect to the granting of assistance under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 606</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3217.</num>
<heading> Maintenance and public inspection of list of approved applications for financial assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain as a permanent part of the records of the Department a list of applications approved for financial assistance under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make the list available for public inspection during the regular business hours of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additions to list</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following information shall be added to the list maintained under subsection (a) as soon as an application described in subsection (a)(1) is approved:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The name of the applicant and, in the case of a corporate application, the name of each officer and director of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount and duration of the financial assistance for which application is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The purposes for which the proceeds of the financial assistance are to be used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 607</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3218.</num>
<heading> Records and audits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping and disclosure requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each recipient of assistance under this chapter shall keep such records as the Secretary shall require, including records that fully disclose—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount and the disposition by the recipient of the proceeds of the assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the total cost of the project in connection with which the assistance is given or used;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount and nature of the portion of the cost of the project provided by other sources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to books for examination and audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, the Inspector General of the Department, and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any duly authorized representative, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient that relate to assistance received under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 608</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3219.</num>
<heading> Relationship to assistance under other law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter authorizes or permits any reduction in the amount of Federal assistance that any State or other entity eligible under this chapter is entitled to receive under any other Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 609</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3616</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3220.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of certifications by applicants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under terms and conditions determined by the Secretary, the Secretary may accept the certifications of an applicant for assistance under this chapter that the applicant meets the requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 610</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3221.</num>
<heading> Brownfields redevelopment report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of brownfield site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “brownfield site” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 9601(39) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2004-10-27">October 27, 2004</date>, the Comptroller General shall prepare a report that evaluates the grants made by the Economic Development Administration for the economic development of brownfield sites.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify each project conducted during the previous 10-year period in which grant funds have been used for brownfield sites redevelopment activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> include for each project a description of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the type of economic development activities conducted;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if remediation activities were conducted—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the type of remediation activities; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of grant money used for those activities in dollars and as a percentage of the total grant award;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the economic development and environmental standards applied, if applicable;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the economic development impact of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the role of Federal, State, or local environmental agencies, if any; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> public participation in the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a copy of the report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 611</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3222.</num>
<heading> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent that any portion of grants made under this chapter are used for an economic development project that involves remediation, the remediation shall be conducted in compliance with all applicable Federal, State, and local laws and standards.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VI, § 612</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>FUNDING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3231.</num>
<heading> General authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for public works and economic development</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3141 of this title</ref>, to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $170,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $195,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $220,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $245,000,000 for fiscal year 2028; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $270,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for planning and grants for administrative expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3143 of this title</ref>, to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $90,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $110,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $120,000,000 for fiscal year 2028; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $130,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for training, research, and technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3147 of this title</ref>, to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $30,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $35,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2028; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $45,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for economic adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3149 of this title</ref> (other than subsections (d) and (e)), to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $65,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $75,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $85,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $95,000,000 for fiscal year 2028; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $105,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to coal communities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3149(d) of this title</ref> $75,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to nuclear host communities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3149(e) of this title</ref>, to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to carry out paragraph (2)(A), $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to carry out paragraph (2)(B), $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2027.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Renewable energy program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3154d of this title</ref> $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Workforce training grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3154e of this title</ref> $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, to remain available until expended, of which $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029 shall be used to carry out subsection (c) of that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Critical Supply Chain Site Development grant program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3154h of this title</ref> $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical Assistance Liaisons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out <ref>section 3200 of this title</ref> $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Salaries and expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for salaries and expenses of administering this chapter, to remain available until expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $33,377,000 for fiscal year 2004; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such sums as are necessary for each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VII, § 701</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3617</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–373, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2004-10-27">Oct. 27, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2236(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3232.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for defense conversion activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to amounts made available under <ref>section 3231 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out <ref>section 3149(c)(1) of this title</ref>, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pilot projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds made available under subsection (a) may be used for activities including pilot projects for privatization of, and economic development activities for, closed or realigned military or Department of Energy installations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VII, § 702</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3617</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3233.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for disaster economic recovery activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to amounts made available under <ref>section 3231 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out <ref>section 3149(c)(2) of this title</ref>, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal share of the cost of activities funded with amounts made available under subsection (a) shall be up to 100 percent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–136, title VII, § 703</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3617</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3234.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2236(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 3201</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>