<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 124—</num>
<heading>PUBLIC HOUSING DRUG ELIMINATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PUBLIC AND ASSISTED HOUSING DRUG ELIMINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11901.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Federal Government has a duty to provide public and other federally assisted low-income housing that is decent, safe, and free from illegal drugs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> public and other federally assisted low-income housing in many areas suffers from rampant drug-related or violent crime;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> drug dealers are increasingly imposing a reign of terror on public and other federally assisted low-income housing tenants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the increase in drug-related and violent crime not only leads to murders, muggings, and other forms of violence against tenants, but also to a deterioration of the physical environment that requires substantial government expenditures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> local law enforcement authorities often lack the resources to deal with the drug problem in public and other federally assisted low-income housing, particularly in light of the recent reductions in Federal aid to cities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Federal Government should provide support for effective safety and security measures to combat drug-related and violent crime, primarily in and around public housing proj­ects with severe crime problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> closer cooperation should be encouraged between public and assisted housing managers, local law enforcement agencies, and residents in developing and implementing anti-crime programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> anti-crime strategies should be improved through the expansion of community-oriented policing initiatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5122</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–625, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 586(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2646</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11902.</num>
<heading> Authority to make grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, may make grants to public housing agencies, public housing resident management corporations that are principally managing, as determined by the Secretary, public housing projects owned by public housing agencies, recipients of assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [<ref>25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.], Indian tribes <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004019">1</ref> and private, for-profit and nonprofit owners of federally assisted low-income housing for use in eliminating drug-related and violent crime.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consortia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to terms and conditions established by the Secretary, public housing agencies may form consortia for purposes of applying for grants under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5123</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–625, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title I, § 161(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–330, title VII, § 704(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title II, § 220(1)</ref>, title V, § 586(c), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2488</ref>, 2647.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11903.</num>
<heading> Eligible activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public and assisted housing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants under this subchapter may be used in public housing or other federally assisted low-income housing projects for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the employment of security personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reimbursement of local law enforcement agencies for additional security and protective services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> physical improvements which are specifically designed to enhance security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the employment of one or more individuals—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to investigate drug-related or violent crime in and around the real property comprising any public or other federally assisted low-income housing project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide evidence relating to such crime in any administrative or judicial proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the provision of training, communications equipment, and other related equipment for use by voluntary tenant patrols acting in cooperation with local law enforcement officials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> programs designed to reduce use of drugs in and around public or other federally assisted low-income housing projects, including drug-abuse prevention, intervention, referral, and treatment programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> where a public housing agency, an Indian tribe, or recipient of assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [<ref>25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.] receives a grant, providing funding to nonprofit resident management corporations and resident councils to develop security and drug abuse prevention programs involving site residents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> sports programs and sports activities that serve primarily youths from public or other federally assisted low-income housing projects and are operated in conjunction with, or in furtherance of, an organized program or plan designed to reduce or eliminate drugs and drug-related problems in and around such projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other PHA-owned housing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, grants under this subchapter may be used to eliminate drug-related crime in and around housing owned by public housing agencies that is not public housing assisted under the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1437</ref> et seq.] and is not otherwise federally assisted, for the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (a), but only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the housing is located in a high intensity drug trafficking area designated pursuant to section 1504 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004020">1</ref> of title 21; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public housing agency owning the housing demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that drug-related or violent activity in or around the housing has a detrimental effect on or about the real property comprising any public or other federally assisted low-income housing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5124</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–625, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title I, § 161(c)</ref>, (d)(2), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3718</ref>, 3719; <ref>Pub. L. 104–330, title VII, § 704(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title II, § 220(2)</ref>, title V, § 586(d), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2488</ref>, 2647.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11903a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 582(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2644</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11904.</num>
<heading> Applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To receive a grant under this subchapter, a public housing agency, a public housing resident management corporation, an Indian tribe <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004021">1</ref> a recipient of assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [<ref>25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.], or an owner of federally assisted low-income housing shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such additional information as the Secretary may reasonably require. Such application shall include a plan for addressing the problem of drug-related or violent crime in and around of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004022">2</ref> the housing administered or owned by the applicant for which the application is being submitted, which plan shall be coordinated with and may be included in the public housing agency plan submitted to the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 1437c–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> One-year renewable grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An eligible applicant that is a public housing agency may apply for a 1-year grant under this subchapter that, subject to the availability of appropriated amounts, shall be renewed annually for a period of not more than 4 additional years, except that such renewal shall be contingent upon the Secretary finding, upon an annual or more frequent review, that the grantee agency is performing under the terms of the grant and applicable laws in a satisfactory manner and meets such other requirements as the Secretary may prescribe. The Secretary may adjust the amount of any grant received or renewed under this paragraph to take into account increases or decreases in amounts appropriated for these purposes or such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility and preference</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may not provide assistance under this subchapter to an applicant that is a public housing agency unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency will use the grants to continue or expand activities eligible for assistance under this subchapter, as in effect immediately before the effective date under section 503(a) of the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, in which case the Secretary shall provide preference to such applicant; except that preference under this subparagraph shall not preclude selection by the Secretary of other meritorious applications that address urgent or serious crime problems nor be construed to require continuation of activities determined by the Secretary to be unworthy of continuation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the agency is in the class established under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> PHAs having urgent or serious crime problems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall, by regulations issued after notice and opportunity for public comment, set forth criteria for establishing a class of public housing agencies that have urgent or serious crime problems. The Secretary may reserve a portion of the amount appropriated to carry out this subchapter in each fiscal year only for grants for public housing agencies in such class, except that any amounts from such portion reserved that are not obligated to agencies in the class shall be made available only for agencies that are subject to a preference under paragraph (2)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability to federally assisted low-income housing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to federally assisted low-income housing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve applications under subsection (b) that are not subject to a preference under subsection (b)(2)(A) on the basis of thresholds or criteria such as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the extent of the drug-related or violent crime problem in and around the public or federally assisted low-income housing project or projects proposed for assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the quality of the plan to address the crime problem in the public or federally assisted low-income housing project or projects proposed for assistance, including the extent to which the plan includes initiatives that can be sustained over a period of several years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the capability of the applicant to carry out the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent to which tenants, the local government and the local community support and participate in the design and implementation of the activities proposed to be funded under the application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federally assisted low-income housing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to the selection criteria specified in subsection (c), the Secretary may establish other criteria for the evaluation of applications submitted by owners of federally assisted low-income housing, except that such additional criteria shall be designed only to reflect—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> relevant differences between the financial resources and other characteristics of public housing authorities and owners of federally assisted low-income housing, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> relevant differences between the problem of drug-related or violent crime in public housing and the problem of drug-related or violent crime in federally assisted low-income housing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High intensity drug trafficking areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In evaluating the extent of the drug-related crime problem pursuant to subsection (c), the Secretary may consider whether housing projects proposed for assistance are located in a high intensity drug trafficking area designated pursuant to section 1504 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004023">3</ref> of title 21.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5125</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–625, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title I, § 161(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–330, title VII, § 704(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title II, § 220(3)</ref>, title V, § 586(e), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2488</ref>, 2647.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11905.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Controlled substance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “controlled substance” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 802 of title 21</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drug-related crime</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “drug-related crime” means the illegal manufacture, sale, distribution, use, or possession with intent to manufacture, sell, distribute, or use a controlled substance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federally assisted low-income housing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “federally assisted low-income housing” means housing assisted under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 1715<i>l</i>(d)(3), section 1715<i>l</i>(d)(4), or 1715z–1 of title 12;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 1701s of title 12</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>section 1437f of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recipient</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “recipient”, when used in reference to the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [<ref>25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.], has the meaning given such term in section 4 of such Act [<ref>25 U.S.C. 4103</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 4(12) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004024">1</ref> of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996, <ref>25 U.S.C. 4103(12)</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5126</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–625, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–330, title VII, § 704(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title II, § 220(4)</ref>, title V, § 586(f), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2488</ref>, 2649; <ref>Pub. L. 106–74, title II, § 227(a)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. A, title I, § 175(d)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1534</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11906.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grantee reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall require grantees under this subchapter to provide periodic reports that include the obligation and expenditure of grant funds, the progress made by the grantee in implementing the plan described in <ref>section 11904(a) of this title</ref>, and any change in the incidence of drug-related crime in projects assisted under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> HUD reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress not later than 18 months after <date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date>, describing the system used to distribute funding to grantees under this section, which shall include descriptions of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the methodology used to distribute amounts made available under this subchapter among public housing agencies, including provisions used to provide for renewals of ongoing programs funded under this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> actions taken by the Secretary to ensure that amounts made available under this subchapter are not used to fund baseline local government services, as described in <ref>section 11907(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of funding awards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall cause to be published in the Federal Register notice of all grant awards made pursuant to this subchapter, which shall identify the grantees and the amount of the grants. Such notice shall be published not less frequently than annually.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5127</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 586(g)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11907.</num>
<heading> Monitoring</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall audit and monitor the programs funded under this subchapter to ensure that assistance provided under this subchapter is administered in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of funding baseline services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts provided under this subchapter may not be used to reimburse or support any local law enforcement agency or unit of general local government for the provision of services that are included in the baseline of services required to be provided by any such entity pursuant to a local cooperation agreement under <ref>section 1437c(e)(2) of this title</ref> or any provision of an annual contributions contract for payments in lieu of taxation pursuant to <ref>section 1437d(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each public housing agency that receives grant amounts under this subchapter shall describe, in the report under <ref>section 11906(a) of this title</ref>, such baseline of services for the unit of general local government in which the jurisdiction of the agency is located.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the effective enforcement of this section, which may include the use of on-site monitoring, independent public audit requirements, certification by local law enforcement or local government officials regarding the performance of baseline services referred to in subsection (b), and entering into agreements with the Attorney General to achieve compliance, and verification of compliance, with the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5128</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 586(g)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11908.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subchapter $310,000,000 for fiscal year 1999, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2000, 2001, 2002, and 2003.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Set-aside for federally assisted low-income housing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of any amounts made available in any fiscal year to carry out this subchapter not more than 6.25 percent shall be available for grants for federally assisted low-income housing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Set-aside for technical assistance and program oversight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of any amounts appropriated in any fiscal year to carry out this subchapter, amounts shall be available to the extent provided in appropriations Acts to provide training, technical assistance, contract expertise, program oversight, program assessment, execution, and other assistance for or on behalf of public housing agencies, recipients of assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [<ref>25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.], resident organizations, and officials and employees of the Department (including training and the cost of necessary travel for participants in such training, by or to officials and employees of the Department and of public housing agencies, and to residents and to other eligible grantees). Assistance and other activities carried out using amounts made available under this subsection may be provided directly or indirectly by grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5129</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 586(g)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11909.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 586(g)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2649</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>DRUG-FREE PUBLIC HOUSING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11921.</num>
<heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to reaffirm the principle that decent affordable shelter is a basic necessity, and the general welfare of the Nation and the health and living standards of its people require better coordination and training in drug prevention programs among the public officials and agencies responsible for administering the public housing programs of the Nation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5142</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11922.</num>
<heading> Clearinghouse on drug abuse in public housing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish, in the Office of Public Housing in the Department of Housing and Urban Development, a clearinghouse to receive, collect, process, and assemble information regarding the abuse of controlled substances in public housing projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The clearinghouse established under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> respond to inquiries by members of the public requesting assistance in investigating, studying, and working on the problem of the abuse of controlled substances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> receive, collect, process, assemble, and provide information on programs, authorities, institutions, and agencies, that may further assist members of the public requesting information from the clearinghouse.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5143</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11923.</num>
<heading> Regional training program on drug abuse in public housing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a regional training program for the training of public housing officials, to better prepare and educate the officials to confront the widespread abuse of controlled substances in the communities in which the officials work.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regional training program established under subsection (a) shall be conducted within 12 months after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, by a national training unit established by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5144</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11924.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Controlled substance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “controlled substance” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 802 of title 21</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5145</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11925.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall issue any regulations necessary to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5146</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>