<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 37—</num>
<heading>COMMUNITY FACILITIES AND ADVANCE LAND ACQUISITION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3101.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to assist and encourage the communities of the Nation fully to meet the needs of their citizens by making it possible, with Federal grant assistance, for their governmental bodies (1) to construct adequate basic water and sewer facilities needed to promote the efficient and orderly growth and development of our communities, (2) to construct neighborhood facilities needed to enable them to carry on programs of necessary social services, and (3) to acquire, in a planned and orderly fashion, land to be utilized in the future for public purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–117, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 489</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–448, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 533</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 3102, 3103.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3104.</num>
<heading> Advance acquisition of land for public purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to make grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to encourage and assist the timely acquisition of land planned to be utilized in the future for public purposes, the Secretary is authorized to make grants to States and local public bodies and agencies to assist in financing the acquisition of a fee simple estate or other interest in such land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount of grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of any grant made under this section shall not exceed the aggregate amount of reasonable interest charges on the loans or other financial obligations incurred to finance the acquisition of such land for a period not in excess of the lesser of (1) five years from the date of acquisition of such land or (2) the period of time between the date on which the land was acquired and the date its use began for the purpose for which it was acquired: <i>Provided</i>, That where all or any portion of the cost of such land is not financed through borrowings, the amount of the grant shall be computed on the basis of the aggregate amount of reasonable interest charges that the Secretary determines would have been required.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of land for public purpose within reasonable period of time</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No grant shall be made under this section unless the Secretary determines that the land will be utilized for a public purpose within a reasonable period of time and that such utilization will contribute to economy, efficiency, and the comprehensively planned development of the area. The Secretary shall in all cases require that land acquired with the assistance of a grant under this section be utilized for a public purpose within five years after the date on which a contract to make such grant is entered into, unless the Secretary determines that due to unusual circumstances a longer period of time is necessary and in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diversion of land; repayment; interim use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No land acquired with assistance under this section shall, without approval of the Secretary, be diverted from the purpose originally approved. The Secretary shall approve no such diversion unless he finds that the diversion is in accord with the then applicable comprehensive plan for the area. In cases of a diversion of land to other than a public purpose, the Secretary may require repayment of the grant, or substitution of land of approximately equal fair market value, whichever he deems appropriate. An interim use of the land for a public or private purpose in accordance with standards prescribed by the Secretary, or approved by him, shall not constitute a diversion within the meaning of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for other Federal loans or grant programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no project for which land is acquired with assistance under this section shall, solely as a result of such advance acquisition, be considered ineligible for the purpose of any other Federal loan or grant program, and the amount of the purchase price paid for the land by the recipient of a grant under this section may be considered an eligible cost for the purpose of such other Federal loan or grant program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–117, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 491</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–19, § 22(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 26</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–448, title VI, § 603(b)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 107(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3105.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In the performance of, and with respect to, the functions, powers, and duties vested in him by this chapter, the Secretary shall (in addition to any authority otherwise vested in him) have the functions, powers, and duties set forth in section 1749a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003313">1</ref> of title 12, except subsections (a), (c)(2), and (f) thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized, notwithstanding the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31, to make advance or progress payments on account of any grant made pursuant to this chapter. No part of any grant authorized to be made by the provisions of this chapter shall be used for the payment of ordinary governmental operating expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–117, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 492</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–19, § 22(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3106.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The term “State” means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The term “local public bodies and agencies” includes public corporate bodies or political subdivisions; public agencies or instrumentalities of one or more States, municipalities, or political subdivisions of one or more States (including public agencies and instrumentalities of one or more municipalities or other political subdivisions of one or more States); Indian tribes; and boards or commissions established under the laws of any State to finance specific capital improvement projects.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The term “development cost” means the cost of constructing the facility and of acquiring the land on which it is located, including necessary site improvements to permit its use as a site for the facility.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–117, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3107.</num>
<heading> Labor standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors on projects assisted under sections 3102 and 3103 of this title shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40. No such project shall be approved without first obtaining adequate assurance that these labor standards will be maintained upon the construction work. The Secretary of Labor shall have, with respect to the labor standards specified in this section, the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (15 F.R. 3176; <ref>64 Stat. 1267</ref>), and <ref>section 3145 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–117, title VII, § 707</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3108.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year commencing after <date date="1965-06-30">June 30, 1965</date>, and ending prior to <date date="1969-07-01">July 1, 1969</date>, not to exceed (1) $200,000,000 (or $350,000,000 in the case of the fiscal year commencing <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>) for grants under <ref>section 3102 of this title</ref>, (2) $50,000,000 for grants under <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>, and (3) $25,000,000 for grants under <ref>section 3104 of this title</ref>. In addition, there is authorized to be appropriated for grants under <ref>section 3102 of this title</ref> not to exceed $115,000,000 for the fiscal year commencing <date date="1969-07-01">July 1, 1969</date>, and not to exceed $100,000,000 for the fiscal year commencing <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>. In addition, upon the enactment of the Emergency Community Facilities Act of 1970, there is authorized to be appropriated for grants under <ref>section 3102 of this title</ref> not to exceed $1,000,000,000 for the fiscal year commencing <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>. In addition, there is authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year commencing <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, not to exceed $50,000,000 for grants under <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>. In addition, there are authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year commencing <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, not to exceed $40,000,000 for grants under <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any amounts appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended, and any amounts authorized for any fiscal year under this section but not appropriated may be appropriated for any succeeding fiscal year commencing prior to <date date="1974-07-01">July 1, 1974</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–117, title VII, § 708</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–448, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 534</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–152, title III, § 305(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–431, § 3(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1970-10-06">Oct. 6, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–335, § 3</ref>, <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–117, § 8</ref>, <date date="1973-10-02">Oct. 2, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>