<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 123—</num>
<heading>DRUG ABUSE EDUCATION AND PREVENTION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DRUG EDUCATION AND PREVENTION RELATING TO YOUTH GANGS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11801.</num>
<heading> Establishment of drug abuse education and prevention program relating to youth gangs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families, shall make grants to, and enter into contracts with, public and nonprofit private agencies (including agencies described in paragraph (7)(A) acting jointly), organizations (including community based organizations with demonstrated experience in this field), institutions, and individuals, to carry out projects and activities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to prevent and to reduce the participation of youth in the activities of gangs that engage in illicit drug-related activities,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote the involvement of youth in lawful activities in communities in which such gangs commit drug-related crimes,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to prevent the abuse of drugs by youth, to educate youth about such abuse, and to refer for treatment and rehabilitation members of such gangs who abuse drugs,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to support activities of local police departments and other local law enforcement agencies to conduct educational outreach activities in communities in which gangs commit drug-related crimes,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to inform gang members and their families of the availability of treatment and rehabilitation services for drug abuse,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to facilitate Federal and State cooperation with local school officials to assist youth who are likely to participate in gangs that commit drug-related crimes,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> to facilitate coordination and cooperation among—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> local education, juvenile justice, employment and social service agencies, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> drug abuse referral, treatment, and rehabilitation programs,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">for the purpose of preventing or reducing the participation of youth in activities of gangs that commit drug-related crimes, and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to provide technical assistance to eligible organizations in planning and implementing drug abuse education, prevention, rehabilitation, and referral programs for youth who are members of gangs that commit drug-related crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3501</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–132, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-18">Oct. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11802.</num>
<heading> Application for grants and contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agency, organization, institution, or individual desiring to receive a grant, or to enter into a contract, under <ref>section 11801 of this title</ref> shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require by rule.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each application for assistance under this subchapter shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> set forth a project or activity for carrying out one or more of the purposes specified in <ref>section 11801 of this title</ref> and specifically identify each such purpose such project or activity is designed to carry out,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide that such project or activity shall be administered by or under the supervision of the applicant,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for the proper and efficient administration of such project or activity,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide for regular evaluation of the operation of such project or activity,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide that regular reports on such project or activity shall be submitted to the Secretary, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide such fiscal control and fund accounting procedures as may be necessary to ensure prudent use, proper disbursement, and accurate accounting of funds received under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3502</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11803.</num>
<heading> Approval of applications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In selecting among applications submitted under <ref>section 11802(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall give priority to applicants who propose to carry out projects and activities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the purposes specified in <ref>section 11801 of this title</ref> in geographical areas in which frequent and severe drug-related crimes are committed by gangs whose membership is composed primarily of youth, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the applicant demonstrates have the broad support of community based organizations in such geographical areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3503</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–204, title X, § 1001(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11804.</num>
<heading> Coordination with juvenile justice programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate the program established by <ref>section 11801 of this title</ref> with the programs and activities carried out under the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 [<ref>34 U.S.C. 11101</ref> et seq.] and with the programs and activities of the Attorney General, to ensure that all such programs and activities are complementary and not duplicative.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3504</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11805.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out this subchapter, there are authorized to be appropriated $16,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1993 and 1994.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3505</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–132, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-18">Oct. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11806.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit, to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate, a report describing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the types of projects and activities for which grants and contracts were made under this subchapter for such fiscal year,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number and characteristics of the youth and families served by such projects and activities, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> each of such projects and activities the Secretary considers to be exemplary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3506</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–132, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-18">Oct. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PROGRAM FOR RUNAWAY AND HOMELESS YOUTH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11821.</num>
<heading> Establishment of program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program aims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall make grants to public and private nonprofit agencies, organizations, and institutions to carry out research, demonstration, and services projects designed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide individual, family, and group counseling to runaway youth and their families and to homeless youth for the purpose of preventing or reducing the illicit use of drugs by such youth,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to develop and support peer counseling programs for runaway and homeless youth related to the illicit use of drugs,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to develop and support community education activities related to illicit use of drugs by runaway and homeless youth, including outreach to youth individually,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to provide to runaway and homeless youth in rural areas assistance (including the development of community support groups) related to the illicit use of drugs,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide to individuals involved in providing services to runaway and homeless youth, information and training regarding issues related to the illicit use of drugs by runaway and homeless youth,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to support research on the illicit drug use by runaway and homeless youth, and the effects on such youth of drug abuse by family members, and any correlation between such use and attempts at suicide, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to improve the availability and coordination of local services related to drug abuse, for runaway and homeless youth.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In selecting among applicants for grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to agencies and organizations that have experience in providing services to runaway and homeless youth.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Grants under this section may be made for a period not to exceed 3 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3511</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11822.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the end of a fiscal year for which funds are appropriated to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary shall submit to the President, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the President pro tempore of the Senate a report that contains—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the types of projects and activities for which grants were made under this subchapter for such fiscal year,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the number and characteristics of the youth and families served by such projects and activities, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of exemplary projects and activities for which grants were made under this subchapter for such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3512</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11823.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out this subchapter, there are authorized to be appropriated $16,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1993 and 1994.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3513</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–132, § 2</ref>, <date date="1991-10-18">Oct. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11824.</num>
<heading> Applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any State, unit of local government (or combination of units of local government), agency, organization, institution, or individual desiring to receive a grant, or enter into a contract, under this subchapter shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as may be prescribed by the Federal officer who is authorized to make such grant or enter into such contract (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “appropriate Federal officer”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with guidelines established by the appropriate Federal officer, each application for assistance under this subchapter shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> set forth a project or activity for carrying out one or more of the purposes for which such grant or contract is authorized to be made and expressly identify each such purpose such project or activity is designed to carry out,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide that such project or activity shall be administered by or under the supervision of the applicant,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide for the proper and efficient administration of such project or activity,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide for regular evaluation of such project or activity,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide that regular reports on such project or activity shall be sent to the appropriate Federal officer, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide for such fiscal control and fund accounting procedures as may be necessary to ensure prudent use, proper disbursement, and accurate accounting of funds received under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3514</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11825.</num>
<heading> Review of applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In reviewing applications submitted under this subchapter, the appropriate Federal officer shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the relative cost and effectiveness of the proposed project or activity in carrying out purposes for which the requested grant or contract is authorized to be made,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the extent to which such project or activity will incorporate new or innovative techniques,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the increase in capacity of the State or the public or nonprofit private agency, organization, institution, or individual involved to provide services to address the illicit use of drugs by runaway and homeless youth,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent to which such project or activity serves communities which have high rates of illicit drug use by juveniles (including runaway and homeless youth),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the extent to which such project or activity will provide services in geographical areas where similar services are unavailable or in short supply, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the extent to which such project or activity will increase the level of services, or coordinate other services, in the community available to eligible youth.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competitive process</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Applications submitted under this subchapter shall be selected for approval through a competitive process to be established by rule by the appropriate Federal officer. As part of such a process, such officer shall publish a notice in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> announcing the availability of funds to carry out this subchapter,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> stating the general criteria applicable to the selection of applicants to receive such funds, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> describing the procedures applicable to submitting and reviewing applications for such funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As part of such process, each application referred to in subsection (a) shall be subject to peer review by individuals (excluding officers and employees of the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services) who have expertise in the subject matter related to the project or activity proposed in such application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The appropriate Federal officer shall expedite the consideration of an application referred to in subsection (a) if the applicant demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004015">1</ref> such officer, that the failure to expedite such consideration would prevent the effective implementation of the project or activity set forth in such application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3515</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4257</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–204, title X, § 1001(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>COMMUNITY PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11841.</num>
<heading> Community youth activity program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Block grant program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make grants to eligible States to enable such States to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State, acting on its own behalf or on behalf of a person, shall submit to the Secretary an application that contains such information and is in such form as may be required by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstration of need</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the application submitted under paragraph (1), the State shall demonstrate a need for the activities described in subsection (e) and provide a description of those activities and projects that will receive financial assistance from a grant made under this section to the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of grant</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State that submits for a fiscal year an application under subsection (b) that meets the requirements of the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, receive a grant in an amount determined in accordance with paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs of national significance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of amounts appropriated or otherwise available to carry out this section for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve 5 percent to be provided for activities and projects of national significance or projects expected to have a significant impact in preventing the abuse of drugs by youth.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified appropriations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Of the aggregate amount appropriated under subsection (g) for any fiscal year and after reserving the amount required by paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> allot—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 25 percent equally among the eligible States if such amount is less than $40,000,000; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> $250,000 to each eligible State if such amount equals or exceeds $40,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> allot one-half of 1 percent of such amount on the basis of need among Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> set aside the remainder to be disbursed as described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “State” does not include Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remainder</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Amounts referred to in subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be used by the Secretary to make grants, on a competitive basis and taking into consideration with respect to the States—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the highest proportions of school-aged youth are <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004016">1</ref> at risk of drug abuse;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if a tangible need has been identified by the State involved; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the State involved has proposed the funding of additional projects targeted at the areas of highest need;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">to carry out the activities and projects that are consistent with the activities described in subsection (e)(1). The activities and projects for which such grants are made shall be selected by the Secretary from among proposed activities and projects submitted to the Secretary by the States. Such grants shall be made to the States for redistribution to the persons on whose behalf the State submitted an application under subsection (b).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> projects aimed at youth who are not in school or who are at risk of dropping out of school;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> projects that seek to reinvolve dropouts in educational programs, involve youth community-based activities, develop training or employment opportunities for dropouts, or provide youth with alternatives to drug abuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> projects to provide after-school, vacation, and weekend activities designed to give youth opportunities to actively participate in a variety of activities, including youth sports programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> activities and projects that are consistent with activities and projects described in subsection (e)(1) and that include participation by the business community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> projects that provide outreach to individuals of all ages who are at high risk of involvement with drug abuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> projects targeted to communities with the most serious drug abuse problems to enable such communities to develop programs that coordinate Federal, State, and local efforts to develop comprehensive, long-term, community-wide prevention and education strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> projects that seek to involve youth who are members of gangs or who may join a gang, in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> educational programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> community-based activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> training or employment opportunities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other alternatives to gang involvement;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> programs for unsupervised children before and after school, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> education and instruction consistent with part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> athletic activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> creative activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other programs designed to reduce the risk of drug abuse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> projects that seek to inform youth regarding the existence and operation of the projects referred to in paragraph (7).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities and projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Financial assistance may be provided with a grant received under subsection (a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004017">2</ref> under this section by a State as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Community services and partnerships</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Such assistance may be provided for community services and partnerships designed to develop community activities targeted at drug abuse prevention through education, training, and recreation projects. Such services may be provided by, and such partnerships may be entered into with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> local educational agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> law enforcement agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> community-based organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> community action agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> local or State recreational departments; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> business organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">in consultation with local and State health departments and with community health or mental health centers when appropriate. Such assistance may be provided to any entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (F), either individually or in partnerships. Applications for such assistance shall include a description of the method to be used to evaluate the impact the particular service or partnership is designed to have on the drug abuse problem within the community.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other activities and projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such assistance may be provided to carry out projects or activities that are consistent with the activities and projects described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project evaluations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the evaluation of activities and projects conducted with financial assistance received under this section. Applications for grants under this section shall include a description of the method to be used in evaluating the impact such activities and programs have on the drug abuse problem within the communities in which such activities and projects are carried out.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $40,000,000 for fiscal year 1989, $55,000,000 for fiscal year 1990, $60,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, $66,550,000 for fiscal year 1992, and $73,205,000 for fiscal year 1993.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3521</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–93, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–226, § 23</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 394(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–285, title II, § 202(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2755</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(k)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2168</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11842.</num>
<heading> Evaluation of drug abuse education and prevention efforts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Method</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop and conduct a structured evaluation of the different approaches utilized across the Nation to reduce drug abuse.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may make grants to or enter into contracts with appropriate entities for the purpose of conducting the evaluations required by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time of reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit a report based on the evaluations prepared under subsection (a) not later than 1 year after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, and another report based on such evaluations not later than 3 years after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>. A third report based on such evaluations shall be submitted by the Secretary not later than <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $12,000,000 in fiscal year 1989, and $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1990 through 1993.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3522</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–93, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–204, title X, § 1001(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11851.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Unless otherwise defined by an Act amended by this title,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004018">1</ref> for purposes of this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004018">1</ref> and the amendments made by this title— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004018">1</ref></chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “community based” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 11103(1) of title 34</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “controlled substance” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 802(6) of title 21</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “controlled substance analogue” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 802(32) of title 21</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “drug” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a beverage containing alcohol,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a controlled substance, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a controlled substance analogue,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Director” means the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “illicit” means unlawful or injurious,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “public agency” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 11103(11) of title 34</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> the term “Secretary” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education for purposes of subtitle A (other than section 3201),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture for purposes of the amendments made by section 3201, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services for purposes of subtitle B,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the term “State” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 11103(7) of title 34</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the term “treatment” has the meaning given it in <ref>section 11103(15) of title 34</ref>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the term “unit of general local government” has the meaning given it in section 11103(8) <sup>1</sup> of title 34.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title III, § 3601</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–204, title X, § 1001(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1827</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–82, title IV, § 405(n)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(13)(J)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>