<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 42—</num>
<heading>NARCOTIC ADDICT REHABILITATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3401.</num>
<heading> Declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Congress that certain persons charged with or convicted of violating Federal criminal laws, who are determined to be addicted to narcotic drugs, and likely to be rehabilitated through treatment, should, in lieu of prosecution or sentencing, be civilly committed for confinement and treatment designed to effect their restoration to health, and return to society as useful members.</p>
<p class="indent0">It is the further policy of the Congress that certain persons addicted to narcotic drugs who are not charged with the commission of any offense should be afforded the opportunity, through civil commitment, for treatment, in order that they may be rehabilitated and returned to society as useful members and in order that society may be protected more effectively from crime and delinquency which result from narcotic addiction.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–793, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-11-08">Nov. 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3402.</num>
<heading> State facilities and personnel for care and treatment; encouragement of adequate provision; benefit of experience of Surgeon General and Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Surgeon General and the Attorney General are authorized to give representatives of States and local subdivisions thereof the benefit of their experience in the care, treatment, and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts so that each State may be encouraged to provide adequate facilities and personnel for the care and treatment of narcotic addicts in its jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–793, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1966-11-08">Nov. 8, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CIVIL COMMITMENT OF PERSONS NOT CHARGED WITH ANY CRIMINAL OFFENSE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 3411 to 3426.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXIV, § 3405(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1221</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>REHABILITATION AND POSTHOSPITALIZATION CARE PROGRAMS AND ASSISTANCE TO STATES AND LOCALITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3441.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXIV, § 3405(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1221</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3442.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 90–574, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-15">Oct. 15, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1011</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>