<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 120—</num>
<heading>ENTERPRISE ZONE DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11501.</num>
<heading> Designation of enterprise zones</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of zones</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Enterprise zone” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “enterprise zone” means any area that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is nominated by one or more local governments and the State or States in which it is located for designation as an enterprise zone (in this section referred to as a “nominated area”); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development designates as an enterprise zone, after consultation with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, Labor, and the Treasury, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an area on an Indian reservation, the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number of designations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may designate not more than 100 nominated areas as enterprise zones.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum designation in rural areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Of the areas designated under subparagraph (A), not less than ⅓ shall be areas that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are within a local government jurisdiction or jurisdictions with a population of less than 50,000 (as determined under the most recent census data available);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are outside of a metropolitan statistical area (as designated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that are determined by the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, to be rural areas.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Areas designated based solely on degree of poverty</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall designate (i) the nominated areas with the highest average ranking with respect to the criteria set forth in subparagraphs (C) and (D) of subsection (c)(3), and the 1 criterion set forth in subparagraph (E)(i) or (E)(ii) of subsection (c)(3) that gives an area a higher ranking; and (ii) for areas described in paragraph (2)(B), the nominated areas with the highest ranking with respect to the 1 criterion set forth in subparagraph (C), (D), (E)(i), or (E)(ii) of subsection (c)(3) that gives an area a higher ranking. For purposes of the preceding sentence, an area shall be ranked within each such criterion on the basis of the amount by which the area exceeds such criterion, with the area that exceeds such criterion by the greatest amount given the highest ranking.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception where inadequate course of action, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An area shall not be designated under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that the course of action with respect to such area is inadequate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate application to rural and other areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall be applied separately with respect to areas described in paragraph (2)(B) and to other areas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on designations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Before designating any area as an enterprise zone, the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation not later than 4 months following <date date="1988-02-05">February 5, 1988</date>, after consultation with the officials described in paragraph (1)(B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the procedures for nominating an area under paragraph (1)(A);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the parameters relating to the size and population characteristics of an enterprise zone; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the manner in which nominated areas will be evaluated based on the criteria specified in subsection (d).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall designate nominated areas as enterprise zones only during the 24-month period beginning on the 1st day of the 1st month following the month in which the date of the enactment of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 occurs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedural rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall not make any designation under paragraph (1) unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the local governments and the State in which the nominated area is located have the authority—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to nominate such area for designation as an enterprise zone;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to make the State and local commitments under subsection (d); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> to provide assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that such commitments will be fulfilled;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a nomination therefor is submitted in such a manner and in such form, and contains such information, as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that any information furnished is reasonably accurate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the State and local governments certify that no portion of the area nominated is already included in an enterprise zone or in an area otherwise nominated to be an enterprise zone.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nomination process for Indian reservations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a nominated area on an Indian reservation, the reservation governing body (as determined by the Secretary of the Interior) shall be deemed to be both the State and local governments with respect to such area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period for which designation is in effect</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any designation of an area as an enterprise zone shall remain in effect during the period beginning on the date of the designation and ending on the earliest of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> December 31 of the 24th calendar year following the calendar year in which such date occurs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the termination date designated by the State and local governments as provided for in their nomination pursuant to subsection (a)(4)(C)(ii); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date the Secretary revokes such designation under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revocation of designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, after consultation with the officials described in subsection (a)(1)(B) and a hearing on the record involving officials of the State or local government involved, may revoke the designation of an area if the Secretary determines that the local government or the State in which it is located is not complying substantially with the State and local commitments pursuant to subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Area and eligibility requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may make a designation of any nominated area under subsection (a)(1) only if it meets the requirements of paragraphs (2) and (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Area requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A nominated area meets the requirements of this paragraph if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the area is within the jurisdiction of the local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the boundary of the area is continuous; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the area—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> has a population, as determined by the most recent census data available, of not less than—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 4,000 if any portion of such area (other than a rural area described in subsection (a)(2)(B)(i)) is located within a metropolitan statistical area (as designated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget) with a population of 50,000 or more; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 1,000 in any other case; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is entirely within an Indian reservation (as determined by the Secretary of the Interior).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), a nominated area meets the requirements of this paragraph if the State and local governments in which it is located certify and the Secretary, after such review of supporting data as he deems appropriate, accepts such certification, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the area is one of pervasive poverty, unemployment, and general distress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the area is located wholly within the jurisdiction of a local government that is eligible for Federal assistance under <ref>section 5318 of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the unemployment rate, as determined by the appropriate available data, was not less than 1.5 times the national unemployment rate for that period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the poverty rate (as determined by the most recent census data available) for each populous census tract (or where not tracted, the equivalent county division as defined by the Bureau of the Census for the purpose of defining poverty areas) within the area was not less than 20 percent for the period to which such data relate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> the area meets at least one of the following criteria:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Not less than 70 percent of the households living in the area have incomes below 80 percent of the median income of households of the local government (determined in the same manner as under <ref>section 5318 of this title</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The population of the area decreased by 20 percent or more between 1970 and 1980 (as determined from the most recent census available).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility requirements for rural areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), a nominated area that is a rural area described in subsection (a)(2)(B) meets the requirements of paragraph (3) if the State and local governments in which it is located certify and the Secretary, after such review of supporting data as he deems appropriate, accepts such certification, that the area meets—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the criteria set forth in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not less than one of the criteria set forth in the other subparagraphs of paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required State and local commitments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No nominated area shall be designated as an enterprise zone unless the local government and the State in which it is located agree in writing that, during any period during which the area is an enterprise zone, such governments will follow a specified course of action designated to reduce the various burdens borne by employers or employees in such area. A course of action shall not be treated as meeting the requirements of this paragraph unless the course of action include provisions described in not less than 4 of the subparagraphs of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Course of action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The course of action under paragraph (1) may be implemented by both such governments and private nongovernmental entities, may be funded from proceeds of any program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or of any program administered by the Secretary of Agriculture under title V of the Housing Act of 1949 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.], and may include, but is not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a reduction of tax rates or fees applying within the enterprise zone;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an increase in the level of public services, or in the efficiency of the delivery of public services, within the enterprise zone;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> actions to reduce, remove, simplify, or streamline paperwork requirements within the enterprise zone;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> involvement in the program by public authorities or private entities, organizations, neighborhood associations, and community groups, particularly those within the nominated area, including a written commitment to provide jobs and job training for, and technical, financial, or other assistance to, employers, employees, and residents of the nominated area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the giving of special preference to contractors owned and operated by members of any minority; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the gift (or sale at below fair market value) of surplus land in the enterprise zone to neighborhood organizations agreeing to operate a business on the land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recognition of past efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In evaluating courses of action agreed to by any State or local government, the Secretary shall take into account the past efforts of such State or local government in reducing the various burdens borne by employers and employees in the area involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of assistance for business relocations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The course of action implemented under paragraph (1) may not include any action to assist—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any establishment relocating from one area to another area; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any subcontractor whose purpose is to divest, or whose economic success is dependent upon divesting, any other contractor or subcontractor of any contract customarily performed by such other contractor or subcontractor.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The limitations established in subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to prohibit assistance for the expansion of an existing business entity through the establishment of a new branch, affiliate, or subsidiary if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> finds that the establishment of the new branch, affiliate, or subsidiary will not result in an increase in unemployment in the area of original location or in any other area where the existing business entity conducts business operations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has no reason to believe that the new branch, affiliate, or subsidiary is being established with the intention of closing down the operations of the existing business entity in the area of its original location or in any other area where the existing business entity conducts business operations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than one government seeks to nominate an area as an enterprise zone, any reference to, or requirement of, this section shall apply to all such governments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local government</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “local government” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any county, city, town, township, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any combination of political subdivisions described in subparagraph (A) recognized by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” includes Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1957</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–628, title X, § 1090(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title VIII, § 834(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3855</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11502.</num>
<heading> Evaluation and reporting requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the close of the 4th calendar year after the year in which the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development first designates areas as enterprise zones pursuant to the amendments made by section 834 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and at the close of each 4th calendar year thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Congress a report on the effects of such designation in accomplishing the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title VIII, § 834(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3855</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11503.</num>
<heading> Interaction with other Federal programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with relocation assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The designation of an enterprise zone under <ref>section 11501 of this title</ref> shall not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> constitute approval of a Federal or federally assisted program or project (within the meaning of the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4601</ref> et seq.)); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> entitle any person displaced from real property located in such zone to any rights or any benefits under such Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enterprise zones treated as labor surplus areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any area that is designated as an enterprise zone under <ref>section 11501 of this title</ref> shall be treated for all purposes under Federal law as a labor surplus area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1961</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11504.</num>
<heading> Waiver or modification of housing and community development rules in enterprise zones</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the written request of the governments that designated and approved an area that has been designated as an enterprise zone under <ref>section 11501 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (or, with respect to any rule issued under title V of the Housing Act of 1949 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.], the Secretary of Agriculture) may, in order to further the job creation, community development, or economic revitalization objectives of the zone, waive or modify all or part of any rule that the Secretary has authority to promulgate, as such rule pertains to the carrying out of projects, activities, or undertakings within the zone.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this section may be construed to authorize the Secretary to waive or modify any rule adopted to carry out a statute or Executive order that prohibits, or the purpose of which is to protect persons against, discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, marital status, national origin, age, or handicap.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A request under subsection (a) shall specify the rule or rules to be waived or modified and the change proposed, and shall briefly describe why the change would promote the achievement of the job creation, community development, or economic revitalization objectives of the enterprise zone. If a request is made to the Secretary of Agriculture, the requesting governments shall send a copy of the request to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development at the time the request is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of requests</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In considering a request, the Secretary shall weigh the extent to which the proposed change is likely to further job creation, community development, or economic revitalization within the enterprise zone against the effect the change is likely to have on the underlying purposes of applicable statutes in the geographic area that would be affected by the change. The Secretary shall approve the request whenever the Secretary finds, in the discretion of the Secretary, that the public interest that the proposed change would serve in furthering such job creation, community development or economic revitalization outweighs the public interest that continuation of the rule unchanged would serve in furthering such underlying purposes. The Secretary shall not approve any request to waive or modify a rule if that waiver or modification would—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> directly violate a statutory requirement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be likely to present a significant risk to the public health, including environmental health or safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of disapproval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a request is disapproved, the Secretary shall inform the requesting governments in writing of the reasons therefor and shall, to the maximum extent possible, work with such governments to develop an alternative, consistent with the standards contained in subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period for determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall discharge the responsibilities of the Secretary under this section in an expeditious manner, and shall make a determination on requests not later than 90 days after their receipt.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A waiver or modification of a rule under subsection (a) shall not be considered to be a rule, rulemaking, or regulation under chapter 5 of title 5. To facilitate reaching a decision on any requested waiver or modification, the Secretary may seek the views of interested parties and, if the views are to be sought, determine how they should be obtained and to what extent, if any, they should be taken into account in considering the request. The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register stating any waiver or modification of a rule under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of subsequent amendment of rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event that the Secretary proposes to amend a rule for which a waiver or modification under this section is in effect, the Secretary shall not change the waiver or modification to impose additional requirements unless the Secretary determines, consistent with standards contained in subsection (d), that such action is necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expiration of waivers and modifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No waiver or modification of a rule under this section shall remain in effect for a longer period than the period for which the enterprise zone designation remains in effect for the area in which the waiver or modification applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “rule” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any rule as defined in <ref>section 551(4) of title 5</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any rulemaking conducted on the record after opportunity for an agency hearing pursuant to sections 556 and 557 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or, with respect to any rule issued under title V of the Housing Act of 1949 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.], the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1962</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11505.</num>
<heading> Coordination with CDBG and UDAG programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Congress that amounts provided under the community development block grant and urban development action grant programs under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.] shall not be reduced in any fiscal year in which the provisions of this chapter are in effect.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–242, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>