<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21B—</num>
<heading>RELIGIOUS FREEDOM RESTORATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2000bb.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the framers of the Constitution, recognizing free exercise of religion as an unalienable right, secured its protection in the First Amendment to the Constitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> laws “neutral” toward religion may burden religious exercise as surely as laws intended to interfere with religious exercise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> governments should not substantially burden religious exercise without compelling justification;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in Employment Division v. Smith, 494 U.S. 872 (1990) the Supreme Court virtually eliminated the requirement that the government justify burdens on religious exercise imposed by laws neutral toward religion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the compelling interest test as set forth in prior Federal court rulings is a workable test for striking sensible balances between religious liberty and competing prior governmental interests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to restore the compelling interest test as set forth in Sherbert v. Verner, 374 U.S. 398 (1963) and Wisconsin v. Yoder, 406 U.S. 205 (1972) and to guarantee its application in all cases where free exercise of religion is substantially burdened; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide a claim or defense to persons whose religious exercise is substantially burdened by government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–141, § 2</ref>, <date date="1993-11-16">Nov. 16, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1488</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2000bb–1.</num>
<heading> Free exercise of religion protected</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Government shall not substantially burden a person’s exercise of religion even if the burden results from a rule of general applicability, except as provided in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Government may substantially burden a person’s exercise of religion only if it demonstrates that application of the burden to the person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is in furtherance of a compelling governmental interest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is the least restrictive means of furthering that compelling governmental interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person whose religious exercise has been burdened in violation of this section may assert that violation as a claim or defense in a judicial proceeding and obtain appropriate relief against a government. Standing to assert a claim or defense under this section shall be governed by the general rules of standing under article III of the Constitution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–141, § 3</ref>, <date date="1993-11-16">Nov. 16, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1488</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2000bb–2.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “government” includes a branch, department, agency, instrumentality, and official (or other person acting under color of law) of the United States, or of a covered entity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “covered entity” means the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each territory and possession of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “demonstrates” means meets the burdens of going forward with the evidence and of persuasion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “exercise of religion” means religious exercise, as defined in <ref>section 2000cc–5 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–141, § 5</ref>, <date date="1993-11-16">Nov. 16, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1489</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–274, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-09-22">Sept. 22, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2000bb–3.</num>
<heading> Applicability</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter applies to all Federal law, and the implementation of that law, whether statutory or otherwise, and whether adopted before or after <date date="1993-11-16">November 16, 1993</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Federal statutory law adopted after <date date="1993-11-16">November 16, 1993</date>, is subject to this chapter unless such law explicitly excludes such application by reference to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Religious belief unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize any government to burden any religious belief.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–141, § 6</ref>, <date date="1993-11-16">Nov. 16, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1489</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–274, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-09-22">Sept. 22, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2000bb–4.</num>
<heading> Establishment clause unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect, interpret, or in any way address that portion of the First Amendment prohibiting laws respecting the establishment of religion (referred to in this section as the “Establishment Clause”). Granting government funding, benefits, or exemptions, to the extent permissible under the Establishment Clause, shall not constitute a violation of this chapter. As used in this section, the term “granting”, used with respect to government funding, benefits, or exemptions, does not include the denial of government funding, benefits, or exemptions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–141, § 7</ref>, <date date="1993-11-16">Nov. 16, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1489</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>