<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 59—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL URBAN POLICY AND NEW COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4501.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Congress and the purpose of this chapter to provide for the development of a national urban policy and to encourage the rational, orderly, efficient, and economic growth, development, and redevelopment of our States, metropolitan areas, cities, counties, towns, and communities in predominantly rural areas which demonstrate a special potential for accelerated growth; to encourage the prudent use and conservation of energy and our natural resources; and to encourage and support development which will assure our communities and their residents of adequate tax bases, community services, job opportunities, and good housing in well-balanced neighborhoods in socially, economically, and physically attractive living environments.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–128, title VI, § 601(a)(2)</ref>–(5), <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Development of a National Urban Policy</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4502.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Congress finds that rapid changes in patterns of urban settlement, including change in population distribution and economic bases of urban areas, have created an imbalance between the Nation’s needs and resources and seriously threaten our physical and social environment, and the financial viability of our cities, and that the economic and social development of the Nation, the proper conservation of our energy and other natural resources, and the achievement of satisfactory living standards depend upon the sound, orderly, and more balanced development of all areas of the Nation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Congress further finds that Federal programs affect the location of population, economic growth, and the character of urban development; that such programs frequently conflict and result in undesirable and costly patterns of urban development and redevelopment which adversely affect the environment and wastefully use energy and other natural resources; and that existing and future programs must be interrelated and coordinated within a system of orderly development and established priorities consistent with a national urban policy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> To promote the general welfare and properly apply the resources of the Federal Government in strengthening the economic and social health of all areas of the Nation and more adequately protect the physical environment and conserve energy and other natural resources, the Congress declares that the Federal Government, consistent with the responsibilities of State and local government and the private sector, must assume responsibility for the development of a national urban policy which shall incorporate social, economic, and other appropriate factors. Such policy shall serve as a guide in making specific decisions at the national level which affect the pattern of urban development and redevelopment and shall provide a framework for development of interstate, State, and local urban policy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress further declares that the national urban policy should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> favor patterns of urbanization and economic development and stabilization which offer a range of alternative locations and encourage the wise and balanced use of physical and human resources in metropolitan and urban regions as well as in smaller urban places which have a potential for accelerated growth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> foster the continued economic strength of all parts of the United States, including central cities, suburbs, smaller communities, local neighborhoods, and rural areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage patterns of development and redevelopment which minimize disparities among States, regions, and cities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> treat comprehensively the problems of poverty and employment (including the erosion of tax bases, and the need for better community services and job opportunities) which are associated with disorderly urbanization and rural decline;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop means to encourage good housing for all Americans without regard to race or creed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> refine the role of the Federal Government in revitalizing existing communities and encouraging planned, large-scale urban and new community development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> strengthen the capacity of general governmental institutions to contribute to balanced urban growth and stabilization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> increase coordination among Federal programs that seek to promote job opportunities and skills, decent and affordable housing, public safety, access to health care, educational opportunities, and fiscal soundness for urban communities and their residents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–128, title VI, § 601(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–479, title II, § 204(i)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 921(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503.</num>
<heading> National Urban Policy Report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal to Congress; contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall transmit to the Congress, not later than <date date="1993-06-01">June 1, 1993</date>, and not later than the first day of June of every odd-numbered year thereafter, a Report on National Urban Policy which shall contribute to the formulation of such a policy, and in addition shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information, statistics, and significant trends relating to the pattern of urban development for the preceding two years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary of significant problems facing the United States as a result of urban trends and developments affecting the well-being of urban areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an examination of the housing and related community development problems experienced by cities undergoing a growth rate which equals or exceeds the national average;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the progress and effectiveness of Federal efforts designed to meet such problems and to carry out the national urban policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an assessment of the policies and structure of existing and proposed interstate planning and developments affecting such policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a review of State, local, and private policies, plans, and programs relevant to such policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> current and foreseeable needs in the areas served by policies, plans, and programs designed to carry out such policy, and the steps being taken to meet such needs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> recommendations for programs and policies for carrying out such policy, including legislative or administrative proposals—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to promote coordination among Federal programs to assist urban areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to enhance the fiscal capacity of fiscally distressed urban areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to promote job opportunities in economically distressed urban areas and to enhance the job skills of residents of such areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to generate decent and affordable housing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to reduce racial tensions and to combat racial and ethnic violence in urban areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to combat urban drug abuse and drug-related crime and violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> to promote the delivery of health care to low-income communities in urban areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> to expand educational opportunities in urban areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to achieve the goals of the national urban policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplementary reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may transmit from time to time to the Congress supplementary reports on urban policy which shall include such supplementary and revised recommendations as may be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist in the preparation of the National Urban Policy Report and any supplementary reports, the President may establish an advisory board, or seek the advice from time to time of temporary advisory boards, the members of whom shall be drawn from among private citizens familiar with the problems of urban areas and from among Federal officials, Governors of States, mayors, county officials, members of State and local legislative bodies, and others qualified to assist in the preparation of such reports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Urban Policy Report shall, when transmitted to Congress, be referred in the Senate to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and in the House of Representatives to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–128, title VI, § 601(c)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 921(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3883</ref>, 3884.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Development of New Communities</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 4511 to 4524.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 474(e)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1239</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4525.</num>
<heading> Real property taxation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this part shall be construed to exempt any real property that may be acquired and held by the Secretary as a result of the exercise of lien or subrogation rights from real property taxation to the same extent, according to its value, as other real property is taxed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title VII, § 724</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1801</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4526.</num>
<heading> Audit by Government Accountability Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Insofar as they relate to any guarantees, loans, or grants made pursuant to this part, the financial transactions of recipients of Federal assistance may be audited by the Government Accountability Office under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. The representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, files and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by such recipients pertaining to such financial transactions and necessary to facilitate the audit.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title VII, § 725</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1801</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4527.</num>
<heading> General powers of Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the performance of, and with respect to, the functions, powers, and duties vested in him by this part, the Secretary, in addition to any authority otherwise vested in him, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have the functions, powers, and duties (including the authority to issue rules and regulations) set forth in section 1749a,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003369">1</ref> except subsections (c)(2), (c)(4), (d), and (f), of title 12: <i>Provided</i>, That subsection (a)(1) of section 1749a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003369">1</ref> of title 12 shall not apply with respect to functions, powers, and duties under section 4520 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003369">1</ref> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have the power, notwithstanding any other provision of law, in connection with any assistance under this part, whether before or after any default, to provide by contract for the extinguishment upon default of any redemption, equitable, legal, or other right, title, or interest of the private new community developer or State land development agency in any mortgage, deed, trust, or other instrument held by or on behalf of the Secretary for the protection of the security interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have the power to foreclose on any property or commence any action to protect or enforce any right conferred upon him by law, contract, or other agreement, and bid for and purchase at any foreclosure or other sale any property in connection with which he has provided assistance pursuant to this part. In the event of any such acquisition, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of real property by the United States, complete, administer, remodel and convert, dispose of, lease, and otherwise deal with, such property. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall also have power to pursue to final collection by way of compromise or otherwise all claims acquired by him in connection with any security, subrogation, or other rights obtained by him in administering this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–609, title VII, § 726</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1801</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 4528 to 4532.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 474(e)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1239</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
</chapter>