<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 93—</num>
<heading>EMERGENCY ENERGY CONSERVATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8501.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serious disruptions have recently occurred in the gasoline and diesel fuel markets of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> it is likely that such disruptions will recur;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> interstate commerce is significantly affected by those market disruptions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an urgent need exists to provide for emergency conservation and other measures with respect to gasoline, diesel fuel, home heating oil, and other energy sources in potentially short supply in order to cope with market disruptions and protect interstate commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> up-to-date and reliable information concerning the supply and demand of gasoline, diesel fuel, and other related data is not available to the President, the Congress, or the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide a means for the Federal Government, States, and units of local government to establish emergency conservation measures with respect to gasoline, diesel fuel, home heating oil, and other energy sources which may be in short supply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish other emergency measures to alleviate disruptions in gasoline and diesel fuel markets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> obtain data concerning such fuels; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> protect interstate commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 757</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8502.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “severe energy supply interruption”, when used with respect to motor fuel or any other energy source, means a national energy supply shortage of such energy source which the President determines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is, or is likely to be, of significant scope and duration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may cause major adverse impact on national security or the national economy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> results, or is likely to result, from an interruption in the energy supplies of the United States, including supplies of imported petroleum products, or from sabotage or an act of God.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “international energy program” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 6202(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “motor fuel” means gasoline and diesel fuel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “person” includes (A) any individual, (B) any corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, trust, joint venture, or joint stock company, and (C) the government or any agency of the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “vehicle” means any vehicle propelled by motor fuel and manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “Governor” means the chief executive officer of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 757</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>EMERGENCY ENERGY CONSERVATION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8511.</num>
<heading> National and State emergency conservation targets</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination and publication of targets</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the President finds, with respect to any energy source for which the President determines a severe energy supply interruption exists or is imminent or that actions to restrain domestic energy demand are required in order to fulfill the obligations of the United States under the international energy program, the President, in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, may establish monthly emergency conservation targets for any such energy source for the Nation generally and for each State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any finding of the President under paragraph (1) shall be promptly transmitted to the Congress, accompanied by such information and analysis as is necessary to provide the basis for such finding, and shall be disseminated to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The State conservation target for any energy source shall be equal to (i) the State base period consumption reduced by (ii) a uniform national percentage.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “State base period consumption” means, for any month, the product of the following factors, as determined by the President:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the consumption of the energy source for which a target is established during the corresponding month in the 12-month period prior to the first month for which the target is established; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a growth adjustment factor, which shall be determined on the basis of the trends in the use in that State of such energy source during the 36-month period prior to the first month for which the target is established.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The President shall adjust, to the extent he determines necessary, any State base period consumption to insure that achievement of a target established for that State under this subsection will not impair the attainment of the objectives of section 753(b)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003842">1</ref> of title 15.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> The President may, to the extent he determines appropriate, further adjust any State base period consumption to reflect—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> reduction in energy consumption already achieved by energy conservation programs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> energy shortages which may affect energy consumption; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> variations in weather from seasonal norms.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the uniform national percentage shall be designed by the President to minimize the impact on the domestic economy of the projected shortage in the energy source for which a target is established by saving an amount of such energy source equivalent to the projected shortage, taking into consideration such other factors related to that shortage as the President considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification and publication of targets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall notify the Governor of each State of each target established under subsection (a) for that State, and shall publish in the Federal Register, the targets, the base period consumption for each State and other data on which the targets are based, and the factors considered under subsection (a)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of targets for Federal agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In connection with the establishment of any national target under subsection (a) the President shall make effective an emergency energy conservation plan for the Federal Government, which plan shall be designed to achieve an equal or greater reduction in use of the energy source for which a target is established than the national percentage referred to in subsection (a)(3)(D). Such plan shall contain measures which the President will implement, in accordance with other applicable provisions of law, to reduce on an emergency basis the use of energy by the Federal Government. In developing such plan the President shall consider the potential for emergency reductions in energy use—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by buildings, facilities, and equipment owned, leased, or under contract by the Federal Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by Federal employees and officials through increased use of car and van pooling, preferential parking for multipassenger vehicles, and greater use of mass transit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of targets</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> From time to time, the President shall review and, consistent with subsection (a), modify to the extent the President considers appropriate the national and State energy conservation targets established under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any modification under this paragraph shall be accompanied by such information and analysis as is necessary to provide the basis therefor and shall be available to the Congress and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Before the end of the 12th month following the establishment of any conservation target under this section, and annually thereafter while such target is in effect, the President shall determine, for the energy source for which that target was established, whether a severe energy supply interruption exists or is imminent or that actions to restrain domestic energy demand are required in order to fulfill the obligations of the United States under the international energy program. The President shall transmit to the Congress and make public the information and other data on which any determination under this subparagraph is based.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the President determines such an energy supply interruption does not exist or is not imminent or such actions are not required, the conservation targets established under this section with respect to such energy source shall cease to be effective.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination and publication of actual consumption nationally and State-by-State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each month the Secretary shall determine and publish in the Federal Register (1) the level of consumption for the most recent month for which the President determines accurate data is available, nationally and for each State, of any energy source for which a target under subsection (a) is in effect, and (2) whether the targets under subsection (a) have been substantially met or are likely to be met.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential authority not to be delegated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the authority vested in the President under this section may not be delegated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 758</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8512.</num>
<heading> State emergency conservation plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State emergency conservation plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than 45 days after the date of the publication of an energy conservation target for a State under <ref>section 8511(b) of this title</ref>, the Governor of that State shall submit to the Secretary a State emergency conservation plan designed to meet or exceed the emergency conservation target in effect for that State under <ref>section 8511(a) of this title</ref>. Such plan shall contain such information as the Secretary may reasonably require. At any time, the Governor may, with the approval of the Secretary, amend a plan established under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, for good cause shown, extend to a specific date the period for the submission of any State’s plan under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice of that extension together with the reasons therefor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each State is encouraged to submit to the Secretary a State emergency conservation plan as soon as possible after <date date="1979-11-05">November 5, 1979</date>, and in advance of such publication of any such target. The Secretary may tentatively approve such a plan in accordance with the provisions of this section. For the purposes of this subchapter such tentative approval shall not be construed to result in a delegation of Federal authority to administer or enforce any measure contained in a State plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conservation measures under State plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each State emergency conservation plan under this section shall provide for emergency reduction in the public and private use of each energy source for which an emergency conservation target is in effect under <ref>section 8511 of this title</ref>. Such State plan shall contain adequate assurances that measures contained therein will be effectively implemented in that State. Such plan may provide for reduced use of that energy source through voluntary programs or through the application of one or more of the following measures described in such plan:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> measures which are authorized under the laws of that State and which will be administered and enforced by officers and employees of the State (or political subdivisions of the State) pursuant to the laws of such State (or political subdivisions); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> measures—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which the Governor requests, and agrees to assume, the responsibility for administration and enforcement in accordance with subsection (d);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> which the attorney general of that State has found that (I) absent a delegation of authority under Federal law, the Governor lacks the authority under the laws of the State to invoke, (II) under applicable State law, the Governor and other appropriate State officers and employees are not prevented from administering and enforcing under a delegation of authority pursuant to Federal law; and (III) if implemented, would not be contrary to State law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> which either the Secretary determines are contained in the standby Federal conservation plan established under <ref>section 8513 of this title</ref> or are approved by the Secretary, in his discretion.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the preparation of such plan (and any amendment to the plan) the Governor shall, to the maximum extent practicable, provide for consultation with representatives of affected businesses and local governments and provide an opportunity for public comment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any State plan submitted to the Secretary under this section may permit persons affected by any measure in such plan to use alternative means of conserving at least as much energy as would be conserved by such measure. Such plan shall provide an effective procedure, as determined by the Secretary, for the approval and enforcement of such alternative means by such State or by any political subdivision of such State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of State plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> As soon as practicable after the date of the receipt of any State plan, but in no event later than 30 days after such date, the Secretary shall review such plan and shall approve it unless the Secretary finds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that, taken as a whole, the plan is not likely to achieve the emergency conservation target established for that State under <ref>section 8511(a) of this title</ref> for each energy source involved,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that, taken as a whole, the plan is likely to impose an unreasonably disproportionate share of the burden of restrictions of energy use on any specific class of industry, business, or commercial enterprise, or any individual segment thereof,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that the requirements of this subchapter regarding the plan have not been met, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> that a measure described in subsection (b)(1) is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> inconsistent with any otherwise applicable Federal law (including any rule or regulation under such law),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an undue burden on interstate commerce, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a tax, tariff, or user fee not authorized by State law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any measure contained in a State plan shall become effective in that State on the date the Secretary approves the plan under this subsection or such later date as may be prescribed in, or pursuant to, the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State administration and enforcement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authority to administer and enforce any measure described in subsection (b)(1)(B) which is in a State plan approved under this section is hereby delegated to the Governor of the State and the other State and local officers and employees designated by the Governor. Such authority includes the authority to institute actions on behalf of the United States for the imposition and collection of civil penalties under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All delegation of authority under paragraph (1) with respect to any State shall be considered revoked effective upon a determination by the President that such delegation should be revoked, but only to the extent of that determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If at any time the conditions of subsection (b)(1)(B)(ii) are no longer satisfied in any State with respect to any measure for which a delegation has been made under paragraph (1), the attorney general of that State shall transmit a written statement to that effect to the Governor of that State and to the President. Such delegation shall be considered revoked effective upon receipt by the President of such written statement and a determination by the President that such conditions are no longer satisfied, but only to the extent of that determination and consistent with such attorney general’s statement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any revocation under paragraph (2) or (3) shall not affect any action or pending proceedings, administrative or civil, not finally determined on the date of such revocation, nor any administrative or civil action or proceeding, whether or not pending, based upon any act committed or liability incurred prior to such revocation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalty</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whoever violates the requirements of any measure described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section which is in a State plan in effect under this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of not to exceed $1,000 for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any penalty under paragraph (1) may be assessed by the court in any action brought in any appropriate United States district court or any other court of competent jurisdiction. Except to the extent provided in paragraph (3), any such penalty collected shall be deposited into the general fund of the United States Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may enter into an agreement with the Governor of any State under which amounts collected pursuant to this subsection may be collected and retained by the State to the extent necessary to cover costs incurred by that State in connection with the administration and enforcement of measures the authority for which is delegated under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 759</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8513.</num>
<heading> Standby Federal conservation plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of standby conservation plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Within 90 days after <date date="1979-11-05">November 5, 1979</date>, the Secretary, in accordance with <ref>section 7191 of this title</ref>, shall establish a standby Federal emergency conservation plan. The Secretary may amend such plan at any time, and shall make such amendments public upon their adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The plan under this section shall be consistent with the attainment of the objectives of section 753(b)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003843">1</ref> of title 15, and shall provide for the emergency reduction in the public and private use of each energy source for which an emergency conservation target is in effect or may be in effect under <ref>section 8511 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of standby conservation plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If the President finds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> after a reasonable period of operation, but not less than 90 days, that a State emergency conservation plan approved and implemented under <ref>section 8512 of this title</ref> is not substantially meeting a conservation target established under <ref>section 8511(a) of this title</ref> for such State and it is likely that such target will continue to be unmet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a shortage exists or is likely to exist in such State for the 60-day period beginning after such finding that is equal to or greater than 8 percent of the projected normal demand, as determined by the President, for an energy source for which such conservation target has been established under <ref>section 8511(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the President shall, after consultation with the Governor of such State, make effective in such State all or any part of the standby Federal conservation plan established under subsection (a) for such period or periods as the President determines appropriate to achieve the target in that State.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the President finds after a reasonable period of time, that the conservation target established under <ref>section 8511(a) of this title</ref> is not being substantially met and it is likely that such target will continue to be unmet in a State which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has no emergency conservation plan approved under <ref>section 8512 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President finds has substantially failed to carry out the assurances regarding implementation set forth in the plan approved under <ref>section 8512 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the President shall, after consultation with the Governor of such State, make effective in such State all or any part of the standby Federal conservation plan established under subsection (a) for such period or periods as the President determines appropriate to achieve the target in that State.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis for findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any finding under subsection (b) shall be accompanied by such information and analysis as is necessary to provide a basis therefor and shall be available to the Congress and the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of State emergency conservation plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003844">2</ref> The Governor of a State in which all or any portion of the standby Federal conservation plan is or will be in effect may submit at any time a State emergency conservation plan, and if it is approved under <ref>section 8512(c) of this title</ref>, all or such portion of the standby Federal conservation plan shall cease to be effective in that State. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect any action or pending proceedings, administrative or civil, not finally determined on such date, nor any administrative or civil action or proceeding, whether or not pending, based upon any act committed or liability incurred prior to such cessation of effectiveness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State substitute emergency conservation measures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After the President makes all or any part of the standby Federal conservation plan effective in any State or political subdivision under subsection (b), the Secretary shall provide procedures whereby such State or any political subdivision thereof may submit to the Secretary for approval one or more measures under authority of State or local law to be implemented by such State or political subdivision and to be substituted for any Federal measure in the Federal plan. The measures may include provisions whereby persons affected by such Federal measure are permitted to use alternative means of conserving at least as much energy as would be conserved by such Federal measure. Such measures shall provide effective procedures, as determined by the Secretary, for the approval and enforcement of such alternative means by such State or by any political subdivision thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may approve the measures under paragraph (1) if he finds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that such measures when in effect will conserve at least as much energy as would be conserved by such Federal measure which would have otherwise been in effect in such State or political subdivision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such measures otherwise meet the requirements of this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such measures would be approved under section 8512(c)(1)(B), (C), and (D) of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Secretary approves measures under this subsection such Federal measure shall cease to be effective in that State or political subdivision. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect any action or pending proceedings, administrative or civil, not finally determined on the date the Federal measure ceases to be effective in that State or political subdivision, nor any administrative or civil action or proceeding, whether or not pending, based upon any act committed or liability incurred prior to such cessation of effectiveness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the Secretary finds after a reasonable period of time that the requirements of this subsection are not being met under the measures in effect under this subsection he may reimpose the Federal measure referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State authority to administer plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of the Governor of any State, the President may provide that the administration and enforcement of all or a portion of the standby Federal conservation plan made effective in that State under subsection (b) be in accordance with section 8512(d)(1), (2), and (4) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential authority not to be delegated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than subsection (f)), the authority vested in the President under this section may not be delegated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements of plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The plan established under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> taken as a whole, be designed so that the plan, if implemented, would be likely to achieve the emergency conservation target under <ref>section 8511 of this title</ref> for which it would be implemented,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> taken as a whole, be designed so as not to impose an unreasonably disproportionate share of the burden of restrictions on energy use on any specific class of industry, business, or commercial enterprise, or any individual segment thereof, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> not contain any measure which the Secretary finds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is inconsistent with any otherwise applicable Federal law (including any rule or regulation under such law),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is an undue burden on interstate commerce,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is a tax, tariff, or user fee, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is a program for the assignment of rights for end-user purchases of gasoline or diesel fuel, as described in section 6263(a)(1)(A) and (B) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan may not authorize weekend closings of retail gasoline stations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the plan established under subsection (a) may not provide for the restriction of hours of sale of motor fuel at retail at any time between Friday noon and Sunday midnight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall not preclude the restriction on such hours of sale if that restriction occurs in connection with a program for restricting hours of sale of motor fuel each day of the week on a rotating basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whoever violates the requirements of such a plan implemented under subsection (b) shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $1,000 for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any penalty under paragraph (1) may be assessed by the court in any action brought in any appropriate United States district court or any other court of competent jurisdiction. Except to the extent provided under paragraph (3), any such penalty collected shall be deposited into the general fund of the United States Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may enter into an agreement with the Governor of any State under which amounts collected pursuant to this subsection may be collected and retained by the State to the extent necessary to cover costs incurred by that State in connection with the administration and enforcement of that portion of the standby Federal conservation plan for which authority is delegated to that State under subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 762</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8514.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Any State may institute an action in the appropriate district court of the United States, including actions for declaratory judgment, for judicial review of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any target established by the President under <ref>section 8511(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any finding by the President under <ref>section 8513(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, relating to the achievement of the emergency energy conservation target of such State, or 8513(b)(2) of this title, relating to the achievement of the emergency energy conservation target of such State or the failure to carry out the assurances regarding implementation contained in an approved plan of such State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any determination by the Secretary disapproving a State plan under <ref>section 8512(c) of this title</ref>, including any determination by the Secretary under <ref>section 8512(c)(1)(B) of this title</ref> that the plan is likely to impose an unreasonably disproportionate share of the burden of restrictions of energy use on any specific class of industry, business, or commercial enterprise, or any individual segment thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such action shall be barred unless it is instituted within 30 calendar days after the date of publication of the establishment of a target referred to in subparagraph (A), the finding by the President referred to in subparagraph (B), or the determination by the Secretary referred to in subparagraph (C), as the case may be.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The district court shall determine the questions of law and upon such determination certify such questions immediately to the United States court of appeals for the circuit involved, which shall hear the matter sitting en banc.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any decision by such court of appeals on a matter certified under paragraph (2) shall be reviewable by the Supreme Court upon attainment of a writ of certiorari. Any petition for such a writ shall be filed no later than 20 days after the decision of the court of appeals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(42)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3360</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Injunctive relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to judicial review under subsection (a)(1)(A), the court shall not have jurisdiction to grant any injunctive relief except in conjunction with a final judgment entered in the case.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(42)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8515.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall monitor the implementation of State emergency conservation plans and of the standby Federal conservation plan and make such recommendations to the Governor of each affected State as he deems appropriate for modification to such plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OTHER AUTOMOBILE FUEL PURCHASE MEASURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8521.</num>
<heading> Minimum automobile fuel purchase measures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the provisions of this subsection are made applicable under subsection (c), no person shall purchase motor fuel from a motor fuel retailer in any transaction for use in any automobile or other vehicle unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the price for the quantity purchased and placed into the fuel tank of that vehicle equals or exceeds $5.00; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any case in which the amount paid for the quantity of motor fuel necessary to fill the fuel tank of that vehicle to capacity is less than $5.00, such person pays to the retailer an additional amount so that the total amount paid in that transaction equals $5.00.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any person selling motor fuel in transactions to which the provisions of this subsection apply shall display at the point of sale notice of such provisions in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> $7.00 to be applicable in case of 8-cylinder vehicles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In applying subsection (a) in the case of any vehicle with an engine having 8 cylinders (or more), “$7.00” shall be substituted for “$5.00”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Unless applicable pursuant to paragraph (2), the requirements of subsection (a) shall apply in any State and shall be administered and enforced as provided in subsection (g) only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Governor of that State submits a request to the Secretary to have such requirements applicable in that State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the attorney general of that State has found that (i) absent a delegation of authority under a Federal law, the Governor lacks the authority under the laws of the State to invoke comparable requirements, (ii) under applicable State law, the Governor and other appropriate State officers and employees are not prevented from administering and enforcing such requirements under a delegation of authority pursuant to Federal law, and (iii) if implemented such requirements would not be contrary to State law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Subject to paragraph (2), such provisions shall cease to apply in any State if the Governor of the State withdraws any request under subparagraph (A).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The requirements of subsection (a) shall apply in every State if there is in effect a finding by the President that nationwide implementation of such requirements would be appropriate and consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Such requirements shall take effect in any State beginning on the 5th day after the Secretary or the President (as the case may be) publishes notice in the Federal Register of the applicability of the requirements to the State pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the authority vested in the President under paragraph (2) may not be delegated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirements of subsection (a) shall not apply to any motorcycle or motorpowered bicycle, or to any comparable vehicle as may be determined by the Secretary by regulation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of minimum levels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may increase the $5.00 and $7.00 amounts specified in subsections (a) and (b) if the Secretary considers it appropriate. Adjustments under this subsection shall be only in even dollar amounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whoever violates the requirements of subsection (a) shall be subject to a civil penalty of not to exceed $100 for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any penalty under paragraph (1) may be assessed by the court in any action under this section brought in any appropriate United States district court or any other court of competent jurisdiction. Except to the extent provided in paragraph (3), any such penalty collected shall be deposited into the general fund of the United States Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may enter into an agreement with the Governor of any State under which amounts collected pursuant to this subsection may be collected and retained by the State to the extent necessary to cover costs incurred by that State in connection with the administration and enforcement of the requirements of subsection (a) the authority for which is delegated under subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and enforcement delegated to States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is hereby delegated to the Governor of any State, and other State and local officers and employees designated by the Governor, the authority to administer and enforce, within that State, any provision of this subchapter which is to be administered and enforced in accordance with this section. Such authority includes the authority to institute actions on behalf of the United States for the imposition and collection of civil penalties under subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> All delegation of authority under paragraph (1) with respect to any State shall be considered revoked effective (i) upon the receipt of a written waiver of authority signed by the Governor of such State or (ii) upon a determination by the President that such delegation should be revoked, but only to the extent of that determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If at any time the conditions of subsection (c)(1)(B) are no longer satisfied in any State to which a delegation has been made under paragraph (1), the attorney general of that State shall transmit a written statement to that effect to the Governor of that State and to the President. Such delegation shall be considered revoked effective upon receipt by the President of such written statement and a determination by the President that such conditions are no longer satisfied, but only to the extent of that determination and consistent with such attorney general’s statement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any revocation under subparagraph (A) or (B) shall not affect any action or pending proceedings, administrative or civil, not finally determined on the date of such revocation, nor any administrative or civil action or proceeding, whether or not pending, based on any act committed or liability incurred prior to such revocation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall administer and enforce any provision of this subchapter which has been made effective under subsection (c)(2) and for which a delegation of authority is considered revoked under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The charging and collecting of amounts referred to in subsection (a)(2) under the requirements of subsection (a), or similar amounts collected under comparable requirements under any State law, shall not be considered a violation of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003845">1</ref> [<ref>15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.] or any regulation thereunder; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any Federal or State law requiring the labeling or disclosure of the maximum price per gallon of any fuel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8522.</num>
<heading> Out-of-State vehicles to be exempted from odd-even motor fuel purchase restrictions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of any Federal, State, or local law, any odd-even fuel purchase plan in effect in any State may not prohibit the sale of motor fuel to any person for use in a vehicle bearing a license plate issued by any authority other than that State or a State contiguous to that State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Odd-even fuel purchase plan” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section the term “odd-even fuel purchase plan” means any motor fuel sales restriction under which a person may purchase motor fuel for use in any vehicle only on days (or other periods of time) determined on the basis of a number or letter appearing on the license plate of that vehicle (or on any similar basis).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>STUDIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8531.</num>
<heading> Study and report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study of commercial and industrial storage of fuel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1979-11-05">November 5, 1979</date>, the Secretary shall conduct a study and report to the Congress regarding the commercial and industrial storage of gasoline and middle distillates (other than storage in facilities which have capacities of less than 500 gallons or storage used exclusively and directly for agricultural, residential, petroleum refining, or pipeline transportation purposes).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Such report shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> indicate to what extent storage activities have increased since <date date="1978-11-01">November 1, 1978</date>, and what business establishments (including utilities) have been involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the estimated amount of gasoline and middle distillates (in the aggregate and by type and region) which are in storage within the United States at the time of the study, the amounts which were in storage at the same time during the calendar year preceding the study, and the purposes for which such storage is maintained; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> contain such findings and recommendations for legislation and administrative action as the Secretary considers appropriate, including recommendations for improving the availability and quality of data concerning such storage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 241</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8532.</num>
<heading> Middle distillate monitoring program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 60 days after <date date="1979-11-05">November 5, 1979</date>, the Secretary shall establish and maintain a data collection program for monitoring, at the refining, wholesale, and retail levels, the supply and demand levels of middle distillates on a periodic basis in each State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The program to be established under paragraph (1) shall provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the prompt collection of relevant demand and supply data under the authority available to the Secretary under other law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the submission to Congress of periodic reports each containing a concise narrative analysis of the most recent data which the Secretary determines are accurate, and a discussion on a State-by-State basis of trends in such data which the Secretary determines are significant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> All data and information collected under this program shall be available to the Congress and committees of the Congress, and, in accordance with otherwise applicable law, to appropriate State and Federal agencies and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection authorizes the direct or indirect regulation of the price of any middle distillate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “middle distillate” has the same meaning as given that term in section 211.51 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="1979-11-05">November 5, 1979</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>, the President shall submit a report to Congress in which the President shall examine the middle distillate situation, summarizing the data, information, and analyses described in subsection (a) and discussing in detail matters required to be addressed in findings made pursuant to section 760a(d)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003846">1</ref> of title 15.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 242</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8541.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall use the authority provided under <ref>section 796 of title 15</ref> for the collection of such information as may be necessary for the enforcement of the provisions of subchapters I and II of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In carrying out his responsibilities under this chapter, the Secretary shall insure that timely and adequate information concerning the supplies, pricing, and distribution of motor fuels (and other energy sources which are the subject of targets in effect under <ref>section 8511 of this title</ref>) is obtained, analyzed, and made available to the public. Any Federal agency having responsibility for collection of such information under any other authority shall cooperate fully in facilitating the collection of such information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No State law or State program in effect on <date date="1979-11-05">November 5, 1979</date>, or which may become effective thereafter, shall be superseded by any provision of this chapter, or any rule, regulation, or order thereunder, except insofar as such State law or State program is in conflict with any such provision of section 8513 or 8521 of this title (or any rule, regulation, or order under this subchapter relating thereto) in any case in which measures have been implemented in that State under the authority of section 8513 or 8521 of this title (as the case may be).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The provisions of subchapters I, II, III, and IV of this chapter, including any actions taken thereunder, shall cease to have effect on <date date="1983-07-01">July 1, 1983</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such expiration shall not affect any action or pending proceeding, administrative or civil, not finally determined on such date, nor any administrative or civil action or proceeding, whether or not pending, based upon any act committed or liability incurred prior to such expiration date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>