<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 114—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION AND ADVOCACY FOR INDIVIDUALS WITH MENTAL ILLNESS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION AND ADVOCACY SYSTEMS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Establishment of Systems</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10801.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and statement of purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> individuals with mental illness are vulnerable to abuse and serious injury;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> family members of individuals with mental illness play a crucial role in being advocates for the rights of individuals with mental illness where the individuals are minors, the individuals are legally competent and choose to involve the family members, and the individuals are legally incompetent and the legal guardians, conservators, or other legal representatives are members of the family;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> individuals with mental illness are subject to neglect, including lack of treatment, adequate nutrition, clothing, health care, and adequate discharge planning; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> State systems for monitoring compliance with respect to the rights of individuals with mental illness vary widely and are frequently inadequate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to ensure that the rights of individuals with mental illness are protected; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to assist States to establish and operate a protection and advocacy system for individuals with mental illness which will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protect and advocate the rights of such individuals through activities to ensure the enforcement of the Constitution and Federal and State statutes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> investigate incidents of abuse and neglect of individuals with mental illness if the incidents are reported to the system or if there is probable cause to believe that the incidents occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173</ref>, §§ 3, 10(2), <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1217</ref>, 1219.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10802.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “abuse” means any act or failure to act by an employee of a facility rendering care or treatment which was performed, or which was failed to be performed, knowingly, recklessly, or intentionally, and which caused, or may have caused, injury or death to a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003971">1</ref> individual with mental illness, and includes acts such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the rape or sexual assault of a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the striking of a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the use of excessive force when placing a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness in bodily restraints; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the use of bodily or chemical restraints on a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness which is not in compliance with Federal and State laws and regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “eligible system” means the system established in a State to protect and advocate the rights of persons with developmental disabilities under subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 15041</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “facilities” may include, but need not be limited to, hospitals, nursing homes, community facilities for individuals with mental illness, board and care homes, homeless shelters, and jails and prisons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “individual with mental illness” means, except as provided in <ref>section 10804(d) of this title</ref>, an individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who has a significant mental illness or emotional impairment, as determined by a mental health professional qualified under the laws and regulations of the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> who is an inpatient or resident in a facility rendering care or treatment, even if the whereabouts of such inpatient or resident are unknown;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> who is in the process of being admitted to a facility rendering care or treatment, including persons being transported to such a facility; or”; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003972">2</ref></content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> who is involuntarily confined in a municipal detention facility for reasons other than serving a sentence resulting from conviction for a criminal offense; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who satisfies the requirements of subparagraph (A) and lives in a community setting, including their own home.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “neglect” means a negligent act or omission by any individual responsible for providing services in a facility rendering care or treatment which caused or may have caused injury or death to a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness or which placed a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness at risk of injury or death, and includes an act or omission such as the failure to establish or carry out an appropriate individual program plan or treatment plan for a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness, the failure to provide adequate nutrition, clothing, or health care to a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness, or the failure to provide a safe environment for a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness, including the failure to maintain adequate numbers of appropriately trained staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “American Indian consortium” means a consortium established under part C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003973">3</ref> (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6042</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173</ref>, §§ 4, 10(1), <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1217</ref>, 1219; <ref>Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXII, § 3206(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–402, title IV, § 401(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10803.</num>
<heading> Allotments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall make allotments under this subchapter to eligible systems to establish and administer systems—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which meet the requirements of <ref>section 10805 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> which are designed to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> investigate incidents of abuse and neglect of individuals with mental illness if the incidents are reported to the system or if there is probable cause to believe that the incidents occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 10(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10804.</num>
<heading> Use of allotments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An eligible system may use its allotment under this subchapter to enter into contracts with State agencies and nonprofit organizations which operate throughout the State. In order to be eligible for a contract under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such an agency shall be independent of any agency which provides treatment or services (other than advocacy services) to individuals with mental illness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such an agency or organization shall have the capacity to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In carrying out paragraph (1), an eligible system should consider entering into contracts with organizations including, in particular, groups run by individuals who have received or are receiving mental health services, or the family members of such individuals, which,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003974">1</ref> provide protection or advocacy services to individuals with mental illness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligation of allotments; technical assistance and training</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If an eligible system is a public entity, the government of the State in which the system is located may not require the system to obligate more than 5 percent of its allotment under this subchapter in any fiscal year for administrative expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An eligible system may not use more than 10 percent of any allotment under this subchapter for any fiscal year for the costs of providing technical assistance and training to carry out this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation of individuals with mental illness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An eligible system may use its allotment under this subchapter to provide representation to individuals with mental illness in Federal facilities who request representation by the eligible system. Representatives of such individuals from such system shall be accorded all the rights and authority accorded to other representatives of residents of such facilities pursuant to State law and other Federal laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition for purposes of representation of individuals with mental illness; priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The definition of “individual with a mental illness” contained in section 10802(4)(B)(iii) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003975">2</ref> of this title shall apply, and thus an eligible system may use its allotment under this subchapter to provide representation to such individuals, only if the total allotment under this subchapter for any fiscal year is $30,000,000 or more, and in such case, an eligible system must give priority to representing persons with mental illness as defined in subparagraphs (A) and (B)(i) of <ref>section 10802(4) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509, § 7(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173</ref>, §§ 5, 10(2), <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1217</ref>, 1219; <ref>Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXII, § 3206(c)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1194</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10805.</num>
<heading> System requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority; independent status; access to facilities and records; advisory council; annual report; grievance procedure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A system established in a State under <ref>section 10803 of this title</ref> to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> have the authority to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> investigate incidents of abuse and neglect of individuals with mental illness if the incidents are reported to the system or if there is probable cause to believe that the incidents occurred;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pursue administrative, legal, and other appropriate remedies to ensure the protection of individuals with mental illness who are receiving care or treatment in the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> pursue administrative, legal, and other remedies on behalf of an individual who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> was a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003976">1</ref> individual with mental illness; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is a resident of the State,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">but only with respect to matters which occur within 90 days after the date of the discharge of such individual from a facility providing care or treatment;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be independent of any agency in the State which provides treatment or services (other than advocacy services) to individuals with mental illness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have access to facilities in the State providing care or treatment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> in accordance with <ref>section 10806 of this title</ref>, have access to all records of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any individual who is a client of the system if such individual, or the legal guardian, conservator, or other legal representative of such individual, has authorized the system to have such access;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any individual (including an individual who has died or whose whereabouts are unknown)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who by reason of the mental or physical condition of such individual is unable to authorize the system to have such access;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who does not have a legal guardian, conservator, or other legal representative, or for whom the legal guardian is the State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> with respect to whom a complaint has been received by the system or with respect to whom as a result of monitoring or other activities (either of which result from a complaint or other evidence) there is probable cause to believe that such individual has been subject to abuse or neglect; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> any individual with a mental illness, who has a legal guardian, conservator, or other legal representative, with respect to whom a complaint has been received by the system or with respect to whom there is probable cause to believe the health or safety of the individual is in serious and immediate jeopardy, whenever—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such representative has been contacted by such system upon receipt of the name and address of such representative;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such system has offered assistance to such representative to resolve the situation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> such representative has failed or refused to act on behalf of the individual;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> have an arrangement with the Secretary and the agency of the State which administers the State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] for the furnishing of the information required by subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> establish an advisory council—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which will advise the system on policies and priorities to be carried out in protecting and advocating the rights of individuals with mental illness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which shall include attorneys, mental health professionals, individuals from the public who are knowledgeable about mental illness, a provider of mental health services, individuals who have received or are receiving mental health services, and family members of such individuals, and at least 60 percent the membership of which shall be comprised of individuals who have received or are receiving mental health services or who are family members of such individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> which shall be chaired by an individual who has received or is receiving mental health services or who is a family member of such an individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> on <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, and January 1 of each succeeding year, prepare and transmit to the Secretary and the head of the State mental health agency of the State in which the system is located, and make publicly available, a report describing the activities, accomplishments, and expenditures of the system during the most recently completed fiscal year, including a section prepared by the advisory council that describes the activities of the council and its assessment of the operations of the system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> on an annual basis, provide the public with an opportunity to comment on the priorities established by, and the activities of, the system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> establish a grievance procedure for clients or prospective clients of the system to assure that individuals with mental illness have full access to the services of the system and for individuals who have received or are receiving mental health services, family members of such individuals with mental illness, or representatives of such individuals or family members to assure that the eligible system is operating in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter and subchapter III; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> not use allotments provided to a system in a manner inconsistent with <ref>section 14404 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual survey report; plan of corrections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the agency of a State which administers its State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] shall provide the eligible system of the State with a copy of each annual survey report and plan of corrections for cited deficiencies made pursuant to titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq., 1396 et seq.] with respect to any facility rendering care or treatment to individuals with mental illness in the State in which such system is located. A report or plan shall be made available within 30 days after the completion of the report or plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Governing authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each system established in a State, through allotments received under <ref>section 10803 of this title</ref>, to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness shall have a governing authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In States in which the governing authority is organized as a private non-profit entity with a multi-member governing board, or a public system with a multi-member governing board, such governing board shall be selected according to the policies and procedures of the system. The governing board shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> members (to be selected no later than <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>) who broadly represent or are knowledgeable about the needs of the clients served by the system; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a governing authority organized as a private non-profit entity, members who broadly represent or are knowledgeable about the needs of the clients served by the system including the chairperson of the advisory council of such system.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">As used in this subparagraph, the term “members who broadly represent or are knowledgeable about the needs of the clients served by the system” shall be construed to include individuals who have received or are receiving mental health services and family members of such individuals.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The governing authority established under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be responsible for the planning, design, implementation, and functioning of the system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consistent with subparagraph (A), jointly develop the annual priorities of the system with the advisory council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509</ref>, §§ 4–6(a), 7(c), <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2543–2545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173</ref>, §§ 6, 10, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1218</ref>, 1219; <ref>Pub. L. 105–12, § 9(m)</ref>, <date date="1997-04-30">Apr. 30, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 28</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title VI, § 6022(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10806.</num>
<heading> Access to records</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An eligible system which, pursuant to <ref>section 10805(a)(4) of this title</ref>, has access to records which, under Federal or State law, are required to be maintained in a confidential manner by a provider of mental health services, shall, except as provided in subsection (b), maintain the confidentiality of such records to the same extent as is required of the provider of such services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), an eligible system which has access to records pursuant to <ref>section 10805(a)(4) of this title</ref> may not disclose information from such records to the individual who is the subject of the information if the mental health professional responsible for supervising the provision of mental health services to such individual has provided the system with a written determination that disclosure of such information to such individual would be detrimental to such individual’s health.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If disclosure of information has been denied under paragraph (1) to an individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such individual;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the legal guardian, conservator, or other legal representative of such individual; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an eligible system, acting on behalf of an individual described in subparagraph (B),</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may select another mental health professional to review such information and to determine if disclosure of such information would be detrimental to such individual’s health. If such mental health professional determines, based on professional judgment, that disclosure of such information would not be detrimental to the health of such individual, the system may disclose such information to such individual.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An eligible system may select a mental health professional under subparagraph (A)(iii) on behalf of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual whose legal guardian is the State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an individual who has a legal guardian, conservator, or other legal representative other than the State if such guardian, conservator, or representative does not, within a reasonable time after such individual is denied access to information under paragraph (1), select a mental health professional under subparagraph (A) to review such information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> If the laws of a State prohibit an eligible system from obtaining access to the records of individuals with mental illness in accordance with <ref>section 10805(a)(4) of this title</ref> and this section, <ref>section 10805(a)(4) of this title</ref> and this section shall not apply to such system before—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the date such system is no longer subject to such a prohibition; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever occurs first.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “records” includes reports prepared by any staff of a facility rendering care and treatment or reports prepared by an agency charged with investigating reports of incidents of abuse, neglect, and injury occurring at such facility that describe incidents of abuse, neglect, and injury occurring at such facility and the steps taken to investigate such incidents, and discharge planning records.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An eligible system shall have access to the type of records described in subparagraph (A) in accordance with the provisions of subsection (a) and paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 10(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10807.</num>
<heading> Legal actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Prior to instituting any legal action in a Federal or State court on behalf of a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003977">1</ref> individual with mental illness, an eligible system, or a State agency or nonprofit organization which entered into a contract with an eligible system under <ref>section 10804(a) of this title</ref>, shall exhaust in a timely manner all administrative remedies where appropriate. If, in pursuing administrative remedies, the system, agency, or organization determines that any matter with respect to such individual will not be resolved within a reasonable time, the system, agency, or organization may pursue alternative remedies, including the initiation of a legal action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) does not apply to any legal action instituted to prevent or eliminate imminent serious harm to a <sup>1</sup> individual with mental illness.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 10(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Administrative Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10821.</num>
<heading> Applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission for allotment; contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No allotment may be made under this subchapter to an eligible system unless an application therefor is submitted to the Secretary. Each such application shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assurances that amounts paid to such system from an allotment under this subchapter will be used to supplement and not to supplant the level of non-Federal funds available in the State in which such system is established to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assurances that such system will have a staff which is trained or being trained to provide advocacy services to individuals with mental illness and to work with family members of clients served by the system where the individuals with mental illness are minors, legally competent and do not object, and legally incompetent and the legal guardians, conservators, or other legal representatives are family members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assurances that such system, and any State agency or nonprofit organization with which such system may enter into a contract under <ref>section 10804(a) of this title</ref>, will not, in the case of any individual who has a legal guardian, conservator, or representative other than the State, take actions which are duplicative of actions taken on behalf of such individual by such guardian, conservator, or representative unless such guardian, conservator, or representative requests the assistance of such system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such other information as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Satisfaction of requirements regarding trained staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The assurance required under subsection (a)(2) regarding trained staff may be satisfied through the provision of training by individuals who have received or are receiving mental health services and family members of such individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of applications and assurances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Applications submitted under this section shall remain in effect for a 4-year period, and the assurances required under this section shall be for the same 4-year period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509, § 7(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173</ref>, §§ 7, 10(2), <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1218</ref>, 1219; <ref>Pub. L. 102–321, title I, § 163(c)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 377</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10822.</num>
<heading> Allotment formula and reallotments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2) and subject to the availability of appropriations under <ref>section 10827 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall make allotments under <ref>section 10803 of this title</ref> from amounts appropriated under <ref>section 10827 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year to eligible systems on the basis of a formula prescribed by the Secretary which is based equally—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on the population of each State in which there is an eligible system; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on the population of each such State weighted by its relative per capita income.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the term “relative per capita income” means the quotient of the per capita income of the United States and the per capita income of the State, except that if the State is Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of Palau, or the Virgin Islands, the quotient shall be considered to be one.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The minimum amount of the allotment of an eligible system shall be the product (rounded to the nearest $100) of the appropriate base amount determined under subparagraph (B) and the factor specified in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of subparagraph (A), the appropriate base amount—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for American Samoa, Guam, the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of Palau, and the Virgin Islands, is $139,300; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for any other State, is $260,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The factor specified in this subparagraph is the ratio of the amount appropriated under <ref>section 10827 of this title</ref> for the fiscal year for which the allotment is being made to the amount appropriated under such section for fiscal year 1995.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> If the total amount appropriated for a fiscal year is at least $25,000,000, the Secretary shall make an allotment in accordance with subparagraph (A) to the eligible system serving the American Indian consortium.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent that all the amounts appropriated under <ref>section 10827 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year are not allotted to eligible systems because—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one or more eligible systems have not submitted an application for an allotment for such fiscal year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one or more eligible systems have notified the Secretary that they do not intend to use the full amount of their allotment,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the amount which is not so allotted shall be reallotted among the remaining eligible systems.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount of an allotment to an eligible system for a fiscal year which the Secretary determines will not be required by the system during the period for which it is available shall be available for reallotment by the Secretary to other eligible systems with respect to which such a determination has not been made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make reallotments under paragraphs (1) and (2) on such date or dates as the Secretary may fix (but not earlier than 30 days after the Secretary has published notice of the intention of the Secretary to make such reallotment in the Federal Register). A reallotment to an eligible system shall be made in proportion to the original allotment of such system for such fiscal year, but with such proportionate amount for such system being reduced to the extent it exceeds the sum the Secretary estimates such system needs and will be able to use during such period. The total of such reductions shall be similarly reallotted among eligible systems whose proportionate amounts were not so reduced. Any amount so reallotted to an eligible system for a fiscal year shall be deemed to be a part of its allotment under subsection (a) for such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 483</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509, § 7(e)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXII, § 3206(d)</ref>, (e), <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1194</ref>, 1195.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10823.</num>
<heading> Payments under allotments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year, the Secretary shall make payments to each eligible system from its allotment under this subchapter. Any amount paid to an eligible system for a fiscal year and remaining unobligated at the end of such year shall remain available to such system for the next fiscal year for the purposes for which it was made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10824.</num>
<heading> Reports by Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall include in each report required under <ref>section 15005 of this title</ref> a separate statement which contains—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the activities, accomplishments, and expenditures of systems to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness supported with payments from allotments under this subchapter, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a specification of the total number of individuals with mental illness served by such systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the types of activities undertaken by such systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the types of facilities providing care or treatment with respect to which such activities are undertaken;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a description of the manner in which such activities are initiated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of the accomplishments resulting from such activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> systems to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness supported with payments from allotments under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> activities conducted by States to protect and advocate such rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> mechanisms established by residential facilities for individuals with mental illness to protect and advocate such rights; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the coordination among such systems, activities, and mechanisms;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a specification of the number of systems established with allotments under this subchapter and of whether each such system was established by a public or nonprofit private entity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommendations for activities and services to improve the protection and advocacy of the rights of individuals with mental illness and a description of needs for such activities and services which have not been met by systems established under this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> using data from the existing required annual program progress reports submitted by each system funded under this subchapter, a detailed accounting for each such system of how funds are spent, disaggregated according to whether the funds were received from the Federal Government, the State government, a local government, or a private entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In preparing each statement required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall use and include information submitted to the Secretary in the reports required under <ref>section 10805(a)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 10(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–402, title IV, § 401(b)(13)(B)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title VI, § 6022(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10825.</num>
<heading> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall use not more than 2 percent of the amounts appropriated under <ref>section 10827 of this title</ref> to provide technical assistance to eligible systems with respect to activities carried out under this subchapter, consistent with requests by such systems for such assistance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509, § 7(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10826.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out this subchapter through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="1991-11-27">November 27, 1991</date>, the Secretary shall promulgate final regulations to carry out this subchapter and subchapter III.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 9</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–321, title I, § 163(c)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 377</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10827.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for allotments under this subchapter, $19,500,000 for fiscal year 1992, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1993 through 2003.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–509, § 7(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-20">Oct. 20, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 8</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXII, § 3206(f)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>RESTATEMENT OF BILL OF RIGHTS FOR MENTAL HEALTH PATIENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10841.</num>
<heading> Restatement of bill of rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that, as previously stated in title V of the Mental Health Systems Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 9501</ref> et seq.], each State should review and revise, if necessary, its laws to ensure that mental health patients receive the protection and services they require, and that in making such review and revision, States should take into account the recommendations of the President’s Commission on Mental Health and the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A person admitted to a program or facility for the purpose of receiving mental health services should be accorded the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The right to appropriate treatment and related services in a setting and under conditions that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are the most supportive of such person’s personal liberty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> restrict such liberty only to the extent necessary consistent with such person’s treatment needs, applicable requirements of law, and applicable judicial orders.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The right to an individualized, written, treatment or service plan (such plan to be developed promptly after admission of such person), the right to treatment based on such plan, the right to periodic review and reassessment of treatment and related service needs, and the right to appropriate revision of such plan, including any revision necessary to provide a description of mental health services that may be needed after such person is discharged from such program or facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The right to ongoing participation, in a manner appropriate to such person’s capabilities, in the planning of mental health services to be provided such person (including the right to participate in the development and periodic revision of the plan described in subparagraph (B)), and, in connection with such participation, the right to be provided with a reasonable explanation, in terms and language appropriate to such person’s condition and ability to understand, of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such person’s general mental condition and, if such program or facility has provided a physical examination, such person’s general physical condition;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the objectives of treatment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the nature and significant possible adverse effects of recommended treatments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the reasons why a particular treatment is considered appropriate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the reasons why access to certain visitors may not be appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any appropriate and available alternative treatments, services, and types of providers of mental health services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The right not to receive a mode or course of treatment, established pursuant to the treatment plan, in the absence of such person’s informed, voluntary, written consent to such mode or course of treatment, except treatment—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> during an emergency situation if such treatment is pursuant to or documented contemporaneously by the written order of a responsible mental health professional; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as permitted under applicable law in the case of a person committed by a court to a treatment program or facility.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The right not to participate in experimentation in the absence of such person’s informed, voluntary, written consent, the right to appropriate protections in connection with such participation, including the right to a reasonable explanation of the procedure to be followed, the benefits to be expected, the relative advantages of alternative treatments, and the potential discomforts and risks, and the right and opportunity to revoke such consent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The right to freedom from restraint or seclusion, other than as a mode or course of treatment or restraint or seclusion during an emergency situation if such restraint or seclusion is pursuant to or documented contemporaneously by the written order of a responsible mental health professional.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The right to a humane treatment environment that affords reasonable protection from harm and appropriate privacy to such person with regard to personal needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The right to confidentiality of such person’s records.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> The right to access, upon request, to such person’s mental health care records, except such person may be refused access to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information in such records provided by a third party under assurance that such information shall remain confidential; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> specific material in such records if the health professional responsible for the mental health services concerned has made a determination in writing that such access would be detrimental to such person’s health, except that such material may be made available to a similarly licensed health professional selected by such person and such health professional may, in the exercise of professional judgment, provide such person with access to any or all parts of such material or otherwise disclose the information contained in such material to such person.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The right, in the case of a person admitted on a residential or inpatient care basis, to converse with others privately, to have convenient and reasonable access to the telephone and mails, and to see visitors during regularly scheduled hours, except that, if a mental health professional treating such person determines that denial of access to a particular visitor is necessary for treatment purposes, such mental health professional may, for a specific, limited, and reasonable period of time, deny such access if such mental health professional has ordered such denial in writing and such order has been incorporated in the treatment plan for such person. An order denying such access should include the reasons for such denial.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The right to be informed promptly at the time of admission and periodically thereafter, in language and terms appropriate to such person’s condition and ability to understand, of the rights described in this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> The right to assert grievances with respect to infringement of the rights described in this section, including the right to have such grievances considered in a fair, timely, and impartial grievance procedure provided for or by the program or facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subparagraph (J), the right of access to (including the opportunities and facilities for private communication with) any available—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> rights protection service within the program or facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> rights protection service within the State mental health system designed to be available to such person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> system established under subchapter I to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> qualified advocate;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">for the purpose of receiving assistance to understand, exercise, and protect the rights described in this section and in other provisions of law.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> The right to exercise the rights described in this section without reprisal, including reprisal in the form of denial of any appropriate, available treatment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> The right to referral as appropriate to other providers of mental health services upon discharge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The rights described in this section should be in addition to and not in derogation of any other statutory or constitutional rights.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The rights to confidentiality of and access to records as provided in subparagraphs (H) and (I) of paragraph (1) should remain applicable to records pertaining to a person after such person’s discharge from a program or facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No otherwise eligible person should be denied admission to a program or facility for mental health services as a reprisal for the exercise of the rights described in this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section should—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> obligate an individual mental health or health professional to administer treatment contrary to such professional’s clinical judgment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> prevent any program or facility from discharging any person for whom the provision of appropriate treatment, consistent with the clinical judgment of the mental health professional primarily responsible for such person’s treatment, is or has become impossible as a result of such person’s refusal to consent to such treatment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> require a program or facility to admit any person who, while admitted on prior occasions to such program or facility, has repeatedly frustrated the purposes of such admissions by withholding consent to proposed treatment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> obligate a program or facility to provide treatment services to any person who is admitted to such program or facility solely for diagnostic or evaluative purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> In order to assist a person admitted to a program or facility in the exercise or protection of such person’s rights, such person’s attorney or legal representatives should have reasonable access to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the areas of the program or facility where such person has received treatment, resided, or had access; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> pursuant to the written authorization of such person, the records and information pertaining to such person’s diagnosis, treatment, and related services described in paragraph (1)(I).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Each program and facility should post a notice listing and describing, in language and terms appropriate to the ability of the persons to whom such notice is addressed to understand, the rights described in this section of all persons admitted to such program or facility. Each such notice should conform to the format and content for such notices, and should be posted in all appropriate locations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a person adjudicated by a court of competent jurisdiction as being incompetent to exercise the right to consent to treatment or experimentation described in subparagraph (D) or (E) of paragraph (1), or the right to confidentiality of or access to records described in subparagraph (H) or (I) of such paragraph, or to provide authorization as described in paragraph (3)(C)(iii), such right may be exercised or such authorization may be provided by the individual appointed by such court as such person’s guardian or representative for the purpose of exercising such right or such authorization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a person who lacks capacity to exercise the right to consent to treatment or experimentation under subparagraph (D) or (E) of paragraph (1), or the right to confidentiality of or access to records described in subparagraph (H) or (I) of such paragraph, or to provide authorization as described in paragraph (3)(C)(iii), because such person has not attained an age considered sufficiently advanced under State law to permit the exercise of such right or such authorization to be legally binding, such right may be exercised or such authorization may be provided on behalf of such person by a parent or legal guardian of such person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A) and (B), in the case of a person admitted to a program or facility for the purpose of receiving mental health services, no individual employed by or receiving any remuneration from such program or facility should act as such person’s guardian or representative.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 10(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CONSTRUCTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10851.</num>
<heading> Construction of subchapters I and II; “individual with mental illness” defined</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subchapters I and II shall not be construed as establishing any new rights for individuals with mental illness.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “individual with mental illness” has the same meaning as in section 10802(3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003978">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–319, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 489</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–173, § 10</ref>, <date date="1991-11-27">Nov. 27, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>