<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 125—</num>
<heading>RENEWABLE ENERGY AND ENERGY EFFICIENCY TECHNOLOGY COMPETITIVENESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12001.</num>
<heading> Finding, purpose, and general authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that it is in the national security and economic interest of the United States to foster greater efficiency in the use of available energy supplies and greater use of renewable energy technologies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to authorize the Secretary of Energy, acting in accordance with <ref>section 13541 of this title</ref>, to pursue an aggressive national program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies in order to ensure a stable and secure future energy supply by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> achieving as soon as practicable cost competitive use of those technologies without need of Federal financial incentives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establishing long-term Federal research goals and multiyear funding levels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> directing the Secretary to undertake initiatives to improve the ability of the private sector to commercialize in the near term renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> fostering collaborative efforts involving the private sector through government support of a program of demonstration and commercial application projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, acting in accordance with <ref>section 13541 of this title</ref>, is authorized and directed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pursue a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application with the private sector, to achieve the purpose of this chapter, including the goals established under <ref>section 12003 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> undertake demonstration and commercial application projects as provided in <ref>section 12005 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–218, § 2</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1859</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XII, § 1202(d)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2959</ref>, 2960.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12002.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “invention” means an invention or discovery that is patented or for which a patent may be obtained under title 35, or any novel variety of plant that is protected or for which plant variety protection may be obtained under the Plant Variety Protection Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2321</ref> et seq.) and that is conceived or reduced to practice as a result of work under an agreement entered into under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “non-Federal person” means an entity located in the United States, the controlling interest (as defined by the Secretary) of which is held by persons of the United States, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a for-profit business;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a private foundation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a nonprofit organization such as a university;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a trade or professional society; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a unit of State or local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “small business”, with respect to a participant in any demonstration and commercial application project under this chapter, means a private firm that does not exceed the numerical size standard promulgated by the Small Business Administration under <ref>section 632(a) of title 15</ref> for the Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) code designated by the Secretary of Energy as the primary business activity to be undertaken in the demonstration and commercial application project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the term “source reduction” means any practice which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduces the amount of any hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant entering any waste stream or otherwise released into the environment, including fugitive emissions, prior to recycling, treatment, or disposal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reduces the hazards to the public health and the environment associated with the release of such substances, pollutants, or contaminants,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">including equipment or technology modifications, process or procedure modifications, reformulation or redesign of products, substitution of raw materials, and improvements in housekeeping, maintenance, training, and inventory control, but not including any practice which alters the physical, chemical, or biological characteristics or the volume of a hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant through a process or activity which itself is not integral to and necessary for the production of a product or the providing of a service; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004025">1</ref></continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “United States” means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–218, § 3</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1859</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XII, § 1202(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2960</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12003.</num>
<heading> National goals and multi-year funding for Federal alcohol from biomass and other technology programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following are declared to be the national goals for the alcohol from biomass and other energy technology programs being carried out by the Secretary:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alcohol from biomass</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In general, the goal of the Alcohol From Biomass Program shall be to advance research and development to a point where alcohol from biomass technology is cost-competitive with conventional hydrocarbon transportation fuels, and to promote the integration of this technology into the transportation fuel sector of the economy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Specific goals for producing ethanol from biomass shall be to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> reduce the cost of alcohol to 70 cents per gallon;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> improve the overall biomass carbohydrate conversion efficiency to 91 percent;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> reduce the capital cost component of the cost of alcohol to 23 cents per gallon; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> reduce the operating and maintenance component of the cost of alcohol to 47 cents per gallon.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> Specific goals for producing methanol from biomass shall be to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> reduce the cost of alcohol to 47 cents per gallon; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> reduce the capital component of the cost of alcohol to 16 cents per gallon.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other technologies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall submit to the Congress, as part of the first report submitted under <ref>section 12006 of this title</ref>, recommendations for specific cost goals and other pertinent goals for 1995 for Department of Energy research, development, and demonstration programs in Biofuels Energy Systems, Biodiesel Energy Systems, Hydrogen Energy Systems, Solar Buildings Energy Systems, Marine Energy Systems, Geothermal Energy Systems, Low-Head Hydro, and Energy Storage Systems.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amended goals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary determines that any of the goals established under this section is no longer appropriate, the Secretary shall notify Congress, as part of a report submitted under <ref>section 12006 of this title</ref>, of the reason for the determination and provide an amended goal that is consistent with the purpose stated in <ref>section 12001(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for the following renewable energy research, development, and demonstration programs: the Biofuels Energy Systems Program, the Hydrogen Energy Systems Program, the Solar Buildings Energy Systems Program, the Marine Energy Systems Program, and the Geothermal Energy Systems Program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> not to exceed $113,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not to exceed $19,000,000 shall be available for the Geothermal Energy Systems Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not to exceed $4,000,000 shall be available for the Hydrogen Energy Systems Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> not to exceed $121,000,000 for fiscal year 1992, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not to exceed $20,500,000 shall be available for the Geothermal Energy Systems Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not to exceed $5,000,000 shall be available for the Hydrogen Energy Systems Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each of the President’s annual budget requests submitted to Congress after <date date="1989-12-11">December 11, 1989</date>, shall include as separate line items each of the categories of renewable energy programs described in this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–218, § 4</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1860</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XII, § 1202(b)</ref>, title XXI, § 2125(1)–(3), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2958</ref>, 3085; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title III, § 3006(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12004.</num>
<heading> Energy efficiency authorizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for the following energy efficiency research, development, and demonstration programs: transportation, industrial, buildings and community systems, multi-sector, and policy and management—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> not to exceed $201,100,000 for fiscal year 1991, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not to exceed $68,300,000 shall be available for the transportation program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not to exceed $53,500,000 shall be available for the industrial program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> not to exceed $210,600,000 for fiscal year 1992, of which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not to exceed $71,000,000 shall be available for the transportation program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not to exceed $54,700,000 shall be available for the industrial program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–218, § 5</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1862</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XXI, § 2125(4)</ref>–(6), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12005.</num>
<heading> Demonstration and commercial application projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to direct the Secretary to further the commercialization of renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies through a five-year program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstration and commercial application projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall solicit proposals for demonstration and commercial application projects for renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies pursuant to subsection (c). Such projects may include projects for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the production and sale of electricity, thermal energy, or other forms of energy using a renewable energy technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> increasing the efficiency of energy use; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> improvements in, or expansion of, facilities for the manufacture of renewable energy or energy efficiency technologies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each project selected under this section shall include at least one for-profit business. Activities supported under this section shall be performed in the United States. Each project under this section shall require the manufacture and reproduction substantially within the United States for commercial sale of any invention or product that may result from the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forms of financial assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In supporting projects selected under subsection (c), the Secretary may choose from among the forms of agreements described in <ref>section 13541 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In supporting projects selected under subsection (c), the Secretary may also enter into agreements with private lenders to pay a portion of the interest on loans made for such projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Cost sharing for projects under this section shall be conducted according to the procedures described in section 13542(b) and (c) of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory Committee</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall establish an Advisory Committee on Demonstration and Commercial Application of Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Technologies (in this chapter referred to as the “Advisory Committee”) to advise the Secretary on the development of the solicitation and evaluation criteria for projects under this section, and on otherwise carrying out his responsibilities under this section. The Secretary shall appoint members to the Advisory Committee, including at least one member representing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the National Laboratories of the Department of Energy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Solar Energy Research Institute;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Electric Power Research Institute;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Gas Research Institute;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the National Institute of Building Sciences;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> associations of firms in the major renewable energy manufacturing industries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> associations of firms in the major energy efficiency manufacturing industries.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to require the Secretary to reestablish the Advisory Committee in place under this subsection as of <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, or to perform again any duties performed by such advisory committee before <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Not later than 18 months after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Advisory Committee shall provide the Secretary with a report assessing the implementation of the program under this section, including specific recommendations for improvements or changes to the program and solicitation process. The Secretary shall transmit such report and, if any, the Secretary’s recommendations to the Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Solicitation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than 9 months after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Secretary shall solicit proposals for projects under this section. The Secretary may make additional solicitations for proposals if the Secretary determines that such solicitations are necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A solicitation for proposals under this paragraph shall establish a closing date for receipt of proposals. The Secretary may, if necessary, extend the closing date for receipt of proposals for a period not to exceed 90 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Each solicitation under this paragraph shall include a description of the criteria, developed by the Secretary, according to which proposals will be evaluated. In developing such criteria, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the need for Federal involvement to commercialize the technology or speed commercialization of the technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the potential for the technology to have significant market penetration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the potential energy efficiency gains or energy supply contributions of the technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> potential environmental improvements associated with the technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the export potential of the technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the likelihood that the proposal is technically sufficient to achieve the objective of the solicitation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the degree to which non-Federal financial participation is involved in the proposal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> the business and financial history of the proposer or proposers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> any other factor the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project technologies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Projects under this section may include the following technologies:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Conversion of cellulosic biomass to liquid fuels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Ethanol and ethanol byproduct processes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Direct combustion or gasification of biomass.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Biofuels energy systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Photovoltaics, including utility scale and remote applications.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Solar thermal, including solar water heating.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Wind energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> High temperature and low temperature geothermal energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Fuel cells, including transportation and stationary applications.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Nondefense high-temperature superconducting electricity technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Source reduction technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Factory-made housing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> Advanced district cooling.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall, within 120 days after the closing date established under paragraph (1)(B), select proposals to receive financial assistance under this section. In selecting proposals under this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consider each proposal’s ability to meet the criteria developed pursuant to paragraph (1)(C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> attempt to achieve technological and geographic diversity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1994.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–218, § 6</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1863</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2956</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12006.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">One year after <date date="1989-12-11">December 11, 1989</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall report to Congress on the programs and projects supported under this chapter and the progress being made toward accomplishing the goals and purposes set forth in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National renewable energy and energy efficiency management plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, shall prepare a three-year management plan to be administered and carried out by the Secretary in the conduct of activities under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> After opportunity for public comment and consideration, as appropriate, of such comment, the Secretary shall publish the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to describing the Secretary’s intentions for administering this chapter, the plan shall include a comprehensive strategy for assisting the private sector—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in commercializing the renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies developed under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in meeting competition from foreign suppliers of products derived from renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The plan shall address the role of federally-assisted research, development, and demonstration in the achievement of applicable national policy goals of the National Energy Policy Plan required under <ref>section 7321 of this title</ref> and the plan developed under <ref>section 5905 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> In addition, the Plan <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004026">1</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contain a detailed assessment of program needs, objectives, and priorities for each of the programs authorized under <ref>section 12005 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> use a uniform prioritization methodology to facilitate cost-benefit analyses of proposals in various program areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establish milestones for setting forth specific technology transfer activities under each program area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> include annual and five-year cost estimates for individual programs under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identify program areas for which funding levels have been changed from the previous year’s Plan.<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Within one year after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Secretary shall submit a revised management plan under this section to Congress. Thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a management plan every three years at the time of submittal of the President’s annual budget submission to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on options</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As part of the first report submitted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report analyzing options available to the Secretary under existing law to assist the private sector with the timely commercialization of wind, photovoltaic, solar thermal, biofuels, hydrogen, solar buildings, marine, geothermal, low-head hydro, and energy storage renewable energy technologies and energy efficiency technologies through emphasis on development and demonstration assistance to specific technologies in the research, development, and demonstration programs of the Department of Energy that are near commercial application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–218, § 9</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1868</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XII, § 1202(c)</ref>, (d)(5), title XXIII, § 2303(b), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2959</ref>, 2960, 3093; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title III, § 3006(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2512</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12007.</num>
<heading> No antitrust immunity or defenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to convey to any person, partnership, corporation, or other entity immunity from civil or criminal liability under any antitrust law or to create defenses to actions under any antitrust law. As used in this section, “antitrust laws” means those Acts set forth in <ref>section 12 of title 15</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–218, § 10</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>