<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 118—</num>
<heading>ALZHEIMER’S DISEASE AND RELATED DEMENTIAS RESEARCH</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11201.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> best estimates indicate that between 2,000,000 and 3,000,000 Americans presently have Alzheimer’s disease or related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> estimates of the number of individuals afflicted with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias are unreliable because current diagnostic procedures lack accuracy and sensitivity and because there is a need for epidemiological data on incidence and prevalence of such disease and dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> studies estimate that between one-half and two-thirds of patients in nursing homes meet the clinical and mental status criteria for dementia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the cost of caring for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias is great, and conservative estimates range between $38,000,000,000 and $42,000,000,000 per year solely for direct costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> progress in the neurosciences and behavioral sciences has demonstrated the interdependence and mutual reinforcement of basic science, clinical research, and services research for Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> programs initiated as part of the Decade of the Brain are likely to provide significant progress in understanding the fundamental mechanisms underlying the causes of, and treatments for, Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> although substantial progress has been made in recent years in identifying possible leads to the causes of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias, and more progress can be expected in the near future, there is little likelihood of a breakthrough in the immediate future that would eliminate or substantially reduce—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of individuals with the disease and dementias; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the difficulties of caring for the individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the responsibility for care of individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias falls primarily on their families, and the care is financially and emotionally devastating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> attempts to reduce the emotional and financial burden of caring for dementia patients is impeded by a lack of knowledge about such patients, how to care for such patients, the costs associated with such care, the effectiveness of various modes of care, the quality and type of care necessary at various stages of the disease, and other appropriate services that are needed to provide quality care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the results of the little research that has been undertaken concerning dementia has been inadequate or the results have not been widely disseminated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> more knowledge is needed concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the epidemiology of, and the identification of risk factors for, Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the development of methods for early diagnosis, functional assessment, and psychological evaluation of individuals with Alzheimer’s disease for the purpose of monitoring the course of the disease and developing strategies for improving the quality of life for such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the understanding of the optimal range and cost-effectiveness of community and institutional services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families, particularly with respect to the design, delivery, staffing, and mix of such services and the coordination of such services with other services, and with respect to the relationship of formal to informal support services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the understanding of optimal methods to combine formal support services provided by health care professionals with informal support services provided by family, friends, and neighbors of individuals with Alzheimer’s disease, and the identification of ways family caregivers can be sustained through interventions to reduce psychological and social problems and physical problems induced by stress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> existing data that are relevant to Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the costs incurred in caring for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> it is imperative to provide appropriate coordination of the efforts of the Federal Government in the provision of services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> it is important to increase the understanding of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias by the diverse range of personnel involved in the care of individuals with such disease and dementias; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> it is imperative that the Social Security Administration be provided information pertaining to Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias, particularly for personnel in such Administration involved in the establishment and updating of criteria for determining whether an individual is under a disability for purposes of titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq., 1381 et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–507, § 4</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COUNCIL ON ALZHEIMER’S DISEASE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 11211, 11212.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title VI, § 601(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3286</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ADVISORY PANEL ON ALZHEIMER’S DISEASE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 11221 to 11223.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III–A—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL ALZHEIMER’S PROJECT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11225.</num>
<heading> The National Alzheimer’s Project</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of Alzheimer’s</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this Act, the term “Alzheimer’s” means Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services the National Alzheimer’s Project (referred to in this Act as the “Project”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of the Project</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be responsible for the creation and maintenance of an integrated national plan to overcome Alzheimer’s;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide information on, and coordination of, Alzheimer’s research and services across all Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> accelerate the development of treatments that would prevent, halt, or reverse the course of Alzheimer’s;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> improve the—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promotion of healthy aging and reduction and mitigation of risk factors for Alzheimer’s;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> early diagnosis of Alzheimer’s disease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordination of the care and treatment of citizens with Alzheimer’s;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ensure the inclusion of ethnic and racial populations and other underserved populations, including individuals with developmental disabilities such as Down syndrome, at higher risk for Alzheimer’s or least likely to receive care, in clinical, research, and service efforts with the purpose of decreasing health disparities in Alzheimer’s;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide information on, and promote the adoption of, healthy behaviors that may reduce the risk of cognitive decline and promote and protect cognitive health; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> coordinate with international bodies to integrate and inform the fight against Alzheimer’s globally.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of the Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> oversee the creation and updating of the national plan described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> use discretionary authority to evaluate all Federal programs around Alzheimer’s, including budget requests and approvals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee, shall carry out an annual assessment of the Nation’s progress, across public and private sectors, in preparing for the escalating burden of Alzheimer’s, including both implementation steps and recommendations for priority actions based on the assessment, including consideration of public-private collaborations, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory Council</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established an Advisory Council on Alzheimer’s Research, Care, and Services (referred to in this Act as the “Advisory Council”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Advisory Council shall be comprised of the following experts:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A designee of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A designee of the Administration on Aging.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A designee of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> A designee of the Indian Health Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> A designee of the Office of the Director of the National Institutes of Health.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The Surgeon General.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> A designee of the National Science Foundation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> A designee of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> A designee of the Food and Drug Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> A designee of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> A designee of the Department of Justice.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> A designee of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiii)</num>
<content> A designee of the Social Security Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiv)</num>
<content> 2 or more other designees, as determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, at least one of whom has expertise in risk factors associated with the development or the progression of Alzheimer’s.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In addition to the members outlined in subparagraph (A), the Advisory Council shall include 15 expert members from outside the Federal Government, which shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 2 Alzheimer’s patient advocates;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 2 Alzheimer’s caregivers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 2 health care providers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> 2 representatives of State health departments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> 3 researchers with Alzheimer’s-related expertise in basic, translational, clinical, or drug development science, including at least one researcher with demonstrated experience in recruitment and retention of underrepresented groups into research or clinical trials related to dementia;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> 2 voluntary health association representatives, including a national Alzheimer’s disease organization that has demonstrated experience in research, care, and patient services, and a State-based advocacy organization that provides services to families and professionals, including information and referral, support groups, care consultation, education, and safety services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> 1 individual with a diagnosis of Alzheimer’s disease; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> 1 representative from a historically underserved population whose lifetime risk for developing Alzheimer’s is markedly higher than that of other populations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Advisory Council shall meet quarterly and such meetings shall be open to the public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Advisory Council shall provide to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee and Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> annual evaluations of all federally funded efforts in Alzheimer’s research, risk reduction, public health, clinical care, and institutional-, home-, and community-based programs and their outcomes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommendations for priority actions to expand, eliminate, coordinate, or condense programs based on the program’s performance, mission, and purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> recommendations to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> reduce the financial impact of Alzheimer’s on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Medicare and other federally funded programs; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> families living with Alzheimer’s disease; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> improve health outcomes and reduce disparities; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> annual evaluations of the implementation, including outcomes, of the recommendations, including priorities if necessary, through an updated national plan under subsection (d)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Advisory Council shall terminate on <date date="2035-12-31">December 31, 2035</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Agencies both within the Department of Health and Human Services and outside of the Department that have data relating to Alzheimer’s shall share such data with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee, to enable the Secretary, or the Secretary’s designee, to complete the report described in subsection (g).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee, shall submit to Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> an annual report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an evaluation; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003990">1</ref> of all federally funded efforts in Alzheimer’s research, clinical care, and institutional-, home-, and community-based programs and their outcomes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the Secretary’s process for identifying and updating what conditions constitute Alzheimer’s disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an evaluation of all federally funded programs based on program performance, mission, and purpose related to Alzheimer’s disease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> recommendations for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> priority actions based on the evaluation conducted by the Secretary and the Advisory Council to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> reduce the financial impact of Alzheimer’s on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Medicare and other federally funded programs; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> families living with Alzheimer’s disease; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> improve health outcomes and reduce disparities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> implementation steps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> priority actions to improve the prevention, diagnosis, treatment, care, institutional-, home-, and community-based programs of Alzheimer’s disease for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and their caregivers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an annually updated national plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Professional judgment budget</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For fiscal year 2024 and each subsequent fiscal year, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall prepare and submit, directly to the President for review and transmittal to Congress, after reasonable opportunity for comment, but without change, by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Advisory Council, an annual budget estimate for the initiatives of the National Institutes of Health pursuant to the reports and recommendations made under this Act, including an estimate of the number and type of personnel needs for the National Institutes of Health.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Project shall expire on <date date="2035-12-31">December 31, 2035</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–375, § 2</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–92, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-10-01">Oct. 1, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–93, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-10-01">Oct. 1, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1565</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH RELATING TO SERVICES FOR INDIVIDUALS WITH ALZHEIMER’S DISEASE AND RELATED DEMENTIAS AND THEIR FAMILIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11231.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11232.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 11241, 11242.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11243.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref></heading>
</section>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 1—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of National Institute of Mental Health</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11251.</num>
<heading> Research program and plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Mental Health shall conduct, or make grants for the conduct of, research relevant to appropriate services and specialized care for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of plan; contents; revision</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Mental Health shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that the research conducted under subsection (a) includes research concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> mental health services and treatment modalities relevant to the mental, behavioral, and psychological problems associated with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the most effective methods for providing comprehensive multidimensional assessments to obtain information about the current functioning of, and needs for the care of, individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the optimal range, types, and cost-effectiveness of services and specialized care for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families, in community and residential settings (including home care, day care, and respite care), and in institutional settings, particularly with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the design of the services and care;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> appropriate staffing for the provision of the services and care;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the timing of the services and care during the progression of the disease or dementias; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the appropriate mix and coordination of the services and specialized care;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the efficacy of various special care units in the United States for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease, including an assessment of the costs incurred in operating such units, the evaluation of best practices for the development of appropriate standards to be used by such units, and the measurement of patient outcomes in such units;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> methods to combine formal support services provided by health care professionals for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias with informal support services provided for such individuals by their families, friends, and neighbors, including services such as day care services, respite care services, home care services, nursing home services, and other residential services and care, and an evaluation of the services actually used for such individuals and the sources of payment for such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> methods to sustain family members who provide care for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias through interventions to reduce psychological and social problems and physical problems induced by stress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> improved methods to deliver services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families, including services such as outreach services, comprehensive assessment and care management services, outpatient treatment services, home care services, respite care services, adult day care services, partial hospitalization services, nursing home services, and other residential services and care; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the research is coordinated with, and uses, to the maximum extent feasible, resources of, other Federal programs relating to Alzheimer’s disease and dementia, including centers supported under <ref>section 285e–2 of this title</ref>, centers supported by the National Institute of Mental Health on the psychopathology of the elderly, relevant activities of the Administration on Aging, other programs and centers involved in research on Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias supported by the Department, and other programs relating to Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias which are planned or conducted by Federal agencies other than the Department, State or local agencies, community organizations, or private foundations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 931</ref>, formerly § 944, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3809</ref>; renumbered § 931, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–507, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11252.</num>
<heading> Dissemination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Mental Health shall disseminate the results of research conducted under this part to appropriate professional entities and to the public.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 932</ref>, formerly § 945, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3810</ref>; renumbered § 932, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11253.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1992 through 1996.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 933</ref>, formerly § 946, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3810</ref>; renumbered § 933, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–507, § 7(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 2—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11261.</num>
<heading> Research program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall conduct, or make grants for the conduct of, research relevant to appropriate services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research subjects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall ensure that research conducted under subsection (a) shall include research—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> concerning improving the organization, delivery, and financing of services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families, including research on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the design, staffing, and operation of special care units for the individuals in institutional settings, as well as individuals in institutional settings,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003991">1</ref> as well as individuals in home care, day care, and respite care; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the exploration and enhancement of services such as home care, day care, and respite care, that provide alternatives to institutional care;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> concerning the costs incurred by individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and by their families in obtaining services, particularly services that are essential to the individuals and that are not generally required by other patients under long-term care programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> concerning the costs, cost-effectiveness, and effectiveness of various interventions to provide services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conducted in consultation with the Director of the National Institute on Aging and the Commissioner of the Administration on Aging, concerning the role of physicians in caring for persons with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families, including the role of a physician in connecting such persons with appropriate health care and supportive services, including those supported through State and area agencies on aging designated under section 3025(a)(1) and (2)(A) of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> conducted in consultation with the Director of the National Institute on Aging and the Commissioner of the Administration on Aging, concerning legal and ethical issues, including issues associated with special care units, facing individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and facing their families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 934</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–507, § 7(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3285</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–129, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-06">Dec. 6, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11262.</num>
<heading> Dissemination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Center for Health Services Research and Health Care Technology Assessment shall disseminate the results of research conducted under this part to appropriate professional entities and to the public.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 935</ref>, formerly § 948, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3812</ref>; renumbered § 935, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11263.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1992 through 1996.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 936</ref>, formerly § 949, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3812</ref>; renumbered § 936, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–507, § 7(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 3—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11271.</num>
<heading> Research program and plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall conduct, or make grants for the conduct of, research relevant to appropriate services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of plan; contents; revision</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Within 6 months after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall prepare and transmit to the Chairman of the Council a plan for research to be conducted under (a).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003992">1</ref> The plan shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide for a determination of the types of services required by individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families to allow such individuals to remain living at home or in a community-based setting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for a determination of the costs of providing needed services to individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families, including the expenditures for institutional, home, and community-based services and the source of payment for such expenditures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide for an assessment of the adequacy of benefits provided through the Medicare and Medicaid programs and through private health insurance for needed services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide for a determination of the costs to the Medicare and Medicaid programs and to private health insurers (if available) of providing covered benefits to individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and their families.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Within one year after transmitting the plan required under paragraph (1), and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall prepare and transmit to the Chairman of the Council such revisions of such plan as the Administrator considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation for preparation and revision of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In preparing and revising the plan required by subsection (b), the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall consult with the Chairman of the Council and the heads of agencies within the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 937</ref>, formerly § 949A, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3812</ref>; renumbered § 937, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 900(e)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11272.</num>
<heading> Dissemination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall disseminate the results of research conducted under this part to appropriate professional entities and to the public.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 938</ref>, formerly § 949B, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3812</ref>; renumbered § 938, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 900(e)(5)(C)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11273.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out this part, there are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1988 through 1991.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 939</ref>, formerly § 949C, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3813</ref>; renumbered § 939, <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 11281, 11282.</num>
<heading> Transferred</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11283.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 142(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3057</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>EDUCATIONAL ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11291.</num>
<heading> Providing information for personnel of Social Security Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall develop a mechanism to ensure the prompt provision of the most current information concerning Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias to the Commissioner of Social Security, particularly information which will increase the understanding of personnel of the Social Security Administration concerning such disease and dementias.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commissioner of Social Security shall ensure that information received under subsection (a) is provided to personnel of the Social Security Administration, particularly personnel involved in the process of determining, for purposes of titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq., 1381 et seq.], whether an individual is under a disability.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 961</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11292.</num>
<heading> Education of public, individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and their families, and health and long-term care providers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training models grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director of the National Institute on Aging may award grants to eligible entities to assist the entities in developing and evaluating model training programs—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> health care professionals, including mental health professionals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> health care paraprofessionals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> personnel, including information and referral, case management, and in-home services personnel (including personnel receiving support under the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.)), providing supportive services to the elderly and the families of the elderly;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> family caregivers providing care and treatment for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related disorders; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> personnel of local organizations (including community groups, business and labor groups, and religious, educational, and charitable organizations) that have traditionally not been involved in planning and developing long-term care services; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> with attention to such variables as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> curricula development for training and continuing education programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> care setting; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> intervention technique.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive grants under this subsection, an entity shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an educational institution providing training and education in medicine, psychology, nursing, social work, gerontology, or health care administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an educational institution providing preparatory training and education of personnel for nursing homes, hospitals, and home or community settings; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an Alzheimer’s Disease Research Center described in <ref>section 285e–2(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Educational grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute on Aging is authorized to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities to assist such entities in establishing programs, for educating health care providers and the families of individuals with Alzheimer’s disease or related disorders, regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> caring for individuals with such diseases or disorders; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the availability in the community of public and private sources of assistance, including financial assistance, for caring for such individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In awarding grants under this section, the Director of the National Institute on Aging shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> award the grants on the basis of merit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> award the grants in a manner that will ensure access to the programs described in subsections (a) and (b) by rural, minority, and underserved populations throughout the country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure that the grants are distributed among the principal geographic regions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Director of the National Institute on Aging at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information, as the Director may reasonably require, including, at a minimum, an assurance that the entity will coordinate programs provided under this section with the State agency designated under section 305(a)(1) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 3025(a)(1)</ref>], in the State in which the entity will provide such programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute on Aging shall coordinate the award of grants under this section with the heads of other appropriate agencies, including the Commissioner of the Administration on Aging.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 962</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–507, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11293.</num>
<heading> Education programs for safety and transportation personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute on Aging, through centers supported under <ref>section 285e–2 of this title</ref>, training academies, and continuing education programs, shall conduct education and information dissemination activities concerning Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias for personnel involved in ensuring the public safety and providing public transportation. Such activities shall be designed to enhance the ability of such personnel to respond appropriately to individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias whom such personnel may encounter in the course of their employment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 963</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11294.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To carry out sections 11291 and 11293 of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1988 through 1991.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1992 through 1996, to carry out <ref>section 11292 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–660, title IX, § 964</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–507, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>