<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 40—</num>
<heading>SOIL INFORMATION ASSISTANCE FOR COMMUNITY PLANNING AND RESOURCE DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3271.</num>
<heading> Availability of soil surveys under soil survey program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In recognition of the increasing need for soil surveys by the States and other public agencies in connection with community planning and resource development for protecting and improving the quality of the environment, meeting recreational needs, conserving land and water resources, providing for multiple uses of such resources, and controlling and reducing pollution from sediment and other pollutants in areas of rapidly changing uses, including farmlands being shifted to other uses, resulting from rapid expansions in the uses of land for industry, housing, transportation, recreation, and related services, it is the sense of Congress that the soil survey program of the United States Department of Agriculture should be conducted so as to make available soil surveys to meet such needs of the States and other public agencies in connection with community planning and resource development.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–560, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3272.</num>
<heading> Cooperative assistance to State and other public agencies; types of assistance; private engineering services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to provide soil surveys to assist States, their political subdivisions, soil and water conservation districts, towns, cities, planning boards and commissions, community development districts, and other public agencies in community planning and resource development for the protection and improvement of the quality of the environment, recreational development, the conservation of land and water resources, the development of multiple uses of such resources, and the control and prevention of pollution from sediment and other pollutants in areas of rapidly changing uses, including farm and nonfarm areas, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, upon the request of a State or other public agency, provide by means of such cooperative arrangements with the State or other public agency as he may deem advisable, the following assistance with respect to such areas and purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the making of studies and reports necessary for the classification and interpretation of kinds of soil;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an intensification of the use and benefits of the National Cooperative Soil Survey;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the furnishing of technical and other assistance needed for use of soil surveys; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> consultation with other Federal agencies participating or assisting in the planning and development of such areas in order to assure the coordination of the work under this chapter with the related work of such other agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0">The provision by the Secretary of such assistance shall not interfere with the furnishing of engineering services by private engineering firms or consultants for on-site sampling and testing of sites or for design and construction of specific engineering works.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–560, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3273.</num>
<heading> Contributions of State or other public agencies toward cost of soil surveys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is further the sense of the Congress that the Secretary shall make a reasonable effort to assure that the contributions of any State or other public agency under any cooperative agreement which may be entered into between the Secretary and such State or other public agency with respect to a soil survey shall be a substantial portion of the cost of such soil survey.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–560, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3274.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter, such sums to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–560, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>