<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 148—</num>
<heading>WINDSTORM IMPACT REDUCTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 15701.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Hurricanes, tropical storms, tornadoes, and thunderstorms can cause significant loss of life, injury, destruction of property, and economic and social disruption. All States and regions are vulnerable to these hazards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States currently sustains several billion dollars in economic damages each year due to these windstorms. In recent decades, rapid development and population growth in high-risk areas has greatly increased overall vulnerability to windstorms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Improved windstorm impact reduction measures have the potential to reduce these losses through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cost-effective and affordable design and construction methods and practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> effective mitigation programs at the local, State, and national level;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> improved data collection and analysis and impact prediction methodologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> engineering research on improving new structures and retrofitting existing ones to better withstand windstorms, atmospheric-related research to better understand the behavior and impact of windstorms on the built environment, and subsequent application of those research results; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> public education and outreach.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> There is an appropriate role for the Federal Government in supporting windstorm impact reduction. An effective Federal program in windstorm impact reduction will require interagency coordination, and input from individuals, academia, the private sector, and other interested non-Federal entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1675</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lifelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “lifelines” means public works and utilities, including transportation facilities and infrastructure, oil and gas pipelines, electrical power and communication facilities and infrastructure, and water supply and sewage treatment facilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Program” means the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program established by <ref>section 15703(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Windstorm</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “windstorm” means any storm with a damaging or destructive wind component, such as a hurricane, tropical storm, northeaster, tornado, or thunderstorm.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1676</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–52, § 2</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15703.</num>
<heading> National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program, the purpose of which is to achieve major measurable reductions in the losses of life and property from windstorms through a coordinated Federal effort, in cooperation with other levels of government, academia, and the private sector, aimed at improving the understanding of windstorms and their impacts and developing and encouraging the implementation of cost-effective mitigation measures to reduce those impacts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of Program agencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall have the primary responsibility for planning and coordinating the Program. In carrying out this paragraph, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that the Program includes the necessary components to promote the implementation of windstorm risk reduction measures by Federal, State, and local governments, national standards and model building code organizations, architects and engineers, and others with a role in planning and constructing buildings and lifelines;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> support the development of performance-based engineering tools, and work with appropriate groups to promote the commercial application of such tools, including through wind-related model building codes, voluntary standards, and construction best practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> request the assistance of Federal agencies other than the Program agencies, as necessary to assist in carrying out this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> coordinate all Federal post-windstorm investigations to the extent practicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> when warranted by research or investigative findings, issue recommendations to assist in informing the development of model codes, and provide information to Congress on the use of such recommendations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Institute of Standards and Technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the lead agency responsibilities described under paragraph (1), the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall be responsible for carrying out research and development to improve model building codes, voluntary standards, and best practices for the design, construction, and retrofit of buildings, structures, and lifelines.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Science Foundation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The National Science Foundation shall support research in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engineering and the atmospheric sciences to improve the understanding of the behavior of windstorms and their impact on buildings, structures, and lifelines; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> economic and social factors influencing windstorm risk reduction measures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall support atmospheric sciences research to improve the understanding of the behavior of windstorms and their impact on buildings, structures, and lifelines.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Emergency Management Agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Federal Emergency Management Agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> support—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the development of risk assessment tools and effective mitigation techniques;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> windstorm-related data collection and analysis;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> public outreach and information dissemination; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> promotion of the adoption of windstorm preparedness and mitigation measures, including for households, businesses, and communities, consistent with the Agency’s all-hazards approach; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> work closely with national standards and model building code organizations, in conjunction with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to promote the implementation of research results and promote better building practices within the building design and construction industry, including architects, engineers, contractors, builders, and inspectors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program components</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Program shall consist of three primary mitigation components: improved understanding of windstorms, windstorm impact assessment, and windstorm impact reduction. The components shall be implemented through activities such as data collection and analysis, risk assessment, outreach, technology transfer, and research and development. To the extent practicable, research activities authorized under this chapter shall be peer-reviewed, and the components shall be designed to be complementary to, and avoid duplication of, other public and private hazard reduction efforts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Understanding of windstorms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Activities to enhance the understanding of windstorms shall include research to improve knowledge of and data collection on the impact of severe wind on buildings, structures, and infrastructure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Windstorm impact assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Activities to improve windstorm impact assessment shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> development of mechanisms for collecting and inventorying information on the performance of buildings, structures, and infrastructure in windstorms and improved collection of pertinent information from sources, including the design and construction industry, insurance companies, and building officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> research, development, and technology transfer to improve loss estimation and risk assessment systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> research, development, and technology transfer to improve simulation and computational modeling of windstorm impacts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Windstorm impact reduction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Activities to reduce windstorm impacts shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> development of improved outreach and implementation mechanisms to translate existing information and research findings into cost-effective and affordable practices for design and construction professionals, and State and local officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> development of cost-effective and affordable windstorm-resistant systems, structures, and materials for use in new construction and retrofit of existing construction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> outreach and information dissemination related to cost-effective and affordable construction techniques, loss estimation and risk assessment methodologies, and other pertinent information regarding windstorm phenomena to Federal, State, and local officials, the construction industry, and the general public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall each include in their agency’s annual budget request to Congress a description of their agency’s projected activities under the Program for the fiscal year covered by the budget request, along with an assessment of what they plan to spend on those activities for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency Coordinating Committee on Windstorm Impact Reduction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Windstorm Impact Reduction, chaired by the Director or the Director’s designee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to the chair, the Committee shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the heads or such designees of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the National Science Foundation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Office of Science and Technology Policy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Office of Management and Budget; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the head of any other Federal agency, or such designee, the chair considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Committee shall meet not less than once a year at the call of the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General purpose and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Committee shall oversee the planning and coordination of the Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Committee shall develop and submit to Congress, not later than 1 year after <date date="2015-09-30">September 30, 2015</date>, a Strategic Plan for the Program that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prioritized goals for the Program that will mitigate against the loss of life and property from future windstorms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> short-term, mid-term, and long-term research objectives to achieve those goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the role of each Program agency in achieving the prioritized goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the methods by which progress towards the goals will be assessed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an explanation of how the Program will foster the transfer of research results into outcomes, such as improved model building codes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Progress report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2015-09-30">September 30, 2015</date>, the Committee shall submit to the Congress a report on the progress of the Program that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the activities funded under the Program, a description of how these activities align with the prioritized goals and research objectives established in the Strategic Plan, and the budgets, per agency, for these activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the outcomes achieved by the Program for each of the goals identified in the Strategic Plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of any recommendations made to change existing building codes that were the result of Program activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a description of the extent to which the Program has incorporated recommendations from the Advisory Committee on Windstorm Impact Reduction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinated budget</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Committee shall develop a coordinated budget for the Program, which shall be submitted to the Congress not later than 60 days after the date of the President’s budget submission for each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1676</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–52, § 3</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15704.</num>
<heading> National Advisory Committee on Windstorm Impact Reduction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall establish an Advisory Committee on Windstorm Impact Reduction, which shall be composed of at least 7 and not more than 15 members who are qualified to provide advice on windstorm impact reduction and represent related scientific, architectural, and engineering disciplines, none of whom may be employees of the Federal Government, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> representatives of research and academic institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> industry standards development organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> emergency management agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> State and local government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> business communities, including the insurance industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Advisory Committee on Windstorm Impact Reduction shall offer assessments and recommendations on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> trends and developments in the natural, engineering, and social sciences and practices of windstorm impact mitigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the priorities of the Program’s Strategic Plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the coordination of the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the effectiveness of the Program in meeting its purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any revisions to the Program which may be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Advisory Committee established under this section shall serve without compensation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At least every 2 years, the Advisory Committee shall report to the Director on the assessments carried out under subsection (b) and its recommendations for ways to improve the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Charter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 1013(b)(2) of title 5</ref>, the Advisory Committee shall not be required to file a charter subsequent to its initial charter, filed under <ref>section 1008(c) of title 5</ref>, before the termination date specified in subsection (f) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Advisory Committee shall terminate on <date date="2017-09-30">September 30, 2017</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflict of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An Advisory Committee member shall recuse himself from any Advisory Committee activity in which he has an actual pecuniary interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1678</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–52, § 4</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(277)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15705.</num>
<heading> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter supersedes any provision of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5401</ref> et seq.]. No design, construction method, practice, technology, material, mitigation methodology, or hazard reduction measure of any kind developed under this chapter shall be required for a home certified under section 616 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5415</ref>), pursuant to standards issued under such Act, without being subject to the consensus development process and rulemaking procedures of that Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15706.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Emergency Management Agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Emergency Management Agency for carrying out this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $5,332,000 for fiscal year 2015;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $5,332,000 for fiscal year 2016; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $5,332,000 for fiscal year 2017.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Science Foundation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Science Foundation for carrying out this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $9,682,000 for fiscal year 2015;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $9,682,000 for fiscal year 2016; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $9,682,000 for fiscal year 2017.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Institute of Standards and Technology</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Standards and Technology for carrying out this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $4,120,000 for fiscal year 2015;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $4,120,000 for fiscal year 2016; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $4,120,000 for fiscal year 2017.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for carrying out this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $2,266,000 for fiscal year 2015;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $2,266,000 for fiscal year 2016; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $2,266,000 for fiscal year 2017.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1679</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–52, § 5</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15707.</num>
<heading> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies carrying out activities under this chapter and the statutes amended by this chapter shall work together to ensure that research, technologies, and response techniques are shared among the programs authorized in this chapter in order to coordinate the Nation’s efforts to reduce vulnerability to the hazards described in this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>