<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1033—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL MILITARY PARKS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 103301.</num>
<heading> Military maneuvers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To obtain practical benefits of great value to the country from the establishment of national military parks, the parks and their approaches are declared to be national fields for military maneuvers for the Regular Army or Regular Air Force and the National Guard or militia of the States. National military parks shall be opened for those purposes only in the discretion of the Secretary, and under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103302.</num>
<heading> Camps for military instruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assembling of Forces and Detailing of Instructors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army or Secretary of the Air Force, within the limits of appropriations that may be available for that purpose, may assemble in camp at such season of the year and for such period as the Secretary of the Army or Secretary of the Air Force may designate, at the field of military maneuvers, such portions of the military forces of the United States as the Secretary of the Army or Secretary of the Air Force may think best, to receive military instruction there. The Secretary of the Army of Secretary of the Air Force may detail instructors from the Regular Army or Regular Air Force, respectively, for those forces during their exercises.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army or Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe regulations governing the assembling of the National Guard or militia of the States on the maneuvering grounds.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103303.</num>
<heading> Performance of duties of commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The duties of commissions in charge of national military parks shall be performed under the direction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103304.</num>
<heading> Recovery of land withheld</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States may bring a civil action in the courts of the United States against a person to whom land lying within a national military park has been leased that refuses to give up possession of the land to the United States after the termination of the lease, and after possession has been demanded for the United States by the park superintendent, or against a person retaining possession of land lying within the boundary of a national military park that the person has sold to the United States for park purposes and received payment therefor, after possession of the land has been demanded for the United States by the park superintendent, to recover possession of the land withheld. The civil action shall be brought according to the statutes of the State in which the national military park is situated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Trespass</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person described in subsection (a) shall be guilty of trespass.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103305.</num>
<heading> Travel expenses incident to study of battlefields</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Mileage of officers of the Army and actual expenses of civilian employees traveling on duty in connection with the studies, surveys, and field investigations of battlefields shall be paid from the appropriations made to meet expenses for those purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103306.</num>
<heading> Studies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Study of Battlefields for Commemorative Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army may make studies and investigations and, where necessary, surveys of all battlefields within the continental limits of the United States on which troops of the United States or of the original 13 colonies have been engaged against a common enemy, with a view to preparing a general plan and such detailed projects as may be required for properly commemorating such battlefields or other adjacent points of historic and military interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of Estimate of Cost of Projected Surveys in Appropriation Estimates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army shall include annually in the Department of the Interior appropriation estimates a list of the battlefields for which surveys or other field investigations are planned for the fiscal year in question, with the estimated cost of making each survey or other field investigation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purchase of Real Estate for National Military Park Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No real estate shall be purchased for national military park purposes by the Federal Government unless a report on the real estate has been made by the Secretary of the Army through the President to Congress under subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army, through the President, shall annually submit to Congress a detailed report of progress made under this subchapter, with recommendations for further operations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>