<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3123—</num>
<heading>COMMISSION FOR THE PRESERVATION OF AMERICA’S HERITAGE ABROAD</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 312301.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “Commission” means the Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad established under <ref>section 312303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312302.</num>
<heading> Declaration of national interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Because the fabric of a society is strengthened by visible reminders of the historical roots of the society, it is in the national interest to encourage the preservation and protection of the cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings associated with the foreign heritage of United States citizens.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312303.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established a commission to be known as the Commission for the Preservation of America’s Heritage Abroad.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall consist of 21 members appointed by the President, 7 of whom shall be appointed after consultation with the Speaker of the House of Representatives and 7 of whom shall be appointed after consultation with the President pro tempore of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Term.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the Commission shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vacancy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member appointed to fill a vacancy on the Commission shall serve for the remainder of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Member until successor appointed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member may retain membership on the Commission until the member’s successor has been appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall designate the Chairman of the Commission from among its members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission shall meet at least once every 6 months.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compensation and Expenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Commission shall receive no pay on account of their service on the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission, members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as individuals employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312304.</num>
<heading> Duties and powers; administrative support</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify and publish a list of cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings located abroad that are associated with the foreign heritage of United States citizens from eastern and central Europe, particularly cemeteries, monuments, and buildings that are in danger of deterioration or destruction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage the preservation and protection of those cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings by obtaining, in cooperation with the Secretary of State, assurances from foreign governments that the cemeteries, monuments, and buildings will be preserved and protected; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prepare and disseminate reports on the condition of, and the progress toward preserving and protecting, those cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Powers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hold hearings, request attendance, take testimony, and receive evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission or any member it authorizes may, for the purposes of carrying out this chapter, hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, request such attendance, take such testimony, and receive such evidence, as the Commission considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appoint personnel and fix pay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may appoint such personnel (subject to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service) and may fix the pay of such personnel (subject to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5), as the Commission considers desirable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procure temporary and intermittent services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services to the same extent as is authorized by <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, but at rates for individuals not to exceed the daily equivalent of the maximum annual rate of basic pay then in effect under <ref>section 5376 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detail personnel to commisison </inline><ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">1</ref><inline class="small-caps"/>.—</heading>
<content>On request of the Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency, including the Secretary of State, may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its duties under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secure information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States, including the Department of State, any information necessary to enable it to carry out this chapter. On the request of the Chairman of the Commission, the head of the department or agency shall furnish the information to the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Gifts or donations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of money or property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of mails</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and on the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission on a reimbursable basis administrative support services as the Commission may request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312305.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the end of each fiscal year, the Commission shall transmit to the President a report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a detailed statement of the activities and accomplishments of the Commission during the fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any recommendations of the Commission for legislation and administrative actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>