<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3027—</num>
<heading>HISTORIC PRESERVATION PROGRAMS AND AUTHORITIES FOR INDIAN TRIBES AND NATIVE HAWAIIAN ORGANIZATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 302701.</num>
<heading> Program to assist Indian tribes in preserving historic property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish a program and promulgate regulations to assist Indian tribes in preserving their historic property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Communication and Cooperation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall foster communication and cooperation between Indian tribes and State Historic Preservation Officers in the administration of the national historic preservation program to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that all types of historic property and all public interests in historic property are given due consideration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage coordination among Indian tribes, State Historic Preservation Officers, and Federal agencies in historic preservation planning and in the identification, evaluation, protection, and interpretation of historic property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal Values</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program under subsection (a) shall be developed in a manner to ensure that tribal values are taken into account to the extent feasible. The Secretary may waive or modify requirements of this subdivision to conform to the cultural setting of tribal heritage preservation goals and objectives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of Tribal Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The tribal programs implemented by specific tribal organizations may vary in scope, as determined by each Indian tribe’s chief governing authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult with Indian tribes, other Federal agencies, State Historic Preservations <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002019">1</ref> Officers, and other interested parties concerning the program under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302702.</num>
<heading> Indian tribe to assume functions of State Historic Preservation Officer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An Indian tribe may assume all or any part of the functions of a State Historic Preservation Officer in accordance with sections 302302 and 302303 of this title, with respect to tribal land, as those responsibilities may be modified for tribal programs through regulations issued by the Secretary, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Indian tribe’s chief governing authority so requests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Indian tribe designates a tribal preservation official to administer the tribal historic preservation program, through appointment by the Indian tribe’s chief governing authority or as a tribal ordinance may otherwise provide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the tribal preservation official provides the Secretary with a plan describing how the functions the tribal preservation official proposes to assume will be carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary determines, after consulting with the Indian tribe, the appropriate State Historic Preservation Officer, the Council (if the Indian tribe proposes to assume the functions of the State Historic Preservation Officer with respect to review of undertakings under <ref>section 306108 of this title</ref>), and other Indian tribes, if any, whose tribal or aboriginal land may be affected by conduct of the tribal preservation program, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the tribal preservation program is fully capable of carrying out the functions specified in the plan provided under paragraph (3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the plan defines the remaining responsibilities of the Secretary and the State Historic Preservation Officer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the plan provides, with respect to properties neither owned by a member of the Indian tribe nor held in trust by the Secretary for the benefit of the Indian tribe, at the request of the owner of the properties, that the State Historic Preservation Officer, in addition to the tribal preservation official, may exercise the historic preservation responsibilities in accordance with sections 302302 and 302303 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> based on satisfaction of the conditions stated in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4), the Secretary approves the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302703.</num>
<heading> Apportionment of grant funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In consultation with interested Indian tribes, other Native American organizations, and affected State Historic Preservation Officers, the Secretary shall establish and implement procedures for carrying out <ref>section 302902(c)(1)(A) of this title</ref> with respect to tribal programs that assume responsibilities under <ref>section 302702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302704.</num>
<heading> Contracts and cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">At the request of an Indian tribe whose preservation program has been approved to assume functions and responsibilities pursuant to <ref>section 302702 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with the Indian tribe permitting the assumption by the Indian tribe of any part of the responsibilities described in <ref>section 302304(b) of this title</ref> on tribal land, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary and the Indian tribe agree on additional financial assistance, if any, to the Indian tribe for the costs of carrying out those authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary finds that the tribal historic preservation program has been demonstrated to be sufficient to carry out the contract or cooperative agreement and this division; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the contract or cooperative agreement specifies the continuing responsibilities of the Secretary or of the appropriate State Historic Preservation Officers and provides for appropriate participation by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Indian tribe’s traditional cultural authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> representatives of other Indian tribes whose traditional land is under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe assuming responsibilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the interested public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302705.</num>
<heading> Agreement for review under tribal historic preservation regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council may enter into an agreement with an Indian tribe to permit undertakings on tribal land to be reviewed under tribal historic preservation regulations in place of review under regulations promulgated by the Council to govern compliance with <ref>section 306108 of this title</ref>, if the Council, after consultation with the Indian tribe and appropriate State Historic Preservation Officers, determines that the tribal preservation regulations will afford historic property consideration equivalent to that afforded by the Council’s regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302706.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for inclusion on National Register</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Property of traditional religious and cultural importance to an Indian tribe or Native Hawaiian organization may be determined to be eligible for inclusion on the National Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out its responsibilities under <ref>section 306108 of this title</ref>, a Federal agency shall consult with any Indian tribe or Native Hawaiian organization that attaches religious and cultural significance to property described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hawaii</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out responsibilities under <ref>section 302303 of this title</ref>, the State Historic Preservation Officer for Hawaii shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with Native Hawaiian organizations in assessing the cultural significance of any property in determining whether to nominate the property to the National Register;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consult with Native Hawaiian organizations in developing the cultural component of a preservation program or plan for the property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enter into a memorandum of understanding or agreement with Native Hawaiian organizations for the assessment of the cultural significance of a property in determining whether to nominate the property to the National Register and to carry out the cultural component of the preservation program or plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>