<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2001—</num>
<heading>COORDINATION OF PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 200101.</num>
<heading> Findings and declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds and declares it is desirable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that all American people of present and future generations be assured adequate outdoor recreation resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for all levels of government and private interests to take prompt and coordinated action to the extent practicable without diminishing or affecting their respective powers and functions to conserve, develop, and utilize those resources for the benefit and enjoyment of the American people.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3169</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 200102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Council</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Council” means the Federal Interagency Council on Outdoor Recreation established under section 200104.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal land and water management agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Federal land and water management agency” means the National Park Service, Bureau of Land Management, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Reclamation, Forest Service, Corps of Engineers, and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal recreational lands and waters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Federal recreational lands and waters” has the meaning given the term in section 802 of the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 6801</ref>) and also includes Federal lands and waters managed by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, Corps of Engineers, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State”, to the extent practicable, as determined by the Secretary, includes Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United States</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “United States”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> includes the District of Columbia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, as determined by the Secretary, includes Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–234, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 200103.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary to carry out certain functions and activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out this chapter, the Secretary may perform the functions and activities described in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inventory and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may prepare and maintain a continuing inventory and evaluation of outdoor recreation needs and resources of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Classification System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may prepare a system for classification of outdoor recreation resources to assist in the effective and beneficial use and management of such resources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Technical Assistance and Advice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide technical assistance and advice to and cooperate with States, political subdivisions, and private interests, including nonprofit organizations, with respect to outdoor recreation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interstate and Regional Cooperation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may encourage interstate and regional cooperation in the planning, acquisition, and development of outdoor recreation resources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research, Information, and Education Programs and Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sponsor, engage in, and assist in research relating to outdoor recreation, directly or by contract or cooperative agreements, and make payments for such purposes without regard to the limitations of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31 concerning advances of funds when the Secretary considers such action to be in the public interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> undertake studies and assemble information concerning outdoor recreation, directly or by contract or cooperative agreement, and disseminate the information without regard to <ref>section 3204 of title 39</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> cooperate with educational institutions and others to assist in establishing education programs and activities and to encourage public use and benefits from outdoor recreation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperation and Coordination with Federal Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cooperate with and provide technical assistance to Federal agencies and obtain from them information, data, reports, advice, and assistance that are needed and can reasonably be furnished in carrying out the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote coordination of Federal plans and activities generally relating to outdoor recreation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agency furnishing advice or assistance under this paragraph may expend its own funds for those purposes, with or without reimbursement, as may be agreed to by that agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may accept and use donations of money, property, personal services, or facilities for the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–234, title I, § 112(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 200104.</num>
<heading> Federal interagency council on outdoor recreation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish an interagency council, to be known as the “Federal Interagency Council on Outdoor Recreation”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Composition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall be composed of representatives of each of the following agencies, to be appointed by the head of the respective agency:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The National Park Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Land Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Indian Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Reclamation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Forest Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Army Corps of Engineers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional participants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the members of the Council appointed under paragraph (1), the Secretary may invite participation in the Council’s meetings or other activities from representatives of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Council on Environmental Quality.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Natural Resources Conservation Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Rural development programs of the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Department of Transportation, including the Federal Highway Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Tennessee Valley Authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> The Department of Commerce, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Economic Analysis;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the National Travel and Tourism Office; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Economic Development Administration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> An applicable State agency or office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> An applicable agency or office of a local government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Other organizations or interests, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In determining additional participants under this subsection, the Secretary shall seek to ensure that States are invited and represented in the Council’s meetings or other activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leadership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The leadership of the Council shall rotate every 2 years among the Council members appointed under paragraph (1), or as otherwise determined by the Secretary in consultation with the Secretaries of Agriculture, Defense, and Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding section 708 of title VII of division E of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<ref>Public Law 117–328</ref>), the Council members appointed under paragraph (1) may enter into agreements to share the management and operational costs of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall meet as frequently as appropriate for the purposes of coordinating on issues related to outdoor recreation, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> recreation programs and management policies across Federal land and water management agencies, including activities associated with the implementation of the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 6801</ref> et seq.), as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the response by Federal land and water management agencies to public health emergencies or other emergencies, including those that result in disruptions to, or closures of, Federal recreational lands and waters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> investments relating to outdoor recreation on Federal recreational lands and waters, including funds made available under section 40804(b)(7) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 6592a(b)(7)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> management of emerging technologies on Federal recreational lands and waters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> research activities, including quantifying the economic impacts of recreation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> dissemination to the public of recreation-related information, in a manner that ensures the recreation-related information is easily accessible with modern communication devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the improvement of access to Federal recreational lands and waters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> the identification and engagement of partners outside the Federal Government—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to promote outdoor recreation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to facilitate collaborative management of outdoor recreation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to provide additional resources relating to enhancing outdoor recreation opportunities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> any other outdoor recreation-related issues that the Council determines necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section affects the authorities, regulations, or policies of any Federal agency described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3171</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–234, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>