<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1013—</num>
<heading>EMPLOYEES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101301.</num>
<heading> Maintenance management system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Service shall implement a maintenance management system in the maintenance and operations programs of the System. The system shall include the following elements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A workload inventory of assets including detailed information that quantifies for all assets (including buildings, roads, utility systems, and grounds that must be maintained) the characteristics affecting the type of maintenance work performed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A set of maintenance tasks that describe the maintenance work in each System unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A description of work standards including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> frequency of maintenance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> measurable quality standard to which assets should be maintained;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> methods for accomplishing work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> required labor, equipment, and material resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> expected worker production for each maintenance task.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A work program and performance budget that develops an annual work plan identifying maintenance needs and financial resources to be devoted to each maintenance task.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A work schedule that identifies and prioritizes tasks to be done in a specific time period and specifies required labor resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Work orders specifying job authorizations and a record of work accomplished that can be used to record actual labor and material costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Reports and special analyses that compare planned versus actual accomplishments and costs and that can be used to evaluate maintenance operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101302.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary to carry out certain activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To facilitate the administration of the System, the Secretary, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may consider advisable, may carry out the activities described in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may provide transportation of employees located at an isolated area of the System and to members of their families, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the area is not adequately served by commercial transportation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the transportation is incidental to official transportation services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recreation Facilities, Equipment, and Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide recreation facilities, equipment, and services for use by employees and their families located at an isolated area of the System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Field and Special Purpose Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may purchase field and special purpose equipment required by employees for the performance of assigned functions. The purchased equipment shall be regarded and listed as System equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meals and Lodging</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide meals and lodging, as the Secretary considers appropriate, for members of the United States Park Police and other employees of the Service, as the Secretary may designate, serving temporarily on extended special duty in System units. For this purpose the Secretary may use funds appropriated for the expenses of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101303.</num>
<heading> Medical attention for employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the administration of the Service, the Secretary may contract for medical attention and service for employees and to make necessary payroll deductions agreed to by the employees for that medical attention and service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employees Located at Isolated Situations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may provide, out of amounts appropriated for the general expense of the System units, medical attention for employees of the Service located at isolated situations, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> moving the employees to hospitals or other places where medical assistance is available; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in case of death, to remove the bodies of deceased employees to the nearest place where they can be prepared for shipment or for burial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101304.</num>
<heading> Personal equipment and property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purchase of Personal Equipment and Supplies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may purchase personal equipment and supplies for employees of the Service and make deductions for the equipment and supplies from amounts appropriated for salary payments or otherwise due the employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lost, Damaged, or Destroyed Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in the administration of the Service, may reimburse employees and other owners of horses, vehicles, and other equipment lost, damaged, or destroyed while in the custody of the employee or the Department of the Interior, under authorization, contract, or loan, for necessary firefighting, trail, or other official business. Reimbursement shall be made from any available funds in the appropriation to which the hire of the equipment would be properly chargeable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equipment Required To Be Furnished by Field Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require field employees of the Service to furnish horses, motor and other vehicles, and miscellaneous equipment necessary for the performance of their official work; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide, at Federal Government expense, forage, care, and housing for animals, and housing or storage and fuel for vehicles and other equipment required to be furnished.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hire, Rental, and Purchase of Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, under regulations the Secretary may prescribe, may authorize the hire, rental, or purchase of property from employees of the Service whenever it would promote the public interest to do so.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101305.</num>
<heading> Travel expenses of System employees and dependents of deceased employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the administration of the System, the Secretary may, under regulations the Secretary may prescribe, pay the travel expenses (including the costs of packing, crating, and transporting (including draying) personal property) of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employees, on permanent change of station of the employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> dependents of deceased employees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the nearest housing reasonably available that is of a standard not less than that which is vacated, including compensation for not to exceed 60 days rental cost, in the case of an employee who occupied Federal Government housing and whose death requires the housing to be promptly vacated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the nearest port of entry in the conterminous 48 States in the case of an employee whose last permanent station was outside the conterminous 48 States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>SERVICE CAREER DEVELOPMENT, TRAINING, AND MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101321.</num>
<heading> Service employee training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall develop a comprehensive training program for employees in all professional careers in the workforce of the Service for the purpose of ensuring that the workforce has available the best up-to-date knowledge, skills, and abilities with which to manage, interpret, and protect the resources of the System.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101322.</num>
<heading> Management development and training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain a clear plan for management training and development under which career professional Service employees from any appropriate academic field may obtain sufficient training, experience, and advancement opportunity to enable those qualified to move into System unit management positions, including the position of superintendent of a System unit.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>HOUSING IMPROVEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101331.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Field employee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “field employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee of the Service who is exclusively assigned by the Service to perform duties at a field unit, and the members of the employee’s family; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other individual who is authorized to occupy Federal Government quarters under <ref>section 5911 of title 5</ref>, and for whom there is no feasible alternative to the provision of Federal Government housing, and the members of the individual’s family.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Primary resource values</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “primary resource values” means resources that are specifically mentioned in the enabling legislation for that field unit or other resource value recognized under Federal statute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “quarters” means quarters owned or leased by the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seasonal quarters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “seasonal quarters” means quarters typically occupied by field employees who are hired on assignments of 6 months or less.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101332.</num>
<heading> General authority of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rental Housing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To enhance the ability of the Secretary, acting through the Director, to effectively manage System units, the Secretary may where necessary and justified—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make available employee housing, on or off land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> rent that housing to field employees at rates based on the reasonable value of the housing in accordance with requirements applicable under <ref>section 5911 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Development Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use authorities granted by statute in combination with one another in the furtherance of providing where necessary and justified affordable field employee housing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction Limitations on Federal Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not utilize any land for the purposes of providing field employee housing under this subchapter that will affect a primary resource value of the area or adversely affect the mission of the Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rental Rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall establish rental rates for all quarters occupied by field employees of the Service that are based on the reasonable value of the quarters in accordance with requirements applicable under <ref>section 5911 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101333.</num>
<heading> Criteria for providing housing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain criteria under which housing is provided to employees of the Service. The Secretary shall examine the criteria with respect to the circumstances under which the Service requires an employee to occupy Federal Government quarters, so as to provide necessary services or protect Federal Government property or because of a lack of availability of non-Federal housing in a geographic area.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101334.</num>
<heading> Authorization for housing agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, pursuant to the authorities contained in this subchapter and subject to the appropriation of necessary funds in advance, enter into housing agreements with housing entities under which the housing entities may develop, construct, rehabilitate, or manage housing, located on or off public land, for rent to Service employees who meet the housing eligibility criteria developed by the Secretary pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101335.</num>
<heading> Housing programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Joint Public-Private Sector Housing Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lease-to-build program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the appropriation of necessary funds in advance, the Secretary may lease—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Federal land and interests in land to qualified persons for the construction of field employee quarters for any period not to exceed 50 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> developed and undeveloped non-Federal land for providing field employee quarters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive leasing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each lease under paragraph (1)(A) shall be awarded through the use of publicly advertised, competitively bid, or competitively negotiated contracting procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each lease under paragraph (1)(A)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall stipulate whether operation and maintenance of field employee quarters is to be provided by the lessee, field employees, or the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall require that the construction and rehabilitation of field employee quarters be done in accordance with the requirements of the Service and local applicable building codes and industry standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall contain additional terms and conditions as may be appropriate to protect the Federal interest, including limits on rents that the lessee may charge field employees for the occupancy of quarters, conditions on maintenance and repairs, and agreements on the provision of charges for utilities and other infrastructure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> may be granted at less than fair market value if the Secretary determines that the lease will improve the quality and availability of field employee quarters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contributions by federal government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may make payments, subject to appropriations, or contributions in kind, in advance or on a continuing basis, to reduce the costs of planning, construction, or rehabilitation of quarters on or off Federal land under a lease under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Rental Guarantee Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the appropriation of necessary funds in advance, the Secretary may enter into a lease-to-build arrangement as set forth in subsection (a) with further agreement to guarantee the occupancy of field employee quarters constructed or rehabilitated under the lease. A guarantee made under this paragraph shall be in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on guarantees.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specific guarantees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not guarantee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the occupancy of more than 75 percent of the units constructed or rehabilitated under the lease; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at a rental rate that exceeds the rate based on the reasonable value of the housing in accordance with requirements applicable under <ref>section 5911 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Total of outstanding guarantees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Outstanding guarantees shall not be in excess of $3,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement to rent to federal government employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A guarantee may be made under this subsection only if the lessee agrees to permit the Secretary to utilize for housing purposes any units for which the guarantee is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation and maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A lease shall be void if the lessee fails to maintain a satisfactory level of operation and maintenance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101336.</num>
<heading> Contracts for the management of field employee quarters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the appropriation of necessary funds in advance, the Secretary may enter into contracts of any duration for the management, repair, and maintenance of field employee quarters. The contract shall contain terms and conditions that the Secretary considers necessary or appropriate to protect the interests of the United States and ensure that necessary quarters are available to field employees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101337.</num>
<heading> Leasing of seasonal employee quarters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may lease quarters at or near a System unit for use as seasonal quarters for field employees if the Secretary finds that there is a shortage of adequate and affordable seasonal quarters at or near the System unit and that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the requirement for the seasonal field employee quarters is temporary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> leasing would be more cost-effective than construction of new seasonal field employee quarters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The rent charged to field employees under the lease shall be a rate based on the reasonable value of the quarters in accordance with requirements applicable under <ref>section 5911 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unrecovered Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may pay the unrecovered costs of leasing seasonal quarters under this section from annual appropriations for the year in which the lease is made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101338.</num>
<heading> General leasing provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption From Leasing Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 102901 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 1302 of title 40</ref> shall not apply to leases issued by the Secretary under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proceeds From Leases</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The proceeds from any lease under <ref>section 101335(a)(1) of this title</ref> and any lease under <ref>section 101337 of this title</ref> shall be retained by the Service and deposited in the special fund established for maintenance and operation of quarters.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101339.</num>
<heading> Assessment and priority listing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> complete a condition assessment for all field employee housing, including the physical condition of the housing and the necessity and suitability of the housing for carrying out the mission of the Service, using existing information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop a Service-wide priority listing, by structure, identifying the units in greatest need for repair, rehabilitation, replacement, or initial construction.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3129</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101340.</num>
<heading> Use of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenditure Shall Follow Priority Listing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Expenditure of any funds authorized and appropriated for new construction, repair, or rehabilitation of housing under this chapter shall follow the housing priority listing established by the Secretary under <ref>section 101339 of this title</ref>, in sequential order, to the maximum extent practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonconstruction Funds in Annual Budget Submittal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each fiscal year the President’s proposed budget to Congress shall include identification of nonconstruction funds to be spent for Service housing maintenance and operations that are in addition to rental receipts collected.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3129</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>