<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1021—</num>
<heading>PRIVILEGES AND LEASES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 102101.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No lease or grant of a privilege that interferes with free access</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No natural curiosity, wonder, or object of interest shall be leased or granted to anyone on such terms as to interfere with free access by the public to any System unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for grazing livestock</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, under such regulations and on such terms as the Secretary may prescribe, may grant the privilege to graze livestock within a System unit when, in the Secretary’s judgment, the use is not detrimental to the primary purpose for which the System unit was created. This paragraph does not apply to Yellowstone National Park.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advertising and Competitive Bids Not Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may grant privileges and enter into leases described in subsection (a), and enter into related contracts with responsible persons, firms, or corporations, without advertising and without securing competitive bids.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment or Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No contract, lease, or privilege described in subsection (a) or (b) that is entered into or granted shall be assigned or transferred by the grantee, lessee, or licensee without the prior written approval of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102102.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary to enter into lease for buildings and associated property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To facilitate the administration of the System, the Secretary, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may consider advisable, and except as provided in subsection (b) and subject to subsection (c), may enter into a lease with any person or government entity for the use of buildings and associated property administered by the Secretary as part of the System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not use a lease under subsection (a) to authorize the lessee to engage in activities that are subject to authorization by the Secretary through a concession contract, commercial use authorization, or similar instrument.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Buildings and associated property leased under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be used for an activity that is consistent with the purposes established by law for the System unit in which the building is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall not result in degradation of the purposes and values of the System unit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be compatible with Service programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Rental Amounts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to a lease under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> payment of fair market value rental shall be required; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 1302 of title 40</ref> shall not apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adjustment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may adjust the rental amount as appropriate to take into account any amounts to be expended by the lessee for preservation, maintenance, restoration, improvement, or repair and related expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Account.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Rental payments under a lease under subsection (a) shall be deposited in a special account in the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts in the special account shall be available until expended, without further appropriation, for infrastructure needs at System units, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> facility refurbishment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> repair and replacement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> infrastructure projects associated with System unit resource protection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> direct maintenance of the leased buildings and associated property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accountability and results</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall develop procedures for the use of the special account that ensure accountability and demonstrated results consistent with this section and sections 100101(b), 100502, 100507, 100751(b), 100754, 100901(b) and (c), 100906(a) and (d), 101302(b)(1) and (c) to (e), 101306, 101702(b) and (c), 101901, 102701, and 102702 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations implementing this section that include provisions to encourage and facilitate competition in the leasing process and provide for timely and adequate public comment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>