<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1031—</num>
<heading>APPROPRIATIONS AND ACCOUNTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 103101.</num>
<heading> Availability and use of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credits of Receipts for Meals and Quarters Furnished Federal Government Employees in the Field</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Cash collections and payroll deductions made for meals and quarters furnished by the Service to employees of the Federal Government in the field and to cooperating agencies may be credited as a reimbursement to the current appropriation for the administration of the System unit in which the accommodations are furnished.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability for Expense of Recording Donated Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Appropriations made for the Service shall be available for any expenses incident to the preparation and recording of title evidence covering land to be donated to the United States for administration by the Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds for Law Enforcement and Emergencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds, not to exceed $250,000 per incident, available to the Service may be used, with the approval of the Secretary, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maintain law and order in emergency and other unforeseen law enforcement situations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct emergency search and rescue operations in the System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Replenishment of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary expends funds under paragraph (1), the funds shall be replenished by a supplemental appropriation for which the Secretary shall make a request as promptly as possible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contribution for Annuity Benefits.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Necessary amounts are appropriated for reimbursement, pursuant to the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act amendments of 1957 (<ref>Public Law 85–157</ref>, <ref>71 Stat. 391</ref>), to the District of Columbia on a monthly basis for benefit payments by the District of Columbia to United States Park Police annuitants under section 12 of the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act (ch. 433, <ref>39 Stat. 718</ref>), to the extent that those payments exceed contributions made by active Park Police members covered under the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonavailability of appropriations to the service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Appropriations made to the Service are not available for the purpose of making reimbursements under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waterproof Footwear</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Appropriations for the Service that are available for the purchase of equipment may be used for purchase of waterproof footwear, which shall be regarded and listed as System equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103102.</num>
<heading> Appropriations authorized and available for certain purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Appropriations for the Service are authorized and are available for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administration, protection, improvement, and maintenance of areas, under the jurisdiction of other Federal agencies, that are devoted to recreational use pursuant to cooperative agreements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> necessary local transportation and subsistence in kind of individuals selected for employment or as cooperators, serving without other compensation, while attending fire protection training camps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> administration, protection, maintenance, and improvement of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> educational lectures in or in the vicinity of and with respect to System units, and services of field employees in cooperation with such nonprofit scientific and historical societies engaged in educational work in System units as the Secretary may designate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> travel expenses of employees attending—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Federal Government camps for training in forest fire prevention and suppression;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation National Police Academy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Federal, State, or municipal schools for training in building fire prevention and suppression;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> investigation and establishment of water rights in accordance with local custom, laws, and decisions of courts, including the acquisition of water rights or of land or interests in land or rights-of-way for use and protection of water rights necessary or beneficial in the administration and public use of System units;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> official telephone service in the field in the case of official telephones installed in private houses when authorized under regulations established by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> provision of transportation for children in nearby communities to and from any System unit used in connection with organized recreation and interpretive programs of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3164</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103103.</num>
<heading> Amounts provided by private entities for utility services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts provided to the Service by private entities for utility services shall be credited to the appropriate account and remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103104.</num>
<heading> Recovery of costs associated with special use permits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Service may recover all costs of providing necessary services associated with special use permits. The reimbursements shall be credited to the appropriation current at that time.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>