<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3053—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL CENTER FOR PRESERVATION TECHNOLOGY AND TRAINING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 305301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Board” means the Preservation Technology and Training Board established pursuant to <ref>section 305303 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Center</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Center” means the National Center for Preservation Technology and Training established pursuant to <ref>section 305302 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305302.</num>
<heading> National Center for Preservation Technology and Training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established within the Department of the Interior a National Center for Preservation Technology and Training. The Center shall be located at Northwestern State University of Louisiana in Natchitoches, Louisiana.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of the Center shall be to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and distribute preservation and conservation skills and technologies for the identification, evaluation, conservation, and interpretation of historic property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop and facilitate training for Federal, State, and local resource preservation professionals, cultural resource managers, maintenance personnel, and others working in the preservation field;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> take steps to apply preservation technology benefits from ongoing research by other agencies and institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> facilitate the transfer of preservation technology among Federal agencies, State and local governments, universities, international organizations, and the private sector; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> cooperate with related international organizations including the International Council on Monuments and Sites, the International Center for the Study of Preservation and Restoration of Cultural Property, and the International Council on Museums.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purposes shall be carried out through research, professional training, technical assistance, and programs for public awareness, and through a program of grants established under <ref>section 305304 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Center shall be headed by an Executive Director with demonstrated expertise in historic preservation appointed by the Secretary with advice of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance From Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall provide the Center assistance in obtaining such personnel, equipment, and facilities as may be needed by the Center to carry out its activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305303.</num>
<heading> Preservation Technology and Training Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established a Preservation Technology and Training Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide leadership, policy advice, and professional oversight to the Center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise the Secretary on priorities and the allocation of grants among the activities of the Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> submit an annual report to the President and Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall be comprised of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 6 members appointed by the Secretary, who shall represent appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies, State and local historic preservation commissions, and other public and international organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 6 members appointed by the Secretary on the basis of outstanding professional qualifications, who represent major organizations in the fields of archeology, architecture, conservation, curation, engineering, history, historic preservation, landscape architecture, planning, or preservation education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305304.</num>
<heading> Preservation grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in consultation with the Board, shall provide preservation technology and training grants to eligible applicants with a demonstrated institutional capability and commitment to the purposes of the Center, in order to ensure an effective and efficient system of research, information distribution, and skills training in all the related historic preservation fields.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grant Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Grants provided under this section shall be allocated in such a fashion as to reflect the diversity of the historic preservation fields and shall be geographically distributed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limit on amount a recipient may receive</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No grant recipient may receive more than 10 percent of the grants allocated under this section within any year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limit on administrative costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total administrative costs, direct and indirect, charged for carrying out grants under this section may not exceed 25 percent of the aggregate costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Applicants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Eligible applicants may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Federal and non-Federal laboratories;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accredited museums;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> universities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> nonprofit organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> System units and offices and Cooperative Park Study Units of the System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> State Historic Preservation Offices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> tribal preservation offices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Native Hawaiian organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards and Methods</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Grants shall be awarded in accordance with accepted professional standards and methods, including peer review of projects.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305305.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Grants and Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Center may accept—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> grants and donations from private individuals, groups, organizations, corporations, foundations, and other entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfers of funds from other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts and Cooperative Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to appropriations, the Center may enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with Federal, State, local, and tribal governments, Native Hawaiian organizations, educational institutions, and other public entities to carry out the Center’s responsibilities under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds appropriated for the Center shall be in addition to funds appropriated for Service programs, centers, and offices in existence on <date date="1992-10-30">October 30, 1992</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 305306.</num>
<heading> Service preservation centers and offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To improve the use of existing Service resources, the Secretary shall fully utilize and further develop the Service preservation (including conservation) centers and regional offices. The Secretary shall improve the coordination of the centers and offices within the Service, and shall, where appropriate, coordinate their activities with the Center and with other appropriate parties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>