<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3086—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES AFRICAN-AMERICAN BURIAL GROUNDS PRESERVATION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 308601.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Burial ground</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “burial ground” means any natural or prepared physical location, whether originally below, on, or above the surface of the earth, into which human remains are deposited as a part of the death rite or ceremony of a culture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Historic</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “historic”, with respect to a property, means a property that can reasonably be considered to date back at least 50 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Program” means the United States African-American Burial Grounds Preservation Program established under section 308602(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. DD, title VI, § 643(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308602.</num>
<heading> United States African-American Burial Grounds Preservation Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish within the Service, in accordance with this chapter, a program to be known as the “United States African-American Burial Grounds Preservation Program”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary, in consultation with the National Trust for Historic Preservation and members of the African-American heritage community, shall develop a program for the provision of grants in accordance with section 308603(a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may accept monetary donations to further the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consent of Private Property Owner Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Burial grounds shall only be considered for a grant under the Program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with the consent of the property owner; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at the request of an individual, landowner, private or nonprofit organization, State, Tribal, or local government, or other entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. DD, title VI, § 643(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308603.</num>
<heading> Authority to make grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may make grants to other Federal agencies, State, local, and Tribal governments, other public entities, educational institutions, historic preservation groups, and private nonprofit organizations in accordance with this chapter for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the identification of historic African-American burial grounds that may qualify for the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the preservation and restoration of African-American burial grounds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the interpretation of African-American burial grounds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> related research and documentation for historic African-American burial grounds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Funding.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any amounts made available for a fiscal year under paragraph (1) that are not used during that fiscal year shall be available for use under this section during any subsequent fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. DD, title VI, § 643(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308604.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding with, and provide technical assistance to, the heads of other Federal agencies, States, units of local government, Tribal governments, regional governmental bodies, nonprofit organizations, educational institutions, and private entities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to achieve the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to ensure effective coordination of the Federal elements and non-Federal elements provided a grant or other assistance under the Program with System units and programs of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. DD, title VI, § 643(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308605.</num>
<heading> Private property protection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> authorizes the Secretary to require or affect the management or use of private property without the written consent of the owner of the private property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prohibits the Secretary from providing land management guidance or requirements relating to private property as a condition of a grant provided to the owner of the private property under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be construed as creating any new regulatory burden on any Federal, State, Tribal, or private entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. DD, title VI, § 643(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>