<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3125—</num>
<heading>PRESERVATION OF HISTORICAL AND ARCHEOLOGICAL DATA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 312501.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “State” includes a State, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312502.</num>
<heading> Threat of irreparable loss or destruction of significant scientific, prehistorical, historical, or archeological data by Federal construction projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Activity of Federal Agency.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When any Federal agency finds, or is notified, in writing, by an appropriate historical or archeological authority, that its activities in connection with any Federal construction project or federally licensed project, activity, or program may cause irreparable loss or destruction of significant scientific, prehistorical, historical, or archeological data, the agency shall notify the Secretary, in writing, and shall provide the Secretary with appropriate information concerning the project, program, or activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recovery, protection, and preservation of data</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may request the Secretary to undertake the recovery, protection, and preservation of the data (including preliminary survey, or other investigation as needed, and analysis and publication of the reports resulting from the investigation); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may, with funds appropriated for the project, program, or activity, undertake those activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Copies of reports of any investigations made pursuant to this section shall be submitted to the Secretary, who shall make them available to the public for inspection and review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Activity of Private Person, Association, or Public Entity.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recovery by secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When any Federal agency provides financial assistance by loan, grant, or otherwise to any private person, association, or public entity, the Secretary, if the Secretary determines that significant scientific, prehistorical, historical, or archeological data might be irrevocably lost or destroyed, may, with funds appropriated expressly for this purpose—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct, with the consent of all persons, associations, or public entities having a legal interest in the property, a survey of the affected site; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> undertake the recovery, protection, and preservation of the data (including analysis and publication).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall, unless otherwise agreed to in writing, compensate any person, association, or public entity damaged as a result of delays in construction or as a result of the temporary loss of the use of private or any nonfederally owned land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312503.</num>
<heading> Survey and recovery by Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary, on notification, in writing, by any Federal or State agency or appropriate historical or archeological authority that scientific, prehistorical, historical, or archeological data are being or may be irrevocably lost or destroyed by any Federal or federally assisted or licensed project, activity, or program, shall, if the Secretary determines that the data are significant and are being or may be irrevocably lost or destroyed and after reasonable notice to the agency responsible for funding or licensing the project, activity, or program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct or cause to be conducted a survey and other investigation of the areas that are or may be affected; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recover and preserve the data (including analysis and publication) that, in the opinion of the Secretary, are not being, but should be, recovered and preserved in the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When Survey or Recovery Not Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No survey or recovery work shall be required pursuant to this section that, in the determination of the head of the responsible agency, would impede Federal or federally assisted or licensed projects or activities undertaken in connection with any emergency, including projects or activities undertaken in anticipation of, or as a result of, a natural disaster.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initiation of Survey</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall initiate the survey or recovery effort within—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 60 days after notification pursuant to subsection (a); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such time as may be agreed on with the head of the agency responsible for funding or licensing the project, activity, or program in all other cases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation by Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall, unless otherwise agreed to in writing, compensate any person, association, or public entity damaged as a result of delays in construction or as a result of the temporary loss of the use of private or nonfederally owned land.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312504.</num>
<heading> Progress reports by Secretary on surveys and work undertaken as result of surveys</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Progress Reports to Funding or Licensing Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall keep the agency responsible for funding or licensing the project notified at all times of the progress of any survey made under this chapter or of any work undertaken as a result of a survey, in order that there will be as little disruption or delay as possible in the carrying out of the functions of the agency. The survey and recovery programs shall terminate at a time agreed on by the Secretary and the head of the agency unless extended by agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposition of Relics and Specimens</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult with any interested Federal and State agencies, educational and scientific organizations, private institutions, and qualified individuals, with a view to determining the ownership of, and the most appropriate repository for, any relics and specimens recovered as a result of any work performed as provided for in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination of Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall coordinate all Federal survey and recovery activities authorized under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312505.</num>
<heading> Notice of dam construction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before any Federal agency undertakes the construction of a dam, or issues a license to any private individual or corporation for the construction of a dam, it shall give written notice to the Secretary setting forth the site of the proposed dam and the approximate area to be flooded and otherwise changed if construction is undertaken.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dams With Certain Detention Capacity or Reservoir</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to any flood water retarding dam that provides fewer than 5,000 acre-feet of detention capacity, and with respect to any other type of dam that creates a reservoir of fewer than 40 surface acres, this section shall apply only when the constructing agency, in its preliminary surveys, finds or is presented with evidence that historical or archeological materials exist or may be present in the proposed reservoir area.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312506.</num>
<heading> Administration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the administration of this chapter, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into contracts or make cooperative agreements with any Federal or State agency, educational or scientific organization, or institution, corporation, association, or qualified individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtain the services of experts and consultants or organizations of experts and consultants in accordance with <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> accept and utilize funds made available for salvage archeological purposes by any private person or corporation or transferred to the Secretary by any Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312507.</num>
<heading> Assistance to Secretary by Federal agencies responsible for construction projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance of Federal Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out this chapter, any Federal agency responsible for a construction project may assist the Secretary or may transfer to the Secretary funds as may be agreed on, but not more than 1 percent of the total amount authorized to be appropriated for the project, except that the 1 percent limitation under this section shall not apply if the cost of the project is $50,000 or less. The costs of the survey, recovery, analysis, and publication shall be deemed nonreimbursable project costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated for purposes of this section shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312508.</num>
<heading> Costs for identification, surveys, evaluation, and data recovery with respect to historic property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 312507(a) of this title</ref> or any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identification, surveys, and evaluation carried out with respect to historic property within project areas may be treated for purposes of any law or rule of law as planning costs of the project and not as costs of mitigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reasonable costs for identification, surveys, evaluation, and data recovery carried out with respect to historic property within project areas may be charged to Federal licensees and permittees as a condition to the issuance of the license or permit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Federal agencies, with the concurrence of the Secretary and after notification of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, may waive, in appropriate cases, the 1 percent limitation under <ref>section 312507(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>