<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1005—</num>
<heading>AREAS OF NATIONAL PARK SYSTEM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 100501.</num>
<heading> Areas included in System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The System shall include any area of land and water administered by the Secretary, acting through the Director, for park, monument, historic, parkway, recreational, or other purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100502.</num>
<heading> General management plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">General management plans for the preservation and use of each System unit, including areas within the national capital area, shall be prepared and revised in a timely manner by the Director. On January 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a list indicating the current status of completion or revision of general management plans for each System unit. General management plans for each System unit shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> measures for the preservation of the area’s resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> indications of types and general intensities of development (including visitor circulation and transportation patterns, systems, and modes) associated with public enjoyment and use of the area, including general locations, timing of implementation, and anticipated costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identification of and implementation commitments for visitor carrying capacities for all areas of the System unit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> indications of potential modifications to the external boundaries of the System unit, and the reasons for the modifications.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100503.</num>
<heading> Five-year strategic plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Strategic and Performance Plans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each System unit shall prepare and make available to the public a 5-year strategic plan and an annual performance plan. The plans shall reflect the Service policies, goals, and outcomes represented in the Service-wide strategic plan prepared pursuant to <ref>section 306 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Budget.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a part of the annual performance plan for a System unit prepared pursuant to subsection (a), following receipt of the appropriation for the unit from the Operations of the National Park System account (but not later than January 1 of each year), the superintendent of the System unit shall develop and make available to the public the budget for the current fiscal year for that System unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The budget shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> funding allocations for resource preservation (including resource management), visitor services (including maintenance, interpretation, law enforcement, and search and rescue), and administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> allocations into each of the categories in subparagraph (A) of all funds retained from fees collected for that year, including special use permits, concession franchise fees, and recreation use and entrance fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100504.</num>
<heading> Study and planning of park, parkway, and recreational-area facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall cause the Service to make a comprehensive study, other than on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, of the public park, parkway, and recreational area programs of the United States, States, and political subdivisions of States and of areas of land throughout the United States that are or may be chiefly valuable as public park, parkway, or recreational areas. A study shall not be made in any State without the consent and approval of the State officials, boards, or departments having jurisdiction over the land. The study shall be such as, in the judgment of the Secretary, will provide data helpful in developing a plan for coordinated and adequate public park, parkway, and recreational-area facilities for the people of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperation and agreements with other entities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In making the study and to accomplish the purposes of this section, the Secretary, acting through the Director—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall seek and accept the cooperation and assistance of Federal departments or agencies having jurisdiction of land belonging to the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may cooperate and make agreements with and seek and accept the assistance of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> other Federal agencies and instrumentalities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> States, political subdivisions of States, and agencies and instrumentalities of either of them.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State planning</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purpose of developing coordinated and adequate public park, parkway, and recreational-area facilities for the people of the United States, the Secretary may aid States and political subdivisions of States in planning public park, parkway, and recreational areas and in cooperating with one another to accomplish these ends. Aid shall be made available through the Service acting in cooperation with such State agencies or agencies of political subdivisions of States as the Secretary considers best.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consent of Congress to Agreements Between States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The consent of Congress is given to any 2 or more States to negotiate and enter into compacts or agreements with one another with reference to planning, establishing, developing, improving, and maintaining any park, parkway, or recreational area. No compact or agreement shall be effective until approved by the legislatures of the States that are parties to the compact or agreement and by Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3099</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100505.</num>
<heading> Periodic review of System</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary To Conduct Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall conduct a systematic and comprehensive review of certain aspects of the System and on a periodic basis (but not less often than every 3 years) submit to the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report on the findings of the review, together with recommendations as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In conducting and preparing the report, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate officials of affected Federal, State, and local agencies and national, regional, and local organizations. The consultation shall include holding public hearings that the Secretary determines to be appropriate to provide a full opportunity for public comment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents of report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report shall contain the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A comprehensive listing of all authorized but unacquired parcels of land within the exterior boundaries of each System unit as of <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A priority listing of all those unacquired parcels by System unit and for the System as a whole. The list shall describe the acreage and ownership of each parcel, the estimated cost of acquisition for each parcel (subject to any statutory acquisition limitations for the land), and the basis for the estimate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An analysis and evaluation of the current and future needs of each System unit for resource management, interpretation, construction, operation and maintenance, personnel, and housing, together with an estimate of the costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3099</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100506.</num>
<heading> Boundary changes to System units</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall maintain criteria to evaluate any proposed changes to the boundaries of System units, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> analysis of whether or not an existing boundary provides for the adequate protection and preservation of the natural, historic, cultural, scenic and recreational resources integral to the System unit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an evaluation of each parcel proposed for addition or deletion to a System unit based on the analysis under paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an assessment of the impact of potential boundary adjustments taking into consideration the factors in <ref>section 100505(c)(3) of this title</ref> and the effect of the adjustments on the local communities and surrounding area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proposal of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In proposing a boundary change to a System unit, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult with affected agencies of State and local governments, surrounding communities, affected landowners, and private national, regional, and local organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> apply the criteria developed pursuant to subsection (a) and accompany the proposal with a statement reflecting the results of the application of the criteria; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include with the proposal an estimate of the cost for acquiring any parcels proposed for acquisition, the basis for the estimate, and a statement on the relative priority for the acquisition of each parcel within the priorities for acquisition of other parcels for the System unit and for the System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Minor Boundary Changes.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When the Secretary determines that to do so will contribute to, and is necessary for, the proper preservation, protection, interpretation, or management of a System unit, the Secretary may, following timely notice in writing to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate of the Secretary’s intention to do so, and by publication of a revised boundary map or other description in the Federal Register—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make minor changes to the boundary of the System unit, and amounts appropriated from the Fund shall be available for acquisition of any land, water, and interests in land or water added to the System unit by the boundary change subject to such statutory limitations, if any, on methods of acquisition and appropriations thereof as may be specifically applicable to the System unit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> acquire by donation, purchase with donated funds, transfer from any other Federal agency, or exchange, land, water, or interests in land or water adjacent to the System unit, except that in exercising the Secretary’s authority under this subparagraph the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not alienate property administered as part of the System to acquire land by exchange;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not acquire property without the consent of the owner; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> may acquire property owned by a State or political subdivision of a State only by donation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prior to making a determination under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with the governing body of the county, city, town, or other jurisdiction or jurisdictions having primary taxing authority over the land or interest to be acquired as to the impacts of the proposed action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action to advance local public awareness</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall take such steps as the Secretary considers appropriate to advance local public awareness of the proposed action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of acquisitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Land, water, and interests in land or water acquired in accordance with this subsection shall be administered as part of the System unit to which they are added, subject to the laws and regulations applicable to the System unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When authority applies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of paragraph (1)(A), in all cases except the case of technical boundary changes (resulting from such causes as survey error or changed road alignments), the authority of the Secretary under paragraph (1)(A) shall apply only if each of the following conditions is met:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The sum of the total acreage of the land, water, and interests in land or water to be added to the System unit and the total acreage of the land, water, and interests in land or water to be deleted from the System unit is not more than 5 percent of the total Federal acreage authorized to be included in the System unit and is less than 200 acres.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The acquisition, if any, is not a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The sum of the total appraised value of the land, water, and interests in land or water to be added to the System unit and the total appraised value of the land, water, and interests in land or water to be deleted from the System unit does not exceed $750,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The proposed boundary change is not an element of a more comprehensive boundary change proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The proposed boundary has been subject to a public review and comment period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Director obtains written consent for the boundary change from all property owners whose land, water, or interests in land or water, or a portion of whose land, water, or interests in land or water, will be added to or deleted from the System unit by the boundary change.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The land abuts other Federal land administered by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Act of congress required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Minor boundary changes involving only deletions of acreage owned by the Federal Government and administered by the Service may be made only by Act of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100507.</num>
<heading> Additional areas for System</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Monitoring Areas for Inclusion in System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall investigate, study, and continually monitor the welfare of areas whose resources exhibit qualities of national significance and that may have potential for inclusion in the System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Submission of List of Areas Recommended for Study for Potential Inclusion.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When list is to be submitted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the beginning of each calendar year, with the annual budget submission, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a list of areas recommended for study for potential inclusion in the System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors to be considered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In developing the list to be submitted under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the areas that have the greatest potential to meet the established criteria of national significance, suitability, and feasibility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> themes, sites, and resources not already adequately represented in the System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> public petitions and Congressional resolutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accompanying synopsis</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Accompanying the annual listing of areas shall be a synopsis, for each report previously submitted, of the current and changed condition of the resource integrity of the area and other relevant factors, compiled as a result of continual periodic monitoring and embracing the period since the previous submission or initial report submission one year earlier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional authorization required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No study of the potential of an area for inclusion in the System may be initiated except as provided by specific authorization of an Act of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to conduct certain activities not limited</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section and sections 100901(b), 101702(b) and (c), and 102102 of this title do not limit the authority of the Service to conduct preliminary resource assessments, gather data on potential study areas, provide technical and planning assistance, prepare or process nominations for administrative designations, update previous studies, or complete reconnaissance surveys of individual areas requiring a total expenditure of less than $25,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Study of rivers or trails not affected</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to or affect or alter the study of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any river segment for potential addition to the national wild and scenic rivers system; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any trail for potential addition to the national trails system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Study of Areas for Potential Inclusion.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Study to be completed within 3 years</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall complete the study for each area for potential inclusion in the System within 3 complete fiscal years following the date on which funds are first made available for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opportunity for public involvement required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each study under this section shall be prepared with appropriate opportunity for public involvement, including at least one public meeting in the vicinity of the area under study, and after reasonable efforts to notify potentially affected landowners and State and local governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consider whether the area under study—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> possesses nationally significant natural or cultural resources and represents one of the most important examples of a particular resource type in the country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a suitable and feasible addition to the System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of study</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each study—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> with regard to the area being studied, shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the rarity and integrity of the resources;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the threats to those resources;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> whether similar resources are already protected in the System or in other public or private ownership;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the public use potential;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the interpretive and educational potential;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> costs associated with acquisition, development, and operation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the socioeconomic impacts of any designation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> the level of local and general public support; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> whether the area is of appropriate configuration to ensure long-term resource protection and visitor use;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall consider whether direct Service management or alternative protection by other public agencies or the private sector is appropriate for the area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall identify what alternative or combination of alternatives would in the professional judgment of the Director be most effective and efficient in protecting significant resources and providing for public enjoyment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> may include any other information that the Secretary considers to be relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance with national environmental policy act of 1969</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each study shall be completed in compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendation of preferred management option</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The letter transmitting each completed study to Congress shall contain a recommendation regarding the Secretary’s preferred management option for the area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">List of Areas Previously Studied.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of list</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the beginning of each calendar year, with the annual budget submission, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, in numerical order of priority for addition to the System—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of areas that have been previously studied that contain primarily historical resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a list of areas that have been previously studied that contain primarily natural resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In developing the lists, the Secretary should consider threats to resource values, cost escalation factors, and other factors listed in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Areas eligible for inclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary should include on the lists only areas for which the supporting data are current and accurate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">List of Areas That Exhibit Danger or Threats to the Integrity of Their Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the beginning of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate a complete and current list of all areas listed on the Registry of Natural Landmarks, and areas of national significance listed on the National Register of Historic places, that exhibit known or anticipated damage or threats to the integrity of their resources, with notations as to the nature and severity of the damage or threats.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports and Listings Printed as House Documents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report and annual listing described in this section shall be printed as a House document. If adequate supplies of previously printed identical reports remain available, newly submitted identical reports shall be omitted from printing on receipt by the Speaker of the House of Representatives of a joint letter from the chairman of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the chairman of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of Senate indicating that to be the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall designate a single office to prepare all new area studies and to implement other functions under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Studies of potential new system units and monitoring the welfare of system unit resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out studies for potential new System units and for monitoring the welfare of historical and natural resources referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (d)(1), there is authorized to be appropriated not more than $1,000,000 for each fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Monitoring welfare and integrity of national landmarks</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To monitor the welfare and integrity of the national landmarks, there is authorized to be appropriated not more than $1,500,000 for each fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Carrying out subsections</inline> (b), (c), and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> (g).—</heading>
<content>To carry out subsections (b), (c), and (g), there is authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>