<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1019—</num>
<heading>CONCESSIONS AND COMMERCIAL USE AUTHORIZATIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>AUTHORITY OF SECRETARY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101901.</num>
<heading> Utility services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To facilitate the administration of the System, the Secretary, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers advisable, may furnish, on a reimbursement of appropriation basis, all types of utility services to concessioners, contractors, permittees, or other users of the services, within the System. The reimbursements for cost of the services may be credited to the appropriation current at the time reimbursements are received.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COMMERCIAL VISITOR SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101911.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advisory board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Advisory Board” means the National Park Service Concessions Management Advisory Board established under <ref>section 101919 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preferential right of renewal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “preferential right of renewal” means the right of a concessioner, subject to a determination by the Secretary that the facilities or services authorized by a prior contract continue to be necessary and appropriate within the meaning of <ref>section 101912 of this title</ref>, to match the terms and conditions of any competing proposal that the Secretary determines to be the best proposal for a proposed new concession contract that authorizes the continuation of the facilities and services provided by the concessioner under its prior contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3138</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101912.</num>
<heading> Findings and declaration of policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In furtherance of section 100101(a), Congress finds that the preservation and conservation of System unit resources and values requires that public accommodations, facilities, and services that have to be provided within those System units should be provided only under carefully controlled safeguards against unregulated and indiscriminate use, so that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> visitation will not unduly impair those resources and values; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> development of public accommodations, facilities, and services within System units can best be limited to locations that are consistent to the highest practicable degree with the preservation and conservation of the resources and values of the System units.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Declaration of Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It is the policy of Congress that the development of public accommodations, facilities, and services in System units shall be limited to accommodations, facilities, and services that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are necessary and appropriate for public use and enjoyment of the System unit in which they are located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are consistent to the highest practicable degree with the preservation and conservation of the resources and values of the System unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3138</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101913.</num>
<heading> Award of concession contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In furtherance of the findings and policy stated in <ref>section 101912 of this title</ref>, and except as provided by this subchapter or otherwise authorized by law, the Secretary shall utilize concession contracts to authorize a person, corporation, or other entity to provide accommodations, facilities, and services to visitors to System units. Concession contracts shall be awarded as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive selection process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this section, all proposed concession contracts shall be awarded by the Secretary to the person, corporation, or other entity submitting the best proposal, as determined by the Secretary through a competitive selection process. The competitive process shall include simplified procedures for small, individually-owned entities seeking award of a concession contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation of proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as otherwise provided in this section, prior to awarding a new concession contract (including renewals or extensions of existing concession contracts) the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall publicly solicit proposals for the concession contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in connection with the solicitation, shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prepare a prospectus and publish notice of its availability at least once in local or national newspapers or trade publications, by electronic means, or both, as appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> make the prospectus available on request to all interested persons.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information to be included in prospectus</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The prospectus shall include the following information:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The minimum requirements for the contract as set forth in paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The terms and conditions of any existing concession contract relating to the services and facilities to be provided, including all fees and other forms of compensation provided to the United States by the concessioner.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Other authorized facilities or services that may be provided in a proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Facilities and services to be provided by the Secretary to the concessioner, including public access, utilities, and buildings.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An estimate of the amount of compensation due an existing concessioner from a new concessioner under the terms of a prior concession contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A statement as to the weight to be given to each selection factor identified in the prospectus and the relative importance of those factors in the selection process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Other information related to the proposed concession operation that is provided to the Secretary pursuant to a concession contract or is otherwise available to the Secretary, as the Secretary determines is necessary to allow for the submission of competitive proposals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Where applicable, a description of a preferential right to the renewal of the proposed concession contract held by an existing concessioner as set forth in paragraph (7).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consideration of proposals.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No proposal shall be considered that fails to meet the minimum requirements as determined by the Secretary. The minimum requirements shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The minimum acceptable franchise fee or other forms of consideration to the Federal Government.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Any facilities, services, or capital investment required to be provided by the concessioner.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Measures necessary to ensure the protection, conservation, and preservation of resources of the System unit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rejection of proposal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall reject any proposal, regardless of the franchise fee offered, if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the person, corporation, or entity is not qualified or is not likely to provide satisfactory service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the proposal is not responsive to the objectives of protecting and preserving resources of the System unit and of providing necessary and appropriate facilities and services to the public at reasonable rates.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">All proposals fail to meet mimimum</inline> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> <inline class="small-caps">requirements or are rejected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If all proposals submitted to the Secretary fail to meet the minimum requirements or are rejected by the Secretary, the Secretary shall establish new minimum contract requirements and re-initiate the competitive selection process pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and conditions materially amended or not incorporated in contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not execute a concession contract that materially amends or does not incorporate the proposed terms and conditions of the concession contract as set forth in the applicable prospectus. If proposed material amendments or changes are considered appropriate by the Secretary, the Secretary shall resolicit offers for the concession contract incorporating the material amendments or changes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection of the best proposal.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors in selection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In selecting the best proposal, the Secretary shall consider the following principal factors:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The responsiveness of the proposal to the objectives of protecting, conserving, and preserving resources of the System unit and of providing necessary and appropriate facilities and services to the public at reasonable rates.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The experience and related background of the person, corporation, or entity submitting the proposal, including the past performance and expertise of the person, corporation or entity in providing the same or similar facilities or services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The financial capability of the person, corporation, or entity submitting the proposal.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The proposed franchise fee, except that consideration of revenue to the United States shall be subordinate to the objectives of protecting, conserving, and preserving resources of the System unit and of providing necessary and appropriate facilities to the public at reasonable rates.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secondary factors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may also consider such secondary factors as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Development of regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In developing regulations to implement this subchapter, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which plans for employment of Indians (including Native Alaskans) and involvement of businesses owned by Indians, Indian tribes, or Native Alaskans in the operation of a concession contract should be identified as a factor in the selection of a best proposal under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Congressional notification.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall submit any proposed concession contract with anticipated annual gross receipts in excess of $5,000,000 or a duration of more than 10 years to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiting period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall not award any proposed concession contract to which subparagraph (A) applies until at least 60 days subsequent to the notification of both Committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Preferential right of renewal.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall not grant a concessioner a preferential right to renew a concession contract, or any other form of preference to a concession contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall grant a preferential right of renewal to an existing concessioner with respect to proposed renewals of the categories of concession contracts described by paragraph (8), subject to the requirements of that paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entitlement to award of new contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A concessioner that successfully exercises a preferential right of renewal in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter shall be entitled to award of the proposed new concession contract to which the preference applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Outfitter and guide services and small contracts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Paragraph (7) shall apply only to the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), concession contracts that solely authorize the provision of specialized backcountry outdoor recreation guide services that require the employment of specially trained and experienced guides to accompany System unit visitors in the backcountry so as to provide a safe and enjoyable experience for visitors who otherwise may not have the skills and equipment to engage in that activity.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (C), concession contracts with anticipated annual gross receipts under $500,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Outfitting and guide concessioners.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Description</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Outfitting and guide concessioners, where otherwise qualified, include concessioners that provide guided river running, hunting, fishing, horseback, camping, and mountaineering experiences.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When entitled to preferential right</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An outfitting and guide concessioner is entitled to a preferential right of renewal under this subchapter only if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the contract with the outfitting and guide concessioner does not grant the concessioner any interest, including any leasehold surrender interest or possessory interest, in capital improvements on land owned by the United States within a System unit, other than a capital improvement constructed by a concessioner pursuant to the terms of a concession contract prior to <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, or constructed or owned by a concessioner or the concessioner’s predecessor before the subject land was incorporated into the System;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the concessioner has operated satisfactorily during the term of the contract (including any extension); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the concessioner has submitted a responsive proposal for a proposed new concession contract that satisfies the minimum requirements established by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (4).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract with estimated gross receipts of less than $500,000</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A concessioner that holds a concession contract that the Secretary estimates will result in gross annual receipts of less than $500,000 if renewed shall be entitled to a preferential right of renewal under this subchapter if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary has determined that the concessioner has operated satisfactorily during the term of the contract (including any extension); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the concessioner has submitted a responsive proposal for a proposed new concession contract that satisfies the minimum requirements established by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (4).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">New or additional services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may propose to amend the applicable terms of an existing concessions contract to provide new and additional services where the Secretary determines the services are necessary and appropriate for public use and enjoyment of the unit of the National Park System in which they are located and are consistent to the highest practicable degree with the preservation and conservation of the resources and values of the unit. Such new and additional services shall not represent a material change to the required and authorized services as set forth in the applicable prospectus or contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary not limited</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as limiting the authority of the Secretary to determine whether to issue a concession contract or to establish its terms and conditions in furtherance of the policies expressed in this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding this section, the Secretary may award, without public solicitation, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Temporary contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To avoid interruption of services to the public at a System unit, the Secretary may award a temporary concession contract or an extension of an existing concessions contract for a term not to exceed 3 years, except that prior to making the award, the Secretary shall take all reasonable and appropriate steps to consider alternatives to avoid the interruption.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract in extraordinary circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may award a concession contract in extraordinary circumstances where compelling and equitable considerations require the award of a concession contract to a particular party in the public interest. Award of a concession contract under this subparagraph shall not be made by the Secretary until at least 30 days after—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> publication in the Federal Register of notice of the Secretary’s intention to award the contract and the reasons for the action; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> submission of notice to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1490</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101914.</num>
<heading> Term of concession contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A concession contract entered into pursuant to this subchapter shall generally be awarded for a term of 10 years or less. The Secretary may award a contract for a term of up to 20 years if the Secretary determines that the contract terms and conditions, including the required construction of capital improvements, warrant a longer term.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101915.</num>
<heading> Protection of concessioner investment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Capital improvement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “capital improvement” means a structure, a fixture, or nonremovable equipment provided by a concessioner pursuant to the terms of a concession contract and located on land of the United States within a System unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consumer price index</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “Consumer Price Index” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the “Consumer Price Index—All Urban Consumers” published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Index is not published, another regularly published cost-of-living index approximating the Consumer Price Index.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leasehold Surrender Interest in Capital Improvements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A concessioner that constructs a capital improvement on land owned by the United States within a System unit pursuant to a concession contract shall have a leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement subject to the following terms and conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A concessioner shall have a leasehold surrender interest in each capital improvement constructed by a concessioner under a concession contract, consisting solely of a right to compensation for the capital improvement to the extent of the value of the concessioner’s leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pledge as security</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A leasehold surrender interest may be pledged as security for financing of a capital improvement or the acquisition of a concession contract when approved by the Secretary pursuant to this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer and relinquishment or waiver of interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A leasehold surrender interest shall be transferred by the concessioner in connection with any transfer of the concession contract and may be relinquished or waived by the concessioner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limit on extinguishing or taking interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A leasehold surrender interest shall not be extinguished by the expiration or other termination of a concession contract and may not be taken for public use except on payment of just compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Value of interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The value of a leasehold surrender interest in a capital improvement shall be an amount equal to the initial value (construction cost of the capital improvement), increased (or decreased) by the same percentage increase (or decrease) as the percentage increase (or decrease) in the Consumer Price Index, from the date of making the investment in the capital improvement by the concessioner to the date of payment of the value of the leasehold surrender interest, less depreciation of the capital improvement as evidenced by the condition and prospective serviceability in comparison with a new unit of like kind.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Value of interest in certain new concession contracts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">How value is determined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may provide, in any new concession contract that the Secretary estimates will have a leasehold surrender interest of more than $10,000,000, that the value of any leasehold surrender interest in a capital improvement shall be based on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a reduction on an annual basis, in equal portions, over the same number of years as the time period associated with the straight line depreciation of the initial value (construction cost of the capital improvement), as provided by applicable Federal income tax laws and regulations in effect on <date date="1998-11-12">November 12, 1998</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an alternative formula that is consistent with the objectives of this subchapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">When alternative formula may be used</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use an alternative formula under subparagraph (A)(ii) only if the Secretary determines, after scrutiny of the financial and other circumstances involved in the particular concession contract (including providing notice in the Federal Register and opportunity for comment), that the alternative formula is, compared to the standard method of determining value provided for in paragraph (5), necessary to provide a fair return to the Federal Government and to foster competition for the new contract by providing a reasonable opportunity to make a profit under the new contract. If no responsive offers are received in response to a solicitation that includes the alternative formula, the concession opportunity shall be resolicited with the leasehold surrender interest value as described in paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Increase in value of interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Where a concessioner, pursuant to the terms of a concession contract, makes a capital improvement to an existing capital improvement in which the concessioner has a leasehold surrender interest, the cost of the additional capital improvement shall be added to the then-current value of the concessioner’s leasehold surrender interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Possessory Interest Existing Before November </inline>13, 1998.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A concessioner that has obtained a possessory interest (as defined pursuant to the Act of <date date="1965-10-09">October 9, 1965</date> (known as the National Park Service Concessions Policy Act; <ref>Public Law 89–249</ref>, <ref>79 Stat. 969</ref>), as in effect on <date date="1998-11-12">November 12, 1998</date>) under the terms of a concession contract entered into before <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, shall, on the expiration or termination of the concession contract, be entitled to receive compensation for the possessory interest improvements in the amount and manner as described by the concession contract. Where that possessory interest is not described in the existing concession contract, compensation of possessory interest shall be determined in accordance with the laws in effect on <date date="1998-11-12">November 12, 1998</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing concessioner awarded a new contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A concessioner awarded a new concession contract to replace an existing concession contract after <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, instead of directly receiving the possessory interest compensation, shall have a leasehold surrender interest in its existing possessory interest improvements under the terms of the new concession contract and shall carry over as the initial value of the leasehold surrender interest (instead of construction cost) an amount equal to the value of the existing possessory interest as of the termination date of the previous concession contract. In the event of a dispute between the concessioner and the Secretary as to the value of the possessory interest, the matter shall be resolved through binding arbitration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">New concessioner awarded a contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A new concessioner awarded a concession contract and required to pay a prior concessioner for possessory interest in prior improvements shall have a leasehold surrender interest in the prior improvements. The initial value in the leasehold surrender interest (instead of construction cost) shall be an amount equal to the value of the existing possessory interest as of the termination date of the previous concession contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">De novo review of value determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary, or either party to a value determination proceeding conducted under a Service concession contract issued before <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, considers that the value determination decision issued pursuant to the proceeding misinterprets or misapplies relevant contractual requirements or their underlying legal authority, the Secretary or either party may seek, within 180 days after the date of the decision, de novo review of the value determination decision by the United States Court of Federal Claims. The Court of Federal Claims may make an order affirming, vacating, modifying or correcting the determination decision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transition to Successor Concessioner</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On expiration or termination of a concession contract entered into after <date date="1998-11-13">November 13, 1998</date>, a concessioner shall be entitled under the terms of the concession contract to receive from the United States or a successor concessioner the value of any leasehold surrender interest in a capital improvement as of the date of the expiration or termination. A successor concessioner shall have a leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement under the terms of a new concession contract and the initial value of the leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement (instead of construction cost) shall be the amount of money the new concessioner is required to pay the prior concessioner for its leasehold surrender interest under the terms of the prior concession contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title to Improvements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Title to any capital improvement constructed by a concessioner on land owned by the United States in a System unit shall be vested in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101916.</num>
<heading> Reasonableness of rates and charges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A concession contract shall permit the concessioner to set reasonable and appropriate rates and charges for facilities, goods, and services provided to the public, subject to approval under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Approval by Secretary Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors to consider</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A concessioner’s rates and charges to the public shall be subject to approval by the Secretary. The approval process utilized by the Secretary shall be as prompt and as unburdensome to the concessioner as possible and shall rely on market forces to establish reasonableness of rates and charges to the maximum extent practicable. The Secretary shall approve rates and charges that the Secretary determines to be reasonable and appropriate. Unless otherwise provided in the concession contract, the reasonableness and appropriateness of rates and charges shall be determined primarily by comparison with those rates and charges for facilities, goods, and services of comparable character under similar conditions, with due consideration to the following factors and other factors deemed relevant by the Secretary:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Length of season.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Peakloads.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Average percentage of occupancy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Accessibility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Availability and costs of labor and materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Type of patronage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rates and charges not to exceed market rates and charges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Rates and charges may not exceed the market rates and charges for comparable facilities, goods, and services, after taking into account the factors referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 6 months after receiving recommendations from the Advisory Board regarding concessioner rates and charges to the public, the Secretary shall implement the recommendations or report to Congress the reasons for not implementing the recommendations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3145</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101917.</num>
<heading> Franchise fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A concession contract shall provide for payment to the Federal Government of a franchise fee or other monetary consideration as determined by the Secretary, on consideration of the probable value to the concessioner of the privileges granted by the particular contract involved. Probable value shall be based on a reasonable opportunity for net profit in relation to capital invested and the obligations of the concession contract. Consideration of revenue to the United States shall be subordinate to the objectives of protecting and preserving System units and of providing necessary and appropriate services for visitors at reasonable rates.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provisions To Be Specified in Contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of the franchise fee or other monetary consideration paid to the United States for the term of the concession contract shall be specified in the concession contract and may be modified only to reflect extraordinary unanticipated changes from the conditions anticipated as of the effective date of the concession contract. The Secretary shall include in concession contracts with a term of more than 5 years a provision that allows reconsideration of the franchise fee at the request of the Secretary or the concessioner in the event of extraordinary unanticipated changes. The provision shall provide for binding arbitration in the event that the Secretary and the concessioner are unable to agree on an adjustment to the franchise fee in those circumstances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Account in Treasury.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit and availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All franchise fees (and other monetary consideration) paid to the United States pursuant to concession contracts shall be deposited in a special account established in the Treasury. Twenty percent of the funds deposited in the special account shall be available for expenditure by the Secretary, without further appropriation, to support activities throughout the System regardless of the System unit in which the funds were collected. The funds deposited in the special account shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subaccount for each system unit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be established within the special account a subaccount for each System unit. Each subaccount shall be credited with 80 percent of the franchise fees (and other monetary consideration) collected at a single System unit under concession contracts. The funds credited to the subaccount for a System unit shall be available for expenditure by the Secretary, without further appropriation, for use at the System unit for visitor services and for purposes of funding high-priority and urgently necessary resource management programs and operations. The funds credited to a subaccount shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reduction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may reduce the percentage allocation otherwise applicable under paragraph (2) to a unit or area of the National Park Service for a fiscal year if the Secretary determines that the revenues collected at the unit or area exceed the reasonable needs of the unit or area for which expenditures may be made for that fiscal year. In no event may a percentage allocation be reduced below 60 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–42, div. E, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 249</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101918.</num>
<heading> Transfer or conveyance of concession contracts or leasehold surrender interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No concession contract or leasehold surrender interest may be transferred, assigned, sold, or otherwise conveyed or pledged by a concessioner without prior written notification to, and approval by, the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall approve a transfer or conveyance described in subsection (a) unless the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the individual, corporation, or other entity seeking to acquire a concession contract is not qualified or able to satisfy the terms and conditions of the concession contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the transfer or conveyance would have an adverse impact on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the protection, conservation, or preservation of the resources of the System unit; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provision of necessary and appropriate facilities and services to visitors at reasonable rates and charges; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the terms of the transfer or conveyance are likely, directly or indirectly, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce the concessioner’s opportunity for a reasonable profit over the remaining term of the concession contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adversely affect the quality of facilities and services provided by the concessioner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> result in a need for increased rates and charges to the public to maintain the quality of the facilities and services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification or Renegotiation of Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms and conditions of any concession contract under this section shall not be subject to modification or open to renegotiation by the Secretary because of a transfer or conveyance described in subsection (a) unless the transfer or conveyance would have an adverse impact as described in subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101919.</num>
<heading> National Park Service Concessions Management Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a National Park Service Concessions Management Advisory Board whose purpose shall be to advise the Secretary and Service on matters relating to management of concessions in the System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Advisory Board shall advise on each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Policies and procedures intended to ensure that services and facilities provided by concessioners—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are necessary and appropriate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meet acceptable standards at reasonable rates with a minimum of impact on System unit resources and values; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provide the concessioners with a reasonable opportunity to make a profit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Ways to make Service concession programs and procedures more cost effective, more process efficient, less burdensome, and timelier.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Advisory Board shall make recommendations to the Secretary regarding each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Service contracting with the private sector to conduct appropriate elements of concession management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Ways to make the review or approval of concessioner rates and charges to the public more efficient, less burdensome, and timelier.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The nature and scope of products that qualify as Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts within the meaning of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The allocation of concession fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Board shall provide an annual report on its activities to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advisory Board Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Members of the Advisory Board shall be appointed on a staggered basis by the Secretary for a term not to exceed 4 years and shall serve at the pleasure of the Secretary. The Advisory Board shall be comprised of not more than 7 individuals appointed from among citizens of the United States not in the employment of the Federal Government and not in the employment of or having an interest in a Service concession. Of the 7 members of the Advisory Board—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one member shall be privately employed in the hospitality industry and have both broad knowledge of hotel or food service management and experience in the parks and recreation concession business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> one member shall be privately employed in the tourism industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> one member shall be privately employed in the accounting industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> one member shall be privately employed in the outfitting and guide industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> one member shall be a State government employee with expertise in park concession management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> one member shall be active in promotion of traditional arts and crafts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> one member shall be active in a nonprofit conservation organization involved in parks and recreation programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service on Advisory Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Service of an individual as a member of the Advisory Board shall not be deemed to be service or employment bringing the individual within the provisions of any Federal law relating to conflicts of interest or otherwise imposing restrictions, requirements, or penalties in relation to the employment of individuals, the performance of services, or the payment or receipt of compensation in connection with claims, proceedings, or matters involving the United States. Service as a member of the Advisory Board shall not be deemed service in an appointive or elective position in the Federal Government for purposes of <ref>section 8344 of title 5</ref> or other comparable provisions of Federal law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Advisory Board shall continue to exist until <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>. In all other respects, it shall be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(329)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4342</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101920.</num>
<heading> Contracting for services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contracting Authorized.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management elements for which contract required to maximum extent practicable</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall contract with private entities to conduct or assist in elements of the management of the Service concession program considered by the Secretary to be suitable for non-Federal performance. Those management elements shall include each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Health and safety inspections.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Quality control of concession operations and facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Strategic capital planning for concession facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Analysis of rates and charges to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management elements for which contract allowed</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may also contract with private entities to assist the Secretary with each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Preparation of the financial aspects of prospectuses for Service concession contracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Development of guidelines for a System capital improvement and maintenance program for all concession occupied facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Making recommendations to the Director regarding the conduct of annual audits of concession fee expenditures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Management Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consider, taking into account the recommendations of the Advisory Board, contracting out other elements of the concessions management program, as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary Not Diminished</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall diminish the governmental responsibilities and authority of the Secretary to administer concession contracts and activities pursuant to this subchapter and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of this title. The Secretary reserves the right to make the final decision or contract approval on contracting services dealing with the management of the Service concessions program under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101921.</num>
<heading> Multiple contracts within a System unit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If multiple concession contracts are awarded to authorize concessioners to provide the same or similar outfitting, guiding, river running, or other similar services at the same approximate location or resource within a System unit, the Secretary shall establish a comparable franchise fee structure for those contracts or similar contracts, except that the terms and conditions of any existing concession contract shall not be subject to modification or open to renegotiation by the Secretary because of an award of a new contract at the same approximate location or resource.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101922.</num>
<heading> Use of nonmonetary consideration in concession contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1302 of title 40</ref> shall not apply to concession contracts awarded by the Secretary pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101923.</num>
<heading> Recordkeeping requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A concessioner and any subconcessioner shall keep such records as the Secretary may prescribe to enable the Secretary to determine that all terms of a concession contract have been and are being faithfully performed. The Secretary and any authorized representative of the Secretary shall, for the purpose of audit and examination, have access to those records and to other records of the concessioner or subconcessioner pertinent to the concession contract and all terms and conditions of the concession contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to Records by Comptroller General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General and any authorized representative of the Comptroller General shall, until the expiration of 5 calendar years after the close of the business year of each concessioner or subconcessioner, have access to and the right to examine any pertinent records described in subsection (a) of the concessioner or subconcessioner related to the contract involved.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101924.</num>
<heading> Promotion of sale of Indian, Alaska Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Promoting the sale of authentic United States Indian, Alaskan Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts relating to the cultural, historical, and geographic characteristics of System units is encouraged, and the Secretary shall ensure that there is a continuing effort to enhance the handicraft trade where it exists and establish the trade in appropriate areas where the trade does not exist.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption From Franchise Fee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In furtherance of the purposes of subsection (a), the revenue derived from the sale of United States Indian, Alaska Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts shall be exempt from any franchise fee payments under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101925.</num>
<heading> Commercial use authorizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent specified in this section, the Secretary, on request, may authorize a private person, corporation, or other entity to provide services to visitors to System units through a commercial use authorization. A commercial use authorization shall not be considered to be a concession contract under this subchapter and no other section of this subchapter shall be applicable to a commercial use authorization except where expressly stated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Issuance of Commercial Use Authorizations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority of this section may be used only to authorize provision of services that the Secretary determines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will have minimal impact on resources and values of a System unit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are consistent with the purpose for which the System unit was established and with all applicable management plans and Service policies and regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of commercial use authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require payment of a reasonable fee for issuance of a commercial use authorization, the fees to remain available without further appropriation to be used, at a minimum, to recover associated management and administrative costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> require that the provision of services under a commercial use authorization be accomplished in a manner consistent to the highest practicable degree with the preservation and conservation of System unit resources and values;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take appropriate steps to limit the liability of the United States arising from the provision of services under a commercial use authorization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> have no authority under this section to issue more commercial use authorizations than are consistent with the preservation and proper management of System unit resources and values; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> shall establish other conditions for issuance of a commercial use authorization that the Secretary determines to be appropriate for the protection of visitors, provision of adequate and appropriate visitor services, and protection and proper management of System unit resources and values.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any commercial use authorization shall be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> commercial operations with annual gross receipts of not more than $25,000 resulting from services originating and provided solely within a System unit pursuant to the commercial use authorization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the incidental use of resources of the System unit by commercial operations that provide services originating and terminating outside the boundaries of the System unit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> uses by organized children’s camps, outdoor clubs, and nonprofit institutions (including back country use); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other uses, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonprofit Institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nonprofit institutions are not required to obtain commercial use authorizations unless taxable income is derived by the institution from the authorized use.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A commercial use authorization shall not provide for the construction of any structure, fixture, or improvement on federally-owned land within the boundaries of a System unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of any commercial use authorization shall not exceed 2 years. No preferential right of renewal or similar provisions for renewal shall be granted by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person, corporation, or other entity seeking or obtaining a commercial use authorization shall not be precluded from submitting a proposal for concession contracts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101926.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations appropriate for the implementation of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall include appropriate provisions to ensure that concession services and facilities to be provided in a System unit are not segmented or otherwise split into separate concession contracts for the purposes of seeking to reduce anticipated annual gross receipts of a concession contract below $500,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall further define the term “United States Indian, Alaskan Native, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts” for the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>COMMERCIAL SERVICES AUTHORIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 101931.</num>
<heading> Contract authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subchapter II, the Secretary may award and administer commercial services contracts (and related professional services contracts) for the operation and expansion of commercial visitor facilities and visitor services programs in System units. The commercial services contracts that may be awarded shall be limited to those that are necessary and appropriate for public use and enjoyment of the unit of the System in which they are located, and, that are consistent with the preservation and conservation of the resources and values of the unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Contracts may be awarded under subsection (a) without regard to Federal laws and regulations governing procurement by Federal agencies, with the exception of laws and regulations related to Federal government contracts governing working conditions and wage rates, including the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.), sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the “Davis-Bacon Act”), and any civil rights provisions otherwise applicable thereto.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Commercial Services Contracts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may issue a commercial services contract under this subchapter when the Secretary determines that the contract meets the objectives of expanding, modernizing, and improving the condition of commercial visitor facilities and the services provided to visitors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No contracts may be awarded under this subchapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the provision of outfitter and guide services described in section 101913(8); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to authorize the provision of facilities or services for which the Secretary has granted to an existing concessioner a preferential right of renewal as defined in sections 101911 and 101913.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101932.</num>
<heading> Award of commercial services contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive Selection Process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (c), commercial services contracts shall be awarded by the Secretary through a competitive selection process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation of Proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before awarding a new commercial services contract, the Secretary shall publicly solicit proposals for the contract, except as provided in subsection (c). In connection with such solicitation, the Secretary shall prepare a request for proposals and shall publish notice of its availability.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101933.</num>
<heading> Term of commercial services contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A commercial services contract entered into pursuant to this title shall be awarded for a term not to exceed 10 years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101934.</num>
<heading> Capital improvements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person or entity awarded a contract under this subchapter shall receive no leasehold surrender interest, as defined in section 101915, in capital improvements constructed under the terms of the contract.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101935.</num>
<heading> Financial management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revolving Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is established a revolving fund that shall be available to the Secretary without fiscal year limitation for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> expenses necessary for the management, improvement, enhancement, operation, construction, and maintenance of commercial visitor services and facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> payment of possessory interest and leasehold surrender interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Collection of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Funds collected by the Secretary pursuant to the contracts awarded under this subchapter shall be credited to the revolving fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to transfer to the revolving fund, without reimbursement, any additional funds or revenue in connection with the functions to be carried out under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts in the revolving fund shall be used by the Secretary in furtherance of the purposes of this title. No funds from this account may be used to decrease the availability of services and programs to the public.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101936.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the effective date of this subchapter, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations appropriate for its implementation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101937.</num>
<heading> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall modify the terms or conditions of any concessions contracts awarded under subchapter II or the ability of the National Park Service to enter into concessions contracts under the National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998 (title IV of <ref>Public Law 105–391</ref>) including the use of leaseholder surrender interest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101938.</num>
<heading> Sunset</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority given to the Secretary under this subchapter shall expire 9 years after the date of the enactment of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1494</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. G, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>