<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3203—</num>
<heading>MONUMENTS, RUINS, SITES, AND OBJECTS OF ANTIQUITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 320301.</num>
<heading> National monuments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presidential Declaration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may, in the President’s discretion, declare by public proclamation historic landmarks, historic and prehistoric structures, and other objects of historic or scientific interest that are situated on land owned or controlled by the Federal Government to be national monuments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reservation of Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may reserve parcels of land as a part of the national monuments. The limits of the parcels shall be confined to the smallest area compatible with the proper care and management of the objects to be protected.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relinquishment to Federal Government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When an object is situated on a parcel covered by a bona fide unperfected claim or held in private ownership, the parcel, or so much of the parcel as may be necessary for the proper care and management of the object, may be relinquished to the Federal Government and the Secretary may accept the relinquishment of the parcel on behalf of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Extension or Establishment of National Monuments in Wyoming</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No extension or establishment of national monuments in Wyoming may be undertaken except by express authorization of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 320302.</num>
<heading> Permits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Grant Permit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, or the Secretary of the Army may grant a permit for the examination of ruins, the excavation of archeological sites, and the gathering of objects of antiquity on land under their respective jurisdictions to an institution that the Secretary concerned considers properly qualified to conduct the examination, excavation, or gathering, subject to such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Examination, Excavation, or Gathering</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A permit may be granted only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the examination, excavation, or gathering is undertaken for the benefit of a reputable museum, university, college, or other recognized scientific or educational institution, with a view to increasing the knowledge of the objects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the gathering shall be made for permanent preservation in a public museum.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 320303.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of the Army shall make and publish uniform regulations for the purpose of carrying out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>