<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3029—</num>
<heading>GRANTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 302901.</num>
<heading> Awarding of grants and availability of grant funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No grant may be made under this division unless application for the grant is submitted to the Secretary in accordance with regulations and procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grant Not Treated as Taxable Income</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No grant made pursuant to this division shall be treated as taxable income for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall make funding available to individual States and the National Trust as soon as practicable after execution of a grant agreement. For purposes of administration, grants to individual States and the National Trust each shall be deemed to be one grant and shall be administered by the Service as one grant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302902.</num>
<heading> Grants to States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall administer a program of matching grants to the States for the purposes of carrying out this division.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Conditions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading> In general <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002020">1</ref>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No grant may be made under this division—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> unless the application is in accordance with the comprehensive statewide historic preservation plan that has been approved by the Secretary after considering its relationship to the comprehensive statewide outdoor recreation plan prepared pursuant to chapter 2003 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> unless the grantee has agreed to make reports, in such form and containing such information, as the Secretary may from time to time require;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> unless the grantee has agreed to assume, after completion of the project, the total cost of the continued maintenance, repair, and administration of the property in a manner satisfactory to the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> until the grantee has complied with such further terms and conditions as the Secretary may consider necessary or advisable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may waive the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (C) of paragraph (1) for any grant under this division to the National Trust.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Amount limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No grant may be made under this division for more than 60 percent of the aggregate costs of carrying out projects and programs under the administrative control of the State Historic Preservation Officer as specified in <ref>section 302303 of this title</ref> in any one fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Source of state share of costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as permitted by other law, the State share of the costs referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be contributed by non-Federal sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction on Use of Real Property To Meet Non-Federal Share of Cost of Project</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No State shall be permitted to utilize the value of real property obtained before <date date="1966-10-15">October 15, 1966</date>, in meeting the non-Federal share of the cost of a project for which a grant is made under this division.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Apportionment of Grant Amounts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bases for apportionment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amounts appropriated and made available for grants to the States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the purposes of this division shall be apportioned among the States by the Secretary on the basis of needs as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for projects and programs under this division for each fiscal year shall be apportioned among the States as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall notify each State of its apportionment under paragraph (1)(B) within 30 days after the date of enactment of legislation appropriating funds under this division.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reapportionment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any amount of any apportionment that has not been paid or obligated by the Secretary during the fiscal year in which the notification is given or during the 2 fiscal years after that fiscal year shall be reapportioned by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (1)(B). The Secretary shall analyze and revise as necessary the method of apportionment. The method and any revision shall be published by the Secretary in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of funds to certified local governments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less than 10 percent of the annual apportionment distributed by the Secretary to each State for the purposes of carrying out this division shall be transferred by the State, pursuant to the requirements of this division, to certified local governments for historic preservation projects or programs of the certified local governments. In any year in which the total annual apportionment to the States exceeds $65,000,000, 50 percent of the excess shall also be transferred by the States to certified local governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines for use and distribution of funds to certified local governments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish guidelines for the use and distribution of funds under paragraph (4) to ensure that no certified local government receives a disproportionate share of the funds available, and may include a maximum or minimum limitation on the amount of funds distributed to any single certified local government. The guidelines shall not limit the ability of any State to distribute more than 10 percent of its annual apportionment under paragraph (4), nor shall the Secretary require any State to exceed the 10 percent minimum distribution to certified local governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total direct and indirect administrative costs charged for carrying out State projects and programs shall not exceed 25 percent of the aggregate costs (except in the case of a grant to the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, or the Republic of Palau).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302903.</num>
<heading> Grants to National Trust</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary of the Interior</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may administer grants to the National Trust consistent with the purposes of its charter and this division.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may make grants to the National Trust, on terms and conditions and in amounts (not exceeding $90,000 with respect to any one structure) as the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development considers appropriate, to cover the costs incurred by the National Trust in renovating or restoring structures that the National Trust considers to be of historic or architectural value and that the National Trust has accepted and will maintain (after the renovation or restoration) for historic purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302904.</num>
<heading> Direct grants for the preservation of properties included on National Register</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall administer a program of direct grants for the preservation of properties included on the National Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Available Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds to support the program annually shall not exceed 10 percent of the amount appropriated annually for the Historic Preservation Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Uses of Grants.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Grants under this section may be made by the Secretary, in consultation with the appropriate State Historic Preservation Officer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for the preservation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> National Historic Landmarks that are threatened with demolition or impairment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> historic property of World Heritage significance;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for demonstration projects that will provide information concerning professional methods and techniques having application to historic property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for the training and development of skilled labor in trades and crafts, and in analysis and curation, relating to historic preservation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to assist individuals or small businesses within any historic district included on the National Register to remain within the district.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limit on certain grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be made under subparagraph (A) or (D) of paragraph (1) only to the extent that the project cannot be carried out in as effective a manner through the use of an insured loan under <ref>section 303901 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302905.</num>
<heading> Religious property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Grants may be made under this chapter for the preservation, stabilization, restoration, or rehabilitation of religious property listed on the National Register if the purpose of the grant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is secular;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> does not promote religion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> seeks to protect qualities that are historically significant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Section</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the use of any funds made available under this subdivision for the acquisition of any religious property listed on the National Register.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302906.</num>
<heading> Grants and loans to Indian tribes and nonprofit organizations representing ethnic or minority groups</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, in consultation with the appropriate State Historic Preservation Officer, make grants or loans or both under this subdivision to Indian tribes and to nonprofit organizations representing ethnic or minority groups for the preservation of their cultural heritage.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302907.</num>
<heading> Grants to Indian tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer a program of direct grants to Indian tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations for the purpose of carrying out this division as it pertains to Indian tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations. Matching fund requirements may be modified. Federal funds available to an Indian tribe or Native Hawaiian organization may be used as matching funds for the purposes of the Indian tribe’s or Native Hawaiian organization’s conducting its responsibilities pursuant to this subdivision.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302908.</num>
<heading> Grants to the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As part of the program of matching grant assistance from the Historic Preservation Fund to States, the Secretary shall administer a program of direct grants to the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau in furtherance of the Compact of Free Association between the United States and the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands, approved by the Compact of Free Association Act of 1985 (<ref>48 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq., 2001 et seq.), and the Compact of Free Association between the United States and Palau, approved by the Joint Resolution entitled “Joint Resolution to approve the ‘Compact of Free Association’ between the United States and Government <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">1</ref> of Palau, and for other purposes” (<ref>48 U.S.C. 1931</ref> et seq.) or any successor enactment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Goal of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The goal of the program shall be to establish historic and cultural preservation programs that meet the unique needs of each of those nations so that at the termination of the compacts the programs shall be firmly established.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basis of Allocating Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amounts to be made available under this subsection shall be allocated by the Secretary on the basis of needs as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waivers and Modifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may waive or modify the requirements of this subdivision to conform to the cultural setting of those nations. Matching funds may be waived or modified.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302909.</num>
<heading> Prohibited use of grant amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No part of any grant made under this subdivision shall be used to compensate any person intervening in any proceeding under this division.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 302910.</num>
<heading> Recordkeeping</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A recipient of assistance under this division shall keep—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> such records as the Secretary shall prescribe, including records that fully disclose—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the disposition by the recipient of the proceeds of the assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which the assistance is given or used; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the amount and nature of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>