<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3111—</num>
<heading>PRESERVE AMERICA PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 311101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Council</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Council” means the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Heritage tourism</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “heritage tourism” means the conduct of activities to attract and accommodate visitors to a site or area based on the unique or special aspects of the history, landscape (including trail systems), and culture of the site or area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “program” means the Preserve America Program established under section 311102(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 311102.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the Department of the Interior the Preserve America Program, under which the Secretary, in partnership with the Council, may provide competitive grants to States, local governments (including local governments in the process of applying for designation as Preserve America Communities under <ref>section 311103 of this title</ref>, Indian tribes, communities designated as Preserve America Communities under <ref>section 311103 of this title</ref>, State historic preservation offices, and tribal historic preservation offices to support preservation efforts through heritage tourism, education, and historic preservation planning activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligible Projects.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following projects shall be eligible for a grant under this chapter:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A project for the conduct of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> research on, and documentation of, the history of a community; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> surveys of the historic resources of a community.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An education and interpretation project that conveys the history of a community or site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A planning project (other than building rehabilitation) that advances economic development using heritage tourism and historic preservation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A training project that provides opportunities for professional development in areas that would aid a community in using and promoting its historic resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A project to support heritage tourism in a Preserve America Community designated under <ref>section 311103 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Other nonconstruction projects that identify or promote historic properties or provide for the education of the public about historic properties that are consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In providing grants under this chapter, the Secretary shall provide only one grant to each eligible project selected for a grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In providing grants under this chapter, the Secretary may give preference to projects that carry out the purposes of both the program and the Save America’s Treasures Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consultation and Notification.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall consult with the Council in preparing the list of projects to be provided grants for a fiscal year under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days before the date on which the Secretary provides grants for a fiscal year under the program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a list of any eligible projects that are to be provided grants under the program for the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cost-Sharing Requirement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The non-Federal share of the cost of carrying out a project provided a grant under this chapter shall be not less than 50 percent of the total cost of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of non-federal share</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The non-Federal share required under paragraph (1) shall be in the form of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cash; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> donated supplies and related services, the value of which shall be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that each applicant for a grant has the capacity to secure, and a feasible plan for securing, the non-Federal share for an eligible project required under paragraph (1) before a grant is provided to the eligible project under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 311103.</num>
<heading> Designation of Preserve America Communities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To be considered for designation as a Preserve America Community, a community, tribal area, or neighborhood shall submit to the Council an application containing such information as the Council may require.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be designated as a Preserve America Community under the program, a community, tribal area, or neighborhood that submits an application under subsection (a) shall, as determined by the Chairman of the Council, in consultation with the Secretary, meet criteria required by the Chairman of the Council and, in addition, consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> protection and celebration of the heritage of the community, tribal area, or neighborhood;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use of the historic assets of the community, tribal area, or neighborhood for economic development and community revitalization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encouragement of people to experience and appreciate local historic resources through education and heritage tourism programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Local Governments Previously Certified for Historic Preservation Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall establish an expedited process for Preserve America Community designation for local governments previously certified for historic preservation activities under <ref>section 302502 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairman of the Council, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish any guidelines that are necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–289, title V, § 501(d)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1490</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 311104.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall develop any guidelines and issue any regulations that the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 311105.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter $25,000,000 for each fiscal year, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3249</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXX, § 3033(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>