<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1201—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL HERITAGE AREA SYSTEM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 120101.</num>
<heading> Definition of National Heritage Area</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “National Heritage Area” means a component of the National Heritage Area System described in section 120102(b).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–339, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 120102.</num>
<heading> Establishment of National Heritage Area System</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To recognize certain areas of the United States that tell nationally significant stories and to conserve, enhance, and interpret those nationally significant stories and the natural, historic, scenic, and cultural resources of areas that illustrate significant aspects of the heritage of the United States, there is established a National Heritage Area System through the administration of which the Secretary may provide technical and financial assistance to local coordinating entities to support the establishment, development, and continuity of the National Heritage Areas.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Heritage Area System Components</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The National Heritage Area System shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each National Heritage Area, National Heritage Corridor, National Heritage Canalway, Cultural Heritage Corridor, National Heritage Route, and National Heritage Partnership designated by Congress before or on the date of enactment of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> each National Heritage Area designated by Congress after the date of enactment of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Relationship to the System.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to system units</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, participation and assistance by any administrator of the System unit that is located near or encompassed by a National Heritage Area in local initiatives for the National Heritage Area to conserve and interpret resources consistent with the applicable management plan for the National Heritage Area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> work with local coordinating entities to promote public enjoyment of System units and System-related resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Treatment.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A National Heritage Area shall not be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> considered to be a System unit; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> subject to the authorities applicable to System units.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this paragraph affects the administration of a System unit located within the boundaries of a National Heritage Area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct or review, as applicable, feasibility studies in accordance with section 120103(a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of, and submit to Congress a report that includes recommendations regarding the role of the Service with respect to, each National Heritage Area, in accordance with section 120104;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enter into cooperative agreements with other Federal agencies, States, Tribal governments, local governments, local coordinating entities, and other interested individuals and entities to achieve the purposes of the National Heritage Area System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide information, promote understanding, and encourage research regarding National Heritage Areas, in partnership with local coordinating entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide national oversight, analysis, coordination, technical and financial assistance, and support to ensure consistency and accountability of the National Heritage Area System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–339, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 120103.</num>
<heading> National Heritage Area studies and designation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Studies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may carry out or review a study to assess the suitability and feasibility of each proposed National Heritage Area for designation as a National Heritage Area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Preparation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A study under paragraph (1) may be carried out—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by the Secretary, in consultation with State and local historic preservation officers, State and local historical societies, State and local tourism offices, and other appropriate organizations and governmental agencies; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by interested individuals or entities, if the Secretary certifies that the completed study meets the requirements of paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after receiving a study carried out by interested individuals or entities under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary shall review and certify whether the study meets the requirements of paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A study under paragraph (1) shall include analysis, documentation, and determinations on whether the proposed National Heritage Area—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> has an assemblage of natural, historic, and cultural resources that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> represent distinctive aspects of the heritage of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are worthy of recognition, conservation, interpretation, and continuing use; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> would be best managed—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> through partnerships among public and private entities; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by linking diverse and sometimes noncontiguous resources and active communities;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reflects traditions, customs, beliefs, and folklife that are a valuable part of the story of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> provides outstanding opportunities—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to conserve natural, historic, cultural, or scenic features; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for recreation and education;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> contains resources that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are important to any identified themes of the proposed National Heritage Area; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> retain a degree of integrity capable of supporting interpretation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> includes a diverse group of residents, business interests, nonprofit organizations, and State and local governments that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are involved in the planning of the proposed National Heritage Area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have developed a conceptual financial plan that outlines the roles of all participants in the proposed National Heritage Area, including the Federal Government; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> have demonstrated significant support for the designation of the proposed National Heritage Area;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> has a potential management entity to work in partnership with the individuals and entities described in subparagraph (E) to develop the proposed National Heritage Area while encouraging State and local economic activity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> has a conceptual boundary map that is supported by the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each study carried out under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any correspondence received by the Secretary demonstrating support for, or opposition to, the establishment of the National Heritage Area;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the findings of the study; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Timing.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Studies carried out by the secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to a study carried out by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2)(A)(i), the Secretary shall submit a report under subparagraph (A) not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available to carry out the study.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Studies carried out by other interested parties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to a study carried out by interested individuals or entities in accordance with paragraph (2)(A)(ii), the Secretary shall submit a report under subparagraph (A) not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary certifies under paragraph (2)(B) that the study meets the requirements of paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An area shall be designated as a National Heritage Area only by an Act of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–339, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 120104.</num>
<heading> Evaluation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At reasonable and appropriate intervals, as determined by the Secretary, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of a National Heritage Area in accordance with subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prepare and submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that includes recommendations for the continued role of the Service with respect to each National Heritage Area in accordance with subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Components</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An evaluation under subsection (a)(1) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> assess the progress of the applicable local coordinating entity of a National Heritage Area with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> accomplishing the purposes of the applicable National Heritage Area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> achieving the goals and objectives of the management plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> analyze Federal, State, local, Tribal government, and private investments in the National Heritage Area to determine the leverage and impact of the investments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> review the management structure, partnership relationships, and funding of the National Heritage Area for purposes of identifying the critical components for sustainability of the National Heritage Area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under subsection (a)(2) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> if the report contains a recommendation of the Secretary that Federal funding for the applicable National Heritage Area should be continued, an analysis of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any means by which that Federal funding may be reduced or eliminated over time; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the appropriate time period necessary to achieve the recommended reduction or elimination of Federal funding; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the report contains a recommendation of the Secretary that Federal funding for the applicable National Heritage Area should be eliminated, a description of potential impacts on conservation, interpretation, and sustainability in the applicable National Heritage Area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–339, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>