<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1001—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 100101.</num>
<heading> Promotion and regulation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, shall promote and regulate the use of the National Park System by means and measures that conform to the fundamental purpose of the System units, which purpose is to conserve the scenery, natural and historic objects, and wild life in the System units and to provide for the enjoyment of the scenery, natural and historic objects, and wild life in such manner and by such means as will leave them unimpaired for the enjoyment of future generations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Declarations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading> 1970 <inline class="small-caps">declarations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Congress declares that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the National Park System, which began with establishment of Yellowstone National Park in 1872, has since grown to include superlative natural, historic, and recreation areas in every major region of the United States and its territories and possessions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> these areas, though distinct in character, are united through their interrelated purposes and resources into one National Park System as cumulative expressions of a single national heritage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> individually and collectively, these areas derive increased national dignity and recognition of their superb environmental quality through their inclusion jointly with each other in one System preserved and managed for the benefit and inspiration of all the people of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> it is the purpose of this division to include all these areas in the System and to clarify the authorities applicable to the System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading> 1978 <inline class="small-caps">reaffirmation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Congress reaffirms, declares, and directs that the promotion and regulation of the various System units shall be consistent with and founded in the purpose established by subsection (a), to the common benefit of all the people of the United States. The authorization of activities shall be construed and the protection, management, and administration of the System units shall be conducted in light of the high public value and integrity of the System and shall not be exercised in derogation of the values and purposes for which the System units have been established, except as directly and specifically provided by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this title:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Director” means the Director of the National Park Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National park system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “National Park System” means the areas of land and water described in <ref>section 100501 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Service” means the National Park Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “System” means the National Park System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">System unit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “System unit” means one of the areas described in <ref>section 100501 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>