<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3087—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL MARITIME HERITAGE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 308701.</num>
<heading> Policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be the policy of the Federal Government, in partnership with the States and local governments and private organizations and individuals, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use measures, including financial and technical assistance, to foster conditions under which our modern society and our historic maritime resources can exist in productive harmony;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide leadership in the preservation of the historic maritime resources of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> contribute to the preservation of historic maritime resources and give maximum encouragement to organizations and individuals undertaking preservation by private means; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assist State and local governments to expand their maritime historic preservation programs and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National trust</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “National Trust” means the National Trust for Historic Preservation in the United States established under <ref>section 312102 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Private nonprofit organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “private nonprofit organization” means any person that is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 501(a)</ref>) and described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 501(c)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Program” means the National Maritime Heritage Grants Program established under <ref>section 308703(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State historic preservation officer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State Historic Preservation Officer” means a State Historic Preservation Officer appointed pursuant to <ref>section 302301(1) of this title</ref> by the chief executive official of a State having a State Historic Preservation Program approved by the Secretary under that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308703.</num>
<heading> National Maritime Heritage Grants Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is established in the Department of the Interior the National Maritime Heritage Grants Program, to foster in the American public a greater awareness and appreciation of the role of maritime endeavors in our Nation’s history and culture. The Program shall consist of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> annual grants to the National Trust for subgrants administered by the National Trust for maritime heritage education projects under subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> grants to State Historic Preservation Officers for maritime heritage preservation projects carried out or administered by those Officers under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grants for Maritime Heritage Education Projects.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants to national trust</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, subject to paragraph (2), and the availability of amounts for that purpose under <ref>section 308704(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, shall make an annual grant to the National Trust for maritime heritage education projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of grants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts received by the National Trust as an annual grant under this subsection shall be used to make subgrants to State and local governments and private nonprofit organizations to carry out education projects that have been approved by the Secretary under subsection (f) and that consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> assistance to any maritime museum or historical society for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> existing and new educational programs, exhibits, educational activities, conservation, and interpretation of artifacts and collections;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> minor improvements to educational and museum facilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other similar activities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> activities designed to encourage the preservation of traditional maritime skills, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> building and operation of vessels of all sizes and types for educational purposes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> special skills such as wood carving, sail making, and rigging;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> traditional maritime art forms; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> sail training;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> other educational activities relating to historic maritime resources, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> maritime  educational  waterborne-experience programs in historic vessels or vessel reproductions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> maritime archeological field schools; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> educational programs on other aspects of maritime history;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> heritage programs focusing on maritime historic resources, including maritime heritage trails and corridors; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the construction and use of reproductions of historic maritime resources for educational purposes, if a historic maritime resource no longer exists or would be damaged or consumed through direct use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grants for Maritime Heritage Preservation Projects.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants to state historic preservation officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, acting through the National Maritime Initiative of the Service and subject to paragraph (2), and the availability of amounts for that purpose under <ref>section 308704(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, shall make grants to State Historic Preservation Officers for maritime heritage preservation projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of grants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts received by a State Historic Preservation Officer as a grant under this subsection shall be used by the Officer to carry out, or to make subgrants to local governments and private nonprofit organizations to carry out, projects that have been approved by the Secretary under subsection (f) for the preservation of historic maritime resources through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identification of historic maritime resources, including underwater archeological sites;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acquisition of historic maritime resources for the purposes of preservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> repair, restoration, stabilization, maintenance, or other capital improvements to historic maritime resources, in accordance with standards prescribed by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> research, recording (through drawings, photographs, or otherwise), planning (through feasibility studies, architectural and engineering services, or otherwise), and other services carried out as part of a preservation program for historic maritime resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Direct Grant and Subgrant Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To qualify for a subgrant from the National Trust under subsection (b), or a direct grant to or a subgrant from a State Historic Preservation Officer under subsection (c), a person shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> demonstrate that the project for which the direct grant or subgrant will be used has the potential for reaching a broad audience with an effective educational program based on American maritime history, technology, or the role of maritime endeavors in American culture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> match the amount of the direct grant or subgrant, on a 1-to-1 basis, with non-Federal assets from non-Federal sources, which may include cash or donated services fairly valued as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> maintain records as may be reasonably necessary to fully disclose—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount and the disposition of the proceeds of the direct grant or subgrant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total cost of the project for which the direct grant or subgrant is made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other records as may be required by the Secretary, including such records as will facilitate an effective accounting for project funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide access to the Secretary for the purposes of any required audit and examination of any records of the person; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> be a unit of State or local government, or a private nonprofit organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures, Terms, and Conditions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An application for a subgrant under subsection (b), or a direct grant or subgrant under subsection (c), shall be submitted under procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person may not receive a subgrant under subsection (b), or a direct grant or subgrant under subsection (c), unless the person agrees to assume, after completion of the project for which the direct grant or subgrant is awarded, the total cost of the continued maintenance, repair, and administration of any property for which the subgrant will be used in a manner satisfactory to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Allocation of, and Limitation on, Grant Funding.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent feasible, the Secretary shall ensure that the amount made available under subsection (b) for maritime heritage education projects is equal to the amount made available under subsection (c) for maritime heritage preservation projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount provided by the Secretary in a fiscal year as grants under this section for projects relating to historic maritime resources owned or operated by the Federal Government shall not exceed 40 percent of the total amount available for the fiscal year for grants under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication of Direct Grant and Subgrant Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall publish annually in the Federal Register and otherwise as the Secretary considers appropriate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a solicitation of applications for direct grants and subgrants under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a list of priorities for the making of those direct grants and subgrants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a single deadline for the submission of applications for those direct grants and subgrants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> other relevant information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Direct Grant and Subgrant Administration.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Responsibility.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National trust</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Trust is responsible for administering subgrants for maritime heritage education projects under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary is responsible for administering direct grants for maritime heritage preservation projects under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State historic preservation officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>State Historic Preservation Officers are responsible for administering subgrants for maritime heritage preservation projects under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The appropriate responsible party under paragraph (1) shall administer direct grants or subgrants by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> publicizing the Program to prospective grantees, subgrantees, and the public at large, in cooperation with the Service, the Maritime Administration, and other appropriate government agencies and private institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> answering inquiries from the public, including providing information on the Program as requested;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> distributing direct grant and subgrant applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> receiving direct grant and subgrant applications and ensuring their completeness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> keeping records of all direct grant and subgrant awards and expenditures of funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> monitoring progress of projects carried out with direct grants and subgrants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> providing to the Secretary such progress reports as may be required by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance of Maritime Preservation Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, the National Trust, and the State Historic Preservation Officers may, individually or jointly, enter into cooperative agreements with any private nonprofit organization with appropriate expertise in maritime preservation issues, or other qualified maritime preservation organizations, to assist in the administration of the Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives an annual report on the Program, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the total number of grant applications submitted and approved under the Program in the period covered by the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a detailed description of each project funded under the Program in the period covered by the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the results or accomplishments of each such project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommended priorities for achieving the policy set forth in <ref>section 308701 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308704.</num>
<heading> Funding</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds From Sale and Scrapping of Obsolete Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the amount of funds credited in a fiscal year to the Vessel Operations Revolving Fund established by <ref>section 50301(a) of title 46</ref> that is attributable to the sale of obsolete vessels in the National Defense Reserve Fleet that are scrapped or sold under section 57102, 57103, or 57104 of title 46 shall be available until expended as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Fifty percent shall be available to the Administrator of the Maritime Administration for such acquisition, maintenance, repair, reconditioning, or improvement of vessels in the National Defense Reserve Fleet as is authorized under other Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Twenty five percent shall be available to the Administrator of the Maritime Administration for the payment or reimbursement of expenses incurred by or on behalf of State maritime academies or the United States Merchant Marine Academy for facility and training ship maintenance, repair, and modernization, and for the purchase of simulators and fuel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The remainder shall be available to the Secretary to carry out the Program, as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) does not apply to amounts credited to the Vessel Operations Revolving Fund before <date date="1994-07-01">July 1, 1994</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts for Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Allocation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and paragraph (2), of the amounts available each fiscal year for the Program under subsection (a)(1)(C)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 50 percent shall be used for grants under section 308703(b); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 50 percent shall be used for grants under section 308703(c).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Set aside.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less than 25 percent of the amounts available each fiscal year for the Program under subsection (a)(1)(C) shall be used for the preservation and presentation to the public of the maritime heritage property of the Maritime Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Direct transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide amounts used for the preservation and presentation to the public of the maritime heritage property of the Maritime Administration through direct transfers to the Maritime Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Maritime Administrator may waive the application of clause (i) for any fiscal year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administrative expenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not more than 15 percent or $500,000, whichever is less, of the amount available for the Program under subsection (a)(1)(C) for a fiscal year may be used for expenses of administering the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Of the amount available under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one half shall be allocated to the National Trust for expenses incurred in administering grants under <ref>section 308703(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one half shall be allocated as appropriate by the Secretary to the Service and participating State Historic Preservation Officers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Disposal of Vessels.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall dispose (by sale or by purchase of disposal services) of all vessels described in paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in accordance with a priority system for disposing of vessels, as determined by the Secretary, that shall include provisions requiring the Maritime Administration to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> dispose of all deteriorated high priority ships that are available for disposal within 12 months of their designation as available for disposal; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> give priority to the disposition of those vessels that pose the most significant danger to the environment or cost the most to maintain;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the manner that provides the best value to the Federal Government, except in any case in which obtaining the best value would require towing a vessel and the towing poses a serious threat to the environment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in accordance with the plan of the Department of Transportation for disposal of those vessels and requirements under sections 57102 to 57104 of title 46.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Description of vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The vessels referred to in paragraph (1) are the vessels in the National Defense Reserve Fleet after <date date="1994-07-01">July 1, 1994</date>, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are not assigned to the Ready Reserve Force component of the National Defense Reserve Fleet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are not specifically authorized or required by statute to be used for a particular purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Available Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts available under this section shall not be considered in any determination of the amounts available to the Department of the Interior.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308705.</num>
<heading> Designation of America’s National Maritime Museum</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>America’s National Maritime Museum shall be composed of the museums designated by law to be museums of America’s National Maritime Museum on the basis that the museums—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> house a collection of maritime artifacts clearly representing the Nation’s maritime heritage; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide outreach programs to educate the public about the Nation’s maritime heritage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initial Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following museums (meeting the criteria specified in subsection (a)) are designated as museums of America’s National Maritime Museum:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Mariners’ Museum, located at 100 Museum Drive, Newport News, Virginia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The South Street Seaport Museum, located at 207 Front Street, New York, New York.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Future Designation of Other Museums Not Precluded</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The designation of the museums referred to in subsection (b) as museums of America’s National Maritime Museum does not preclude the designation by law of any other museum that meets the criteria specified in subsection (a) as a museum of America’s National Maritime Museum.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reference to Museums</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any reference in any law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to a museum designated by law to be a museum of America’s National Maritime Museum shall be deemed to be a reference to that museum as a museum of America’s National Maritime Museum.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308706.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, after consultation with the National Trust, the National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers, and appropriate members of the maritime heritage community, shall prescribe appropriate guidelines, procedures, and regulations to carry out the chapter, including direct grant and subgrant priorities, the method of solicitation and review of direct grant and subgrant proposals, criteria for review of direct grant and subgrant proposals, administrative requirements, reporting and recordkeeping requirements, and any other requirements the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 308707.</num>
<heading> Applicability of other authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorities contained in this chapter shall be in addition to, and shall not be construed to supersede or modify those contained in division A of this subtitle.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>