<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 2—</num>
<heading>OTHER HIGHWAYS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 201.</num>
<heading> Federal lands and tribal transportation programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Recognizing the need for all public Federal and tribal transportation facilities to be treated under uniform policies similar to the policies that apply to Federal-aid highways and other public transportation facilities, the Secretary of Transportation, in collaboration with the Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies, shall coordinate a uniform policy for all public Federal and tribal transportation facilities that shall apply to Federal lands transportation facilities, tribal transportation facilities, and Federal lands access transportation facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds authorized for the tribal transportation program, the Federal lands transportation program, and the Federal lands access program shall be available for contract upon apportionment, or on October 1 of the fiscal year for which the funds were authorized if no apportionment is required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount remaining</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any amount remaining unexpended for a period of 3 years after the close of the fiscal year for which the funds were authorized shall lapse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the department responsible for the administration of funds under this subsection may incur obligations, approve projects, and enter into contracts under such authorizations, which shall be considered to be contractual obligations of the United States for the payment of the cost thereof, the funds of which shall be considered to have been expended when obligated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Expenditure.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any funds authorized for any fiscal year after the date of enactment of this section under the Federal lands transportation program, the Federal lands access program, and the tribal transportation program shall be considered to have been expended if a sum equal to the total of the sums authorized for the fiscal year and previous fiscal years have been obligated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credited funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any funds described in subparagraph (A) that are released by payment of final voucher or modification of project authorizations shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> credited to the balance of unobligated authorizations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> immediately available for expenditure.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not apply to funds authorized before the date of enactment of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contractual obligation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), the authorization by the Secretary, or the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency if the agency is the contracting office, of engineering and related work for the development, design, and acquisition associated with a construction project, whether performed by contract or agreement authorized by law, or the approval by the Secretary of plans, specifications, and estimates for construction of a project, shall be considered to constitute a contractual obligation of the Federal Government to pay the total eligible cost of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any project funded under this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any project funded pursuant to agreements authorized by this title or any other title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> affects the application of the Federal share associated with the project being undertaken under this section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> modifies the point of obligation associated with Federal salaries and expenses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal share.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal and federal lands transportation program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the Federal lands transportation program or the tribal transportation program shall be 100 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal lands access program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the Federal lands access program shall be be <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref> up to 100 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transportation Planning.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation planning procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In consultation with the Secretary of each appropriate Federal land management agency, the Secretary shall implement transportation planning procedures for Federal lands and tribal transportation facilities that are consistent with the planning processes required under sections 134 and 135.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of transportation improvement program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The transportation improvement program developed as a part of the transportation planning process under this section shall be approved by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion in other plans</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each regionally significant tribal transportation program, Federal lands transportation program, and Federal lands access program project shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> developed in cooperation with State and metropolitan planning organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> included in appropriate tribal transportation program plans, Federal lands transportation program plans, Federal lands access program plans, State and metropolitan plans, and transportation improvement programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion in state programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The approved tribal transportation program, Federal lands transportation program, and Federal lands access program transportation improvement programs shall be included in appropriate State and metropolitan planning organization plans and programs without further action on the transportation improvement program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Asset management</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary and the Secretary of each appropriate Federal land management agency shall, to the extent appropriate, implement safety, bridge, pavement, and congestion management systems for facilities funded under the tribal transportation program and the Federal lands transportation program in support of asset management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Data collection.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Data collection.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies shall collect and report data necessary to implement the Federal lands transportation program, the Federal lands access program, and the tribal transportation program.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Data collected to implement the tribal transportation program shall be in accordance with the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Data collected under this paragraph includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> inventory and condition information on Federal lands transportation facilities and tribal transportation facilities; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> bridge inspection and inventory information on any Federal bridge open to the public.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies, shall define the collection and reporting data standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal data collection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the data to be collected under subparagraph (A), not later than 90 days after the last day of each fiscal year, any entity carrying out a project under the tribal transportation program under section 202 shall submit to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior, based on obligations and expenditures under the tribal transportation program during the preceding fiscal year, the following data:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The names of projects and activities carried out by the entity under the tribal transportation program during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A description of the projects and activities identified under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The current status of the projects and activities identified under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> An estimate of the number of jobs created and the number of jobs retained by the projects and activities identified under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative research and technology deployment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may conduct cooperative research and technology deployment in coordination with Federal land management agencies, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Funding.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out the activities described in this subsection for Federal lands transportation facilities, Federal lands access transportation facilities, and other federally owned roads open to public travel (as that term is defined in section 125(e)), the Secretary shall for each fiscal year combine and use not greater than 20 percent of the funds authorized for programs under sections 203 and 204.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the activities described in subparagraph (A), funds described under that subparagraph may be used for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> bridge inspections on any federally owned bridge even if that bridge is not included on the inventory described under section 203; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> transportation planning activities carried out by Federal land management agencies eligible for funding under this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursable Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out work under reimbursable agreements with any State, local, or tribal government under this title, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may, without regard to any other provision of law (including regulations), record obligations against accounts receivable from the entity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall credit amounts received from the entity to the appropriate account, which shall occur not later than 90 days after the date of the original request by the Secretary for payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To enable the efficient use of funds made available for the Federal lands transportation program and the Federal lands access program, the funds may be transferred by the Secretary within and between each program with the concurrence of, as appropriate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the affected Secretaries of the respective Federal land management agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> State departments of transportation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> local government agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The funds described in paragraph (1) shall be credited back to the loaning entity with funds that are currently available for obligation at the time of the credit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Alternative Contracting Methods.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including the Federal Acquisition Regulation), a contracting method available to a State under this title may be used by the Secretary, on behalf of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Federal land management agency, in using any funds pursuant to section 203, 204, or 308;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a Federal land management agency, in using any funds pursuant to <ref>section 1535 of title 31</ref> for any of the eligible uses described in sections 203(a)(1) and 204(a)(1) and paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 308(a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a Tribal government, in using funds pursuant to section 202(b)(7)(D).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Methods described</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The contracting methods referred to in paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> project bundling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> bridge bundling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> design-build contracting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 2-phase contracting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> long-term concession agreements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any method tested, or that could be tested, under an experimental program relating to contracting methods carried out by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> affects the application of the Federal share for the project carried out with a contracting method under this subsection; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> modifies the point of obligation of Federal salaries and expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1119(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 473</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 1117(a), 1120, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1356</ref>, 1358; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 11113(a), 11305(a), 11525(<i>l</i>), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 479</ref>, 531, 607.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 202.</num>
<heading> Tribal transportation program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds made available under the tribal transportation program shall be used by the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of the Interior to pay the costs of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> transportation planning, research, maintenance, engineering, rehabilitation, restoration, construction, and reconstruction of tribal transportation facilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> adjacent vehicular parking areas;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> interpretive signage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> acquisition of necessary scenic easements and scenic or historic sites;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> provisions for pedestrians and bicycles;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<chapeau> environmental mitigation in or adjacent to tribal land—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to improve public safety and reduce vehicle-caused wildlife mortality while maintaining habitat connectivity; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to mitigate the damage to wildlife, aquatic organism passage, habitat, and ecosystem connectivity, including the costs of constructing, maintaining, replacing, or removing culverts and bridges, as appropriate;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> construction and reconstruction of roadside rest areas, including sanitary and water facilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> other appropriate public road facilities as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operation and maintenance of transit programs and facilities that are located on, or provide access to, tribal land, or are administered by a tribal government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any transportation project eligible for assistance under this title that is located within, or that provides access to, tribal land, or is associated with a tribal government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In connection with an activity described in paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior may enter into a contract or other appropriate agreement with respect to the activity with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State (including a political subdivision of a State); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indian labor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Indian labor may be employed, in accordance with such rules and regulations as may be promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior, to carry out any construction or other activity described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal employment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No maximum limitation on Federal employment shall be applicable to the construction or improvement of tribal transportation facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds for construction and improvement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All funds made available for the construction and improvement of tribal transportation facilities shall be administered in conformity with regulations and agreements jointly approved by the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated for the tribal transportation program, not more than 5 percent may be used by the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior for program management and oversight and project-related administrative expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal technical assistance centers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior may reserve amounts from administrative funds of the Bureau of Indian Affairs that are associated with the tribal transportation program to fund tribal technical assistance centers under section 504(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Maintenance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, of the amount of funds allocated to an Indian tribe from the tribal transportation program, for the purpose of maintenance (excluding road sealing, which shall not be subject to any limitation), the Secretary shall not use an amount more than the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 25 percent; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $500,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Responsibility of bureau of indian affairs and secretary of the interior.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bureau of indian affairs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Bureau of Indian Affairs shall retain primary responsibility, including annual funding request responsibility, for Bureau of Indian Affairs road maintenance programs on Indian reservations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary of the interior</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior shall ensure that funding made available under this subsection for maintenance of tribal transportation facilities for each fiscal year is supplementary to, and not in lieu of, any obligation of funds by the Bureau of Indian Affairs for road maintenance programs on Indian reservations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tribal-state road maintenance agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An Indian tribe and a State may enter into a road maintenance agreement under which an Indian tribe shall assume the responsibility of the State for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> tribal transportation facilities; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> roads providing access to tribal transportation facilities.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Agreements entered into under clause (i) shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> be negotiated between the State and the Indian tribe; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> not require the approval of the Secretary.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The cooperation of States, counties, or other local subdivisions may be accepted in construction and improvement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds received</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any funds received from a State, county, or local subdivision shall be credited to appropriations available for the tribal transportation program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Competitive bidding.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Construction.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to clause (ii) and subparagraph (B), construction of each project shall be performed by contract awarded by competitive bidding.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Clause (i) shall not apply if the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior affirmatively finds that, under the circumstances relating to the project, a different method is in the public interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), <ref>section 23 of the Act of June 25, 1910</ref> (<ref>25 U.S.C. 47</ref>) and section 7(b) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5307(b)</ref>) shall apply to all funds administered by the Secretary of the Interior that are appropriated for the construction and improvement of tribal transportation facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Funds Distribution.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">National tribal transportation facility inventory.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with the Secretary, shall maintain a comprehensive national inventory of tribal transportation facilities that are eligible for assistance under the tribal transportation program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation facilities included in the inventory</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of identifying the tribal transportation system and determining the relative transportation needs among Indian tribes, the Secretary shall include, at a minimum, transportation facilities that are eligible for assistance under the tribal transportation program that an Indian tribe has requested, including facilities that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> were included in the Bureau of Indian Affairs system inventory prior to <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are owned by an Indian tribal government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> are owned by the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> were constructed or reconstructed with funds from the Highway Trust Fund under the Indian reservation roads program since 1983;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> are public roads or bridges within the exterior boundary of Indian reservations, Alaska Native villages, and other recognized Indian communities (including communities in former Indian reservations in the State of Oklahoma) in which the majority of residents are American Indians or Alaska Natives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> are public roads within or providing access to an Indian reservation or Indian trust land or restricted Indian land that is not subject to fee title alienation without the approval of the Federal Government, or Indian or Alaska Native villages, groups, or communities in which Indians and Alaska Natives reside, whom the Secretary of the Interior has determined are eligible for services generally available to Indians under Federal laws specifically applicable to Indians; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> are primary access routes proposed by tribal governments, including roads between villages, roads to landfills, roads to drinking water sources, roads to natural resources identified for economic development, and roads that provide access to intermodal terminals, such as airports, harbors, or boat landings.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on primary access routes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this paragraph, a proposed primary access route is the shortest practicable route connecting 2 points of the proposed route.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this paragraph precludes the Secretary from including additional transportation facilities that are eligible for funding under the tribal transportation program in the inventory used for the national funding allocation if such additional facilities are included in the inventory in a uniform and consistent manner nationally.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bridges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All bridges in the inventory shall be recorded in the national bridge inventory administered by the Secretary under section 144.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding sections 563(a) and 565(a) of title 5, the Secretary of the Interior shall maintain any regulations governing the tribal transportation program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Basis for funding formula.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Basis.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>After making the set asides authorized under subparagraph (C) and subsections (a)(6), (c), (d), and (e) on October 1 of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall distribute the remainder authorized to be appropriated for the tribal transportation program under this section among Indian tribes as follows:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> For fiscal year 2013—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> for each Indian tribe, 80 percent of the total relative need distribution factor and population adjustment factor for the fiscal year 2011 funding amount made available to that Indian tribe; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the remainder using tribal shares as described in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> For fiscal year 2014—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> for each Indian tribe, 60 percent of the total relative need distribution factor and population adjustment factor for the fiscal year 2011 funding amount made available to that Indian tribe; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the remainder using tribal shares as described in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<chapeau> For fiscal year 2015—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> for each Indian tribe, 40 percent of the total relative need distribution factor and population adjustment factor for the fiscal year 2011 funding amount made available to that Indian tribe; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the remainder using tribal shares as described in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<chapeau> For fiscal year 2016 and thereafter—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> for each Indian tribe, 20 percent of the total relative need distribution factor and population adjustment factor for the fiscal year 2011 funding amount made available to that Indian tribe; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the remainder using tribal shares as described in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal high priority projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The High Priority Projects program as included in the Tribal Transportation Allocation Methodology of part 170 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the MAP–21), shall not continue in effect.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal shares</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Tribal shares under this program shall be determined using the national tribal transportation facility inventory as calculated for fiscal year 2012, and the most recent data on American Indian and Alaska Native population within each Indian tribe’s American Indian/Alaska Native Reservation or Statistical Area, as computed under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.), in the following manner:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 27 percent in the ratio that the total eligible road mileage in each tribe bears to the total eligible road mileage of all American Indians and Alaskan Natives. For the purposes of this calculation, eligible road mileage shall be computed based on the inventory described in paragraph (1), using only facilities included in the inventory described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 39 percent in the ratio that the total population in each tribe bears to the total population of all American Indians and Alaskan Natives.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 34 percent shall be divided equally among each Bureau of Indian Affairs region. Within each region, such share of funds shall be distributed to each Indian tribe in the ratio that the average total relative need distribution factors and population adjustment factors from fiscal years 2005 through 2011 for a tribe bears to the average total of relative need distribution factors and population adjustment factors for fiscal years 2005 through 2011 in that region.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tribal supplemental funding.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal supplemental funding amount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Of funds made available for each fiscal year for the tribal transportation program, the Secretary shall set aside the following amount for a tribal supplemental program:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> If the amount made available for the tribal transportation program is less than or equal to $275,000,000, 30 percent of such amount.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> If the amount made available for the tribal transportation program exceeds $275,000,000—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> $82,500,000; plus</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> 12.5 percent of the amount made available for the tribal transportation program in excess of $275,000,000.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal supplemental allocation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall distribute tribal supplemental funds as follows:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution among regions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the amounts set aside under clause (i), the Secretary shall distribute to each region of the Bureau of Indian Affairs a share of tribal supplemental funds in proportion to the regional total of tribal shares based on the cumulative tribal shares of all Indian tribes within such region under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution within a region</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Of the amount that a region receives under subclause (I), the Secretary shall distribute tribal supplemental funding among Indian tribes within such region as follows:</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal supplemental amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall determine—</chapeau>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(AA)</num>
<content> which such Indian tribes would be entitled under subparagraph (A) to receive in a fiscal year less funding than they would receive in fiscal year 2011 pursuant to the relative need distribution factor and population adjustment factor, as described in subpart C of part 170 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the MAP–21); and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(BB)</num>
<content> the combined amount that such Indian tribes would be entitled to receive in fiscal year 2011 pursuant to such relative need distribution factor and population adjustment factor in excess of the amount that they would be entitled to receive in the fiscal year under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Combined amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subclause (III), the Secretary shall distribute to each Indian tribe that meets the criteria described in item (aa)(AA) a share of funding under this subparagraph in proportion to the share of the combined amount determined under item (aa)(BB) attributable to such Indian tribe.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ceiling</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribe may not receive under subclause (II) and based on its tribal share under subparagraph (A) a combined amount that exceeds the amount that such Indian tribe would be entitled to receive in fiscal year 2011 pursuant to the relative need distribution factor and population adjustment factor, as described in subpart C of part 170 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the MAP–21).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the amount made available for a region under subclause (I) exceeds the amount distributed among Indian tribes within that region under subclause (II), the Secretary shall distribute the remainder of such region’s funding under such subclause among all Indian tribes in that region in proportion to the combined amount that each such Indian tribe received under subparagraph (A) and subclauses (I), (II), and (III).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transferred funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which funds are made available to the Secretary of the Interior under this paragraph, the funds shall be distributed to, and made available for immediate use by, eligible Indian tribes, in accordance with the formula for distribution of funds under the tribal transportation program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, funds made available to Indian tribes for tribal transportation facilities shall be expended on projects identified in a transportation improvement program approved by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Health and safety assurances</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an Indian tribal government may approve plans, specifications, and estimates and commence road and bridge construction with funds made available from the tribal transportation program through a contract or agreement under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.), if the Indian tribal government—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provides assurances in the contract or agreement that the construction will meet or exceed applicable health and safety standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> obtains the advance review of the plans and specifications from a State-licensed civil engineer that has certified that the plans and specifications meet or exceed the applicable health and safety standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provides a copy of the certification under subparagraph (A) to the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Tribal Government Affairs, Department of Transportation, or the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, Department of the Interior, as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contracts and agreements with indian tribes.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or any interagency agreement, program guideline, manual, or policy directive, all funds made available through the Secretary of the Interior under this chapter and section 125(e) for tribal transportation facilities to pay for the costs of programs, services, functions, and activities, or portions of programs, services, functions, or activities, that are specifically or functionally related to the cost of planning, research, engineering, and construction of any tribal transportation facility shall be made available, upon request of the Indian tribal government, to the Indian tribal government for contracts and agreements for such planning, research, engineering, and construction in accordance with <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002017">1</ref> Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of agency participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All funds, including contract support costs, for programs, functions, services, or activities, or portions of programs, services, functions, or activities, including supportive administrative functions that are otherwise contractible to which subparagraph (A) applies, shall be paid in accordance with subparagraph (A), without regard to the organizational level at which the Department of the Interior has previously carried out such programs, functions, services, or activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contracts and agreements with indian tribes.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or any interagency agreement, program guideline, manual, or policy directive, all funds made available to an Indian tribal government under this chapter for a tribal transportation facility program or project shall be made available, on the request of the Indian tribal government, to the Indian tribal government for use in carrying out, in accordance with the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.), contracts and agreements for the planning, research, design, engineering, construction, and maintenance relating to the program or project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of agency participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with subparagraph (A), all funds, including contract support costs, for a program or project to which subparagraph (A) applies shall be paid to the Indian tribal government without regard to the organizational level at which the Department of the Interior has previously carried out, or the Department of Transportation has previously carried out under the tribal transportation program, the programs, functions, services, or activities involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consortia</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Two or more Indian tribes that are otherwise eligible to participate in a program or project to which this chapter applies may form a consortium to be considered as a single Indian tribe for the purpose of participating in the project under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary as signatory</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to enter into a funding agreement with an Indian tribal government to carry out a tribal transportation facility program or project under subparagraph (A) that is located on an Indian reservation or provides access to the reservation or a community of the Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount an Indian tribal government receives for a program or project under subparagraph (A) shall equal the sum of the funding that the Indian tribal government would otherwise receive for the program or project in accordance with the funding formula established under this subsection and such additional amounts as the Secretary determines equal the amounts that would have been withheld for the costs of the Bureau of Indian Affairs for administration of the program or project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligibility.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to clause (ii) and the approval of the Secretary, funds may be made available under subparagraph (A) to an Indian tribal government for a program or project in a fiscal year only if the Indian tribal government requesting such funds demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary financial stability and financial management capability during the 3 fiscal years immediately preceding the fiscal year for which the request is being made.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribal government that had no uncorrected significant and material audit exceptions in the required annual audit of the contracts or self-governance funding agreements made by the Indian tribe with any Federal agency under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.) during the 3-fiscal year period referred in clause (i) shall be conclusive evidence of the financial stability and financial management capability of the Indian tribe for purposes of clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assumption of functions and duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribal government receiving funding under subparagraph (A) for a program or project shall assume all functions and duties that the Secretary of the Interior would have performed with respect to a program or project under this chapter, other than those functions and duties that inherently cannot be legally transferred under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribal government receiving funding under subparagraph (A) for a program or project shall have all powers that the Secretary of the Interior would have exercised in administering the funds transferred to the Indian tribal government for such program or project under this section if the funds had not been transferred, except to the extent that such powers are powers that inherently cannot be legally transferred under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dispute resolution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event of a disagreement between the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior and an Indian tribe over whether a particular function, duty, or power may be lawfully transferred to the Indian tribe under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.), the Indian tribe shall have the right to pursue all alternative dispute resolution and appeal procedures authorized by that Act, including regulations issued to carry out the Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of contract or agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On the date of the termination of a contract or agreement under this section by an Indian tribal government, the Secretary shall transfer all funds that would have been allocated to the Indian tribal government under the contract or agreement to the Secretary of the Interior to provide continued transportation services in accordance with applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Planning.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each fiscal year, not more than 2 percent of the funds made available for the tribal transportation program shall be allocated among Indian tribal governments that apply for transportation planning pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribal government, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior and, as appropriate, with a State, local government, or metropolitan planning organization, shall carry out a transportation planning process in accordance with section 201(c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection and approval of projects</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A project funded under this section shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> selected by the Indian tribal government from the transportation improvement program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to the approval of the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tribal Transportation Facility Bridges.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nationwide priority program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall maintain a nationwide priority program for improving bridges eligible for the tribal transportation program classified as in poor condition, having low load capacity, or needing geometric improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds made available to carry out this subsection shall be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to carry out any planning, design, engineering, preconstruction, construction, and inspection of new or replacement tribal transportation facility bridges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to replace, rehabilitate, seismically retrofit, paint, apply calcium magnesium acetate, sodium acetate/formate, or other environmentally acceptable, minimally corrosive anti-icing and deicing composition; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to implement any countermeasure for tribal transportation facility bridges classified as in poor condition, having a low load capacity, or needing geometric improvements, including multiple-pipe culverts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible bridges</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible to receive funding under this subsection, a bridge described in paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have an opening of not less than 20 feet;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be classified as a tribal transportation facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be classified as in poor condition, having a low load capacity, or needing geometric improvements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may make funds available under this subsection for preliminary engineering, construction, and construction engineering activities after approval of required documentation and verification of eligibility in accordance with this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Safety.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before making any distribution under subsection (b), the Secretary shall set aside not more than 4 percent of the funds made available under the tribal transportation program for each fiscal year to be allocated based on an identification and analysis of highway safety issues and opportunities on tribal land, as determined by the Secretary, on application of the Indian tribal governments for eligible projects described in section 148(a)(4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project selection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribal government, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior and, as appropriate, with a State, local government, or metropolitan planning organization, shall select projects from the transportation improvement program, subject to the approval of the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal-aid Eligible Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before approving as a project on a tribal transportation facility any project eligible for funds apportioned under section 104 in a State, the Secretary shall, for projects on tribal transportation facilities, determine that the obligation of funds for the project is supplementary to and not in lieu of the obligation of a fair and equitable share of funds apportioned to the State under section 104.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1119(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 476</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 1118, 1446(a)(12), <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1358</ref>, 1438; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 11524(c), 11525(m), title IV, §§ 14004, 14008(d), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 606</ref>, 608, 648, 651.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 203.</num>
<heading> Federal lands transportation program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds made available under the Federal lands transportation program shall be used by the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency to pay the costs of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> program administration, transportation planning, research, preventive maintenance, engineering, rehabilitation, restoration, construction, and reconstruction of Federal lands transportation facilities, and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> adjacent vehicular parking areas;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> acquisition of necessary scenic easements and scenic or historic sites;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provision for pedestrians and bicycles;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> environmental mitigation in or adjacent to Federal land open to the public—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to improve public safety and reduce vehicle-caused wildlife mortality while maintaining habitat connectivity; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to mitigate the damage to wildlife, aquatic organism passage, habitat, and ecosystem connectivity, including the costs of constructing, maintaining, replacing, or removing culverts and bridges, as appropriate;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> construction and reconstruction of roadside rest areas, including sanitary and water facilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> congestion mitigation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> other appropriate public road facilities, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> capital, operations, and maintenance of transit facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any transportation project eligible for assistance under this title that is on a public road within or adjacent to, or that provides access to, Federal lands open to the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> not more $20,000,000 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">1</ref> of the amounts made available per fiscal year to carry out this section for activities eligible under subparagraph (A)(iv)(I).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In connection with an activity described in paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency may enter into a contract or other appropriate agreement with respect to the activity with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State (including a political subdivision of a State); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All appropriations for the construction and improvement of Federal lands transportation facilities shall be administered in conformity with regulations and agreements jointly approved by the Secretary and the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land managing agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The cooperation of States, counties, or other local subdivisions may be accepted in construction and improvement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds received</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any funds received from a State, county, or local subdivision shall be credited to appropriations available for the class of Federal lands transportation facilities to which the funds were contributed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Competitive bidding.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraph (B), construction of each project shall be performed by contract awarded by competitive bidding.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the Secretary or the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency affirmatively finds that, under the circumstances relating to the project, a different method is in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Native plant materials</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out an activity described in paragraph (1), the entity carrying out the activity shall consider, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the use of locally adapted native plant materials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> designs that minimize runoff and heat generation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Agency Program Distributions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On <date date="2011-10-01">October 1, 2011</date>, and on October 1 of each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall allocate the sums authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year for the Federal lands transportation program on the basis of applications of need, as determined by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Secretaries of the applicable Federal land management agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in coordination with the transportation plans required under section 201 of the respective transportation systems of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the National Park Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Forest Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Corps of Engineers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Land Management;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Reclamation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> independent Federal agencies with natural resource and land management responsibilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applications.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each application submitted by a Federal land management agency shall include proposed programs at various potential funding levels, as defined by the Secretary following collaborative discussions with applicable Federal land management agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration by secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In evaluating an application submitted under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider the extent to which the programs support performance management, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the transportation goals of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a state of good repair of transportation facilities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a reduction of bridge deficiencies; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> an improvement of safety;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> high-use Federal recreational sites or Federal economic generators; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the resource and asset management goals of the Secretary of the respective Federal land management agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permissive contents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Applications may include proposed programs the duration of which extend over a multiple-year period to support long-term transportation planning and resource management initiatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">National Federal Lands Transportation Facility Inventory.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies, in cooperation with the Secretary, shall maintain a comprehensive national inventory of public Federal lands transportation facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation facilities included in the inventories</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To identify the Federal lands transportation system and determine the relative transportation needs among Federal land management agencies, the inventories shall include, at a minimum, facilities that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide access to high-use Federal recreation sites or Federal economic generators, as determined by the Secretary in coordination with the respective Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> are owned by 1 of the following agencies:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The National Park Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Forest Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Land Management.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The Corps of Engineers.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Reclamation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The inventories shall be made available to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Updates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies shall update the inventories of the appropriate Federal land management agencies, as determined by the Secretary after collaborative discussions with the Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A decision to add or remove a facility from the inventory shall not be considered a Federal action for purposes of review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bicycle Safety</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency shall prohibit the use of bicycles on each federally owned road that has a speed limit of 30 miles per hour or greater and an adjacent paved path for use by bicycles within 100 yards of the road unless the Secretary determines that the bicycle level of service on that roadway is rated B or higher.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Efficient Implementation of NEPA.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Environmental document</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “environmental document” means an environmental impact statement, environmental assessment, categorical exclusion, or other document prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “project” means a highway project, public transportation capital project, or multimodal project that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> receives funds under this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is authorized under this section or section 204.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project sponsor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “project sponsor” means the Federal land management agency that seeks or receives funds under this title for a project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Environmental review to be completed by federal highway administration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Highway Administration may prepare an environmental document pursuant to the implementing procedures of the Federal Highway Administration to comply with the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requested by a project sponsor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all areas of analysis required by the project sponsor can be addressed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal land management agencies adoption of existing environmental review documents.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the maximum extent practicable, if the Federal Highway Administration prepares an environmental document pursuant to paragraph (2), that environmental document shall address all areas of analysis required by a Federal land management agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Independent evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a Federal land management agency shall not be required to conduct an independent evaluation to determine the adequacy of an environmental document prepared by the Federal Highway Administration pursuant to paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of same document</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In authorizing or implementing a project, a Federal land management agency may use an environmental document previously prepared by the Federal Highway Administration for a project addressing the same or substantially the same action to the same extent that the Federal land management agency could adopt or use a document previously prepared by another Federal agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application by federal land management agencies of categorical exclusions established by federal highway administration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) for a project, the project sponsor may use categorical exclusions designated under that Act in the implementing regulations of the Federal Highway Administration, subject to the conditions that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the project sponsor makes a determination, in consultation with the Federal Highway Administration, that the categorical exclusion applies to the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the project satisfies the conditions for a categorical exclusion under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the use of the categorical exclusion does not otherwise conflict with the implementing regulations of the project sponsor, except any list of the project sponsor that designates categorical exclusions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mitigation commitments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall assist the Federal land management agency with all design and mitigation commitments made jointly by the Secretary and the project sponsor in any environmental document prepared by the Secretary in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1119(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 486</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1119</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 11112, 11311, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 479</ref>, 536.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 204.</num>
<heading> Federal lands access program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds made available under the Federal lands access program shall be used by the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency to pay the cost of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> transportation planning, research, engineering, preventive maintenance, rehabilitation, restoration, context-sensitive solutions, construction, and reconstruction of Federal lands access transportation facilities located on or adjacent to, or that provide access to, Federal land, and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> adjacent vehicular parking areas, including interpretive panels in or adjacent to those areas;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> acquisition of necessary scenic easements and scenic or historic sites;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provisions for pedestrians and bicycles;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> environmental mitigation in or adjacent to Federal land to improve public safety and reduce vehicle-caused wildlife mortality while maintaining habitat connectivity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> construction and reconstruction of roadside rest areas, including sanitary and water facilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> contextual wayfinding markers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> landscaping;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> cooperative mitigation of visual blight, including screening or removal; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> other appropriate public road facilities, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operation and maintenance of transit facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any transportation project eligible for assistance under this title that is within or adjacent to, or that provides access to, Federal land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In connection with an activity described in paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency may enter into a contract or other appropriate agreement with respect to the activity with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State (including a political subdivision of a State); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All appropriations for the construction and improvement of Federal lands access transportation facilities shall be administered in conformity with regulations and agreements approved by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The cooperation of States, counties, or other local subdivisions may be accepted in construction and improvement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds received</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any funds received from a State, county, or local subdivision for a Federal lands access transportation facility project shall be credited to appropriations available under the Federal lands access program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Competitive bidding.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraph (B), construction of each project shall be performed by contract awarded by competitive bidding.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the Secretary or the Secretary of the appropriate Federal land management agency affirmatively finds that, under the circumstances relating to the project, a different method is in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Native plant materials</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out an activity described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that the entity carrying out the activity considers, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the use of locally adapted native plant materials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> designs that minimize runoff and heat generation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Program Distributions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funding made available to carry out the Federal lands access program shall be allocated among those States that have Federal land, in accordance with the following formula:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> 80 percent of the available funding for use in those States that contain at least 1 ½ percent of the total public land in the United States managed by the agencies described in paragraph (2), to be distributed as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> 30 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> recreational visitation within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the recreational visitation within all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> 5 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Federal land area within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Federal land area in all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> 55 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Federal public road miles within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Federal public road miles in all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> 10 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of Federal public bridges within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the number of Federal public bridges in all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> 20 percent of the available funding for use in those States that do not contain at least 1 ½ percent of the total public land in the United States managed by the agencies described in paragraph (2), to be distributed as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> 30 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> recreational visitation within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the recreational visitation within all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> 5 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Federal land area within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Federal land area in all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> 55 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Federal public road miles within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Federal public road miles in all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> 10 percent in the ratio that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of Federal public bridges within each such State; bears to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the number of Federal public bridges in all such States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Data source</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Data necessary to distribute funding under paragraph (1) shall be provided by the following Federal land management agencies:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The National Park Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Forest Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Land Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Corps of Engineers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Programming Decisions Committee.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Programming decisions shall be made within each State by a committee comprised of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a representative of the Federal Highway Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a representative of the State Department of Transportation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a representative of any appropriate political subdivision of the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The committee described in paragraph (1) shall cooperate with each applicable Federal agency in each State before any joint discussion or final programming decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project preference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making a programming decision under paragraph (1), the committee shall give preference to projects that provide access to, are adjacent to, or are located within high-use Federal recreation sites or Federal economic generators, as identified by the Secretaries of the appropriate Federal land management agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1119(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 489</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11113(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 205.</num>
<heading> Forest development roads and trails</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Funds available for forest development roads and trails shall be used by the Secretary of Agriculture to pay for the costs of construction and maintenance thereof, including roads and trails on experimental and other areas under Forest Service administration. In connection therewith, the Secretary of Agriculture may enter into contracts with a State or civil subdivision thereof, and issue such regulations as he deems advisable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Cooperation of States, counties, or other local subdivisions may be accepted but shall not be required by the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Construction estimated to cost $50,000 or more per mile or $50,000 or more per project for projects with a length of less than one mile, exclusive of bridges and engineering, shall be advertised and let to contract. If such estimated cost is less than $50,000 per mile or $50,000 per project for projects with a length of less than one mile or if, after proper advertising, no acceptable bid is received or the bids are deemed excessive, the work may be done by the Secretary of Agriculture on his own account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Funds available for forest development roads and trails shall be available for adjacent vehicular parking areas, which may include electric vehicle charging stations or natural gas vehicle refueling stations, and for sanitary, water, and fire control facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–767</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–657, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–423, § 4(d)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-13">Aug. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–495, § 9</ref>, <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 820</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1032(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1975</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1513(c)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 206.</num>
<heading> Recreational trails program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motorized recreation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “motorized recreation” means off-road recreation using any motor-powered vehicle, except for a motorized wheelchair.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recreational trail</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “recreational trail” means a thoroughfare or track across land or snow, used for recreational purposes such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pedestrian activities, including wheelchair use;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> skating or skateboarding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> equestrian activities, including carriage driving;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> nonmotorized snow trail activities, including skiing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> bicycling or use of other human-powered vehicles;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> aquatic or water activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> motorized vehicular activities, including all-terrain vehicle riding, motorcycling, snowmobiling, use of off-road light trucks, or use of other off-road motorized vehicles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall carry out a program to provide and maintain recreational trails.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible for apportionments under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Governor of the State shall designate the State agency or agencies that will be responsible for administering apportionments made to the State under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the State shall establish a State recreational trail advisory committee that represents both motorized and nonmotorized recreational trail users, which shall meet not less often than once per fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Apportioned Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds apportioned to a State to carry out this section shall be obligated for recreational trails and related projects that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have been planned and developed under the laws, policies, and administrative procedures of the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are identified in, or further a specific goal of, a recreational trail plan, or a statewide comprehensive outdoor recreation plan required by chapter 2003 of title 54, that is in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Permissible uses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Permissible uses of funds apportioned to a State for a fiscal year to carry out this section include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maintenance and restoration of existing recreational trails;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> development and rehabilitation of trailside and trailhead facilities and trail linkages for recreational trails;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> purchase and lease of recreational trail construction and maintenance equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> construction of new recreational trails, except that, in the case of new recreational trails crossing Federal lands, construction of the trails shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> permissible under other law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> necessary and recommended by a statewide comprehensive outdoor recreation plan that is required by chapter 2003 of title 54 and that is in effect;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> approved by the administering agency of the State designated under subsection (c)(1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> approved by each Federal agency having jurisdiction over the affected lands under such terms and conditions as the head of the Federal agency determines to be appropriate, except that the approval shall be contingent on compliance by the Federal agency with all applicable laws, including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1600</ref> et seq.), and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<ref>43 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> acquisition of easements and fee simple title to property for recreational trails or recreational trail corridors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> assessment of trail conditions for accessibility and maintenance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> development and dissemination of publications and operation of educational programs to promote safety and environmental protection, (as those objectives relate to one or more of the uses of recreational trails, supporting non-law enforcement trail safety and trail use monitoring patrol programs, and providing trail-related training), but in an amount not to exceed 5 percent of the apportionment made to the State for the fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> payment of costs to the State incurred in administering the program, but in an amount not to exceed 7 percent of the apportionment made to the State for the fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of apportionments.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), of the apportionments made to a State for a fiscal year to carry out this section—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 40 percent shall be used for recreational trail or related projects that facilitate diverse recreational trail use within a recreational trail corridor, trailside, or trailhead, regardless of whether the project is for diverse motorized use, for diverse nonmotorized use, or to accommodate both motorized and nonmotorized recreational trail use;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 30 percent shall be used for uses relating to motorized recreation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> 30 percent shall be used for uses relating to nonmotorized recreation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Small state exclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any State with a total land area of less than 3,500,000 acres shall be exempt from the requirements of clauses (ii) and (iii) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State administrative costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>State administrative costs eligible for funding under paragraph (2)(H) shall be exempt from the requirements of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Grants.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State may use funds apportioned to the State to carry out this section to make grants to private organizations, municipal, county, State, and Federal Government entities, and other government entities as approved by the State after considering guidance from the State recreational trail advisory committee established under subsection (c)(2), for uses consistent with this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State that makes grants under subparagraph (A) shall establish measures to verify that recipients of the grants comply with the conditions of the program for the use of grant funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Environmental Benefit or Mitigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent practicable and consistent with the other requirements of this section, a State should give consideration to project proposals that provide for the redesign, reconstruction, nonroutine maintenance, or relocation of recreational trails to benefit the natural environment or to mitigate and minimize the impact to the natural environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal Share.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the other provisions of this subsection, the Federal share of the cost of a project and the Federal share of the administrative costs of a State under this section shall be determined in accordance with section 120(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal agency project sponsor</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a Federal agency that sponsors a project under this section may contribute additional Federal funds toward the cost of a project, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the share attributable to the Secretary of Transportation may not exceed the amount determined in accordance with section 120(b) for the cost of a project under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the share attributable to the Secretary and the Federal agency sponsoring the project may not exceed 95 percent of the cost of a project under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of funds from federal programs to provide non-federal share</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the non-Federal share of the cost of the project may include amounts made available by the Federal Government under any Federal program that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expended in accordance with the requirements of the Federal program relating to activities funded and populations served; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> expended on a project that is eligible for assistance under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of recreational trails program funds to match other federal program funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds made available under this section may be used toward the non-Federal matching share for other Federal program funds that are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expended in accordance with the requirements of the Federal program relating to activities funded and populations served; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> expended on a project that is eligible for assistance under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programmatic non-federal share</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State may allow adjustments to the non-Federal share of an individual project for a fiscal year under this section if the Federal share of the cost of all projects carried out by the State under the program (excluding projects funded under paragraph (2) or (3)) using funds apportioned to the State for the fiscal year does not exceed the Federal share as determined in accordance with section 120(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Uses Not Permitted</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A State may not obligate funds apportioned to carry out this section for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> condemnation of any kind of interest in property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> construction of any recreational trail on National Forest System land for any motorized use unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the land has been designated for uses other than wilderness by an approved forest land and resource management plan or has been released to uses other than wilderness by an Act of Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the construction is otherwise consistent with the management direction in the approved forest land and resource management plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> construction of any recreational trail on Bureau of Land Management land for any motorized use unless the land—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has been designated for uses other than wilderness by an approved Bureau of Land Management resource management plan or has been released to uses other than wilderness by an Act of Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the construction is otherwise consistent with the management direction in the approved management plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> upgrading, expanding, or otherwise facilitating motorized use or access to recreational trails predominantly used by nonmotorized recreational trail users and on which, as of <date date="1991-05-01">May 1, 1991</date>, motorized use was prohibited or had not occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Project Administration.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Credit for donations of funds, materials, services, or new right-of-way.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this title or other law shall prevent a project sponsor from offering to donate funds, materials, services, or a new right-of-way for the purposes of a project eligible for assistance under this section. Any funds, or the fair market value of any materials, services, or new right-of-way, may be donated by any project sponsor and shall be credited to the non-Federal share in accordance with subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal project sponsors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any funds or the fair market value of any materials or services may be provided by a Federal project sponsor and shall be credited to the Federal agency’s share in accordance with subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Planning and environmental assessment costs incurred prior to project approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may allow preapproval planning and environmental compliance costs to be credited toward the non-Federal share of the cost of a project described in subsection (d)(2) (other than subparagraph (H)) in accordance with subsection (f), limited to costs incurred less than 18 months prior to project approval.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recreational purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A project funded under this section is intended to enhance recreational opportunity and is not subject to <ref>section 138 of this title</ref> or <ref>section 303 of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuing recreational use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the option of each State, funds apportioned to the State to carry out this section may be treated as Land and Water Conservation Fund apportionments for the purposes of <ref>section 200305(f)(3) of title 54</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperation by private persons.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Written assurances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a condition of making available apportionments for work on recreational trails that would affect privately owned land, a State shall obtain written assurances that the owner of the land will cooperate with the State and participate as necessary in the activities to be conducted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public access</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any use of the apportionments to a State to carry out this section on privately owned land must be accompanied by an easement or other legally binding agreement that ensures public access to the recreational trail improvements funded by the apportionments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds authorized to carry out this section shall be available for obligation in the same manner as if the funds were apportioned under chapter 1, except that the Federal share of the cost of a project under this section shall be determined in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Other Apportioned Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds apportioned to a State under section 104(b) that are obligated for a recreational trail or a related project shall be administered as if the funds were made available to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 146</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1109(b)</ref>–(e), <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1168–1170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–244, title I, § 101(q)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-06">June 6, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3268</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 11134, 11525(n), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 515</ref>, 608.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 207.</num>
<heading> Tribal transportation self-governance program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the requirements of this section, the Secretary shall establish and carry out a program to be known as the tribal transportation self-governance program. The Secretary may delegate responsibilities for administration of the program as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligibility.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), an Indian tribe shall be eligible to participate in the program if the Indian tribe requests participation in the program by resolution or other official action by the governing body of the Indian tribe, and demonstrates, for the preceding 3 fiscal years, financial stability and financial management capability, and transportation program management capability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for determining financial stability and financial management capacity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purposes of paragraph (1), evidence that, during the preceding 3 fiscal years, an Indian tribe had no uncorrected significant and material audit exceptions in the required annual audit of the Indian tribe’s self-determination contracts or self-governance funding agreements with any Federal agency shall be conclusive evidence of the required financial stability and financial management capability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for determining transportation program management capability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall require an Indian tribe to demonstrate transportation program management capability, including the capability to manage and complete projects eligible under this title and projects eligible under chapter 53 of title 49, to gain eligibility for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compacts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compact required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the request of an eligible Indian tribe, and subject to the requirements of this section, the Secretary shall negotiate and enter into a written compact with the Indian tribe for the purpose of providing for the participation of the Indian tribe in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A compact entered into under paragraph (1) shall set forth the general terms of the government-to-government relationship between the Indian tribe and the United States under the program and other terms that will continue to apply in future fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amendments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A compact entered into with an Indian tribe under paragraph (1) may be amended only by mutual agreement of the Indian tribe and the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Funding Agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding agreement required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After entering into a compact with an Indian tribe under subsection (c), the Secretary shall negotiate and enter into a written annual funding agreement with the Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contents.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Formula funding and discretionary grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A funding agreement entered into with an Indian tribe shall authorize the Indian tribe, as determined by the Indian tribe, to plan, conduct, consolidate, administer, and receive full tribal share funding, tribal transit formula funding, and funding to tribes from discretionary and competitive grants administered by the Department for all programs, services, functions, and activities (or portions thereof) that are made available to Indian tribes to carry out tribal transportation programs and programs, services, functions, and activities (or portions thereof) administered by the Secretary that are otherwise available to Indian tribes.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfers of state funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of transferred funds in funding agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A funding agreement entered into with an Indian tribe shall include Federal-aid funds apportioned to a State under chapter 1 if the State elects to provide a portion of such funds to the Indian tribe for a project eligible under section 202(a). The provisions of this section shall be in addition to the methods for making funding contributions described in section 202(a)(9). Nothing in this section shall diminish the authority of the Secretary to provide funds to an Indian tribe under section 202(a)(9).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Method for transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a State elects to provide funds described in subclause (I) to an Indian tribe—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the transfer may occur in accordance with section 202(a)(9); or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the State shall transfer the funds back to the Secretary and the Secretary shall transfer the funds to the Indian tribe in accordance with this section.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for transferred funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a State provides funds described in subclause (I) to an Indian tribe—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the State shall not be responsible for constructing or maintaining a project carried out using the funds or for administering or supervising the project or funds during the applicable statute of limitations period related to the construction of the project; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the Indian tribe shall be responsible for constructing and maintaining a project carried out using the funds and for administering and supervising the project and funds in accordance with this section during the applicable statute of limitations period related to the construction of the project.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of tribal shares</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The tribal shares referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be provided without regard to the agency or office of the Department within which the program, service, function, or activity (or portion thereof) is performed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Flexible and innovative financing.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A funding agreement entered into with an Indian tribe under paragraph (1) shall include provisions pertaining to flexible and innovative financing if agreed upon by the parties.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Terms and conditions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to issue regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may issue regulations to establish the terms and conditions relating to the flexible and innovative financing provisions referred to in clause (i).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and conditions in absence of regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Secretary does not issue regulations under subclause (I), the terms and conditions relating to the flexible and innovative financing provisions referred to in clause (i) shall be consistent with—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<chapeau> agreements entered into by the Department under—</chapeau>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(AA)</num>
<content> section 202(b)(7); and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent6">
<num>(BB)</num>
<content> section 202(d)(5), as in effect before the date of enactment of MAP–21 (<ref>Public Law 112–141</ref>); or</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> regulations of the Department of the Interior relating to flexible financing contained in part 170 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of the FAST Act.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A funding agreement shall set forth—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> terms that generally identify the programs, services, functions, and activities (or portions thereof) to be performed or administered by the Indian tribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for items identified in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the general budget category assigned;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the funds to be provided, including those funds to be provided on a recurring basis;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the time and method of transfer of the funds;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the responsibilities of the Secretary and the Indian tribe; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any other provision agreed to by the Indian tribe and the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Subsequent funding agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of existing agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Absent notification from an Indian tribe that the Indian tribe is withdrawing from or retroceding the operation of 1 or more programs, services, functions, or activities (or portions thereof) identified in a funding agreement, or unless otherwise agreed to by the parties, each funding agreement shall remain in full force and effect until a subsequent funding agreement is executed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective date of subsequent agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms of the subsequent funding agreement shall be retroactive to the end of the term of the preceding funding agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consent of indian tribe required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall not revise, amend, or require additional terms in a new or subsequent funding agreement without the consent of the Indian tribe that is subject to the agreement unless such terms are required by Federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">General Provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Redesign and consolidation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An Indian tribe, in any manner that the Indian tribe considers to be in the best interest of the Indian community being served, may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> redesign or consolidate programs, services, functions, and activities (or portions thereof) included in a funding agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> reallocate or redirect funds for such programs, services, functions, and activities (or portions thereof), if the funds are—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> expended on projects identified in a transportation improvement program approved by the Secretary; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> used in accordance with the requirements in—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> appropriations Acts;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> this title and chapter 53 of title 49; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> any other applicable law.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), if, pursuant to subsection (d), an Indian tribe receives a discretionary or competitive grant from the Secretary or receives State apportioned funds, the Indian tribe shall use the funds for the purpose for which the funds were originally authorized.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Retrocession.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of indian tribes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribe may retrocede (fully or partially) to the Secretary programs, services, functions, or activities (or portions thereof) included in a compact or funding agreement.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reassumption of remaining funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Following a retrocession described in clause (i), the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> reassume the remaining funding associated with the retroceded programs, functions, services, and activities (or portions thereof) included in the applicable compact or funding agreement;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> out of such remaining funds, transfer funds associated with Department of Interior programs, services, functions, or activities (or portions thereof) to the Secretary of the Interior to carry out transportation services provided by the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> distribute funds not transferred under subclause (II) in accordance with applicable law.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Correction of programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary makes a finding under subsection (f)(2)(B) and no funds are available under subsection (f)(2)(A)(ii), the Secretary shall not be required to provide additional funds to complete or correct any programs, functions, services, or activities (or portions thereof).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Unless the Indian tribe rescinds a request for retrocession, the retrocession shall become effective within the timeframe specified by the parties in the compact or funding agreement. In the absence of such a specification, the retrocession shall become effective on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 1 year after the date of submission of the request; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the date on which the funding agreement expires; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such date as may be mutually agreed upon by the parties and, with respect to Department of the Interior programs, functions, services, and activities (or portions thereof), the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Provisions Relating to Secretary.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decisionmaker</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A decision that relates to an appeal of the rejection of a final offer by the Department shall be made either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by an official of the Department who holds a position at a higher organizational level within the Department than the level of the departmental agency in which the decision that is the subject of the appeal was made; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by an administrative judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Termination of compact or funding agreement.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority to terminate.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision to be included in compact or funding agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A compact or funding agreement shall include a provision authorizing the Secretary, if the Secretary makes a finding described in subparagraph (B), to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> terminate the compact or funding agreement (or a portion thereof); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> reassume the remaining funding associated with the reassumed programs, functions, services, and activities included in the compact or funding agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Out of any funds reassumed under clause (i)(II), the Secretary may transfer the funds associated with Department of the Interior programs, functions, services, and activities (or portions thereof) to the Secretary of the Interior to provide continued transportation services in accordance with applicable law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Findings resulting in termination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The finding referred to in subparagraph (A) is a specific finding of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> imminent jeopardy to a trust asset, natural resources, or public health and safety that is caused by an act or omission of the Indian tribe and that arises out of a failure to carry out the compact or funding agreement, as determined by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement with respect to funds or programs transferred to the Indian tribe under the compact or funding agreement, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department, as appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall not terminate a compact or funding agreement (or portion thereof) unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary has first provided written notice and a hearing on the record to the Indian tribe that is subject to the compact or funding agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Indian tribe has not taken corrective action to remedy the mismanagement of funds or programs or the imminent jeopardy to a trust asset, natural resource, or public health and safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subparagraph (C), the Secretary, upon written notification to an Indian tribe that is subject to a compact or funding agreement, may immediately terminate the compact or funding agreement (or portion thereof) if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Secretary makes a finding of imminent substantial and irreparable jeopardy to a trust asset, natural resource, or public health and safety; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the jeopardy arises out of a failure to carry out the compact or funding agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hearings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary terminates a compact or funding agreement (or portion thereof) under clause (i), the Secretary shall provide the Indian tribe subject to the compact or agreement with a hearing on the record not later than 10 days after the date of such termination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Burden of proof</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any hearing or appeal involving a decision to terminate a compact or funding agreement (or portion thereof) under this paragraph, the Secretary shall have the burden of proof in demonstrating by clear and convincing evidence the validity of the grounds for the termination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cost Principles</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In administering funds received under this section, an Indian tribe shall apply cost principles under the applicable Office of Management and Budget circular, except as modified by section 106 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5325</ref>), other provisions of law, or by any exemptions to applicable Office of Management and Budget circulars subsequently granted by the Office of Management and Budget. No other audit or accounting standards shall be required by the Secretary. Any claim by the Federal Government against the Indian tribe relating to funds received under a funding agreement based on any audit conducted pursuant to this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of section 106(f) of that Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5325(f)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall provide funds to an Indian tribe under a funding agreement in an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the sum of the funding that the Indian tribe would otherwise receive for the program, function, service, or activity in accordance with a funding formula or other allocation method established under this title or chapter 53 of title 49; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such additional amounts as the Secretary determines equal the amounts that would have been withheld for the costs of the Bureau of Indian Affairs for administration of the program or project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Construction Programs.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Construction projects carried out under programs administered by an Indian tribe with funds transferred to the Indian tribe pursuant to a funding agreement entered into under this section shall be constructed pursuant to the construction program standards set forth in applicable regulations or as specifically approved by the Secretary (or the Secretary’s designee).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Monitoring</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Construction programs shall be monitored by the Secretary in accordance with applicable regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Facilitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretarial interpretation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary shall interpret all Federal laws, Executive orders, and regulations in a manner that will facilitate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the inclusion of programs, services, functions, and activities (or portions thereof) and funds associated therewith, in compacts and funding agreements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the implementation of the compacts and funding agreements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulation waiver.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Indian tribe may submit to the Secretary a written request to waive application of a regulation promulgated under this section with respect to a compact or funding agreement. The request shall identify the regulation sought to be waived and the basis for the request.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Approvals and denials.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 90 days after the date of receipt of a written request under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall approve or deny the request in writing.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall review any application by an Indian tribe for a waiver bearing in mind increasing opportunities for using flexible policy approaches at the Indian tribal level.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deemed approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary does not approve or deny a request submitted under subparagraph (A) on or before the last day of the 90-day period referred to in clause (i), the request shall be deemed approved.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Denials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the application for a waiver is not granted, the agency shall provide the applicant with the reasons for the denial as part of the written response required in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Finality of decisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A decision by the Secretary under this subparagraph shall be final for the Department.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Disclaimers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon the election of an Indian tribe, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maintain current tribal transportation program funding agreements and program agreements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enter into new agreements under the authority of section 202(b)(7).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on statutory construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to impair or diminish the authority of the Secretary under section 202(b)(7).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except to the extent in conflict with this section (as determined by the Secretary), the following provisions of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act shall apply to compact and funding agreements (except that any reference to the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Health and Human Services in such provisions shall be treated as a reference to the Secretary of Transportation):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subsections (a), (b), (d), (g), and (h) of section 506 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5386</ref>), relating to general provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subsections (b) through (e) and (g) of section 507 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5387</ref>), relating to provisions relating to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Subsections (a), (b), (d), (e), (g), (h), (i), and (k) of section 508 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5388</ref>), relating to transfer of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Section 510 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5390</ref>), relating to Federal procurement laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Section 511 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5391</ref>), relating to civil actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Subsections (a)(1), (a)(2), and (c) through (f) of section 512 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5392</ref>), relating to facilitation, except that subsection (c)(1) of that section shall be applied by substituting “transportation facilities and other facilities” for “school buildings, hospitals, and other facilities”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Subsections (a) and (b) of section 515 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5395</ref>), relating to disclaimers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Subsections (a) and (b) of section 516 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5396</ref>), relating to application of title I provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Section 518 of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5398</ref>), relating to appeals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Definitions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply (except as otherwise expressly provided):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compact</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “compact” means a compact between the Secretary and an Indian tribe entered into under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Department” means the Department of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible indian tribe</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “eligible Indian tribe” means an Indian tribe that is eligible to participate in the program, as determined under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “funding agreement” means a funding agreement between the Secretary and an Indian tribe entered into under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indian tribe</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or community that is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians. In any case in which an Indian tribe has authorized another Indian tribe, an intertribal consortium, or a tribal organization to plan for or carry out programs, services, functions, or activities (or portions thereof) on its behalf under this section, the authorized Indian tribe, intertribal consortium, or tribal organization shall have the rights and responsibilities of the authorizing Indian tribe (except as otherwise provided in the authorizing resolution or in this title). In such event, the term “Indian tribe” as used in this section shall include such other authorized Indian tribe, intertribal consortium, or tribal organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “program” means the tribal transportation self-governance program established under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “transportation programs” means all programs administered or financed by the Department under this title and chapter 53 of title 49.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of other definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the definitions set forth in sections 4 and 501 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 5304</ref>; 5381) apply, except as otherwise expressly provided in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promulgation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the FAST Act, the Secretary shall initiate procedures under subchapter III of chapter 5 of title 5 to negotiate and promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication of proposed regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Proposed regulations to implement this section shall be published in the Federal Register by the Secretary not later than 42 months after such date of enactment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expiration of authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to promulgate regulations under subparagraph (A) shall expire 48 months after such date of enactment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension of deadlines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A deadline set forth in subparagraph (B) or (C) may be extended up to 180 days if the negotiated rulemaking committee referred to in paragraph (2) concludes that the committee cannot meet the deadline and the Secretary so notifies the appropriate committees of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Committee.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A negotiated rulemaking committee established pursuant to <ref>section 565 of title 5</ref> to carry out this subsection shall have as its members only Federal and tribal government representatives, a majority of whom shall be nominated by and be representatives of Indian tribes with funding agreements under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The committee shall confer with, and accommodate participation by, representatives of Indian tribes, inter-tribal consortia, tribal organizations, and individual tribal members.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adaptation of procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall adapt the negotiated rulemaking procedures to the unique context of self-governance and the government-to-government relationship between the United States and Indian tribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading> Effect.—</heading>
<content>The lack of promulgated regulations shall not limit the effect of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of circulars, policies, manuals, guidance, and rules</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless expressly agreed to by the participating Indian tribe in the compact or funding agreement, the participating Indian tribe shall not be subject to any agency circular, policy, manual, guidance, or rule adopted by the Department, except regulations promulgated under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1121(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1359</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–235, § 1</ref>, <date date="2018-08-14">Aug. 14, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11525</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 208.</num>
<heading> Safe routes to school</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In the vicinity of schools</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “in the vicinity of schools”, with respect to a school, means the approximately 2-mile area within bicycling and walking distance of the school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Primary, middle, and high schools</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “primary, middle, and high schools” means schools providing education from kindergarten through 12th grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the requirements of this section, the Secretary shall establish and carry out a safe routes to school program for the benefit of children in primary, middle, and high schools.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of the program established under subsection (b) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to enable and encourage children, including those with disabilities, to walk and bicycle to school;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to make bicycling and walking to school a safer and more appealing transportation alternative, thereby encouraging a healthy and active lifestyle from an early age; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to facilitate the planning, development, and implementation of projects and activities that will improve safety and reduce traffic, fuel consumption, and air pollution in the vicinity of schools.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Apportionment of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year shall be apportioned among the States so that each State receives the amount equal to the proportion that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the total student enrollment in primary, middle, and high schools in each State; bears to</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total student enrollment in primary, middle, and high schools in all States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum apportionment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No State shall receive an apportionment under this section for a fiscal year of less than $1,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Set-aside for administrative expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before apportioning under this subsection amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall set aside not more than $3,000,000 of those amounts for the administrative expenses of the Secretary in carrying out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of student enrollments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Determinations under this subsection relating to student enrollments shall be made by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts apportioned to a State under this section shall be administered by the State department of transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Recipients</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts apportioned to a State under this section shall be used by the State to provide financial assistance to State, local, Tribal, and regional agencies, including nonprofit organizations, that demonstrate an ability to meet the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligible Projects and Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Infrastructure-related projects.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts apportioned to a State under this section may be used for the planning, design, and construction of infrastructure-related projects that will substantially improve the ability of students to walk and bicycle to school, including sidewalk improvements, traffic calming and speed reduction improvements, pedestrian and bicycle crossing improvements, on-street bicycle facilities, off-street bicycle and pedestrian facilities, secure bicycle parking facilities, and traffic diversion improvements in the vicinity of schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Location of projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Infrastructure-related projects under subparagraph (A) may be carried out on any public road or any bicycle or pedestrian pathway or trail in the vicinity of schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Noninfrastructure-related activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to projects described in paragraph (1), amounts apportioned to a State under this section may be used for noninfrastructure-related activities to encourage walking and bicycling to school, including public awareness campaigns and outreach to press and community leaders, traffic education and enforcement in the vicinity of schools, student sessions on bicycle and pedestrian safety, health, and environment, and funding for training, volunteers, and managers of safe routes to school programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less than 10 percent and not more than 30 percent of the amount apportioned to a State under this section for a fiscal year shall be used for noninfrastructure-related activities under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safe routes to school coordinator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each State shall use a sufficient amount of the apportionment of the State for each fiscal year to fund a full-time position of coordinator of the safe routes to school program of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Clearinghouse.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall make grants to a national nonprofit organization engaged in promoting safe routes to schools—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to operate a national safe routes to school clearinghouse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to develop information and educational programs on safe routes to school; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to provide technical assistance and disseminate techniques and strategies used for successful safe routes to school programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall carry out this subsection using amounts set aside for administrative expenses under subsection (d)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a project assisted under this section shall be treated as a project on a Federal-aid highway under chapter 1.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11119(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 209.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 126(d)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2115</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 210.</num>
<heading> Defense access roads</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorization.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When defense access roads are certified to the Secretary as important to the national defense by the Secretary of Defense or such other official as the President may designate, the Secretary is authorized, out of the funds appropriated for defense access roads, to provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the construction and maintenance of defense access roads (including bridges, tubes, tunnels, and culverts or other hydraulic appurtenances on those roads) to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> military reservations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> defense industry sites;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> air or sea ports that are necessary for or are planned to be used for the deployment or sustainment of members of the Armed Forces, equipment, or supplies; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> sources of raw materials;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reconstruction or enhancement of, or improvements to, those roads to ensure the continued effective use of the roads, regardless of current or projected increases in mean tides, recurrent flooding, or other weather-related conditions or natural disasters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> replacing existing highways and highway connections that are shut off from general public use by necessary closures, closures due to mean sea level fluctuation and flooding, or restrictions at—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> military reservations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> air or sea ports that are necessary for or are planned to be used for the deployment or sustainment of members of the Armed Forces, equipment, or supplies; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> defense industry sites.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If it is determined that an action of the Department of Defense will cause a significant transportation impact to access to a military reservation, the Secretary of Defense shall conduct a transportation needs assessment to assess the magnitude of the improvement required to address the impact. The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall determine the magnitude of the required improvements without regard to the extent to which traffic generated by the reservation is greater than other traffic in the vicinity of the reservation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Funds appropriated for the purposes of this section shall be available, without regard to apportionment among the several States, for paying all or any part of the cost of construction, reconstruction, resurfacing, restoration, rehabilitation, and preservation of, or enhancements to, defense access roads.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Funds appropriated for defense maneuvers and exercises, may be used by the Secretary in areas certified to the Secretary by the Secretary of Defense as maneuver areas for such activities for construction, maintenance, reconstruction, enhancement, improvement, and repair as may be necessary to keep the highways in those areas, which have been or may be used for training of the Armed Forces, in suitable condition for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> repairing the damage to those highways caused by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> weather-related events, increases in mean high tide levels, recurrent flooding, or natural disasters; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the operations of men and equipment in such training.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Whenever any project for the construction of a circumferential highway around a city or of a radial intracity route thereto submitted by any State is certified by the Secretary of Defense, or such other official as the President may designate, as being important for civilian or military defense, such project may be constructed out of the funds heretofore or hereafter authorized to be appropriated for defense access roads.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the Secretary shall determine that the State transportation department of any State is unable to obtain possession and the right to enter upon and use the required rights-of-way, lands, or interest in lands, improved or unimproved, required for any project authorized by this section with sufficient promptness, the Secretary is authorized to acquire, enter upon, take possession thereof, and expend funds for projects thereon, prior to approval of title by the Attorney General, in the name of the United States, such rights-of-way, lands, or interest in lands as may be required in such State for such projects by purchase, donation, condemnation, or otherwise in accordance with the laws of the United States (including sections 3114 to 3116 and 3118 of title 40). The cost incurred by the Secretary in acquiring any such rights-of-way, lands, or interest in lands may include the cost of examination and abstract of title, certificate of title, advertising, and any fees incidental to such acquisition; and shall be payable out of the funds available for paying the cost or the Federal share of the cost of the project for which such rights-of-way, lands, or interests in lands are acquired. The Secretary is further authorized and directed by proper deed executed in the name of the United States to convey any lands or interests in lands acquired in any State under the provisions of prior Acts or of this section to the State transportation department of such State or to such political subdivision thereof as its laws may provide, upon such terms and conditions as may be agreed upon by the Secretary and the State transportation department, or political subdivisions to which the conveyance is to be made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The provisions of <ref>section 112 of this title</ref> are applicable to defense access roads.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> If the Secretary shall determine that it is necessary for the expeditious completion of any defense access road project the Secretary may advance to any State out of funds appropriated for defense access roads transferred and available to the Department of Transportation the Federal share of the cost of construction thereof to enable the State transportation department to make prompt payments for acquisition of rights-of-way, and for the construction as it progresses. The sums so advanced shall be deposited in a special fund by the State official authorized by State law to receive such funds, to be disbursed solely upon vouchers approved by the State transportation department for rights-of-way which have been or are being acquired and for construction and other activities actually performed under this section. Upon determination by the Secretary that funds advanced to any State under the provisions of this subsection are no longer required, the amount of the advance which is determined to be in excess of requirements for the project shall be repaid upon demand by the Secretary, and such repayments shall be returned to the credit of the appropriation from which the funds were advanced.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Funds appropriated for the purposes of this section shall be available to pay the cost of repairing damage caused to highways by the operation of vehicles and equipment in the construction of classified military installations and facilities for ballistic missiles if the Secretary shall determine that the State transportation department of any State is, or has been, unable to prevent such damage by restrictions upon the use of such highways without interference with, or delay in, the completion of a contract for the construction of such military reservations or installations. This subsection shall apply notwithstanding any provision of contract holding a party thereto responsible for such damage, if the Secretary of Defense or his designee shall determine, in fact, that construction estimates and the bid of such party did not include allowance for repairing such damage. This subsection shall apply to damage caused by construction work commenced prior to <date date="1961-06-01">June 1, 1961</date>, and still in progress on that date and construction work which is commenced or for which a contract is awarded on or after <date date="1961-06-01">June 1, 1961</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repair of Certain Damages and Infrastructure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The funds appropriated to carry out this section may be used to pay the cost of repairing damage caused, or any infrastructure to mitigate a risk posed, to a defense access road by recurrent or projected recurrent flooding, sea level fluctuation, a natural disaster, or any other current or projected change in applicable environmental conditions, if the Secretary determines that continued access to a military installation, defense industry site, air or sea port necessary for or planned to be used for the deployment or sustainment of members of the Armed Forces, equipment, or supplies, or to a source of raw materials, has been or is projected to be impacted by those events or conditions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–767</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–657, § 8(d)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–61, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1961-06-29">June 29, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 155</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2134</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 133(b)(15)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 172</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1212(a)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 193</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 3(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1211</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2816(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1689</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1516</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2865</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2808</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1885</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 211.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 133(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 173</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 212.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1519(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 575</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 213.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1109(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1343</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 214.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1119(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 491</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 215.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1114(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 468</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 216.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1519(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 575</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 217.</num>
<heading> Bicycle transportation and pedestrian walkways</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of STP and Congestion Mitigation Program Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to project approval by the Secretary, a State may obligate funds apportioned to it under sections 104(b)(2) and 104(b)(4) of this title for construction of pedestrian walkways and bicycle and shared micromobility transportation facilities and for carrying out nonconstruction projects related to safe access for bicyclists and pedestrians.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of National Highway Performance Program Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to project approval by the Secretary, a State may obligate funds apportioned to it under <ref>section 104(b)(1) of this title</ref> for construction of pedestrian walkways and bicycle transportation facilities on land adjacent to any highway on the National Highway System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Federal Lands Highway Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds authorized for forest highways, forest development roads and trails, public lands development roads and trails, park roads, parkways, Indian reservation roads, and public lands highways shall be available, at the discretion of the department charged with the administration of such funds, for the construction of pedestrian walkways and bicycle transportation facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Bicycle and Pedestrian Coordinators</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each State receiving an apportionment under sections 104(b)(2) and 104(b)(4) of this title shall use such amount of the apportionment as may be necessary to fund in the State department of transportation up to 2 positions of bicycle and pedestrian coordinator for promoting and facilitating the increased use of nonmotorized modes of transportation, including developing facilities for the use of pedestrians and bicyclists and public education, promotional, and safety programs for using such facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bridges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case where a highway bridge deck being replaced or rehabilitated with Federal financial participation is located on a highway on which pedestrians or bicyclists are permitted to operate at each end of such bridge, and the Secretary determines that the safe accommodation of pedestrians or bicyclists can be provided at reasonable cost as part of such replacement or rehabilitation, then such bridge shall be so replaced or rehabilitated as to provide such safe accommodations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Share</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For all purposes of this title, construction of a pedestrian walkway or a bicycle or shared micromobility transportation facility shall be deemed to be a highway project and the Federal share payable on account of such construction shall be determined in accordance with section 120(b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Planning and Design.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Bicyclists and pedestrians shall be given due consideration in the comprehensive transportation plans developed by each metropolitan planning organization and State in accordance with sections 134 and 135, respectively. Bicycle transportation facilities and pedestrian walkways shall be considered, where appropriate, in conjunction with all new construction and reconstruction of transportation facilities, except where bicycle and pedestrian use are not permitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Transportation plans and projects shall provide due consideration for safety and contiguous routes for bicyclists and pedestrians. Safety considerations shall include the installation, where appropriate, and maintenance of audible traffic signals and audible signs at street crossings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Motorized Vehicles</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Motorized vehicles may not be permitted on trails and pedestrian walkways under this section, except for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintenance purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when snow conditions and State or local regulations permit, snowmobiles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> motorized wheelchairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> when State or local regulations permit, electric bicycles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> such other circumstances as the Secretary deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No bicycle project may be carried out under this section unless the Secretary has determined that such bicycle project will be principally for transportation, rather than recreation, purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bicycle transportation facility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “bicycle transportation facility” means a new or improved lane, path, or shoulder for use by bicyclists and a traffic control device, shelter, or parking facility for bicycles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Electric bicycle.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “electric bicycle” means a bicycle—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> equipped with fully operable pedals, a saddle or seat for the rider, and an electric motor of less than 750 watts;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that can safely share a bicycle transportation facility with other users of such facility; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that is a class 1 electric bicycle, class 2 electric bicycle, or class 3 electric bicycle.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Classes of electric bicycles.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Class 1 electric bicycle</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii), the term “class 1 electric bicycle” means an electric bicycle, other than a class 3 electric bicycle, equipped with a motor that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> provides assistance only when the rider is pedaling; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ceases to provide assistance when the speed of the bicycle reaches or exceeds 20 miles per hour.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Class 2 electric bicycle</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii), the term “class 2 electric bicycle” means an electric bicycle equipped with a motor that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> may be used exclusively to propel the bicycle; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is not capable of providing assistance when the speed of the bicycle reaches or exceeds 20 miles per hour.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Class 3 electric bicycle</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii), the term “class 3 electric bicycle” means an electric bicycle equipped with a motor that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> provides assistance only when the rider is pedaling; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ceases to provide assistance when the speed of the bicycle reaches or exceeds 28 miles per hour.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pedestrian</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “pedestrian” means any person traveling by foot and any mobility-impaired person using a wheelchair.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Wheelchair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “wheelchair” means a mobility aid, usable indoors, and designed for and used by individuals with mobility impairments, whether operated manually or motorized.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–87, title I, § 124(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 262</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–280, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="1976-05-05">May 5, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–599, title I, § 141(h)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 126A</ref>, formerly § 126, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2116</ref>, renumbered § 126A, <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 133(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 167</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1033</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1975</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 310(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 582</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 168</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1954</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1515</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1104(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1446(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 11133, 11525(p), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 514</ref>, 608.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 218.</num>
<heading> Alaska Highway</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Recognizing the benefits that will accrue to the State of Alaska and to the United States from the reconstruction of the Alaska Highway from the Alaskan border at Beaver Creek, Yukon Territory, to Haines Junction in Canada and the Haines Cutoff Highway from Haines Junction in Canada to Haines, Alaska, the Secretary may provide for the necessary reconstruction of the highway using funds awarded through an applicable competitive grant program, if the highway meets all applicable eligibility requirements for the program, except for the specific requirements established by the agreement for the Alaska Highway Project between the Government of the United States and the Government of Canada. In addition to the funds described in the previous sentence, notwithstanding any other provision of law and on agreement with the State of Alaska, the Secretary is authorized to expend on such highway or the Alaska Marine Highway System any Federal-aid highway funds apportioned to the State of Alaska under this title at a Federal share of 100 per centum. No expenditures shall be made for the construction of the portion of such highways that are in Canada unless an agreement is in place between the Government of Canada and the Government of the United States (including an agreement in existence on the date of enactment of the Surface Transportation Reauthorization Act of 2021) that provides, in part, that the Canadian Government—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> will provide, without participation of funds authorized under this title, all necessary right-of-way for the reconstruction of such highways;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> will not impose any highway toll, or permit any such toll to be charged for the use of such highways by vehicles or persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> will not levy or assess, directly or indirectly, any fee, tax, or other charge for the use of such highways by vehicles or persons from the United States that does not apply equally to vehicles or persons of Canada;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> will continue to grant reciprocal recognition of vehicle registration and driver’s licenses in accordance with agreements between the United States and Canada; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> will maintain such highways after their completion in proper condition adequately to serve the needs of present and future traffic.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The survey and construction work undertaken in Canada pursuant to this section shall be under the general supervision of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “Alaska Marine Highway System” includes all existing or planned transportation facilities and equipment in Alaska, including the lease, purchase, operation, repair, or construction of vessels, terminals, docks, floats, ramps, staging areas, parking lots, bridges and approaches thereto, and necessary roads.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a project assisted under this section in the State of Alaska shall be treated as a project on a Federal-aid highway under chapter 1.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–87, title I, § 127(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 264</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–147</ref>, <date date="1975-12-12">Dec. 12, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 803</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 158</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(g) [title III, § 316]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–439</ref>, 2681–468; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. I, title III, § 327</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title IV, § 4409</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1519(c)(10)</ref>, formerly § 1519(c)(11), <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 576</ref>, renumbered § 1519(c)(10), <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1446(d)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11116</ref>, div. G, title XI, § 71103(g)(2), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 482</ref>, 1326.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 219.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 133(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 173</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>