<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 215—</num>
<heading>GRAND JURY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3321.</num>
<heading> Number of grand jurors; summoning additional jurors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every grand jury impaneled before any district court shall consist of not less than sixteen nor more than twenty-three persons. If less than sixteen of the persons summoned attend, they shall be placed on the grand jury, and the court shall order the marshal to summon, either immediately or for a day fixed, from the body of the district, and not from the bystanders, a sufficient number of persons to complete the grand jury. Whenever a challenge to a grand juror is allowed, and there are not in attendance other jurors sufficient to complete the grand jury, the court shall make a like order to the marshal to summon a sufficient number of persons for that purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3322.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of certain matters occurring before grand jury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A person who is privy to grand jury information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> received in the course of duty as an attorney for the government; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disclosed under rule 6(e)(3)(A)(ii) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may disclose that information to an attorney for the government for use in enforcing section 951 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery and Enforcement Act of 1989 or for use in connection with any civil forfeiture provision of Federal law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Upon motion of an attorney for the government, a court may direct disclosure of matters occurring before a grand jury during an investigation of a banking law violation to identified personnel of a Federal or State financial institution regulatory agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for use in relation to any matter within the jurisdiction of such regulatory agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to assist an attorney for the government to whom matters have been disclosed under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A court may issue an order under paragraph (1) at any time during or after the completion of the investigation of the grand jury, upon a finding of a substantial need.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A person to whom matter has been disclosed under this section shall not use such matter other than for the purpose for which such disclosure was authorized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “banking law violation” means a violation of, or a conspiracy to violate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 215, 656, 657, 1005, 1006, 1007, 1014, 1344, 1956, or 1957;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 1341 or 1343 affecting a financial institution; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any provision of subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “attorney for the government” has the meaning given such term in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “grand jury information” means matters occurring before a grand jury other than the deliberations of the grand jury or the vote of any grand juror.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 964(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 505</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–102, title VII, § 740</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–185, § 10</ref>, <date date="2000-04-25">Apr. 25, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 217</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11002</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 3323 to 3328.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 964(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 505</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>