<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 114—</num>
<heading>TRAFFICKING IN CONTRABAND CIGARETTES AND SMOKELESS TOBACCO</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2341.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “cigarette” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any roll of tobacco wrapped in paper or in any substance not containing tobacco; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any roll of tobacco wrapped in any substance containing tobacco which, because of its appearance, the type of tobacco used in the filler, or its packaging and labeling, is likely to be offered to, or purchased by, consumers as a cigarette described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “contraband cigarettes” means a quantity in excess of 10,000 cigarettes, which bear no evidence of the payment of applicable State or local cigarette taxes in the State or locality where such cigarettes are found, if the State or local government requires a stamp, impression, or other indication to be placed on packages or other containers of cigarettes to evidence payment of cigarette taxes, and which are in the possession of any person other than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a person holding a permit issued pursuant to chapter 52 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as a manufacturer of tobacco products or as an export warehouse proprietor, or a person operating a customs bonded warehouse pursuant to section 311 or 555 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1311</ref> or 1555) or an agent of such person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a common or contract carrier transporting the cigarettes involved under a proper bill of lading or freight bill which states the quantity, source, and destination of such cigarettes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who is licensed or otherwise authorized by the State where the cigarettes are found to account for and pay cigarette taxes imposed by such State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who has complied with the accounting and payment requirements relating to such license or authorization with respect to the cigarettes involved; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an officer, employee, or other agent of the United States or a State, or any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States or a State (including any political subdivision of a State) having possession of such cigarettes in connection with the performance of official duties;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “common or contract carrier” means a carrier holding a certificate of convenience and necessity, a permit for contract carrier by motor vehicle, or other valid operating authority under subtitle IV of title 49, or under equivalent operating authority from a regulatory agency of the United States or of any State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or the Virgin Islands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Attorney General” means the Attorney General of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “smokeless tobacco” means any finely cut, ground, powdered, or leaf tobacco that is intended to be placed in the oral or nasal cavity or otherwise consumed without being combusted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> the term “contraband smokeless tobacco” means a quantity in excess of 500 single-unit consumer-sized cans or packages of smokeless tobacco, or their equivalent, that are in the possession of any person other than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a person holding a permit issued pursuant to chapter 52 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as manufacturer <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002196">1</ref> of tobacco products or as an export warehouse proprietor, a person operating a customs bonded warehouse pursuant to section 311 or 555 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1311</ref>, 1555), or an agent of such person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a common carrier transporting such smokeless tobacco under a proper bill of lading or freight bill which states the quantity, source, and designation of such smokeless tobacco;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a person who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is licensed or otherwise authorized by the State where such smokeless tobacco is found to engage in the business of selling or distributing tobacco products; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has complied with the accounting, tax, and payment requirements relating to such license or authorization with respect to such smokeless tobacco; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an officer, employee, or agent of the United States or a State, or any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States or a State (including any political subdivision of a State), having possession of such smokeless tobacco in connection with the performance of official duties; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002197">2</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–575, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2463</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–449, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XI, § 1112(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2277</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 121(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (6), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 221</ref>, 222.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2342.</num>
<heading> Unlawful acts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person knowingly to ship, transport, receive, possess, sell, distribute, or purchase contraband cigarettes or contraband smokeless tobacco.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person knowingly to make any false statement or representation with respect to the information required by this chapter to be kept in the records of any person who ships, sells, or distributes any quantity of cigarettes in excess of 10,000 in a single transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–575, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2464</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 121(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 221</ref>, 222.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2343.</num>
<heading> Recordkeeping, reporting, and inspection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who ships, sells, or distributes any quantity of cigarettes in excess of 10,000, or any quantity of smokeless tobacco in excess of 500 single-unit consumer-sized cans or packages, in a single transaction shall maintain such information about the shipment, receipt, sale, and distribution of cigarettes as the Attorney General may prescribe by rule or regulation. The Attorney General may require such person to keep such information as the Attorney General considers appropriate for purposes of enforcement of this chapter, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name, address, destination (including street address), vehicle license number, driver’s license number, signature of the person receiving such cigarettes, and the name of the purchaser;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a declaration of the specific purpose of the receipt (personal use, resale, or delivery to another); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a declaration of the name and address of the recipient’s principal in all cases when the recipient is acting as an agent.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such information shall be contained on business records kept in the normal course of business.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Any person, except for a tribal government, who engages in a delivery sale, and who ships, sells, or distributes any quantity in excess of 10,000 cigarettes, or any quantity in excess of 500 single-unit consumer-sized cans or packages of smokeless tobacco, or their equivalent, within a single month, shall submit to the Attorney General, pursuant to rules or regulations prescribed by the Attorney General, a report that sets forth the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The person’s beginning and ending inventory of cigarettes and cans or packages of smokeless tobacco (in total) for such month.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total quantity of cigarettes and cans or packages of smokeless tobacco that the person received within such month from each other person (itemized by name and address).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The total quantity of cigarettes and cans or packages of smokeless tobacco that the person distributed within such month to each person (itemized by name and address) other than a retail purchaser.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Any officer of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives may, during normal business hours, enter the premises of any person described in subsection (a) or (b) for the purposes of inspecting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any records or information required to be maintained by the person under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any cigarettes or smokeless tobacco kept or stored by the person at the premises.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The district courts of the United States shall have the authority in a civil action under this subsection to compel inspections authorized by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whoever denies access to an officer under paragraph (1), or who fails to comply with an order issued under paragraph (2), shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed $10,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any report required to be submitted under this chapter to the Attorney General shall also be submitted to the Secretary of the Treasury and to the attorneys general and the tax administrators of the States from where the shipments, deliveries, or distributions both originated and concluded.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term “delivery sale” means any sale of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco in interstate commerce to a consumer if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the consumer submits the order for such sale by means of a telephone or other method of voice transmission, the mails, or the Internet or other online service, or by any other means where the consumer is not in the same physical location as the seller when the purchase or offer of sale is made; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the cigarettes or smokeless tobacco are delivered by use of the mails, common carrier, private delivery service, or any other means where the consumer is not in the same physical location as the seller when the consumer obtains physical possession of the cigarettes or smokeless tobacco.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “interstate commerce” means commerce between a State and any place outside the State, or commerce between points in the same State but through any place outside the State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–575, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2464</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XI, § 1112(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2277</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 121(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), (c), (g)(1), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 221</ref>, 222, 224; <ref>Pub. L. 111–154, § 4</ref>, <date date="2010-03-31">Mar. 31, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2344.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly violates <ref>section 2342(a) of this title</ref> shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly violates any rule or regulation promulgated under section 2343(a) or 2346 of this title or violates <ref>section 2342(b) of this title</ref> shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Any contraband cigarettes or contraband smokeless tobacco involved in any violation of the provisions of this chapter shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture. The provisions of chapter 46 of title 18 relating to civil forfeitures shall extend to any seizure or civil forfeiture under this section. Any cigarettes or smokeless tobacco so seized and forfeited shall be either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> destroyed and not resold; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> used for undercover investigative operations for the detection and prosecution of crimes, and then destroyed and not resold.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–575, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2464</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, (S), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 121(b)(4)</ref>, (d), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 222</ref>, 223.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2345.</num>
<heading> Effect on State and local law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect the concurrent jurisdiction of a State or local government to enact and enforce its own cigarette tax laws, to provide for the confiscation of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco and other property seized for violation of such laws, and to provide for penalties for the violation of such laws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to inhibit or otherwise affect any coordinated law enforcement effort by a number of State or local governments, through interstate compact or otherwise, to provide for the administration of State or local cigarette tax laws, to provide for the confiscation of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco and other property seized in violation of such laws, and to establish cooperative programs for the administration of such laws.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–575, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2465</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 121(b)(5)</ref>, (e), (g)(2), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 222–224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2346.</num>
<heading> Enforcement and regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Attorney General, subject to the provisions of <ref>section 2343(a) of this title</ref>, shall enforce the provisions of this chapter and may prescribe such rules and regulations as he deems reasonably necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A State, through its attorney general, a local government, through its chief law enforcement officer (or a designee thereof), or any person who holds a permit under chapter 52 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, may bring an action in the United States district courts to prevent and restrain violations of this chapter by any person (or by any person controlling such person), except that any person who holds a permit under chapter 52 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 may not bring such an action against a State or local government. No civil action may be commenced under this paragraph against an Indian tribe or an Indian in Indian country (as defined in section 1151).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A State, through its attorney general, or a local government, through its chief law enforcement officer (or a designee thereof), may in a civil action under paragraph (1) also obtain any other appropriate relief for violations of this chapter from any person (or by any person controlling such person), including civil penalties, money damages, and injunctive or other equitable relief. Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to abrogate or constitute a waiver of any sovereign immunity of a State or local government, or an Indian tribe against any unconsented lawsuit under this chapter, or otherwise to restrict, expand, or modify any sovereign immunity of a State or local government, or an Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The remedies under paragraphs (1) and (2) are in addition to any other remedies under Federal, State, local, or other law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to expand, restrict, or otherwise modify any right of an authorized State official to proceed in State court, or take other enforcement actions, on the basis of an alleged violation of State or other law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to expand, restrict, or otherwise modify any right of an authorized local government official to proceed in State court, or take other enforcement actions, on the basis of an alleged violation of local or other law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–575, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2465</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XI, § 1112(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2277</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 121(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>