<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 205—</num>
<heading>SEARCHES AND SEIZURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3101.</num>
<heading> Effect of rules of court—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3102.</num>
<heading> Authority to issue search warrant—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3103.</num>
<heading> Grounds for issuing search warrant—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3103a.</num>
<heading> Additional grounds for issuing warrant</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to the grounds for issuing a warrant in <ref>section 3103 of this title</ref>, a warrant may be issued to search for and seize any property that constitutes evidence of a criminal offense in violation of the laws of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delay</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to the issuance of any warrant or court order under this section, or any other rule of law, to search for and seize any property or material that constitutes evidence of a criminal offense in violation of the laws of the United States, any notice required, or that may be required, to be given may be delayed if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the court finds reasonable cause to believe that providing immediate notification of the execution of the warrant may have an adverse result (as defined in section 2705, except if the adverse results consist only of unduly delaying a trial) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002228">1</ref> ;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the warrant prohibits the seizure of any tangible property, any wire or electronic communication (as defined in section 2510), or, except as expressly provided in chapter 121, any stored wire or electronic information, except where the court finds reasonable necessity for the seizure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the warrant provides for the giving of such notice within a reasonable period not to exceed 30 days after the date of its execution, or on a later date certain if the facts of the case justify a longer period of delay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extensions of Delay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any period of delay authorized by this section may be extended by the court for good cause shown, subject to the condition that extensions should only be granted upon an updated showing of the need for further delay and that each additional delay should be limited to periods of 90 days or less, unless the facts of the case justify a longer period of delay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report by judge</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 30 days after the expiration of a warrant authorizing delayed notice (including any extension thereof) entered under this section, or the denial of such warrant (or request for extension), the issuing or denying judge shall report to the Administrative Office of the United States Courts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the fact that a warrant was applied for;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the fact that the warrant or any extension thereof was granted as applied for, was modified, or was denied;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the period of delay in the giving of notice authorized by the warrant, and the number and duration of any extensions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the offense specified in the warrant or application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report by administrative office of the united states courts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Beginning with the fiscal year ending <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall transmit to Congress annually a full and complete report summarizing the data required to be filed with the Administrative Office by paragraph (1), including the number of applications for warrants and extensions of warrants authorizing delayed notice, and the number of such warrants and extensions granted or denied during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, in consultation with the Attorney General, is authorized to issue binding regulations dealing with the content and form of the reports required to be filed under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–351, title IX, § 1401(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-06-19">June 19, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3104.</num>
<heading> Issuance of search warrant; contents—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3105.</num>
<heading> Persons authorized to serve search warrant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A search warrant may in all cases be served by any of the officers mentioned in its direction or by an officer authorized by law to serve such warrant, but by no other person, except in aid of the officer on his requiring it, he being present and acting in its execution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3106.</num>
<heading> Officer authorized to serve search warrant—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3107.</num>
<heading> Service of warrants and seizures by Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director, Associate Director, Assistant to the Director, Assistant Directors, agents, and inspectors of the Federal Bureau of Investigation of the Department of Justice are empowered to make seizures under warrant for violation of the laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref>Jan. 10, 1951, ch. 1221, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 1239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3108.</num>
<heading> Execution, service, and return—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3109.</num>
<heading> Breaking doors or windows for entry or exit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The officer may break open any outer or inner door or window of a house, or any part of a house, or anything therein, to execute a search warrant, if, after notice of his authority and purpose, he is refused admittance or when necessary to liberate himself or a person aiding him in the execution of the warrant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3110.</num>
<heading> Property defined—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3111.</num>
<heading> Property seizable on search warrant—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3112.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–79, § 9(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1981-11-16">Nov. 16, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1079</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3113.</num>
<heading> Liquor violations in Indian country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any superintendent of Indian affairs, or commanding officer of a military post, or special agent of the Office of Indian Affairs for the suppression of liquor traffic among Indians and in the Indian country and any authorized deputies under his supervision has probable cause to believe that any person is about to introduce or has introduced any spirituous liquor, beer, wine or other intoxicating liquors named in sections 1154 and 1156 of this title into the Indian country in violation of law, he may cause the places, conveyances, and packages of such person to be searched. If any such intoxicating liquor is found therein, the same, together with such conveyances and packages of such person, shall be seized and delivered to the proper officer, and shall be proceeded against by libel in the proper court, and forfeited, one-half to the informer and one-half to the use of the United States. If such person be a trader, his license shall be revoked and his bond put in suit.</p>
<p class="indent0">Any person in the service of the United States authorized by this section to make searches and seizures, or any Indian may take and destroy any ardent spirits or wine found in the Indian country, except such as are kept or used for scientific, sacramental, medicinal, or mechanical purposes or such as may be introduced therein by the Department of the Army.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 820</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 30</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330004(15)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3114.</num>
<heading> Return of seized property and suppression of evidence; motion—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3115.</num>
<heading> Inventory upon execution and return of search warrant—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3116.</num>
<heading> Records of examining magistrate judge; return to clerk of court—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3117.</num>
<heading> Mobile tracking devices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a court is empowered to issue a warrant or other order for the installation of a mobile tracking device, such order may authorize the use of that device within the jurisdiction of the court, and outside that jurisdiction if the device is installed in that jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As used in this section, the term “tracking device” means an electronic or mechanical device which permits the tracking of the movement of a person or object.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–508, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1858</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3118.</num>
<heading> Implied consent for certain tests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever operates a motor vehicle in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States consents thereby to a chemical test or tests of such person’s blood, breath, or urine, if arrested for any offense arising from such person’s driving while under the influence of a drug or alcohol in such jurisdiction. The test or tests shall be administered upon the request of a police officer having reasonable grounds to believe the person arrested to have been driving a motor vehicle upon the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States while under the influence of drugs or alcohol in violation of the laws of a State, territory, possession, or district.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Refusal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever, having consented to a test or tests by reason of subsection (a), refuses to submit to such a test or tests, after having first been advised of the consequences of such a refusal, shall be denied the privilege of operating a motor vehicle upon the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States during the period of a year commencing on the date of arrest upon which such test or tests was refused, and such refusal may be admitted into evidence in any case arising from such person’s driving while under the influence of a drug or alcohol in such jurisdiction. Any person who operates a motor vehicle in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States after having been denied such privilege under this subsection shall be treated for the purposes of any civil or criminal proceedings arising out of such operation as operating such vehicle without a license to do so.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6477(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4381</ref>, § 3117; renumbered § 3118, <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3574</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>