<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>MAIL FRAUD AND OTHER FRAUD OFFENSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1341.</num>
<heading> Frauds and swindles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, having devised or intending to devise any scheme or artifice to defraud, or for obtaining money or property by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises, or to sell, dispose of, loan, exchange, alter, give away, distribute, supply, or furnish or procure for unlawful use any counterfeit or spurious coin, obligation, security, or other article, or anything represented to be or intimated or held out to be such counterfeit or spurious article, for the purpose of executing such scheme or artifice or attempting so to do, places in any post office or authorized depository for mail matter, any matter or thing whatever to be sent or delivered by the Postal Service, or deposits or causes to be deposited any matter or thing whatever to be sent or delivered by any private or commercial interstate carrier, or takes or receives therefrom, any such matter or thing, or knowingly causes to be delivered by mail or such carrier according to the direction thereon, or at the place at which it is directed to be delivered by the person to whom it is addressed, any such matter or thing, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both. If the violation occurs in relation to, or involving any benefit authorized, transported, transmitted, transferred, disbursed, or paid in connection with, a presidentially declared major disaster or emergency (as those terms are defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5122</ref>)), or affects a financial institution, such person shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 30 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 763</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 34</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 94</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, § (6)(j)(11), <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 961(i)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2504(h)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4861</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXV, § 250006</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2087</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title IX, § 903(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 805</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–179, § 4</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1342.</num>
<heading> Fictitious name or address</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, for the purpose of conducting, promoting, or carrying on by means of the Postal Service, any scheme or device mentioned in <ref>section 1341 of this title</ref> or any other unlawful business, uses or assumes, or requests to be addressed by, any fictitious, false, or assumed title, name, or address or name other than his own proper name, or takes or receives from any post office or authorized depository of mail matter, any letter, postal card, package, or other mail matter addressed to any such fictitious, false, or assumed title, name, or address, or name other than his own proper name, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 763</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(12)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1343.</num>
<heading> Fraud by wire, radio, or television</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, having devised or intending to devise any scheme or artifice to defraud, or for obtaining money or property by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises, transmits or causes to be transmitted by means of wire, radio, or television communication in interstate or foreign commerce, any writings, signs, signals, pictures, or sounds for the purpose of executing such scheme or artifice, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both. If the violation occurs in relation to, or involving any benefit authorized, transported, transmitted, transferred, disbursed, or paid in connection with, a presidentially declared major disaster or emergency (as those terms are defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5122</ref>)), or affects a financial institution, such person shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 30 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>July 16, 1952, ch. 879, § 18(a)</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 722</ref>; amended <ref>July 11, 1956, ch. 561</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 961(j)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2504(i)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4861</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title IX, § 903(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 805</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–179, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1344.</num>
<heading> Bank fraud</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever knowingly executes, or attempts to execute, a scheme or artifice—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to defraud a financial institution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to obtain any of the moneys, funds, credits, assets, securities, or other property owned by, or under the custody or control of, a financial institution, by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 30 years, or both.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1108(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2147</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 961(k)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2504(j)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4861</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1345.</num>
<heading> Injunctions against fraud</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If a person is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> violating or about to violate this chapter or section 287, 371 (insofar as such violation involves a conspiracy to defraud the United States or any agency thereof), or 1001 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> committing or about to commit a banking law violation (as defined in <ref>section 3322(d) of this title</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> committing or about to commit a Federal health care offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Attorney General may commence a civil action in any Federal court to enjoin such violation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If a person is alienating or disposing of property, or intends to alienate or dispose of property, obtained as a result of a banking law violation (as defined in <ref>section 3322(d) of this title</ref>) or a Federal health care offense or property which is traceable to such violation, the Attorney General may commence a civil action in any Federal court—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to enjoin such alienation or disposition of property; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for a restraining order to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prohibit any person from withdrawing, transferring, removing, dissipating, or disposing of any such property or property of equivalent value; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> appoint a temporary receiver to administer such restraining order.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A permanent or temporary injunction or restraining order shall be granted without bond.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The court shall proceed as soon as practicable to the hearing and determination of such an action, and may, at any time before final determination, enter such a restraining order or prohibition, or take such other action, as is warranted to prevent a continuing and substantial injury to the United States or to any person or class of persons for whose protection the action is brought. A proceeding under this section is governed by the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, except that, if an indictment has been returned against the respondent, discovery is governed by the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1205(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2152</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7077</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2521(b)(2)</ref>, title XXXV, § 3542, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4865</ref>, 4925; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330011(k)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2145</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 247</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(b)(14)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1346.</num>
<heading> Definition of “scheme or artifice to defraud”</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, the term “scheme or artifice to defraud” includes a scheme or artifice to deprive another of the intangible right of honest services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7603(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1347.</num>
<heading> Health care fraud</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever knowingly and willfully executes, or attempts to execute, a scheme or artifice—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to defraud any health care benefit program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to obtain, by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises, any of the money or property owned by, or under the custody or control of, any health care benefit program,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">in connection with the delivery of or payment for health care benefits, items, or services, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both. If the violation results in serious bodily injury (as defined in <ref>section 1365 of this title</ref>), such person shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both; and if the violation results in death, such person shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned for any term of years or for life, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> With respect to violations of this section, a person need not have actual knowledge of this section or specific intent to commit a violation of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 242(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2016</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10606(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1348.</num>
<heading> Securities and commodities fraud</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever knowingly executes, or attempts to execute, a scheme or artifice—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to defraud any person in connection with any commodity for future delivery, or any option on a commodity for future delivery, or any security of an issuer with a class of securities registered under section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>l</i>) or that is required to file reports under section 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>o</i>(d)); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to obtain, by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises, any money or property in connection with the purchase or sale of any commodity for future delivery, or any option on a commodity for future delivery, or any security of an issuer with a class of securities registered under section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>l</i>) or that is required to file reports under section 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>o</i>(d));</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than 25 years, or both.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title VIII, § 807(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 804</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–21, § 2(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-20">May 20, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1349.</num>
<heading> Attempt and conspiracy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who attempts or conspires to commit any offense under this chapter shall be subject to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense, the commission of which was the object of the attempt or conspiracy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1350.</num>
<heading> Failure of corporate officers to certify financial reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification of Periodic Financial Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each periodic report containing financial statements filed by an issuer with the Securities Exchange Commission pursuant to section 13(a) or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78m(a)</ref> or 78<i>o</i>(d)) shall be accompanied by a written statement by the chief executive officer and chief financial officer (or equivalent thereof) of the issuer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The statement required under subsection (a) shall certify that the periodic report containing the financial statements fully complies with the requirements of section 13(a) or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act pf <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002107">1</ref> 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78m</ref> or 78<i>o</i>(d)) and that information contained in the periodic report fairly presents, in all material respects, the financial condition and results of operations of the issuer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> certifies any statement as set forth in subsections (a) and (b) of this section knowing that the periodic report accompanying the statement does not comport with all the requirements set forth in this section shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> willfully certifies any statement as set forth in subsections (a) and (b) of this section knowing that the periodic report accompanying the statement does not comport with all the requirements set forth in this section shall be fined not more than $5,000,000, or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title IX, § 906(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1351.</num>
<heading> Fraud in foreign labor contracting</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Work Inside the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever knowingly and with intent to defraud recruits, solicits, or hires a person outside the United States or causes another person to recruit, solicit, or hire a person outside the United States, or attempts to do so, for purposes of employment in the United States by means of materially false or fraudulent pretenses, representations or promises regarding that employment shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Work Outside the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever knowingly and with intent to defraud recruits, solicits, or hires a person outside the United States or causes another person to recruit, solicit, or hire a person outside the United States, or attempts to do so, for purposes of employment performed on a United States Government contract performed outside the United States, or on a United States military installation or mission outside the United States or other property or premises outside the United States owned or controlled by the United States Government, by means of materially false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises regarding that employment, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title II, § 222(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5070</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1706(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1352.</num>
<heading> Demands by foreign officials for bribes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign official</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “foreign official” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any official or employee of a foreign government or any department, agency, or instrumentality thereof; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any senior foreign political figure, as defined in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any official or employee of a public international organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> any person acting in an official capacity for or on behalf of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a government, department, agency, or instrumentality described in subparagraph (A)(i); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a public international organization.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public international organization</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “public international organization” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an organization that is designated by Executive order pursuant to section 1 of the International Organizations Immunities Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 288</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other international organization that is designated by the President by Executive order for the purposes of this section, effective as of the date of publication of the order in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of Demand for a Bribe.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It shall be unlawful for any foreign official or person selected to be a foreign official to corruptly demand, seek, receive, accept, or agree to receive or accept, directly or indirectly, anything of value personally or for any other person or nongovernmental entity, by making use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any person (as defined in section 104A of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78dd–3</ref>), except that that definition shall be applied without regard to whether the person is an offender) while the foreign official or person selected to be a foreign official, or a person acting on behalf of the foreign official or person selected to be a foreign official, is in the territory of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an issuer (as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</ref>)), or any officer, director, employee, or agent of an issuer or any stockholder thereof acting on behalf of the issuer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a domestic concern (as defined in section 104 of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78dd–2</ref>)), or any officer, director, employee, or agent of a domestic concern or any stockholder thereof acting on behalf of the domestic concern; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in return for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> being influenced in the performance of any act or decision of the foreign official or person selected to be a foreign official in the official capacity of the foreign official or person selected to be a foreign official;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> being induced to do or omit to do any act in violation of the lawful duty of the foreign official or person selected to be a foreign official;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> conferring any improper advantage; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> using the influence of the foreign official or person selected to be a foreign official with a foreign government or instrumentality thereof to affect or influence any act or decision of that government or instrumentality,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">in connection with obtaining or retaining business for or with, or directing business to, any person.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $250,000 or 3 times the monetary equivalent of the thing of value, imprisoned for not more than 15 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An offense under paragraph (1) shall be subject to extraterritorial Federal jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State as relevant, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and post on the publicly available website of the Department of Justice, a report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> focusing, in part, on demands by foreign officials for bribes from entities domiciled or incorporated in the United States, and the efforts of foreign governments to prosecute such cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> addressing United States diplomatic efforts to protect entities domiciled or incorporated in the United States from foreign bribery, and the effectiveness of those efforts in protecting such entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> summarizing major actions taken under this section in the previous year, including enforcement actions taken and penalties imposed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> evaluating the effectiveness of the Department of Justice in enforcing this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> detailing what resources or legislative action the Department of Justice needs to ensure adequate enforcement of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection shall not be construed as encompassing conduct that would violate section 30A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78dd–1</ref>) or section 104 or 104A of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78dd–2</ref>; <ref>15 U.S.C. 78dd–3</ref>) whether pursuant to a theory of direct liability, conspiracy, complicity, or otherwise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–78, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-07-30">July 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1512</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>