<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 601—</num>
<heading>IMMUNITY OF WITNESSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6001.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “agency of the United States” means any executive department as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, a military department as defined in <ref>section 102 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the China Trade Act registrar appointed under <ref>53 Stat. 1432</ref> (15 U.S.C. sec. 143), the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Federal Power Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the Surface Transportation Board, the National Labor Relations Board, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Railroad Retirement Board, an arbitration board established under <ref>48 Stat. 1193</ref> (45 U.S.C. sec. 157), the Securities and Exchange Commission, or a board established under <ref>49 Stat. 31</ref> (15 U.S.C. sec. 715d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “other information” includes any book, paper, document, record, recording, or other material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “proceeding before an agency of the United States” means any proceeding before such an agency with respect to which it is authorized to issue subpenas and to take testimony or receive other information from witnesses under oath; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “court of the United States” means any of the following courts: the Supreme Court of the United States, a United States court of appeals, a United States district court established under chapter 5, title 28, United States Code, a United States bankruptcy court established under chapter 6, title 28, United States Code, the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, the District Court of Guam, the District Court of the Virgin Islands, the United States Court of Federal Claims, the Tax Court of the United States, the Court of International Trade, and the Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 926</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–405, § 25</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 877</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title III, § 314</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2678</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–417, title VI, § 601(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1744</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 164(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1543</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4069</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 4(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330013(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 924(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 303(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 943</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6002.</num>
<heading> Immunity generally</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever a witness refuses, on the basis of his privilege against self-incrimination, to testify or provide other information in a proceeding before or ancillary to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a court or grand jury of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an agency of the United States, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> either House of Congress, a joint committee of the two Houses, or a committee or a subcommittee of either House,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">and the person presiding over the proceeding communicates to the witness an order issued under this title, the witness may not refuse to comply with the order on the basis of his privilege against self-incrimination; but no testimony or other information compelled under the order (or any information directly or indirectly derived from such testimony or other information) may be used against the witness in any criminal case, except a prosecution for perjury, giving a false statement, or otherwise failing to comply with the order.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 927</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330013(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6003.</num>
<heading> Court and grand jury proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In the case of any individual who has been or may be called to testify or provide other information at any proceeding before or ancillary to a court of the United States or a grand jury of the United States, the United States district court for the judicial district in which the proceeding is or may be held shall issue, in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, upon the request of the United States attorney for such district, an order requiring such individual to give testimony or provide other information which he refuses to give or provide on the basis of his privilege against self-incrimination, such order to become effective as provided in <ref>section 6002 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A United States attorney may, with the approval of the Attorney General, the Deputy Attorney General, the Associate Attorney General, or any designated Assistant Attorney General or Deputy Assistant Attorney General, request an order under subsection (a) of this section when in his judgment—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the testimony or other information from such individual may be necessary to the public interest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such individual has refused or is likely to refuse to testify or provide other information on the basis of his privilege against self-incrimination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 927</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7020(e)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330013(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6004.</num>
<heading> Certain administrative proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In the case of any individual who has been or who may be called to testify or provide other information at any proceeding before an agency of the United States, the agency may, with the approval of the Attorney General, issue, in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, an order requiring the individual to give testimony or provide other information which he refuses to give or provide on the basis of his privilege against self-incrimination, such order to become effective as provided in <ref>section 6002 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An agency of the United States may issue an order under subsection (a) of this section only if in its judgment—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the testimony or other information from such individual may be necessary to the public interest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such individual has refused or is likely to refuse to testify or provide other information on the basis of his privilege against self-incrimination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 927</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330013(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6005.</num>
<heading> Congressional proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In the case of any individual who has been or may be called to testify or provide other information at any proceeding before or ancillary to either House of Congress, or any committee, or any subcommittee of either House, or any joint committee of the two Houses, a United States district court shall issue, in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, upon the request of a duly authorized representative of the House of Congress or the committee concerned, an order requiring such individual to give testimony or provide other information which he refuses to give or provide on the basis of his privilege against self-incrimination, such order to become effective as provided in <ref>section 6002 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Before issuing an order under subsection (a) of this section, a United States district court shall find that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a proceeding before or ancillary to either House of Congress, the request for such an order has been approved by an affirmative vote of a majority of the Members present of that House;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a proceeding before or ancillary to a committee or a subcommittee of either House of Congress or a joint committee of both Houses, the request for such an order has been approved by an affirmative vote of two-thirds of the members of the full committee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ten days or more prior to the day on which the request for such an order was made, the Attorney General was served with notice of an intention to request the order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Upon application of the Attorney General, the United States district court shall defer the issuance of any order under subsection (a) of this section for such period, not longer than twenty days from the date of the request for such order, as the Attorney General may specify.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 928</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330013(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–292, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 605</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>