<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 50A—</num>
<heading>GENOCIDE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1091.</num>
<heading> Genocide</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basic Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever, whether in time of peace or in time of war and with the specific intent to destroy, in whole or in substantial part, a national, ethnic, racial, or religious group as such—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> kills members of that group;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> causes serious bodily injury to members of that group;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> causes the permanent impairment of the mental faculties of members of the group through drugs, torture, or similar techniques;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> subjects the group to conditions of life that are intended to cause the physical destruction of the group in whole or in part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> imposes measures intended to prevent births within the group; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> transfers by force children of the group to another group;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Punishment for Basic Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The punishment for an offense under subsection (a) is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of an offense under subsection (a)(1), where death results, by death or imprisonment for life and a fine of not more than $1,000,000, or both; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a fine of not more than $1,000,000 or imprisonment for not more than twenty years, or both, in any other case.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incitement Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever directly and publicly incites another to violate subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $500,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attempt and Conspiracy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who attempts or conspires to commit an offense under this section shall be punished in the same manner as a person who completes the offense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is jurisdiction over the offenses described in subsections (a), (c), and (d) if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the offense is committed in whole or in part within the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> regardless of where the offense is committed, the alleged offender is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a national of the United States (as that term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States (as that term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> present in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability of Certain Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding section 3282, in the case of an offense under this section, an indictment may be found, or information instituted, at any time without limitation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–606, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3045</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60003(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1970</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(a)(4)</ref>, (b)(7), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1806</ref>, 1808; <ref>Pub. L. 110–151, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–122, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-22">Dec. 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1092.</num>
<heading> Exclusive remedies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as precluding the application of State or local laws to the conduct proscribed by this chapter, nor shall anything in this chapter be construed as creating any substantive or procedural right enforceable by law by any party in any proceeding.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–606, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3046</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1093.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “children” means the plural and means individuals who have not attained the age of eighteen years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “ethnic group” means a set of individuals whose identity as such is distinctive in terms of common cultural traditions or heritage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “incites” means urges another to engage imminently in conduct in circumstances under which there is a substantial likelihood of imminently causing such conduct;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “members” means the plural;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “national group” means a set of individuals whose identity as such is distinctive in terms of nationality or national origins;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “racial group” means a set of individuals whose identity as such is distinctive in terms of physical characteristics or biological descent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “religious group” means a set of individuals whose identity as such is distinctive in terms of common religious creed, beliefs, doctrines, practices, or rituals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “substantial part” means a part of a group of such numerical significance that the destruction or loss of that part would cause the destruction of the group as a viable entity within the nation of which such group is a part.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–606, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3046</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>