<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 51—</num>
<heading>HOMICIDE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1111.</num>
<heading> Murder</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Murder is the unlawful killing of a human being with malice aforethought. Every murder perpetrated by poison, lying in wait, or any other kind of willful, deliberate, malicious, and premeditated killing; or committed in the perpetration of, or attempt to perpetrate, any arson, escape, murder, kidnapping, treason, espionage, sabotage, aggravated sexual abuse or sexual abuse, child abuse, burglary, or robbery; or perpetrated as part of a pattern or practice of assault or torture against a child or children; or perpetrated from a premeditated design unlawfully and maliciously to effect the death of any human being other than him who is killed, is murder in the first degree.<p class="indent0">Any other murder is murder in the second degree.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States,<p class="indent0">Whoever is guilty of murder in the first degree shall be punished by death or by imprisonment for life;</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever is guilty of murder in the second degree, shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “assault” has the same meaning as given that term in section 113;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “child” means a person who has not attained the age of 18 years and is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under the perpetrator’s care or control; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least six years younger than the perpetrator;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “child abuse” means intentionally or knowingly causing death or serious bodily injury to a child;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “pattern or practice of assault or torture” means assault or torture engaged in on at least two occasions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “serious bodily injury” has the meaning set forth in section 1365; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “torture” means conduct, whether or not committed under the color of law, that otherwise satisfies the definition set forth in section 2340(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 756</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1004</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 87(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–654, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3663</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7025</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60003(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–21, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 652</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1112.</num>
<heading> Manslaughter</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Manslaughter is the unlawful killing of a human being without malice. It is of two kinds:<p class="indent0" role="listItem">Voluntary—Upon a sudden quarrel or heat of passion.</p>
<p class="indent0" role="listItem">Involuntary—In the commission of an unlawful act not amounting to a felony, or in the commission in an unlawful manner, or without due caution and circumspection, of a lawful act which might produce death.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States,<p class="indent0">Whoever is guilty of voluntary manslaughter, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 15 years, or both;</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever is guilty of involuntary manslaughter, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 8 years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 756</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320102</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2109</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1113.</num>
<heading> Attempt to commit murder or manslaughter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 113 of this title</ref>, whoever, within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, attempts to commit murder or manslaughter, shall, for an attempt to commit murder be imprisoned not more than twenty years or fined under this title, or both, and for an attempt to commit manslaughter be imprisoned not more than seven years or fined under this title, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 756</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7058(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3534</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4925</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 705(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1114.</num>
<heading> Protection of officers and employees of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever kills or attempts to kill any officer or employee of the United States or of any agency in any branch of the United States Government (including any member of the uniformed services) while such officer or employee is engaged in or on account of the performance of official duties, or any person assisting such an officer or employee in the performance of such duties or on account of that assistance, shall be punished—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of murder, as provided under section 1111;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of manslaughter, as provided under section 1112; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of attempted murder or manslaughter, as provided in section 1113.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extraterritorial Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is extraterritorial jurisdiction over the conduct prohibited by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 756</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 24</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 93</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 28</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title IV, § 402(c), <ref>66 Stat. 276</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–568, title III, § 304(d)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-29">July 29, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–518, § 10</ref>, <date date="1962-07-02">July 2, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–493, § 3</ref>, <date date="1964-08-27">Aug. 27, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–74, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-15">July 15, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–449, § 2</ref>, <date date="1968-08-02">Aug. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(9)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–513, title II, § 701(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–596, § 17(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–481, § 5</ref>, <date date="1974-10-26">Oct. 26, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–284, § 18</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 514</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–582, § 16</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–87, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–616, § 3(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–630, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–296, § 26(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–466, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–143, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–259, title I, § 128</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–365, § 6</ref>, <date date="1982-10-25">Oct. 25, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–63, title I</ref>, <date date="1983-07-30">July 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 313</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1012</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2142</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 17(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2868</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7026</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 962(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XII, § 1205(h)</ref>, title XVI, § 1606, title XXXV, § 3535, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4831</ref>, 4843, 4925; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–365, § 6</ref>, <date date="1992-09-03">Sept. 3, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 975</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60007</ref>, title XXXIII, §§ 330009(c), 330011(g), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1971</ref>, 2143, 2145; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 727(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–59, § 3(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-18">Nov. 18, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1469</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1115.</num>
<heading> Misconduct or neglect of ship officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every captain, engineer, pilot, or other person employed on any steamboat or vessel, by whose misconduct, negligence, or inattention to his duties on such vessel the life of any person is destroyed, and every owner, charterer, inspector, or other public officer, through whose fraud, neglect, connivance, misconduct, or violation of law the life of any person is destroyed, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">When the owner or charterer of any steamboat or vessel is a corporation, any executive officer of such corporation, for the time being actually charged with the control and management of the operation, equipment, or navigation of such steamboat or vessel, who has knowingly and willfully caused or allowed such fraud, neglect, connivance, misconduct, or violation of law, by which the life of any person is destroyed, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 757</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1116.</num>
<heading> Murder or manslaughter of foreign officials, official guests, or internationally protected persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever kills or attempts to kill a foreign official, official guest, or internationally protected person shall be punished as provided under sections 1111, 1112, and 1113 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Family” includes (a) a spouse, parent, brother or sister, child, or person to whom the foreign official or internationally protected person stands in loco parentis, or (b) any other person living in his household and related to the foreign official or internationally protected person by blood or marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Foreign government” means the government of a foreign country, irrespective of recognition by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “Foreign official” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Chief of State or the political equivalent, President, Vice President, Prime Minister, Ambassador, Foreign Minister, or other officer of Cabinet rank or above of a foreign government or the chief executive officer of an international organization, or any person who has previously served in such capacity, and any member of his family, while in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any person of a foreign nationality who is duly notified to the United States as an officer or employee of a foreign government or international organization, and who is in the United States on official business, and any member of his family whose presence in the United States is in connection with the presence of such officer or employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “Internationally protected person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Chief of State or the political equivalent, head of government, or Foreign Minister whenever such person is in a country other than his own and any member of his family accompanying him; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other representative, officer, employee, or agent of the United States Government, a foreign government, or international organization who at the time and place concerned is entitled pursuant to international law to special protection against attack upon his person, freedom, or dignity, and any member of his family then forming part of his household.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “International organization” means a public international organization designated as such pursuant to section 1 of the International Organizations Immunities Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 288</ref>) or a public organization created pursuant to treaty or other agreement under international law as an instrument through or by which two or more foreign governments engage in some aspect of their conduct of international affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “Official guest” means a citizen or national of a foreign country present in the United States as an official guest of the Government of the United States pursuant to designation as such by the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “National of the United States” has the meaning prescribed in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the victim of an offense under subsection (a) is an internationally protected person outside the United States, the United States may exercise jurisdiction over the offense if (1) the victim is a representative, officer, employee, or agent of the United States, (2) an offender is a national of the United States, or (3) an offender is afterwards found in the United States. As used in this subsection, the United States includes all areas under the jurisdiction of the United States including any of the places within the provisions of sections 5 and 7 of this title and <ref>section 46501(2) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In the course of enforcement of this section and any other sections prohibiting a conspiracy or attempt to violate this section, the Attorney General may request assistance from any Federal, State, or local agency, including the Army, Navy, and Air Force, any statute, rule, or regulation to the contrary notwithstanding.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–539, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1071</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–467, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-08">Oct. 8, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1997</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–163, § 17(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–504, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-24">Oct. 24, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–351, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60003(a)(5)</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330006, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1969</ref>, 2142; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 721(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1117.</num>
<heading> Conspiracy to murder</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If two or more persons conspire to violate section 1111, 1114, 1116, or 1119 of this title, and one or more of such persons do any overt act to effect the object of the conspiracy, each shall be punished by imprisonment for any term of years or for life.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–539, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1071</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60009(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1118.</num>
<heading> Murder by a Federal prisoner</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who, while confined in a Federal correctional institution under a sentence for a term of life imprisonment, commits the murder of another shall be punished by death or by life imprisonment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section—<p class="indent1" role="listItem">“Federal correctional institution” means any Federal prison, Federal correctional facility, Federal community program center, or Federal halfway house.</p>
<p class="indent1" role="listItem">“murder” means a first degree or second degree murder (as defined in section 1111).</p>
<p class="indent1">“term of life imprisonment” means a sentence for the term of natural life, a sentence commuted to natural life, an indeterminate term of a minimum of at least fifteen years and a maximum of life, or an unexecuted sentence of death.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60005(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1119.</num>
<heading> Foreign murder of United States nationals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, “national of the United States” has the meaning stated in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who, being a national of the United States, kills or attempts to kill a national of the United States while such national is outside the United States but within the jurisdiction of another country shall be punished as provided under sections 1111, 1112, and 1113.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Prosecution</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No prosecution may be instituted against any person under this section except upon the written approval of the Attorney General, the Deputy Attorney General, or an Assistant Attorney General, which function of approving prosecutions may not be delegated. No prosecution shall be approved if prosecution has been previously undertaken by a foreign country for the same conduct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No prosecution shall be approved under this section unless the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines that the conduct took place in a country in which the person is no longer present, and the country lacks the ability to lawfully secure the person’s return. A determination by the Attorney General under this paragraph is not subject to judicial review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60009(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1120.</num>
<heading> Murder by escaped prisoners</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, “Federal correctional institution” and “term of life imprisonment” have the meanings stated in section 1118.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense and Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person, having escaped from a Federal correctional institution where the person was confined under a sentence for a term of life imprisonment, kills another shall be punished as provided in sections 1111 and 1112.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60012(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1973</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1121.</num>
<heading> Killing persons aiding Federal investigations or State correctional officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever intentionally kills—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a State or local official, law enforcement officer, or other officer or employee while working with Federal law enforcement officials in furtherance of a Federal criminal investigation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> while the victim is engaged in the performance of official duties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> because of the performance of the victim’s official duties; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> because of the victim’s status as a public servant; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any person assisting a Federal criminal investigation, while that assistance is being rendered and because of it,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be sentenced according to the terms of section 1111, including by sentence of death or by imprisonment for life.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whoever, in a circumstance described in paragraph (3) of this subsection, while incarcerated, intentionally kills any State correctional officer engaged in, or on account of the performance of such officer’s official duties, shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment which shall not be less than 20 years, and may be sentenced to life imprisonment or death.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term, “State correctional officer” includes any officer or employee of any prison, jail, or other detention facility, operated by, or under contract to, either a State or local governmental agency, whose job responsibilities include providing for the custody of incarcerated individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The circumstance referred to in paragraph (1) is that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the correctional officer is engaged in transporting the incarcerated person interstate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the incarcerated person is incarcerated pursuant to a conviction for an offense against the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60015(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1974</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 607(k)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3512</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1122.</num>
<heading> Protection against the human immunodeficiency virus</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever, after testing positive for the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) and receiving actual notice of that fact, knowingly donates or sells, or knowingly attempts to donate or sell, blood, semen, tissues, organs, or other bodily fluids for use by another, except as determined necessary for medical research or testing or in accordance with all applicable guidelines and regulations made by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 377E of the Public Health Service Act, shall be fined or imprisoned in accordance with subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transmission Not Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Transmission of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus does not have to occur for a person to be convicted of a violation of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person convicted of violating the provisions of subsection (a) shall be subject to a fine under this title of not less than $10,000, imprisoned for not less than 1 year nor more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–333, title V, § 514</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2574</ref>, § 1118; renumbered § 1122 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–51, § 3</ref>, <date date="2013-11-21">Nov. 21, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 581</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>