<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 96—</num>
<heading>RACKETEER INFLUENCED AND CORRUPT ORGANIZATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1961.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “racketeering activity” means (A) any act or threat involving murder, kidnapping, gambling, arson, robbery, bribery, extortion, dealing in obscene matter, or dealing in a controlled substance or listed chemical (as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act), which is chargeable under State law and punishable by imprisonment for more than one year; (B) any act which is indictable under any of the following provisions of title 18, United States Code: Section 201 (relating to bribery), section 224 (relating to sports bribery), sections 471, 472, and 473 (relating to counterfeiting), section 659 (relating to theft from interstate shipment) if the act indictable under section 659 is felonious, section 664 (relating to embezzlement from pension and welfare funds), sections 891–894 (relating to extortionate credit transactions), section 932 (relating to straw purchasing), section 933 (relating to trafficking in firearms), section 1028 (relating to fraud and related activity in connection with identification documents), section 1029 (relating to fraud and related activity in connection with access devices), section 1084 (relating to the transmission of gambling information), section 1341 (relating to mail fraud), section 1343 (relating to wire fraud), section 1344 (relating to financial institution fraud), section 1351 (relating to fraud in foreign labor contracting), section 1425 (relating to the procurement of citizenship or nationalization unlawfully), section 1426 (relating to the reproduction of naturalization or citizenship papers), section 1427 (relating to the sale of naturalization or citizenship papers), sections 1461–1465 (relating to obscene matter), section 1503 (relating to obstruction of justice), section 1510 (relating to obstruction of criminal investigations), section 1511 (relating to the obstruction of State or local law enforcement), section 1512 (relating to tampering with a witness, victim, or an informant), section 1513 (relating to retaliating against a witness, victim, or an informant), section 1542 (relating to false statement in application and use of passport), section 1543 (relating to forgery or false use of passport), section 1544 (relating to misuse of passport), section 1546 (relating to fraud and misuse of visas, permits, and other documents), sections 1581–1592 (relating to peonage, slavery, and trafficking in persons).,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002131">1</ref> sections 1831 and 1832 (relating to economic espionage and theft of trade secrets), section 1951 (relating to interference with commerce, robbery, or extortion), section 1952 (relating to racketeering), section 1953 (relating to interstate transportation of wagering paraphernalia), section 1954 (relating to unlawful welfare fund payments), section 1955 (relating to the prohibition of illegal gambling businesses), section 1956 (relating to the laundering of monetary instruments), section 1957 (relating to engaging in monetary transactions in property derived from specified unlawful activity), section 1958 (relating to use of interstate commerce facilities in the commission of murder-for-hire), section 1960 (relating to illegal money transmitters), sections 2251, 2251A, 2252, and 2260 (relating to sexual exploitation of children), sections 2312 and 2313 (relating to interstate transportation of stolen motor vehicles), sections 2314 and 2315 (relating to interstate transportation of stolen property), section 2318 (relating to trafficking in counterfeit labels for phonorecords, computer programs or computer program documentation or packaging and copies of motion pictures or other audiovisual works), section 2319 (relating to criminal infringement of a copyright), section 2319A (relating to unauthorized fixation of and trafficking in sound recordings and music videos of live musical performances), section 2320 (relating to trafficking in goods or services bearing counterfeit marks), section 2321 (relating to trafficking in certain motor vehicles or motor vehicle parts), sections 2341–2346 (relating to trafficking in contraband cigarettes), sections 2421–24 (relating to white slave traffic),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002132">2</ref> sections 175–178 (relating to biological weapons), sections 229–229F (relating to chemical weapons), section 831 (relating to nuclear materials), (C) any act which is indictable under title 29, United States Code, section 186 (dealing with restrictions on payments and loans to labor organizations) or section 501(c) (relating to embezzlement from union funds), (D) any offense involving fraud connected with a case under title 11 (except a case under <ref>section 157 of this title</ref>), fraud in the sale of securities, or the felonious manufacture, importation, receiving, concealment, buying, selling, or otherwise dealing in a controlled substance or listed chemical (as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act), punishable under any law of the United States, (E) any act which is indictable under the Currency and Foreign Transactions Reporting Act, (F) any act which is indictable under the Immigration and Nationality Act, section 274 (relating to bringing in and harboring certain aliens), section 277 (relating to aiding or assisting certain aliens to enter the United States), or section 278 (relating to importation of alien for immoral purpose) if the act indictable under such section of such Act was committed for the purpose of financial gain, or (G) any act that is indictable under any provision listed in section 2332b(g)(5)(B);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, any political subdivision, or any department, agency, or instrumentality thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “person” includes any individual or entity capable of holding a legal or beneficial interest in property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “enterprise” includes any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity, and any union or group of individuals associated in fact although not a legal entity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “pattern of racketeering activity” requires at least two acts of racketeering activity, one of which occurred after the effective date of this chapter and the last of which occurred within ten years (excluding any period of imprisonment) after the commission of a prior act of racketeering activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “unlawful debt” means a debt (A) incurred or contracted in gambling activity which was in violation of the law of the United States, a State or political subdivision thereof, or which is unenforceable under State or Federal law in whole or in part as to principal or interest because of the laws relating to usury, and (B) which was incurred in connection with the business of gambling in violation of the law of the United States, a State or political subdivision thereof, or the business of lending money or a thing of value at a rate usurious under State or Federal law, where the usurious rate is at least twice the enforceable rate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “racketeering investigator” means any attorney or investigator so designated by the Attorney General and charged with the duty of enforcing or carrying into effect this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “racketeering investigation” means any inquiry conducted by any racketeering investigator for the purpose of ascertaining whether any person has been involved in any violation of this chapter or of any final order, judgment, or decree of any court of the United States, duly entered in any case or proceeding arising under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “documentary material” includes any book, paper, document, record, recording, or other material; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “Attorney General” includes the Attorney General of the United States, the Deputy Attorney General of the United States, the Associate Attorney General of the United States, any Assistant Attorney General of the United States, or any employee of the Department of Justice or any employee of any department or agency of the United States so designated by the Attorney General to carry out the powers conferred on the Attorney General by this chapter. Any department or agency so designated may use in investigations authorized by this chapter either the investigative provisions of this chapter or the investigative power of such department or agency otherwise conferred by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 941</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–575, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title III, § 314(g)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II</ref>, §§ 901(g), 1020, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2136</ref>, 2143; <ref>Pub. L. 98–547, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1984-10-25">Oct. 25, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1365(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 50(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3605</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7013, 7020(c), 7032, 7054, 7514, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4395</ref>, 4396, 4398, 4402, 4489; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 968</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3560</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IX, § 90104</ref>, title XVI, § 160001(f), title XXXIII, § 330021(1), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1987</ref>, 2037, 2150; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title III, § 312(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title IV, § 433</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–153, § 3</ref>, <date date="1996-07-02">July 2, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1386</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI</ref>, §§ 601(b)(3), (i)(3), 604(b)(6), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3499</ref>, 3501, 3506; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4005(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2879</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6802(e)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 103(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1211(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 142</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–153, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-05-11">May 11, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–159, div. A, title II, § 12004(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-06-25">June 25, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1328</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962.</num>
<heading> Prohibited activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person who has received any income derived, directly or indirectly, from a pattern of racketeering activity or through collection of an unlawful debt in which such person has participated as a principal within the meaning of section 2, title 18, United States Code, to use or invest, directly or indirectly, any part of such income, or the proceeds of such income, in acquisition of any interest in, or the establishment or operation of, any enterprise which is engaged in, or the activities of which affect, interstate or foreign commerce. A purchase of securities on the open market for purposes of investment, and without the intention of controlling or participating in the control of the issuer, or of assisting another to do so, shall not be unlawful under this subsection if the securities of the issuer held by the purchaser, the members of his immediate family, and his or their accomplices in any pattern or racketeering activity or the collection of an unlawful debt after such purchase do not amount in the aggregate to one percent of the outstanding securities of any one class, and do not confer, either in law or in fact, the power to elect one or more directors of the issuer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person through a pattern of racketeering activity or through collection of an unlawful debt to acquire or maintain, directly or indirectly, any interest in or control of any enterprise which is engaged in, or the activities of which affect, interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person employed by or associated with any enterprise engaged in, or the activities of which affect, interstate or foreign commerce, to conduct or participate, directly or indirectly, in the conduct of such enterprise’s affairs through a pattern of racketeering activity or collection of unlawful debt.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person to conspire to violate any of the provisions of subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 942</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7033</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1963.</num>
<heading> Criminal penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever violates any provision of section 1962 of this chapter shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years (or for life if the violation is based on a racketeering activity for which the maximum penalty includes life imprisonment), or both, and shall forfeit to the United States, irrespective of any provision of State law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any interest the person has acquired or maintained in violation of section 1962;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> any—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> interest in;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> security of;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> claim against; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> property or contractual right of any kind affording a source of influence over;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">any enterprise which the person has established, operated, controlled, conducted, or participated in the conduct of, in violation of section 1962; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any property constituting, or derived from, any proceeds which the person obtained, directly or indirectly, from racketeering activity or unlawful debt collection in violation of section 1962.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The court, in imposing sentence on such person shall order, in addition to any other sentence imposed pursuant to this section, that the person forfeit to the United States all property described in this subsection. In lieu of a fine otherwise authorized by this section, a defendant who derives profits or other proceeds from an offense may be fined not more than twice the gross profits or other proceeds.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Property subject to criminal forfeiture under this section includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> real property, including things growing on, affixed to, and found in land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> tangible and intangible personal property, including rights, privileges, interests, claims, and securities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> All right, title, and interest in property described in subsection (a) vests in the United States upon the commission of the act giving rise to forfeiture under this section. Any such property that is subsequently transferred to a person other than the defendant may be the subject of a special verdict of forfeiture and thereafter shall be ordered forfeited to the United States, unless the transferee establishes in a hearing pursuant to subsection (<i>l</i>) that he is a bona fide purchaser for value of such property who at the time of purchase was reasonably without cause to believe that the property was subject to forfeiture under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Upon application of the United States, the court may enter a restraining order or injunction, require the execution of a satisfactory performance bond, or take any other action to preserve the availability of property described in subsection (a) for forfeiture under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> upon the filing of an indictment or information charging a violation of section 1962 of this chapter and alleging that the property with respect to which the order is sought would, in the event of conviction, be subject to forfeiture under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> prior to the filing of such an indictment or information, if, after notice to persons appearing to have an interest in the property and opportunity for a hearing, the court determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> there is a substantial probability that the United States will prevail on the issue of forfeiture and that failure to enter the order will result in the property being destroyed, removed from the jurisdiction of the court, or otherwise made unavailable for forfeiture; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the need to preserve the availability of the property through the entry of the requested order outweighs the hardship on any party against whom the order is to be entered:</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<proviso class="indent0 firstIndent0"><i>Provided, however</i>, That an order entered pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be effective for not more than ninety days, unless extended by the court for good cause shown or unless an indictment or information described in subparagraph (A) has been filed.</proviso>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A temporary restraining order under this subsection may be entered upon application of the United States without notice or opportunity for a hearing when an information or indictment has not yet been filed with respect to the property, if the United States demonstrates that there is probable cause to believe that the property with respect to which the order is sought would, in the event of conviction, be subject to forfeiture under this section and that provision of notice will jeopardize the availability of the property for forfeiture. Such a temporary order shall expire not more than fourteen days after the date on which it is entered, unless extended for good cause shown or unless the party against whom it is entered consents to an extension for a longer period. A hearing requested concerning an order entered under this paragraph shall be held at the earliest possible time, and prior to the expiration of the temporary order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The court may receive and consider, at a hearing held pursuant to this subsection, evidence and information that would be inadmissible under the Federal Rules of Evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Upon conviction of a person under this section, the court shall enter a judgment of forfeiture of the property to the United States and shall also authorize the Attorney General to seize all property ordered forfeited upon such terms and conditions as the court shall deem proper. Following the entry of an order declaring the property forfeited, the court may, upon application of the United States, enter such appropriate restraining orders or injunctions, require the execution of satisfactory performance bonds, appoint receivers, conservators, appraisers, accountants, or trustees, or take any other action to protect the interest of the United States in the property ordered forfeited. Any income accruing to, or derived from, an enterprise or an interest in an enterprise which has been ordered forfeited under this section may be used to offset ordinary and necessary expenses to the enterprise which are required by law, or which are necessary to protect the interests of the United States or third parties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Following the seizure of property ordered forfeited under this section, the Attorney General shall direct the disposition of the property by sale or any other commercially feasible means, making due provision for the rights of any innocent persons. Any property right or interest not exercisable by, or transferable for value to, the United States shall expire and shall not revert to the defendant, nor shall the defendant or any person acting in concert with or on behalf of the defendant be eligible to purchase forfeited property at any sale held by the United States. Upon application of a person, other than the defendant or a person acting in concert with or on behalf of the defendant, the court may restrain or stay the sale or disposition of the property pending the conclusion of any appeal of the criminal case giving rise to the forfeiture, if the applicant demonstrates that proceeding with the sale or disposition of the property will result in irreparable injury, harm or loss to him. Notwithstanding <ref>31 U.S.C. 3302(b)</ref>, the proceeds of any sale or other disposition of property forfeited under this section and any moneys forfeited shall be used to pay all proper expenses for the forfeiture and the sale, including expenses of seizure, maintenance and custody of the property pending its disposition, advertising and court costs. The Attorney General shall deposit in the Treasury any amounts of such proceeds or moneys remaining after the payment of such expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to property ordered forfeited under this section, the Attorney General is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> grant petitions for mitigation or remission of forfeiture, restore forfeited property to victims of a violation of this chapter, or take any other action to protect the rights of innocent persons which is in the interest of justice and which is not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compromise claims arising under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> award compensation to persons providing information resulting in a forfeiture under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> direct the disposition by the United States of all property ordered forfeited under this section by public sale or any other commercially feasible means, making due provision for the rights of innocent persons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> take appropriate measures necessary to safeguard and maintain property ordered forfeited under this section pending its disposition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General may promulgate regulations with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> making reasonable efforts to provide notice to persons who may have an interest in property ordered forfeited under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> granting petitions for remission or mitigation of forfeiture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the restitution of property to victims of an offense petitioning for remission or mitigation of forfeiture under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the disposition by the United States of forfeited property by public sale or other commercially feasible means;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the maintenance and safekeeping of any property forfeited under this section pending its disposition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the compromise of claims arising under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Pending the promulgation of such regulations, all provisions of law relating to the disposition of property, or the proceeds from the sale thereof, or the remission or mitigation of forfeitures for violation of the customs laws, and the compromise of claims and the award of compensation to informers in respect of such forfeitures shall apply to forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this section, insofar as applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions hereof. Such duties as are imposed upon the Customs Service or any person with respect to the disposition of property under the customs law shall be performed under this chapter by the Attorney General.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (<i>l</i>), no party claiming an interest in property subject to forfeiture under this section may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> intervene in a trial or appeal of a criminal case involving the forfeiture of such property under this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> commence an action at law or equity against the United States concerning the validity of his alleged interest in the property subsequent to the filing of an indictment or information alleging that the property is subject to forfeiture under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to enter orders as provided in this section without regard to the location of any property which may be subject to forfeiture under this section or which has been ordered forfeited under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> In order to facilitate the identification or location of property declared forfeited and to facilitate the disposition of petitions for remission or mitigation of forfeiture, after the entry of an order declaring property forfeited to the United States the court may, upon application of the United States, order that the testimony of any witness relating to the property forfeited be taken by deposition and that any designated book, paper, document, record, recording, or other material not privileged be produced at the same time and place, in the same manner as provided for the taking of depositions under Rule 15 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Following the entry of an order of forfeiture under this section, the United States shall publish notice of the order and of its intent to dispose of the property in such manner as the Attorney General may direct. The Government may also, to the extent practicable, provide direct written notice to any person known to have alleged an interest in the property that is the subject of the order of forfeiture as a substitute for published notice as to those persons so notified.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person, other than the defendant, asserting a legal interest in property which has been ordered forfeited to the United States pursuant to this section may, within thirty days of the final publication of notice or his receipt of notice under paragraph (1), whichever is earlier, petition the court for a hearing to adjudicate the validity of his alleged interest in the property. The hearing shall be held before the court alone, without a jury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The petition shall be signed by the petitioner under penalty of perjury and shall set forth the nature and extent of the petitioner’s right, title, or interest in the property, the time and circumstances of the petitioner’s acquisition of the right, title, or interest in the property, any additional facts supporting the petitioner’s claim, and the relief sought.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The hearing on the petition shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with the interests of justice, be held within thirty days of the filing of the petition. The court may consolidate the hearing on the petition with a hearing on any other petition filed by a person other than the defendant under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> At the hearing, the petitioner may testify and present evidence and witnesses on his own behalf, and cross-examine witnesses who appear at the hearing. The United States may present evidence and witnesses in rebuttal and in defense of its claim to the property and cross-examine witnesses who appear at the hearing. In addition to testimony and evidence presented at the hearing, the court shall consider the relevant portions of the record of the criminal case which resulted in the order of forfeiture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> If, after the hearing, the court determines that the petitioner has established by a preponderance of the evidence that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the petitioner has a legal right, title, or interest in the property, and such right, title, or interest renders the order of forfeiture invalid in whole or in part because the right, title, or interest was vested in the petitioner rather than the defendant or was superior to any right, title, or interest of the defendant at the time of the commission of the acts which gave rise to the forfeiture of the property under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the petitioner is a bona fide purchaser for value of the right, title, or interest in the property and was at the time of purchase reasonably without cause to believe that the property was subject to forfeiture under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the court shall amend the order of forfeiture in accordance with its determination.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Following the court’s disposition of all petitions filed under this subsection, or if no such petitions are filed following the expiration of the period provided in paragraph (2) for the filing of such petitions, the United States shall have clear title to property that is the subject of the order of forfeiture and may warrant good title to any subsequent purchaser or transferee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<chapeau> If any of the property described in subsection (a), as a result of any act or omission of the defendant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> cannot be located upon the exercise of due diligence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has been transferred or sold to, or deposited with, a third party;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has been placed beyond the jurisdiction of the court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> has been substantially diminished in value; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> has been commingled with other property which cannot be divided without difficulty;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the court shall order the forfeiture of any other property of the defendant up to the value of any property described in paragraphs (1) through (5).</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 943</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II</ref>, §§ 302, 2301(a)–(c), <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2040</ref>, 2192; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1153(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–13</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 23</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7034, 7058(d), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4398</ref>, 4403; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3561</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–16, § 3(4)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1607</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1964.</num>
<heading> Civil remedies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to prevent and restrain violations of section 1962 of this chapter by issuing appropriate orders, including, but not limited to: ordering any person to divest himself of any interest, direct or indirect, in any enterprise; imposing reasonable restrictions on the future activities or investments of any person, including, but not limited to, prohibiting any person from engaging in the same type of endeavor as the enterprise engaged in, the activities of which affect interstate or foreign commerce; or ordering dissolution or reorganization of any enterprise, making due provision for the rights of innocent persons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may institute proceedings under this section. Pending final determination thereof, the court may at any time enter such restraining orders or prohibitions, or take such other actions, including the acceptance of satisfactory performance bonds, as it shall deem proper.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any person injured in his business or property by reason of a violation of section 1962 of this chapter may sue therefor in any appropriate United States district court and shall recover threefold the damages he sustains and the cost of the suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, except that no person may rely upon any conduct that would have been actionable as fraud in the purchase or sale of securities to establish a violation of section 1962. The exception contained in the preceding sentence does not apply to an action against any person that is criminally convicted in connection with the fraud, in which case the statute of limitations shall start to run on the date on which the conviction becomes final.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A final judgment or decree rendered in favor of the United States in any criminal proceeding brought by the United States under this chapter shall estop the defendant from denying the essential allegations of the criminal offense in any subsequent civil proceeding brought by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 943</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(24)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–67, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1995-12-22">Dec. 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 758</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1965.</num>
<heading> Venue and process</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any civil action or proceeding under this chapter against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district in which such person resides, is found, has an agent, or transacts his affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In any action under section 1964 of this chapter in any district court of the United States in which it is shown that the ends of justice require that other parties residing in any other district be brought before the court, the court may cause such parties to be summoned, and process for that purpose may be served in any judicial district of the United States by the marshal thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In any civil or criminal action or proceeding instituted by the United States under this chapter in the district court of the United States for any judicial district, subpenas issued by such court to compel the attendance of witnesses may be served in any other judicial district, except that in any civil action or proceeding no such subpena shall be issued for service upon any individual who resides in another district at a place more than one hundred miles from the place at which such court is held without approval given by a judge of such court upon a showing of good cause.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> All other process in any action or proceeding under this chapter may be served on any person in any judicial district in which such person resides, is found, has an agent, or transacts his affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1966.</num>
<heading> Expedition of actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any civil action instituted under this chapter by the United States in any district court of the United States, the Attorney General may file with the clerk of such court a certificate stating that in his opinion the case is of general public importance. A copy of that certificate shall be furnished immediately by such clerk to the chief judge or in his absence to the presiding district judge of the district in which such action is pending. Upon receipt of such copy, such judge shall designate immediately a judge of that district to hear and determine action.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 944</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(24)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3359</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1967.</num>
<heading> Evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any proceeding ancillary to or in any civil action instituted by the United States under this chapter the proceedings may be open or closed to the public at the discretion of the court after consideration of the rights of affected persons.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1968.</num>
<heading> Civil investigative demand</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever the Attorney General has reason to believe that any person or enterprise may be in possession, custody, or control of any documentary materials relevant to a racketeering investigation, he may, prior to the institution of a civil or criminal proceeding thereon, issue in writing, and cause to be served upon such person, a civil investigative demand requiring such person to produce such material for examination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each such demand shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> state the nature of the conduct constituting the alleged racketeering violation which is under investigation and the provision of law applicable thereto;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describe the class or classes of documentary material produced thereunder with such definiteness and certainty as to permit such material to be fairly identified;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> state that the demand is returnable forthwith or prescribe a return date which will provide a reasonable period of time within which the material so demanded may be assembled and made available for inspection and copying or reproduction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identify the custodian to whom such material shall be made available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> No such demand shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contain any requirement which would be held to be unreasonable if contained in a subpena duces tecum issued by a court of the United States in aid of a grand jury investigation of such alleged racketeering violation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require the production of any documentary evidence which would be privileged from disclosure if demanded by a subpena duces tecum issued by a court of the United States in aid of a grand jury investigation of such alleged racketeering violation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Service of any such demand or any petition filed under this section may be made upon a person by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> delivering a duly executed copy thereof to any partner, executive officer, managing agent, or general agent thereof, or to any agent thereof authorized by appointment or by law to receive service of process on behalf of such person, or upon any individual person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> delivering a duly executed copy thereof to the principal office or place of business of the person to be served; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> depositing such copy in the United States mail, by registered or certified mail duly addressed to such person at its principal office or place of business.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A verified return by the individual serving any such demand or petition setting forth the manner of such service shall be prima facie proof of such service. In the case of service by registered or certified mail, such return shall be accompanied by the return post office receipt of delivery of such demand.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall designate a racketeering investigator to serve as racketeer document custodian, and such additional rack­eteering investigators as he shall determine from time to time to be necessary to serve as deputies to such officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person upon whom any demand issued under this section has been duly served shall make such material available for inspection and copying or reproduction to the custodian designated therein at the principal place of business of such person, or at such other place as such custodian and such person thereafter may agree and prescribe in writing or as the court may direct, pursuant to this section on the return date specified in such demand, or on such later date as such custodian may prescribe in writing. Such person may upon written agreement between such person and the custodian substitute for copies of all or any part of such material originals thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The custodian to whom any documentary material is so delivered shall take physical possession thereof, and shall be responsible for the use made thereof and for the return thereof pursuant to this chapter. The custodian may cause the preparation of such copies of such documentary material as may be required for official use under regulations which shall be promulgated by the Attorney General. While in the possession of the custodian, no material so produced shall be available for examination, without the consent of the person who produced such material, by any individual other than the Attorney General. Under such reasonable terms and conditions as the Attorney General shall prescribe, documentary material while in the possession of the custodian shall be available for examination by the person who produced such material or any duly authorized representatives of such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Whenever any attorney has been designated to appear on behalf of the United States before any court or grand jury in any case or proceeding involving any alleged violation of this chapter, the custodian may deliver to such attorney such documentary material in the possession of the custodian as such attorney determines to be required for use in the presentation of such case or proceeding on behalf of the United States. Upon the conclusion of any such case or proceeding, such attorney shall return to the custodian any documentary material so withdrawn which has not passed into the control of such court or grand jury through the introduction thereof into the record of such case or proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Upon the completion of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the racketeering investigation for which any documentary material was produced under this chapter, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any case or proceeding arising from such investigation, the custodian shall return to the person who produced such material all such material other than copies thereof made by the Attorney General pursuant to this subsection which has not passed into the control of any court or grand jury through the introduction thereof into the record of such case or proceeding.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> When any documentary material has been produced by any person under this section for use in any racketeering investigation, and no such case or proceeding arising therefrom has been instituted within a reasonable time after completion of the examination and analysis of all evidence assembled in the course of such investigation, such person shall be entitled, upon written demand made upon the Attorney General, to the return of all documentary material other than copies thereof made pursuant to this subsection so produced by such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> In the event of the death, disability, or separation from service of the custodian of any documentary material produced under any demand issued under this section or the official relief of such custodian from responsibility for the custody and control of such material, the Attorney General shall promptly—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> designate another racketeering investigator to serve as custodian thereof, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> transmit notice in writing to the person who produced such material as to the identity and address of the successor so designated.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any successor so designated shall have with regard to such materials all duties and responsibilities imposed by this section upon his predecessor in office with regard thereto, except that he shall not be held responsible for any default or dereliction which occurred before his designation as custodian.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Whenever any person fails to comply with any civil investigative demand duly served upon him under this section or whenever satisfactory copying or reproduction of any such material cannot be done and such person refuses to surrender such material, the Attorney General may file, in the district court of the United States for any judicial district in which such person resides, is found, or transacts business, and serve upon such person a petition for an order of such court for the enforcement of this section, except that if such person transacts business in more than one such district such petition shall be filed in the district in which such person maintains his principal place of business, or in such other district in which such person transacts business as may be agreed upon by the parties to such petition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Within twenty days after the service of any such demand upon any person, or at any time before the return date specified in the demand, whichever period is shorter, such person may file, in the district court of the United States for the judicial district within which such person resides, is found, or transacts business, and serve upon such custodian a petition for an order of such court modifying or setting aside such demand. The time allowed for compliance with the demand in whole or in part as deemed proper and ordered by the court shall not run during the pendency of such petition in the court. Such petition shall specify each ground upon which the petitioner relies in seeking such relief, and may be based upon any failure of such demand to comply with the provisions of this section or upon any constitutional or other legal right or privilege of such person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> At any time during which any custodian is in custody or control of any documentary material delivered by any person in compliance with any such demand, such person may file, in the district court of the United States for the judicial district within which the office of such custodian is situated, and serve upon such custodian a petition for an order of such court requiring the performance by such custodian of any duty imposed upon him by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> Whenever any petition is filed in any district court of the United States under this section, such court shall have jurisdiction to hear and determine the matter so presented, and to enter such order or orders as may be required to carry into effect the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>