<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 18—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL, CABINET, AND SUPREME COURT ASSASSINATION, KIDNAPPING, AND ASSAULT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 351.</num>
<heading> Congressional, Cabinet, and Supreme Court assassination, kidnapping, and assault; penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever kills any individual who is a Member of Congress or a Member-of-Congress-elect, a member of the executive branch of the Government who is the head, or a person nominated to be head during the pendency of such nomination, of a department listed in <ref>section 101 of title 5</ref> or the second ranking official in such department, the Director (or a person nominated to be Director during the pendency of such nomination) or Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence, the Director (or a person nominated to be Director during the pendency of such nomination) or Deputy Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, a major Presidential or Vice Presidential candidate (as defined in <ref>section 3056 of this title</ref>), or a Justice of the United States, as defined in <ref>section 451 of title 28</ref>, or a person nominated to be a Justice of the United States, during the pendency of such nomination, shall be punished as provided by sections 1111 and 1112 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever kidnaps any individual designated in subsection (a) of this section shall be punished (1) by imprisonment for any term of years or for life, or (2) by death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life, if death results to such individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whoever attempts to kill or kidnap any individual designated in subsection (a) of this section shall be punished by imprisonment for any term of years or for life.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If two or more persons conspire to kill or kidnap any individual designated in subsection (a) of this section and one or more of such persons do any act to effect the object of the conspiracy, each shall be punished (1) by imprisonment for any term of years or for life, or (2) by death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life, if death results to such individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Whoever assaults any person designated in subsection (a) of this section shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and if the assault involved the use of a dangerous weapon, or personal injury results, shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> If Federal investigative or prosecutive jurisdiction is asserted for a violation of this section, such assertion shall suspend the exercise of jurisdiction by a State or local authority, under any applicable State or local law, until Federal action is terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Violations of this section shall be investigated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation. Assistance may be requested from any Federal, State, or local agency, including the Army, Navy, and Air Force, any statute, rule, or regulation to the contrary notwithstanding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> In a prosecution for an offense under this section the Government need not prove that the defendant knew that the victim of the offense was an individual protected by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> There is extraterritorial jurisdiction over the conduct prohibited by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–644, title IV, § 15</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1891</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–285</ref>, §§ 1, 2(a), <date date="1982-10-06">Oct. 6, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 62</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3614</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7074</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320101(d)</ref>, title XXXIII, §§ 330016(1)(K), (L), 330021(1), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2108</ref>, 2147, 2150; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(12)(C)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>, 3509; <ref>Pub. L. 112–87, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>