<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 203—</num>
<heading>ARREST AND COMMITMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3041.</num>
<heading> Power of courts and magistrates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For any offense against the United States, the offender may, by any justice or judge of the United States, or by any United States magistrate judge, or by any chancellor, judge of a supreme or superior court, chief or first judge of the common pleas, mayor of a city, justice of the peace, or other magistrate, of any state where the offender may be found, and at the expense of the United States, be arrested and imprisoned or released as provided in chapter 207 of this title, as the case may be, for trial before such court of the United States as by law has cognizance of the offense. Copies of the process shall be returned as speedily as may be into the office of the clerk of such court, together with the recognizances of the witnesses for their appearances to testify in the case.</p>
<p class="indent0">A United States judge or magistrate judge shall proceed under this section according to rules promulgated by the Supreme Court of the United States. Any state judge or magistrate acting hereunder may proceed according to the usual mode of procedure of his state but his acts and orders shall have no effect beyond determining, pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 3142 of this title</ref>, whether to detain or conditionally release the prisoner prior to trial or to discharge him from arrest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–465, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-06-22">June 22, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 217</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1985</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3042.</num>
<heading> Extraterritorial jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 3041 of this title</ref> shall apply in any country where the United States exercises extraterritorial jurisdiction for the arrest and removal therefrom to the United States of any citizen or national of the United States who is a fugitive from justice charged with or convicted of the commission of any offense against the United States, and shall also apply throughout the United States for the arrest and removal therefrom to the jurisdiction of any officer or representative of the United States vested with judicial authority in any country in which the United States exercises extraterritorial jurisdiction, of any citizen or national of the United States who is a fugitive from justice charged with or convicted of the commission of any offense against the United States in any country where it exercises extraterritorial jurisdiction.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such fugitive first mentioned may, by any officer or representative of the United States vested with judicial authority in any country in which the United States exercises extraterritorial jurisdiction and agreeably to the usual mode of process against offenders subject to such jurisdiction, be arrested and detained or conditionally released pursuant to <ref>section 3142 of this title</ref>, as the case may be, pending the issuance of a warrant for his removal, which warrant the principal officer or representative of the United States vested with judicial authority in the country where the fugitive shall be found shall seasonably issue, and the United States marshal or corresponding officer shall execute.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such marshal or other officer, or the deputies of such marshal or officer, when engaged in executing such warrant without the jurisdiction of the court to which they are attached, shall have all the powers of a marshal of the United States so far as such powers are requisite for the prisoner’s safekeeping and the execution of the warrant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3043.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1986</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3044.</num>
<heading> Complaint—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3045.</num>
<heading> Internal revenue violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Warrants of arrest for violations of internal revenue laws may be issued by United States magistrate judges upon the complaint of a United States attorney, assistant United States attorney, collector, or deputy collector of internal revenue or revenue agent, or private citizen; but no such warrant of arrest shall be issued upon the complaint of a private citizen unless first approved in writing by a United States attorney.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 816</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3046.</num>
<heading> Warrant or summons—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3047.</num>
<heading> Multiple warrants unnecessary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When two or more charges are made, or two or more indictments are found against any person, only one writ or warrant shall be necessary to commit him for trial. It shall be sufficient to state in the writ the name or general character of the offenses, or to refer to them only in general terms.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3048.</num>
<heading> Commitment to another district; removal—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 817</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3049.</num>
<heading> Warrant for removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Only one writ or warrant is necessary to remove a prisoner from one district to another. One copy thereof may be delivered to the sheriff or jailer from whose custody the prisoner is taken, and another to the sheriff or jailer to whose custody he is committed, and the original writ, with the marshal’s return thereon, shall be returned to the clerk of the district to which he is removed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 817</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3050.</num>
<heading> Bureau of Prisons employees’ powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An officer or employee of the Bureau of Prisons may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make arrests on or off of Bureau of Prisons property without warrant for violations of the following provisions regardless of where the violation may occur: sections 111 (assaulting officers), 751 (escape), and 752 (assisting escape) of title 18, United States Code, and section 1826(c) (escape) of title 28, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make arrests on Bureau of Prisons premises or reservation land of a penal, detention, or correctional facility without warrant for violations occurring thereon of the following provisions: sections 661 (theft), 1361 (depredation of property), 1363 (destruction of property), 1791 (contraband), 1792 (mutiny and riot), and 1793 (trespass) of title 18, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> arrest without warrant for any other offense described in title 18 or 21 of the United States Code, if committed on the premises or reservation of a penal or correctional facility of the Bureau of Prisons if necessary to safeguard security, good order, or government property;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if such officer or employee has reasonable grounds to believe that the arrested person is guilty of such offense, and if there is likelihood of such person’s escaping before an arrest warrant can be obtained. If the arrested person is a fugitive from custody, such prisoner shall be returned to custody. Officers and employees of the said Bureau of Prisons may carry firearms under such rules and regulations as the Attorney General may prescribe.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 817</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 65</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3051.</num>
<heading> Powers of Special Agents <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002223">1</ref> of Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Special agents of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, as well as any other investigator or officer charged by the Attorney General with the duty of enforcing any of the criminal, seizure, or forfeiture provisions of the laws of the United States, may carry firearms, serve warrants and subpoenas issued under the authority of the United States and make arrests without warrant for any offense against the United States committed in their presence, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any special agent of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives may, in respect to the performance of his or her duties, make seizures of property subject to forfeiture to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), and except to the extent that such provisions conflict with the provisions of <ref>section 983 of title 18</ref>, United States Code, insofar as section 983 applies, the provisions of the Customs laws relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the seizure, summary and judicial forfeiture, and condemnation of property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the disposition of such property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the remission or mitigation of such forfeiture; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the compromise of claims,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall apply to seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under any applicable provision of law enforced or administered by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of paragraph (1), duties that are imposed upon a customs officer or any other person with respect to the seizure and forfeiture of property under the customs laws of the United States shall be performed with respect to seizures and forfeitures of property under this section by such officers, agents, or any other person as may be authorized or designated for that purpose by the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the disposition of firearms forfeited by reason of a violation of any law of the United States shall be governed by the provisions of section 5872(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XI, § 1113</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3052.</num>
<heading> Powers of Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director, Associate Director, Assistant to the Director, Assistant Directors, inspectors, and agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation of the Department of Justice may carry firearms, serve warrants and subpoenas issued under the authority of the United States and make arrests without warrant for any offense against the United States committed in their presence, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 817</ref>; <ref>Jan. 10, 1951, ch. 1221, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 1239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3053.</num>
<heading> Powers of marshals and deputies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States marshals and their deputies may carry firearms and may make arrests without warrant for any offense against the United States committed in their presence, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 817</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3054.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–79, § 9(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1981-11-16">Nov. 16, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1079</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3055.</num>
<heading> Officers’ powers to suppress Indian liquor traffic</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief special officer for the suppression of the liquor traffic among Indians and duly authorized officers working under his supervision whose appointments are made or affirmed by the Commissioner of Indian Affairs or the Secretary of the Interior may execute all warrants of arrest and other lawful precepts issued under the authority of the United States and in the execution of his duty he may command all necessary assistance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 817</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3056.</num>
<heading> Powers, authorities, and duties of United States Secret Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the United States Secret Service is authorized to protect the following persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President, the Vice President (or other officer next in the order of succession to the Office of President), the President-elect, and the Vice President-elect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The immediate families of those individuals listed in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Former Presidents and their spouses for their lifetimes, except that protection of a spouse shall terminate in the event of remarriage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Children of a former President who are under 16 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Visiting heads of foreign states or foreign governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Other distinguished foreign visitors to the United States and official representatives of the United States performing special missions abroad when the President directs that such protection be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Major Presidential and Vice Presidential candidates and, within 120 days of the general Presidential election, the spouses of such candidates. As used in this paragraph, the term “major Presidential and Vice Presidential candidates” means those individuals identified as such by the Secretary of Homeland Security after consultation with an advisory committee consisting of the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, the majority and minority leaders of the Senate, and one additional member selected by the other members of the committee. The Committee shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Former Vice Presidents, their spouses, and their children who are under 16 years of age, for a period of not more than six months after the date the former Vice President leaves office. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall have the authority to direct the Secret Service to provide temporary protection for any of these individuals at any time thereafter if the Secretary of Homeland Security or designee determines that information or conditions warrant such protection.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The protection authorized in paragraphs (2) through (8) may be declined.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secret Service is authorized to detect and arrest any person who violates—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 508, 509, 510, 871, or 879 of this title or, with respect to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, Federal land banks, and Federal land bank associations, section 213, 216,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002224">1</ref> 433, 493, 657, 709, 1006, 1007, 1011, 1013, 1014, 1907, or 1909 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any of the laws of the United States relating to coins, obligations, and securities of the United States and of foreign governments; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any of the laws of the United States relating to electronic fund transfer frauds, access device frauds, false identification documents or devices, and any fraud or other criminal or unlawful activity in or against any federally insured financial institution; except that the authority conferred by this paragraph shall be exercised subject to the agreement of the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security and shall not affect the authority of any other Federal law enforcement agency with respect to those laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, officers and agents of the Secret Service are authorized to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> execute warrants issued under the laws of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carry firearms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make arrests without warrant for any offense against the United States committed in their presence, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> offer and pay rewards for services and information leading to the apprehension of persons involved in the violation or potential violation of those provisions of law which the Secret Service is authorized to enforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> pay expenses for unforeseen emergencies of a confidential nature under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security and accounted for solely on the Secretary’s certificate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> perform such other functions and duties as are authorized by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds expended from appropriations available to the Secret Service for the purchase of counterfeits and subsequently recovered shall be reimbursed to the appropriations available to the Secret Service at the time of the reimbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly and willfully obstructs, resists, or interferes with a Federal law enforcement agent engaged in the performance of the protective functions authorized by this section or by <ref>section 1752 of this title</ref> shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When directed by the President, the United States Secret Service is authorized to participate, under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, in the planning, coordination, and implementation of security operations at special events of national significance, as determined by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> At the end of each fiscal year, the President through such agency or office as the President may designate, shall report to the Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> what events, if any, were designated special events of national significance for security purposes under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the criteria and information used in making each designation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Under the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secret Service is authorized, at the request of any State or local law enforcement agency in conjunction with an investigation, or at the request of the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, to provide forensic and investigative assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The United States Secret Service shall be maintained as a distinct entity within the Department of Homeland Security and shall not be merged with any other Department function. No personnel and operational elements of the United States Secret Service shall report to an individual other than the Director of the United States Secret Service, who shall report directly to the Secretary of Homeland Security without being required to report through any other official of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 818</ref>; <ref>July 16, 1951, ch. 226, § 4</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 122</ref>; <ref>Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1143, § 2</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–168, title I, § 104(h)</ref>, <date date="1959-08-18">Aug. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–791</ref>, <date date="1962-10-10">Oct. 10, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 809</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–829, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 956</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–186</ref>, <date date="1965-09-15">Sept. 15, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–218</ref>, <date date="1965-09-29">Sept. 29, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–608</ref>, ch. XI, § 1101, <date date="1968-10-21">Oct. 21, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1198</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–644, title V, § 19</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1892</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–651, § 4</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–346, § 8</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–552, title VI, § 609(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-27">Dec. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–408, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-09-11">Sept. 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–297, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–308, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–151, § 115(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-14">Nov. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 977</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–587, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–329, title V, § 530</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 605(i)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–544, § 3</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title V, § 506(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1703(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2313</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–21, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title VI</ref>, §§ 604, 607, 608(a), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 253</ref>, 256; <ref>Pub. L. 110–326, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2008-09-26">Sept. 26, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–257, § 2</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(135)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3056A.</num>
<heading> Powers, authorities, and duties of United States Secret Service Uniformed Division</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> There is hereby created and established a permanent police force, to be known as the “United States Secret Service Uniformed Division”. Subject to the supervision of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division shall perform such duties as the Director, United States Secret Service, may prescribe in connection with the protection of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The White House in the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any building in which Presidential offices are located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Treasury Building and grounds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The President, the Vice President (or other officer next in the order of succession to the Office of President), the President-elect, the Vice President-elect, and their immediate families.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Foreign diplomatic missions located in the metropolitan area of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The temporary official residence of the Vice President and grounds in the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Foreign diplomatic missions located in metropolitan areas (other than the District of Columbia) in the United States where there are located twenty or more such missions headed by full-time officers, except that such protection shall be provided only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the basis of extraordinary protective need;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon request of an affected metropolitan area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> when the extraordinary protective need arises at or in association with a visit to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a permanent mission to, or an observer mission invited to participate in the work of, an international organization of which the United States is a member; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an international organization of which the United States is a member;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">except that such protection may also be provided for motorcades and at other places associated with any such visit and may be extended at places of temporary domicile in connection with any such visit.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Foreign consular and diplomatic missions located in such areas in the United States, its territories and possessions, as the President, on a case-by-case basis, may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Visits of foreign government officials to metropolitan areas (other than the District of Columbia) where there are located twenty or more consular or diplomatic missions staffed by accredited personnel, including protection for motorcades and at other places associated with such visits when such officials are in the United States to conduct official business with the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Former Presidents and their spouses, as provided in <ref>section 3056(a)(3) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> An event designated under <ref>section 3056(e) of title 18</ref> as a special event of national significance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Major Presidential and Vice Presidential candidates and, within 120 days of the general Presidential election, the spouses of such candidates, as provided in <ref>section 3056(a)(7) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Visiting heads of foreign states or foreign governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the direction of the Director of the Secret Service, members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division are authorized to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carry firearms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make arrests without warrant for any offense against the United States committed in their presence, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> perform such other functions and duties as are authorized by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division shall possess privileges and powers similar to those of the members of the Metropolitan Police of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division shall be furnished with uniforms and other necessary equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In carrying out the functions pursuant to paragraphs (7) and (9) of subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security may utilize, with their consent, on a reimbursable basis, the services, personnel, equipment, and facilities of State and local governments, and is authorized to reimburse such State and local governments for the utilization of such services, personnel, equipment, and facilities. The Secretary of Homeland Security may carry out the functions pursuant to paragraphs (7) and (9) of subsection (a) by contract. The authority of this subsection may be transferred by the President to the Secretary of State. In carrying out any duty under paragraphs (7) and (9) of subsection (a), the Secretary of State is authorized to utilize any authority available to the Secretary under title II of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3057.</num>
<heading> Bankruptcy investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any judge, receiver, or trustee having reasonable grounds for believing that any violation under chapter 9 of this title or other laws of the United States relating to insolvent debtors, receiverships or reorganization plans has been committed, or that an investigation should be had in connection therewith, shall report to the appropriate United States attorney all the facts and circumstances of the case, the names of the witnesses and the offense or offenses believed to have been committed. Where one of such officers has made such report, the others need not do so.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The United States attorney thereupon shall inquire into the facts and report thereon to the judge, and if it appears probable that any such offense has been committed, shall without delay, present the matter to the grand jury, unless upon inquiry and examination he decides that the ends of public justice do not require investigation or prosecution, in which case he shall report the facts to the Attorney General for his direction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 818</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 48</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 96</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title III, § 314(i)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3058.</num>
<heading> Interned belligerent nationals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, belonging to the armed land or naval forces of a belligerent nation or belligerent faction and being interned in the United States, in accordance with the law of nations, leaves or attempts to leave said jurisdiction, or leaves or attempts to leave the limits of internment without permission from the proper official of the United States in charge, or willfully overstays a leave of absence granted by such official, shall be subject to arrest by any marshal or deputy marshal of the United States, or by the military or naval authorities thereof, and shall be returned to the place of internment and there confined and safely kept for such period of time as the official of the United States in charge shall direct.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 818</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3571</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 3059 to 3059B.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title III, § 301(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1781</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3060.</num>
<heading> Preliminary examination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by this section, a preliminary examination shall be held within the time set by the judge or magistrate judge pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, to determine whether there is probable cause to believe that an offense has been committed and that the arrested person has committed it.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The date for the preliminary examination shall be fixed by the judge or magistrate judge at the initial appearance of the arrested person. Except as provided by subsection (c) of this section, or unless the arrested person waives the preliminary examination, such examination shall be held within a reasonable time following initial appearance, but in any event not later than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the fourteenth day following the date of the initial appearance of the arrested person before such officer if the arrested person is held in custody without any provision for release, or is held in custody for failure to meet the conditions of release imposed, or is released from custody only during specified hours of the day; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the twentieth day following the date of the initial appearance if the arrested person is released from custody under any condition other than a condition described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> With the consent of the arrested person, the date fixed by the judge or magistrate judge for the preliminary examination may be a date later than that prescribed by subsection (b), or may be continued one or more times to a date subsequent to the date initially fixed therefor. In the absence of such consent of the accused, the judge or magistrate judge may extend the time limits only on a showing that extraordinary circumstances exist and justice requires the delay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Except as provided by subsection (e) of this section, an arrested person who has not been accorded the preliminary examination required by subsection (a) within the period of time fixed by the judge or magistrate judge in compliance with subsections (b) and (c), shall be discharged from custody or from the requirement of bail or any other condition of release, without prejudice, however, to the institution of further criminal proceedings against him upon the charge upon which he was arrested.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> No preliminary examination in compliance with subsection (a) of this section shall be required to be accorded an arrested person, nor shall such arrested person be discharged from custody or from the requirement of bail or any other condition of release pursuant to subsection (d), if at any time subsequent to the initial appearance of such person before a judge or magistrate judge and prior to the date fixed for the preliminary examination pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) an indictment is returned or, in appropriate cases, an information is filed against such person in a court of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Proceedings before United States magistrate judges under this section shall be taken down by a court reporter or recorded by suitable sound recording equipment. A copy of the record of such proceeding shall be made available at the expense of the United States to a person who makes affidavit that he is unable to pay or give security therefor, and the expense of such copy shall be paid by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1179</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–16, § 3(9)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3061.</num>
<heading> Investigative powers of Postal Service personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (b) of this section, Postal Inspectors and other agents of the United States Postal Service designated by the Board of Governors to investigate criminal matters related to the Postal Service and the mails may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve warrants and subpoenas issued under the authority of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make arrests without warrant for offenses against the United States committed in their presence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make arrests without warrant for felonies cognizable under the laws of the United States if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such a felony;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carry firearms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make seizures of property as provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The powers granted by subsection (a) of this section shall be exercised only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the enforcement of laws regarding property in the custody of the Postal Service, property of the Postal Service, the use of the mails, and other postal offenses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent authorized by the Attorney General pursuant to agreement between the Attorney General and the Postal Service, in the enforcement of other laws of the United States, if the Attorney General determines that violations of such laws have a detrimental effect upon the operations of the Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Postal Service may employ police officers for duty in connection with the protection of property owned or occupied by the Postal Service or under the charge and control of the Postal Service, and persons on that property, including duty in areas outside the property to the extent necessary to protect the property and persons on the property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to such property, such officers shall have the power to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enforce Federal laws and regulations for the protection of persons and property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carry firearms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make arrests without a warrant for any offense against the Unites <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002225">1</ref> States committed in the presence of the officer or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if the officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing a felony.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to such property, such officers may have, to such extent as the Postal Service may by regulations prescribe, the power to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> serve warrants and subpoenas issued under the authority of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct investigations, on and off the property in question, of offenses that may have been committed against property owned or occupied by the Postal Service or persons on the property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> As to such property, the Postmaster General may prescribe regulations necessary for the protection and administration of property owned or occupied by the Postal Service and persons on the property. The regulations may include reasonable penalties, within the limits prescribed in subparagraph (B), for violations of the regulations. The regulations shall be posted and remain posted in a conspicuous place on the property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A person violating a regulation prescribed under this subsection shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 30 days, or both.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–560, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-12">Oct. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 998</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(38)(A)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 781</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6251(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1001</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3062.</num>
<heading> General arrest authority for violation of release conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A law enforcement officer, who is authorized to arrest for an offense committed in his presence, may arrest a person who is released pursuant to chapter 207 if the officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the person is violating, in his presence, a condition imposed on the person pursuant to section 3142(c)(1)(B)(iv), (v), (viii), (ix), or (xiii), or, if the violation involves a failure to remain in a specified institution as required, a condition imposed pursuant to section 3142(c)(1)(B)(x).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 204(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1986</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7052</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4401</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3063.</num>
<heading> Powers of Environmental Protection Agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Upon designation by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, any law enforcement officer of the Environmental Protection Agency with responsibility for the investigation of criminal violations of a law administered by the Environmental Protection Agency, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry firearms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> execute and serve any warrant or other processes issued under the authority of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> make arrests without warrant for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any offense against the United States committed in such officer’s presence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any felony offense against the United States if such officer has probable cause to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing that felony offense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The powers granted under subsection (a) of this section shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines approved by the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–582, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-01">Nov. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3064.</num>
<heading> Powers of Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Authorized employees of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration may direct a driver of a commercial motor vehicle (as defined in <ref>section 31132 of title 49</ref>) to stop for inspection of the vehicle, driver, cargo, and required records at or in the vicinity of an inspection site.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title IV, § 4143(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>