<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 113B—</num>
<heading>TERRORISM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2331.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “international terrorism” means activities that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> involve violent acts or acts dangerous to human life that are a violation of the criminal laws of the United States or of any State, or that would be a criminal violation if committed within the jurisdiction of the United States or of any State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> appear to be intended—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to intimidate or coerce a civilian population;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to affect the conduct of a government by mass destruction, assassination, or kidnapping; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> occur primarily outside the territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or transcend national boundaries in terms of the means by which they are accomplished, the persons they appear intended to intimidate or coerce, or the locale in which their perpetrators operate or seek asylum;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “national of the United States” has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “person” means any individual or entity capable of holding a legal or beneficial interest in property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “act of war” means any act occurring in the course of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> declared war;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> armed conflict, whether or not war has been declared, between two or more nations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> armed conflict between military forces of any origin;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the term “domestic terrorism” means activities that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> involve acts dangerous to human life that are a violation of the criminal laws of the United States or of any State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> appear to be intended—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to intimidate or coerce a civilian population;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to affect the conduct of a government by mass destruction, assassination, or kidnapping; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> occur primarily within the territorial jurisdiction of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> the term “military force” does not include any person that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> has been designated as a—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> foreign terrorist organization by the Secretary of State under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1189</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> specially designated global terrorist (as such term is defined in section 594.310 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations) by the Secretary of State or the Secretary of the Treasury; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has been determined by the court to not be a “military force”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4521</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–253, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-03">Oct. 3, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332.</num>
<heading> Criminal penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Homicide</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever kills a national of the United States, while such national is outside the United States, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the killing is murder (as defined in section 1111(a)), be fined under this title, punished by death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life, or both;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the killing is a voluntary manslaughter as defined in <ref>section 1112(a) of this title</ref>, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if the killing is an involuntary manslaughter as defined in <ref>section 1112(a) of this title</ref>, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attempt or Conspiracy With Respect to Homicide</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever outside the United States attempts to kill, or engages in a conspiracy to kill, a national of the United States shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of an attempt to commit a killing that is a murder as defined in this chapter, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a conspiracy by two or more persons to commit a killing that is a murder as defined in <ref>section 1111(a) of this title</ref>, if one or more of such persons do any overt act to effect the object of the conspiracy, be fined under this title or imprisoned for any term of years or for life, or both so fined and so imprisoned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever outside the United States engages in physical violence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with intent to cause serious bodily injury to a national of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with the result that serious bodily injury is caused to a national of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Prosecution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No prosecution for any offense described in this section shall be undertaken by the United States except on written certification of the Attorney General or the highest ranking subordinate of the Attorney General with responsibility for criminal prosecutions that, in the judgment of the certifying official, such offense was intended to coerce, intimidate, or retaliate against a government or a civilian population.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–399, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 896</ref>, § 2331; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–519, § 132(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–27, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1991-04-10">Apr. 10, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–136, § 126</ref>, <date date="1991-10-25">Oct. 25, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 643</ref>; renumbered § 2332 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60022</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1980</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 705(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332a.</num>
<heading> Use of weapons of mass destruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense Against a National of the United States or Within the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person who, without lawful authority, uses, threatens, or attempts or conspires to use, a weapon of mass destruction—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> against a national of the United States while such national is outside of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> against any person or property within the United States, and</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the mail or any facility of interstate or foreign commerce is used in furtherance of the offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such property is used in interstate or foreign commerce or in an activity that affects interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any perpetrator travels in or causes another to travel in interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of the offense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the offense, or the results of the offense, affect interstate or foreign commerce, or, in the case of a threat, attempt, or conspiracy, would have affected interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> against any property that is owned, leased or used by the United States or by any department or agency of the United States, whether the property is within or outside of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> against any property within the United States that is owned, leased, or used by a foreign government,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life, and if death results, shall be punished by death or imprisoned for any term of years or for life.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense by National of the United States Outside of the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any national of the United States who, without lawful authority, uses, or threatens, attempts, or conspires to use, a weapon of mass destruction outside of the United States shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life, and if death results, shall be punished by death, or by imprisonment for any term of years or for life.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “national of the United States” has the meaning given in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “weapon of mass destruction” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any destructive device as defined in <ref>section 921 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any weapon that is designed or intended to cause death or serious bodily injury through the release, dissemination, or impact of toxic or poisonous chemicals, or their precursors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any weapon involving a biological agent, toxin, or vector (as those terms are defined in <ref>section 178 of this title</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any weapon that is designed to release radiation or radioactivity at a level dangerous to human life; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “property” includes all real and personal property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60023(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1980</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title V, § 511(c)</ref>, title VII, § 725, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1284</ref>, 1300; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 605(m)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. I, title II, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–188, title II, § 231(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6802(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3766</ref>, 3767.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332b.</num>
<heading> Acts of terrorism transcending national boundaries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Acts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever, involving conduct transcending national boundaries and in a circumstance described in subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> kills, kidnaps, maims, commits an assault resulting in serious bodily injury, or assaults with a dangerous weapon any person within the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> creates a substantial risk of serious bodily injury to any other person by destroying or damaging any structure, conveyance, or other real or personal property within the United States or by attempting or conspiring to destroy or damage any structure, conveyance, or other real or personal property within the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">in violation of the laws of any State, or the United States, shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of threats, attempts and conspiracies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever threatens to commit an offense under paragraph (1), or attempts or conspires to do so, shall be punished under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Jurisdictional Bases.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The circumstances referred to in subsection (a) are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the mail or any facility of interstate or foreign commerce is used in furtherance of the offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offense obstructs, delays, or affects interstate or foreign commerce, or would have so obstructed, delayed, or affected interstate or foreign commerce if the offense had been consummated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the victim, or intended victim, is the United States Government, a member of the uniformed services, or any official, officer, employee, or agent of the legislative, executive, or judicial branches, or of any department or agency, of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the structure, conveyance, or other real or personal property is, in whole or in part, owned, possessed, or leased to the United States, or any department or agency of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the offense is committed in the territorial sea (including the airspace above and the seabed and subsoil below, and artificial islands and fixed structures erected thereon) of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the offense is committed within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Co-conspirators and accessories after the fact</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Jurisdiction shall exist over all principals and co-conspirators of an offense under this section, and accessories after the fact to any offense under this section, if at least one of the circumstances described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (1) is applicable to at least one offender.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever violates this section shall be punished—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for a killing, or if death results to any person from any other conduct prohibited by this section, by death, or by imprisonment for any term of years or for life;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for kidnapping, by imprisonment for any term of years or for life;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for maiming, by imprisonment for not more than 35 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for assault with a dangerous weapon or assault resulting in serious bodily injury, by imprisonment for not more than 30 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> for destroying or damaging any structure, conveyance, or other real or personal property, by imprisonment for not more than 25 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> for attempting or conspiring to commit an offense, for any term of years up to the maximum punishment that would have applied had the offense been completed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> for threatening to commit an offense under this section, by imprisonment for not more than 10 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consecutive sentence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the court shall not place on probation any person convicted of a violation of this section; nor shall the term of imprisonment imposed under this section run concurrently with any other term of imprisonment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proof Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following shall apply to prosecutions under this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Knowledge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prosecution is not required to prove knowledge by any defendant of a jurisdictional base alleged in the indictment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In a prosecution under this section that is based upon the adoption of State law, only the elements of the offense under State law, and not any provisions pertaining to criminal procedure or evidence, are adopted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extraterritorial Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is extraterritorial Federal jurisdiction—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> over any offense under subsection (a), including any threat, attempt, or conspiracy to commit such offense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> over conduct which, under section 3, renders any person an accessory after the fact to an offense under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investigative Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to any other investigative authority with respect to violations of this title, the Attorney General shall have primary investigative responsibility for all Federal crimes of terrorism, and any violation of section 351(e), 844(e), 844(f)(1), 956(b), 1361, 1366(b), 1366(c), 1751(e), 2152, or 2156 of this title, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall assist the Attorney General at the request of the Attorney General. Nothing in this section shall be construed to interfere with the authority of the United States Secret Service under section 3056.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “conduct transcending national boundaries” means conduct occurring outside of the United States in addition to the conduct occurring in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “facility of interstate or foreign commerce” has the meaning given that term in section 1958(b)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “serious bodily injury” has the meaning given that term in section 1365(g)(3); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002187">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “territorial sea of the United States” means all waters extending seaward to 12 nautical miles from the baselines of the United States, determined in accordance with international law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the term “Federal crime of terrorism” means an offense that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is calculated to influence or affect the conduct of government by intimidation or coercion, or to retaliate against government conduct; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is a violation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> section 32 (relating to destruction of aircraft or aircraft facilities), 37 (relating to violence at international airports), 81 (relating to arson within special maritime and territorial jurisdiction), 175 or 175b (relating to biological weapons), 175c (relating to variola virus), 229 (relating to chemical weapons), subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) of section 351 (relating to congressional, cabinet, and Supreme Court assassination and kidnaping), 831 (relating to nuclear materials), 832 (relating to participation in nuclear and weapons of mass destruction threats to the United States) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002188">2</ref> 842(m) or (n) (relating to plastic explosives), 844(f)(2) or (3) (relating to arson and bombing of Government property risking or causing death), 844(i) (relating to arson and bombing of property used in interstate commerce), 930(c) (relating to killing or attempted killing during an attack on a Federal facility with a dangerous weapon), 956(a)(1) (relating to conspiracy to murder, kidnap, or maim persons abroad), 1030(a)(1) (relating to protection of computers), 1030(a)(5)(A) resulting in damage as defined in 1030(c)(4)(A)(i)(II) through (VI) (relating to protection of computers), 1114 (relating to killing or attempted killing of officers and employees of the United States), 1116 (relating to murder or manslaughter of foreign officials, official guests, or internationally protected persons), 1203 (relating to hostage taking), 1361 (relating to government property or contracts), 1362 (relating to destruction of communication lines, stations, or systems), 1363 (relating to injury to buildings or property within special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States), 1366(a) (relating to destruction of an energy facility), 1751(a), (b), (c), or (d) (relating to Presidential and Presidential staff assassination and kidnaping), 1992 (relating to terrorist attacks and other acts of violence against railroad carriers and against mass transportation systems on land, on water, or through the air), 2155 (relating to destruction of national defense materials, premises, or utilities), 2156 (relating to national defense material, premises, or utilities), 2280 (relating to violence against maritime navigation), 2280a (relating to maritime safety), 2281 through 2281a (relating to violence against maritime fixed platforms), 2332 (relating to certain homicides and other violence against United States nationals occurring outside of the United States), 2332a (relating to use of weapons of mass destruction), 2332b (relating to acts of terrorism transcending national boundaries), 2332f (relating to bombing of public places and facilities), 2332g (relating to missile systems designed to destroy aircraft), 2332h (relating to radiological dispersal devices), 2332i (relating to acts of nuclear terrorism), 2339 (relating to harboring terrorists), 2339A (relating to providing material support to terrorists), 2339B (relating to providing material support to terrorist organizations), 2339C (relating to financing of terrorism), 2339D (relating to military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization), or 2340A (relating to torture) of this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> sections 92 (relating to prohibitions governing atomic weapons) or 236 (relating to sabotage of nuclear facilities or fuel) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2122</ref> or 2284);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> section 46502 (relating to aircraft piracy), the second sentence of section 46504 (relating to assault on a flight crew with a dangerous weapon), section 46505(b)(3) or (c) (relating to explosive or incendiary devices, or endangerment of human life by means of weapons, on aircraft), section 46506 if homicide or attempted homicide is involved (relating to application of certain criminal laws to acts on aircraft), or section 60123(b) (relating to destruction of interstate gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facility) of title 49; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> section 1010A of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (relating to narco-terrorism).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 702(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1291</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(s)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–197, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-25">June 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI</ref>, §§ 6603(a)(1), 6803(c)(3), 6908, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3762</ref>, 3769, 3774; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I</ref>, §§ 110(b)(3)(A), 112, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 208</ref>, 209; <ref>Pub. L. 110–326, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-09-26">Sept. 26, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–23, title VIII</ref>, §§ 805, 811(d), <date date="2015-06-02">June 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 309</ref>, 311.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2332c.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. I, title II, § 201(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–871</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332d.</num>
<heading> Financial transactions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in regulations issued by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, whoever, being a United States person, knowing or having reasonable cause to know that a country is designated under section 6(j) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002189">1</ref> of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. App. 2405) as a country supporting international terrorism, engages in a financial transaction with the government of that country, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “financial transaction” has the same meaning as in section 1956(c)(4); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “United States person” means any—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> United States citizen or national;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permanent resident alien;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> juridical person organized under the laws of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any person in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title III, § 321(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1254</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332e.</num>
<heading> Requests for military assistance to enforce prohibition in certain emergencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may request the Secretary of Defense to provide assistance under <ref>section 382 of title 10</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002190">1</ref> in support of Department of Justice activities relating to the enforcement of <ref>section 2332a of this title</ref> during an emergency situation involving a weapon of mass destruction. The authority to make such a request may be exercised by another official of the Department of Justice in accordance with <ref>section 382(f)(2) of title 10</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002190">1</ref></p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, title XIV, § 1416(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2723</ref>, § 2332d; renumbered § 2332e, <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 605(q)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3510</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332f.</num>
<heading> Bombings of places of public use, government facilities, public transportation systems and infrastructure facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Offenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever unlawfully delivers, places, discharges, or detonates an explosive or other lethal device in, into, or against a place of public use, a state or government facility, a public transportation system, or an infrastructure facility—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with the intent to cause death or serious bodily injury, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with the intent to cause extensive destruction of such a place, facility, or system, where such destruction results in or is likely to result in major economic loss,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attempts and conspiracies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever attempts or conspires to commit an offense under paragraph (1) shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is jurisdiction over the offenses in subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the offense takes place in the United States and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the offense is committed against another state or a government facility of such state, including its embassy or other diplomatic or consular premises of that state;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offense is committed in an attempt to compel another state or the United States to do or abstain from doing any act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> at the time the offense is committed, it is committed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on board a vessel flying the flag of another state;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on board an aircraft which is registered under the laws of another state; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> on board an aircraft which is operated by the government of another state;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a perpetrator is found outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a perpetrator is a national of another state or a stateless person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a victim is a national of another state or a stateless person;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the offense takes place outside the United States and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a perpetrator is a national of the United States or is a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a victim is a national of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a perpetrator is found in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the offense is committed in an attempt to compel the United States to do or abstain from doing any act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the offense is committed against a state or government facility of the United States, including an embassy or other diplomatic or consular premises of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the offense is committed on board a vessel flying the flag of the United States or an aircraft which is registered under the laws of the United States at the time the offense is committed; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the offense is committed on board an aircraft which is operated by the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates this section shall be punished as provided under <ref>section 2332a(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemptions to Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the activities of armed forces during an armed conflict, as those terms are understood under the law of war, which are governed by that law,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> activities undertaken by military forces of a state in the exercise of their official duties; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> offenses committed within the United States, where the alleged offender and the victims are United States citizens and the alleged offender is found in the United States, or where jurisdiction is predicated solely on the nationality of the victims or the alleged offender and the offense has no substantial effect on interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “serious bodily injury” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1365(g)(3) of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002191">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “national of the United States” has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “state or government facility” includes any permanent or temporary facility or conveyance that is used or occupied by representatives of a state, members of Government, the legislature or the judiciary or by officials or employees of a state or any other public authority or entity or by employees or officials of an intergovernmental organization in connection with their official duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “intergovernmental organization” includes international organization (as defined in <ref>section 1116(b)(5) of this title</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “infrastructure facility” means any publicly or privately owned facility providing or distributing services for the benefit of the public, such as water, sewage, energy, fuel, or communications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “place of public use” means those parts of any building, land, street, waterway, or other location that are accessible or open to members of the public, whether continuously, periodically, or occasionally, and encompasses any commercial, business, cultural, historical, educational, religious, governmental, entertainment, recreational, or similar place that is so accessible or open to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “public transportation system” means all facilities, conveyances, and instrumentalities, whether publicly or privately owned, that are used in or for publicly available services for the transportation of persons or cargo;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “explosive” has the meaning given in <ref>section 844(j) of this title</ref> insofar that it is designed, or has the capability, to cause death, serious bodily injury, or substantial material damage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “other lethal device” means any weapon or device that is designed or has the capability to cause death, serious bodily injury, or substantial damage to property through the release, dissemination, or impact of toxic chemicals, biological agents, or toxins (as those terms are defined in <ref>section 178 of this title</ref>) or radiation or radioactive material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “military forces of a state” means the armed forces of a state which are organized, trained, and equipped under its internal law for the primary purpose of national defense or security, and persons acting in support of those armed forces who are under their formal command, control, and responsibility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “armed conflict” does not include internal disturbances and tensions, such as riots, isolated and sporadic acts of violence, and other acts of a similar nature; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “state” has the same meaning as that term has under international law, and includes all political subdivisions thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–197, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-25">June 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332g.</num>
<heading> Missile systems designed to destroy aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Unlawful Conduct.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in paragraph (3), it shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly produce, construct, otherwise acquire, transfer directly or indirectly, receive, possess, import, export, or use, or possess and threaten to use—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an explosive or incendiary rocket or missile that is guided by any system designed to enable the rocket or missile to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> seek or proceed toward energy radiated or reflected from an aircraft or toward an image locating an aircraft; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> otherwise direct or guide the rocket or missile to an aircraft;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any device designed or intended to launch or guide a rocket or missile described in subparagraph (A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any part or combination of parts designed or redesigned for use in assembling or fabricating a rocket, missile, or device described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonweapon</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1)(A) does not apply to any device that is neither designed nor redesigned for use as a weapon.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Excluded conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection does not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct by or under the authority of the United States or any department or agency thereof or of a State or any department or agency thereof; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct pursuant to the terms of a contract with the United States or any department or agency thereof or with a State or any department or agency thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Conduct prohibited by subsection (a) is within the jurisdiction of the United States if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the offense occurs in or affects interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the offense occurs outside of the United States and is committed by a national of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the offense is committed against a national of the United States while the national is outside the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the offense is committed against any property that is owned, leased, or used by the United States or by any department or agency of the United States, whether the property is within or outside the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an offender aids or abets any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this subsection in committing an offense under this section or conspires with any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this subsection to commit an offense under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who violates, or attempts or conspires to violate, subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 and shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment not less than 25 years or to imprisonment for life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who, in the course of a violation of subsection (a), uses, attempts or conspires to use, or possesses and threatens to use, any item or items described in subsection (a), shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 and imprisoned for not less than 30 years or imprisoned for life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the death of another results from a person’s violation of subsection (a), the person shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 and punished by imprisonment for life.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As used in this section, the term “aircraft” has the definition set forth in <ref>section 40102(a)(6) of title 49</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6903</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332h.</num>
<heading> Radiological dispersal devices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Unlawful Conduct.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in paragraph (2), it shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly produce, construct, otherwise acquire, transfer directly or indirectly, receive, possess, import, export, or use, or possess and threaten to use—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any weapon that is designed or intended to release radiation or radioactivity at a level dangerous to human life; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any device or other object that is capable of and designed or intended to endanger human life through the release of radiation or radioactivity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This subsection does not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct by or under the authority of the United States or any department or agency thereof; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct pursuant to the terms of a contract with the United States or any department or agency thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Conduct prohibited by subsection (a) is within the jurisdiction of the United States if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the offense occurs in or affects interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the offense occurs outside of the United States and is committed by a national of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the offense is committed against a national of the United States while the national is outside the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the offense is committed against any property that is owned, leased, or used by the United States or by any department or agency of the United States, whether the property is within or outside the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an offender aids or abets any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this subsection in committing an offense under this section or conspires with any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this subsection to commit an offense under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who violates, or attempts or conspires to violate, subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 and shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment not less than 25 years or to imprisonment for life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who, in the course of a violation of subsection (a), uses, attempts or conspires to use, or possesses and threatens to use, any item or items described in subsection (a), shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 and imprisoned for not less than 30 years or imprisoned for life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the death of another results from a person’s violation of subsection (a), the person shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 and punished by imprisonment for life.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6905</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2332i.</num>
<heading> Acts of nuclear terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Offenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever knowingly and unlawfully—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> possesses radioactive material or makes or possesses a device—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with the intent to cause death or serious bodily injury; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with the intent to cause substantial damage to property or the environment; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> uses in any way radioactive material or a device, or uses or damages or interferes with the operation of a nuclear facility in a manner that causes the release of or increases the risk of the release of radioactive material, or causes radioactive contamination or exposure to radiation—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with the intent to cause death or serious bodily injury or with the knowledge that such act is likely to cause death or serious bodily injury;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with the intent to cause substantial damage to property or the environment or with the knowledge that such act is likely to cause substantial damage to property or the environment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> with the intent to compel a person, an international organization or a country to do or refrain from doing an act,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Threats</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever, under circumstances in which the threat may reasonably be believed, threatens to commit an offense under paragraph (1) shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c). Whoever demands possession of or access to radioactive material, a device or a nuclear facility by threat or by use of force shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attempts and conspiracies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever attempts to commit an offense under paragraph (1) or conspires to commit an offense under paragraph (1) or (2) shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Conduct prohibited by subsection (a) is within the jurisdiction of the United States if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the prohibited conduct takes place in the United States or the special aircraft jurisdiction of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the prohibited conduct takes place outside of the United States and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is committed by a national of the United States, a United States corporation or legal entity or a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is committed on board a vessel of the United States or a vessel subject to the jurisdiction of the United States (as defined in <ref>section 70502 of title 46</ref>) or on board an aircraft that is registered under United States law, at the time the offense is committed; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is committed in an attempt to compel the United States to do or abstain from doing any act, or constitutes a threat directed at the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the prohibited conduct takes place outside of the United States and a victim or an intended victim is a national of the United States or a United States corporation or legal entity, or the offense is committed against any state or government facility of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a perpetrator of the prohibited conduct is found in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates this section shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 and shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the activities of armed forces during an armed conflict, as those terms are understood under the law of war, which are governed by that law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> activities undertaken by military forces of a state in the exercise of their official duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “armed conflict” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2332f(e)(11) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “device” means:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any nuclear explosive device; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any radioactive material dispersal or radiation-emitting device that may, owing to its radiological properties, cause death, serious bodily injury or substantial damage to property or the environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “international organization” has the meaning given that term in section 831(f)(3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002192">1</ref> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “military forces of a state” means the armed forces of a country that are organized, trained and equipped under its internal law for the primary purpose of national defense or security and persons acting in support of those armed forces who are under their formal command, control and responsibility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “national of the United States” has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> “nuclear facility” means:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any nuclear reactor, including reactors on vessels, vehicles, aircraft or space objects for use as an energy source in order to propel such vessels, vehicles, aircraft or space objects or for any other purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any plant or conveyance being used for the production, storage, processing or transport of radioactive material; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a facility (including associated buildings and equipment) in which nuclear material is produced, processed, used, handled, stored or disposed of, if damage to or interference with such facility could lead to the release of significant amounts of radiation or radioactive material;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “nuclear material” has the meaning given that term in section 831(f)(1) <sup>1</sup> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “radioactive material” means nuclear material and other radioactive substances that contain nuclides that undergo spontaneous disintegration (a process accompanied by emission of one or more types of ionizing radiation, such as alpha-, beta-, neutron particles and gamma rays) and that may, owing to their radiological or fissile properties, cause death, serious bodily injury or substantial damage to property or to the environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “serious bodily injury” has the meaning given that term in section 831(f)(4) <sup>1</sup> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “state” has the same meaning as that term has under international law, and includes all political subdivisions thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “state or government facility” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2332f(e)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “United States corporation or legal entity” means any corporation or other entity organized under the laws of the United States or any State, Commonwealth, territory, possession or district of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> “vessel” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1502(19) of title 33</ref>; <sup>1</sup> and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> “vessel of the United States” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 70502 of title 46</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–23, title VIII, § 811(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-06-02">June 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 309</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2333.</num>
<heading> Civil remedies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action and Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any national of the United States injured in his or her person, property, or business by reason of an act of international terrorism, or his or her estate, survivors, or heirs, may sue therefor in any appropriate district court of the United States and shall recover threefold the damages he or she sustains and the cost of the suit, including attorney’s fees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Estoppel Under United States Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A final judgment or decree rendered in favor of the United States in any criminal proceeding under section 1116, 1201, 1203, or 2332 of this title or section 46314, 46502, 46505, or 46506 of title 49 shall estop the defendant from denying the essential allegations of the criminal offense in any subsequent civil proceeding under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Estoppel Under Foreign Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A final judgment or decree rendered in favor of any foreign state in any criminal proceeding shall, to the extent that such judgment or decree may be accorded full faith and credit under the law of the United States, estop the defendant from denying the essential allegations of the criminal offense in any subsequent civil proceeding under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Liability.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “person” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1 of title 1</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an action under subsection (a) for an injury arising from an act of international terrorism committed, planned, or authorized by an organization that had been designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1189</ref>), as of the date on which such act of international terrorism was committed, planned, or authorized, liability may be asserted as to any person who aids and abets, by knowingly providing substantial assistance, or who conspires with the person who committed such an act of international terrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Blocked Assets to Satisfy Judgments of U.S. Nationals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of section 201 of the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 (<ref>28 U.S.C. 1610</ref> note), in any action in which a national of the United States has obtained a judgment against a terrorist party pursuant to this section, the term “blocked asset” shall include any asset of that terrorist party (including the blocked assets of any agency or instrumentality of that party) seized or frozen by the United States under section 805(b) of the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 1904(b)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4522</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–429, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–222, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-09-28">Sept. 28, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 854</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–253, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-03">Oct. 3, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2334.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction and venue</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Venue</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any civil action under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref> against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district where any plaintiff resides or where any defendant resides or is served, or has an agent. Process in such a civil action may be served in any district where the defendant resides, is found, or has an agent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Maritime or Territorial Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the actions giving rise to the claim occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, as defined in <ref>section 7 of this title</ref>, then any civil action under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref> against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district in which any plaintiff resides or the defendant resides, is served, or has an agent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service on Witnesses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A witness in a civil action brought under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref> may be served in any other district where the defendant resides, is found, or has an agent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Convenience of the Forum</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The district court shall not dismiss any action brought under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref> on the grounds of the inconvenience or inappropriateness of the forum chosen, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the action may be maintained in a foreign court that has jurisdiction over the subject matter and over all the defendants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that foreign court is significantly more convenient and appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that foreign court offers a remedy which is substantially the same as the one available in the courts of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Consent of Certain Parties to Personal Jurisdiction.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in paragraph (2), for purposes of any civil action under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref>, a defendant shall be deemed to have consented to personal jurisdiction in such civil action if, regardless of the date of the occurrence of the act of international terrorism upon which such civil action was filed, the defendant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> after the date that is 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Promoting Security and Justice for Victims of Terrorism Act of 2019, makes any payment, directly or indirectly—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to any payee designated by any individual who, after being fairly tried or pleading guilty, has been imprisoned for committing any act of terrorism that injured or killed a national of the United States, if such payment is made by reason of such imprisonment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to any family member of any individual, following such individual’s death while committing an act of terrorism that injured or killed a national of the United States, if such payment is made by reason of the death of such individual; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> after 15 days after the date of enactment of the Promoting Security and Justice for Victims of Terrorism Act of 2019—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> continues to maintain any office, headquarters, premises, or other facilities or establishments in the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> establishes or procures any office, headquarters, premises, or other facilities or establishments in the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> conducts any activity while physically present in the United States on behalf of the Palestine Liberation Organization or the Palestinian Authority.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any defendant who ceases to engage in the conduct described in paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B) for 5 consecutive calendar years. Except with respect to payments described in paragraph (1)(A), no court may consider the receipt of any assistance by a nongovernmental organization, whether direct or indirect, as a basis for consent to jurisdiction by a defendant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for certain activities and locations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining whether a defendant shall be deemed to have consented to personal jurisdiction under paragraph (1)(B), no court may consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any office, headquarters, premises, or other facility or establishment used exclusively for the purpose of conducting official business of the United Nations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any activity undertaken exclusively for the purpose of conducting official business of the United Nations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any activity involving officials of the United States that the Secretary of State determines is in the national interest of the United States if the Secretary reports to the appropriate congressional committees annually on the use of the authority under this subparagraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any activity undertaken exclusively for the purpose of meetings with officials of the United States or other foreign governments, or participation in training and related activities funded or arranged by the United States Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> any activity related to legal representation—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for matters related to activities described in this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for the purpose of adjudicating or resolving claims filed in courts of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to comply with this subsection; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any personal or official activities conducted ancillary to activities listed under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other law (including any treaty), any office, headquarters, premises, or other facility or establishment within the territory of the United States that is not specifically exempted by paragraph (3)(A) shall be considered to be in the United States for purposes of paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defined term</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “defendant” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Palestinian Authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Palestine Liberation Organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any organization or other entity that is a successor to or affiliated with the Palestinian Authority or the Palestine Liberation Organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> any organization or other entity that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is identified in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> self identifies as, holds itself out to be, or carries out conduct in the name of, the “State of Palestine” or “Palestine” in connection with official business of the United Nations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4522</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–253, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-03">Oct. 3, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title IX, § 903(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2335.</num>
<heading> Limitation of actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (b), a suit for recovery of damages under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref> shall not be maintained unless commenced within 10 years after the date the cause of action accrued.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Calculation of Period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The time of the absence of the defendant from the United States or from any jurisdiction in which the same or a similar action arising from the same facts may be maintained by the plaintiff, or of any concealment of the defendant’s whereabouts, shall not be included in the 10-year period set forth in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4523</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XII, § 1251(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2336.</num>
<heading> Other limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acts of War</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No action shall be maintained under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref> for injury or loss by reason of an act of war.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Discovery</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a party to an action under section 2333 seeks to discover the investigative files of the Department of Justice, the Assistant Attorney General, Deputy Attorney General, or Attorney General may object on the ground that compliance will interfere with a criminal investigation or prosecution of the incident, or a national security operation related to the incident, which is the subject of the civil litigation. The court shall evaluate any such objections in camera and shall stay the discovery if the court finds that granting the discovery request will substantially interfere with a criminal investigation or prosecution of the incident or a national security operation related to the incident. The court shall consider the likelihood of criminal prosecution by the Government and other factors it deems to be appropriate. A stay of discovery under this subsection shall constitute a bar to the granting of a motion to dismiss under rules 12(b)(6) and 56 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. If the court grants a stay of discovery under this subsection, it may stay the action in the interests of justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stay of Action for Civil Remedies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may intervene in any civil action brought under section 2333 for the purpose of seeking a stay of the civil action. A stay shall be granted if the court finds that the continuation of the civil action will substantially interfere with a criminal prosecution which involves the same subject matter and in which an indictment has been returned, or interfere with national security operations related to the terrorist incident that is the subject of the civil action. A stay may be granted for up to 6 months. The Attorney General may petition the court for an extension of the stay for additional 6-month periods until the criminal prosecution is completed or dismissed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In a proceeding under this subsection, the Attorney General may request that any order issued by the court for release to the parties and the public omit any reference to the basis on which the stay was sought.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2337.</num>
<heading> Suits against Government officials</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No action shall be maintained under <ref>section 2333 of this title</ref> against—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States, an agency of the United States, or an officer or employee of the United States or any agency thereof acting within his or her official capacity or under color of legal authority; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a foreign state, an agency of a foreign state, or an officer or employee of a foreign state or an agency thereof acting within his or her official capacity or under color of legal authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2338.</num>
<heading> Exclusive Federal jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction over an action brought under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1003(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2339.</num>
<heading> Harboring or concealing terrorists</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever harbors or conceals any person who he knows, or has reasonable grounds to believe, has committed, or is about to commit, an offense under section 32 (relating to destruction of aircraft or aircraft facilities), section 175 (relating to biological weapons), section 229 (relating to chemical weapons), section 831 (relating to nuclear materials), paragraph (2) or (3) of section 844(f) (relating to arson and bombing of government property risking or causing injury or death), section 1366(a) (relating to the destruction of an energy facility), section 2280 (relating to violence against maritime navigation), section 2332a (relating to weapons of mass destruction), or section 2332b (relating to acts of terrorism transcending national boundaries) of this title, section 236(a) (relating to sabotage of nuclear facilities or fuel) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2284(a)</ref>), or section 46502 (relating to aircraft piracy) of title 49, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A violation of this section may be prosecuted in any Federal judicial district in which the underlying offense was committed, or in any other Federal judicial district as provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 376</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4005(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1813</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2339A.</num>
<heading> Providing material support to terrorists</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever provides material support or resources or conceals or disguises the nature, location, source, or ownership of material support or resources, knowing or intending that they are to be used in preparation for, or in carrying out, a violation of section 32, 37, 81, 175, 229, 351, 831, 842(m) or (n), 844(f) or (i), 930(c), 956, 1091, 1114, 1116, 1203, 1361, 1362, 1363, 1366, 1751, 1992, 2155, 2156, 2280, 2281, 2332, 2332a, 2332b, 2332f, 2340A, or 2442 of this title, section 236 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2284</ref>), section 46502 or 60123(b) of title 49, or any offense listed in section 2332b(g)(5)(B) (except for sections 2339A and 2339B) or in preparation for, or in carrying out, the concealment of an escape from the commission of any such violation, or attempts or conspires to do such an act, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 15 years, or both, and, if the death of any person results, shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life. A violation of this section may be prosecuted in any Federal judicial district in which the underlying offense was committed, or in any other Federal judicial district as provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “material support or resources” means any property, tangible or intangible, or service, including currency or monetary instruments or financial securities, financial services, lodging, training, expert advice or assistance, safehouses, false documentation or identification, communications equipment, facilities, weapons, lethal substances, explosives, personnel (1 or more individuals who may be or include oneself), and transportation, except medicine or religious materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “training” means instruction or teaching designed to impart a specific skill, as opposed to general knowledge; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “expert advice or assistance” means advice or assistance derived from scientific, technical or other specialized knowledge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XII, § 120005(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2022</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title III, § 323</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI</ref>, §§ 601(b)(2), (s)(2), (3), 604(b)(5), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>, 3502, 3506; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII</ref>, §§ 805(a), 810(c), 811(f), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 377</ref>, 380, 381; <ref>Pub. L. 107–197, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-25">June 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(a)(7)</ref>, (c)(1), (e)(11), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1807</ref>, 1808, 1811; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6603(a)(2)</ref>, (b), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3762</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 110(b)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–122, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-22">Dec. 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2339B.</num>
<heading> Providing material support or resources to designated foreign terrorist organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unlawful conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever knowingly provides material support or resources to a foreign terrorist organization, or attempts or conspires to do so, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both, and, if the death of any person results, shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life. To violate this paragraph, a person must have knowledge that the organization is a designated terrorist organization (as defined in subsection (g)(6)), that the organization has engaged or engages in terrorist activity (as defined in section 212(a)(3)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act), or that the organization has engaged or engages in terrorism (as defined in section 140(d)(2) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financial institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as authorized by the Secretary, any financial institution that becomes aware that it has possession of, or control over, any funds in which a foreign terrorist organization, or its agent, has an interest, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> retain possession of, or maintain control over, such funds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> report to the Secretary the existence of such funds in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any financial institution that knowingly fails to comply with subsection (a)(2) shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount that is the greater of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $50,000 per violation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> twice the amount of which the financial institution was required under subsection (a)(2) to retain possession or control.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Injunction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever it appears to the Secretary or the Attorney General that any person is engaged in, or is about to engage in, any act that constitutes, or would constitute, a violation of this section, the Attorney General may initiate civil action in a district court of the United States to enjoin such violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extraterritorial Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is jurisdiction over an offense under subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an offender is a national of the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>)) or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an offender is a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> after the conduct required for the offense occurs an offender is brought into or found in the United States, even if the conduct required for the offense occurs outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the offense occurs in whole or in part within the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the offense occurs in or affects interstate or foreign commerce; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an offender aids or abets any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this paragraph in committing an offense under subsection (a) or conspires with any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this paragraph to commit an offense under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extraterritorial jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is extraterritorial Federal jurisdiction over an offense under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Investigations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General shall conduct any investigation of a possible violation of this section, or of any license, order, or regulation issued pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination with the department of the treasury</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Attorney General shall work in coordination with the Secretary in investigations relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the compliance or noncompliance by a financial institution with the requirements of subsection (a)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> civil penalty proceedings authorized under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Referral</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any evidence of a criminal violation of this section arising in the course of an investigation by the Secretary or any other Federal agency shall be referred immediately to the Attorney General for further investigation. The Attorney General shall timely notify the Secretary of any action taken on referrals from the Secretary, and may refer investigations to the Secretary for remedial licensing or civil penalty action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Classified Information in Civil Proceedings Brought by the United States.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Discovery of classified information by defendants.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request by united states</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In any civil proceeding under this section, upon request made ex parte and in writing by the United States, a court, upon a sufficient showing, may authorize the United States to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> redact specified items of classified information from documents to be introduced into evidence or made available to the defendant through discovery under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> substitute a summary of the information for such classified documents; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> substitute a statement admitting relevant facts that the classified information would tend to prove.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order granting request</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the court enters an order granting a request under this paragraph, the entire text of the documents to which the request relates shall be sealed and preserved in the records of the court to be made available to the appellate court in the event of an appeal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Denial of request</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the court enters an order denying a request of the United States under this paragraph, the United States may take an immediate, interlocutory appeal in accordance with paragraph (5). For purposes of such an appeal, the entire text of the documents to which the request relates, together with any transcripts of arguments made ex parte to the court in connection therewith, shall be maintained under seal and delivered to the appellate court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Introduction of classified information; precautions by court.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exhibits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To prevent unnecessary or inadvertent disclosure of classified information in a civil proceeding brought by the United States under this section, the United States may petition the court ex parte to admit, in lieu of classified writings, recordings, or photographs, one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Copies of items from which classified information has been redacted.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Stipulations admitting relevant facts that specific classified information would tend to prove.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A declassified summary of the specific classified information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination by court</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court shall grant a request under this paragraph if the court finds that the redacted item, stipulation, or summary is sufficient to allow the defendant to prepare a defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Taking of trial testimony.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>During the examination of a witness in any civil proceeding brought by the United States under this subsection, the United States may object to any question or line of inquiry that may require the witness to disclose classified information not previously found to be admissible.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action by court</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining whether a response is admissible, the court shall take precautions to guard against the compromise of any classified information, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> permitting the United States to provide the court, ex parte, with a proffer of the witness’s response to the question or line of inquiry; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> requiring the defendant to provide the court with a proffer of the nature of the information that the defendant seeks to elicit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation of defendant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any civil proceeding under this section, it shall be the defendant’s obligation to establish the relevance and materiality of any classified information sought to be introduced.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the court enters an order denying a request of the United States under this subsection, the United States may take an immediate interlocutory appeal in accordance with paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Interlocutory appeal.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subject of appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An interlocutory appeal by the United States shall lie to a court of appeals from a decision or order of a district court—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> authorizing the disclosure of classified information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> imposing sanctions for nondisclosure of classified information; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> refusing a protective order sought by the United States to prevent the disclosure of classified information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Expedited consideration.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An appeal taken pursuant to this paragraph, either before or during trial, shall be expedited by the court of appeals.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeals prior to trial</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an appeal is of an order made prior to trial, an appeal shall be taken not later than 14 days after the decision or order appealed from, and the trial shall not commence until the appeal is resolved.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeals during trial</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If an appeal is taken during trial, the trial court shall adjourn the trial until the appeal is resolved, and the court of appeals—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall hear argument on such appeal not later than 4 days after the adjournment of the trial, excluding intermediate weekends and holidays;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> may dispense with written briefs other than the supporting materials previously submitted to the trial court;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> shall render its decision not later than 4 days after argument on appeal, excluding intermediate weekends and holidays; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> may dispense with the issuance of a written opinion in rendering its decision.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of ruling</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An interlocutory appeal and decision shall not affect the right of the defendant, in a subsequent appeal from a final judgment, to claim as error reversal by the trial court on remand of a ruling appealed from during trial.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the United States from seeking protective orders or asserting privileges ordinarily available to the United States to protect against the disclosure of classified information, including the invocation of the military and State secrets privilege.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “classified information” has the meaning given that term in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “financial institution” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 5312(a)(2) of title 31</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “funds” includes coin or currency of the United States or any other country, traveler’s checks, personal checks, bank checks, money orders, stocks, bonds, debentures, drafts, letters of credit, any other negotiable instrument, and any electronic representation of any of the foregoing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “material support or resources” has the same meaning given that term in section 2339A (including the definitions of “training” and “expert advice or assistance” in that section);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “terrorist organization” means an organization designated as a terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may be prosecuted under this section in connection with the term “personnel” unless that person has knowingly provided, attempted to provide, or conspired to provide a foreign terrorist organization with 1 or more individuals (who may be or include himself) to work under that terrorist organization’s direction or control or to organize, manage, supervise, or otherwise direct the operation of that organization. Individuals who act entirely independently of the foreign terrorist organization to advance its goals or objectives shall not be considered to be working under the foreign terrorist organization’s direction and control.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed or applied so as to abridge the exercise of rights guaranteed under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may be prosecuted under this section in connection with the term “personnel”, “training”, or “expert advice or assistance” if the provision of that material support or resources to a foreign terrorist organization was approved by the Secretary of State with the concurrence of the Attorney General. The Secretary of State may not approve the provision of any material support that may be used to carry out terrorist activity (as defined in section 212(a)(3)(B)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1250</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 810(d)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6603(c)</ref>–(f), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3762</ref>, 3763; <ref>Pub. L. 111–16, § 3(6)</ref>–(8), <date date="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1608</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–23, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="2015-06-02">June 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2339C.</num>
<heading> Prohibitions against the financing of terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Offenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever, in a circumstance described in subsection (b), by any means, directly or indirectly, unlawfully and willfully provides or collects funds with the intention that such funds be used, or with the knowledge that such funds are to be used, in full or in part, in order to carry out—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an act which constitutes an offense within the scope of a treaty specified in subsection (e)(7), as implemented by the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other act intended to cause death or serious bodily injury to a civilian, or to any other person not taking an active part in the hostilities in a situation of armed conflict, when the purpose of such act, by its nature or context, is to intimidate a population, or to compel a government or an international organization to do or to abstain from doing any act,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (d)(1).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attempts and conspiracies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever attempts or conspires to commit an offense under paragraph (1) shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (d)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to predicate act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For an act to constitute an offense set forth in this subsection, it shall not be necessary that the funds were actually used to carry out a predicate act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is jurisdiction over the offenses in subsection (a) in the following circumstances—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the offense takes place in the United States and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a perpetrator was a national of another state or a stateless person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on board a vessel flying the flag of another state or an aircraft which is registered under the laws of another state at the time the offense is committed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on board an aircraft which is operated by the government of another state;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a perpetrator is found outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> was directed toward or resulted in the carrying out of a predicate act against—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a national of another state; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> another state or a government facility of such state, including its embassy or other diplomatic or consular premises of that state;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> was directed toward or resulted in the carrying out of a predicate act committed in an attempt to compel another state or international organization to do or abstain from doing any act; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> was directed toward or resulted in the carrying out of a predicate act—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> outside the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> within the United States, and either the offense or the predicate act was conducted in, or the results thereof affected, interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the offense takes place outside the United States and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a perpetrator is a national of the United States or is a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a perpetrator is found in the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> was directed toward or resulted in the carrying out of a predicate act against—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any property that is owned, leased, or used by the United States or by any department or agency of the United States, including an embassy or other diplomatic or consular premises of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any person or property within the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any national of the United States or the property of such national; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any property of any legal entity organized under the laws of the United States, including any of its States, districts, commonwealths, territories, or possessions;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the offense is committed on board a vessel flying the flag of the United States or an aircraft which is registered under the laws of the United States at the time the offense is committed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the offense is committed on board an aircraft which is operated by the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the offense was directed toward or resulted in the carrying out of a predicate act committed in an attempt to compel the United States to do or abstain from doing any act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concealment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is in the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is outside the United States and is a national of the United States or a legal entity organized under the laws of the United States (including any of its States, districts, commonwealths, territories, or possessions); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> knowingly conceals or disguises the nature, location, source, ownership, or control of any material support or resources, or any funds or proceeds of such funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> knowing or intending that the support or resources are to be provided, or knowing that the support or resources were provided, in violation of <ref>section 2339B of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> knowing or intending that any such funds are to be provided or collected, or knowing that the funds were provided or collected, in violation of subsection (a),</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (d)(2).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsection</inline> (a).—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates subsection (a) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsection</inline> (c).—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates subsection (c) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “funds” means assets of every kind, whether tangible or intangible, movable or immovable, however acquired, and legal documents or instruments in any form, including electronic or digital, evidencing title to, or interest in, such assets, including coin, currency, bank credits, travelers checks, bank checks, money orders, shares, securities, bonds, drafts, and letters of credit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “government facility” means any permanent or temporary facility or conveyance that is used or occupied by representatives of a state, members of a government, the legislature, or the judiciary, or by officials or employees of a state or any other public authority or entity or by employees or officials of an intergovernmental organization in connection with their official duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “proceeds” means any funds derived from or obtained, directly or indirectly, through the commission of an offense set forth in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “provides” includes giving, donating, and transmitting;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “collects” includes raising and receiving;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “predicate act” means any act referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> the term “treaty” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Seizure of Aircraft, done at The Hague on <date date="1970-12-16">December 16, 1970</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Civil Aviation, done at Montreal on <date date="1971-09-23">September 23, 1971</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of Crimes against Internationally Protected Persons, including Diplomatic Agents, adopted by the General Assembly of the United Nations on <date date="1973-12-14">December 14, 1973</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the International Convention against the Taking of Hostages, adopted by the General Assembly of the United Nations on <date date="1979-12-17">December 17, 1979</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Convention on the Physical Protection of Nuclear Material, adopted at Vienna on <date date="1980-03-03">March 3, 1980</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Protocol for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts of Violence at Airports Serving International Civil Aviation, supplementary to the Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Civil Aviation, done at Montreal on <date date="1988-02-24">February 24, 1988</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Maritime Navigation, done at Rome on <date date="1988-03-10">March 10, 1988</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Protocol for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Fixed Platforms located on the Continental Shelf, done at Rome on <date date="1988-03-10">March 10, 1988</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the International Convention for the Suppression of Terrorist Bombings, adopted by the General Assembly of the United Nations on <date date="1997-12-15">December 15, 1997</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “intergovernmental organization” includes international organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the term “international organization” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1116(b)(5) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the term “armed conflict” does not include internal disturbances and tensions, such as riots, isolated and sporadic acts of violence, and other acts of a similar nature;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the term “serious bodily injury” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 1365(g)(3) of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002193">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the term “national of the United States” has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the term “material support or resources” has the same meaning given that term in <ref>section 2339B(g)(4) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the term “state” has the same meaning as that term has under international law, and includes all political subdivisions thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to any other criminal, civil, or administrative liability or penalty, any legal entity located within the United States or organized under the laws of the United States, including any of the laws of its States, districts, commonwealths, territories, or possessions, shall be liable to the United States for the sum of at least $10,000, if a person responsible for the management or control of that legal entity has, in that capacity, committed an offense set forth in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–197, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-25">June 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 724</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4006</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6604</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2339D.</num>
<heading> Receiving military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever knowingly receives military-type training from or on behalf of any organization designated at the time of the training by the Secretary of State under section 219(a)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act as a foreign terrorist organization shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for ten years, or both. To violate this subsection, a person must have knowledge that the organization is a designated terrorist organization (as defined in subsection (c)(4)), that the organization has engaged or engages in terrorist activity (as defined in section 212 of the Immigration and Nationality Act), or that the organization has engaged or engages in terrorism (as defined in section 140(d)(2) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extraterritorial Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is extraterritorial Federal jurisdiction over an offense under this section. There is jurisdiction over an offense under subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an offender is a national of the United States (as defined in <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002194">1</ref> 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act) or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an offender is a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> after the conduct required for the offense occurs an offender is brought into or found in the United States, even if the conduct required for the offense occurs outside the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the offense occurs in whole or in part within the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the offense occurs in or affects interstate or foreign commerce; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> an offender aids or abets any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this paragraph in committing an offense under subsection (a) or conspires with any person over whom jurisdiction exists under this paragraph to commit an offense under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “military-type training” includes training in means or methods that can cause death or serious bodily injury, destroy or damage property, or disrupt services to critical infrastructure, or training on the use, storage, production, or assembly of any explosive, firearm or other weapon, including any weapon of mass destruction (as defined in section 2232a(c)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002195">2</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “serious bodily injury” has the meaning given that term in section 1365(h)(3);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “critical infrastructure” means systems and assets vital to national defense, national security, economic security, public health or safety including both regional and national infrastructure. Critical infrastructure may be publicly or privately owned; examples of critical infrastructure include gas and oil production, storage, or delivery systems, water supply systems, telecommunications networks, electrical power generation or delivery systems, financing and banking systems, emergency services (including medical, police, fire, and rescue services), and transportation systems and services (including highways, mass transit, airlines, and airports); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “foreign terrorist organization” means an organization designated as a terrorist organization under section 219(a)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6602</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>