<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 87—</num>
<heading>PRISONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1791.</num>
<heading> Providing or possessing contraband in prison</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in violation of a statute or a rule or order issued under a statute, provides to an inmate of a prison a prohibited object, or attempts to do so; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> being an inmate of a prison, makes, possesses, or obtains, or attempts to make or obtain, a prohibited object;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Punishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The punishment for an offense under this section is a fine under this title or—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> imprisonment for not more than 20 years, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(C) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(A) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(B) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> imprisonment for not more than one year, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(D), (d)(1)(E), or (d)(1)(F) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> imprisonment for not more than 6 months, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(G) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consecutive Punishment Required in Certain Cases</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any punishment imposed under subsection (b) for a violation of this section involving a controlled substance shall be consecutive to any other sentence imposed by any court for an offense involving such a controlled substance. Any punishment imposed under subsection (b) for a violation of this section by an inmate of a prison shall be consecutive to the sentence being served by such inmate at the time the inmate commits such violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “prohibited object” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a firearm or destructive device or a controlled substance in schedule I or II, other than marijuana or a controlled substance referred to in subparagraph (C) of this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> marijuana or a controlled substance in schedule III, other than a controlled substance referred to in subparagraph (C) of this subsection, ammunition, a weapon (other than a firearm or destructive device), or an object that is designed or intended to be used as a weapon or to facilitate escape from a prison;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a narcotic drug, methamphetamine, its salts, isomers, and salts of its isomers, lysergic acid diethylamide, or phencyclidine;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a controlled substance (other than a controlled substance referred to in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of this subsection) or an alcoholic beverage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any United States or foreign currency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a phone or other device used by a user of commercial mobile service (as defined in section 332(d) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 332(d)</ref>)) in connection with such service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other object that threatens the order, discipline, or security of a prison, or the life, health, or safety of an individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “ammunition”, “firearm”, and “destructive device” have, respectively, the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 921 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the terms “controlled substance” and “narcotic drug” have, respectively, the meanings given those terms in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 802</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “prison” means a Federal correctional, detention, or penal facility or any prison, institution, or facility in which persons are held in custody by direction of or pursuant to a contract or agreement with the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1109(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 52(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3606</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6468(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IX, § 90101</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330003(a), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>,<ref>108 Stat. 1986</ref>, 2140; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(m)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1178</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–225, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-08-10">Aug. 10, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1792.</num>
<heading> Mutiny and riot prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever instigates, connives, willfully attempts to cause, assists, or conspires to cause any mutiny or riot, at any Federal penal, detention, or correctional facility, shall be imprisoned not more than ten years or fined under this title, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1109(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 53(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(O)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1793.</num>
<heading> Trespass on Bureau of Prisons reservations and land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without lawful authority or permission, goes upon a reservation, land, or a facility of the Bureau of Prisons shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 64(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3614</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>