<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 93—</num>
<heading>PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1901.</num>
<heading> Collecting or disbursing officer trading in public property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer of the United States concerned in the collection or the disbursement of the revenues thereof, carries on any trade or business in the funds or debts of the United States, or of any State, or in any public property of either, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and shall be removed from office, and be incapable of holding any office under the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 790</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(J)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1902.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of crop information and speculation thereon</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, employee or person acting for or on behalf of the United States or any department or agency thereof, and having by virtue of his office, employment or position, become possessed of information which might influence or affect the market value of any product of the soil grown within the United States, which information is by law or by the rules of such department or agency required to be withheld from publication until a fixed time, willfully imparts, directly or indirectly, such information, or any part thereof, to any person not entitled under the law or the rules of the department or agency to receive the same; or, before such information is made public through regular official channels, directly or indirectly speculates in any such product by buying or selling the same in any quantity, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">No person shall be deemed guilty of a violation of any such rules, unless prior to such alleged violation he shall have had actual knowledge thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 790</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1903.</num>
<heading> Speculation in stocks or commodities affecting crop insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, while acting in any official capacity in the administration of any Act of Congress relating to crop insurance or to the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation speculates in any agricultural commodity or product thereof, to which such enactments apply, or in contracts relating thereto, or in the stock or membership interests of any association or corporation engaged in handling, processing, or disposing of any such commodity or product, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 790</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1904.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330004(11)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2141</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1905.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of confidential information generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer or employee of the United States or of any department or agency thereof, any person acting on behalf of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, or agent of the Department of Justice as defined in the Antitrust Civil Process Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1311–131</ref>4), or being an employee of a private sector organization who is or was assigned to an agency under chapter 37 of title 5, publishes, divulges, discloses, or makes known in any manner or to any extent not authorized by law any information coming to him in the course of his employment or official duties or by reason of any examination or investigation made by, or return, report or record made to or filed with, such department or agency or officer or employee thereof, which information concerns or relates to the trade secrets, processes, operations, style of work, or apparatus, or to the identity, confidential statistical data, amount or source of any income, profits, losses, or expenditures of any person, firm, partnership, corporation, or association; or permits any income return or copy thereof or any book containing any abstract or particulars thereof to be seen or examined by any person except as provided by law; shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and shall be removed from office or employment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–349, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-12">Sept. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1353</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3970</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title II, § 209(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I, § 1161(d)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2780</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1906.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of information from a bank examination report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an examiner, public or private, or a Government Accountability Office employee with access to bank examination report information under <ref>section 714 of title 31</ref>, discloses the names of borrowers or the collateral for loans of any member bank of the Federal Reserve System, any bank insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, any branch or agency of a foreign bank (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978), or any organization operating under section 25 or section 25(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002125">1</ref> of the Federal Reserve Act, examined by him or subject to Government Accountability Office audit under <ref>section 714 of title 31</ref> to other than the proper officers of such bank, branch, agency, or organization, without first having obtained the express permission in writing from the Comptroller of the Currency as to a national bank or a Federal branch or Federal agency (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (5) and (6) of section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978), the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System as to a State member bank, an uninsured State branch or State agency (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (11) and (12) of section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978), or an organization operating under section 25 or section 25(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002125">1</ref> of the Federal Reserve Act, or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation as to any other insured bank, including any insured branch (as defined in section 3(s) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act),,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002126">2</ref> or from the board of directors of such bank or organization, except when ordered to do so by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by direction of the Congress of the United States, or either House thereof, or any committee of Congress or either House duly authorized or as authorized by <ref>section 714 of title 31</ref> shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–320, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-07-21">July 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 393</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1064</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2597(k)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1907.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of information by farm credit examiner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a farm credit examiner or any examiner, public or private, discloses the names of borrowers of any Federal land bank association or Federal land bank, or any organization examined by him under the provisions of law relating to Federal intermediate credit banks, to other than the proper officers of such institution or organization, without first having obtained express permission in writing from the Land Bank Commissioner or from the board of directors of such institution or organization, except when ordered to do so by a court of competent jurisdiction or by direction of the Congress of the United States or either House thereof, or any committee of Congress or either House duly authorized, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and shall be disqualified from holding office as a farm credit examiner.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–168, title I, § 104(h)</ref>, <date date="1959-08-18">Aug. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–297, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1908.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330004(11)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2141</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1909.</num>
<heading> Examiner performing other services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a national-bank examiner, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation examiner, or farm credit examiner, performs any other service, for compensation, for any bank or banking or loan association, or for any officer, director, or employee thereof, or for any person connected therewith in any capacity, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330004(12), 330016(1)(K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2142</ref>, 2147.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1910.</num>
<heading> Nepotism in appointment of receiver or trustee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a judge of any court of the United States, appoints as receiver, or trustee, any person related to such judge by consanguinity, or affinity, within the fourth degree—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1911.</num>
<heading> Receiver mismanaging property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a receiver, trustee, or manager in possession of any property in any cause pending in any court of the United States, willfully fails to manage and operate such property according to the requirements of the valid laws of the State in which such property shall be situated, in the same manner that the owner or possessor thereof would be bound to do if in possession thereof, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(J)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1912.</num>
<heading> Unauthorized fees for inspection of vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, employee, or agent of the United States or any agency thereof, engaged in inspection of vessels, upon any pretense, receives any fee or reward for his services, except what is allowed to him by law, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both; and shall forfeit his office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1913.</num>
<heading> Lobbying with appropriated moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No part of the money appropriated by any enactment of Congress shall, in the absence of express authorization by Congress, be used directly or indirectly to pay for any personal service, advertisement, telegram, telephone, letter, printed or written matter, or other device, intended or designed to influence in any manner a Member of Congress, a jurisdiction, or an official of any government, to favor, adopt, or oppose, by vote or otherwise, any legislation, law, ratification, policy, or appropriation, whether before or after the introduction of any bill, measure, or resolution proposing such legislation, law, ratification, policy, or appropriation; but this shall not prevent officers or employees of the United States or of its departments or agencies from communicating to any such Member or official, at his request, or to Congress or such official, through the proper official channels, requests for any legislation, law, ratification, policy, or appropriations which they deem necessary for the efficient conduct of the public business, or from making any communication whose prohibition by this section might, in the opinion of the Attorney General, violate the Constitution or interfere with the conduct of foreign policy, counter-intelligence, intelligence, or national security activities. Violations of this section shall constitute violations of <ref>section 1352(a) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1914.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–849, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1126</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1915.</num>
<heading> Compromise of customs liabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer of the United States, without lawful authority compromises or abates or attempts to compromise or abate any claim of the United States arising under the customs laws for any fine, penalty or forfeiture, or in any manner relieves or attempts to relieve any person, vessel, vehicle, merchandise or baggage therefrom, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1916.</num>
<heading> Unauthorized employment and disposition of lapsed appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> violates the provision of <ref>section 3103 of title 5</ref> that an individual may be employed in the civil service in an Executive department at the seat of Government only for services actually rendered in connection with and for the purposes of the appropriation from which he is paid; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> violates the provision of <ref>section 5501 of title 5</ref> that money accruing from lapsed salaries or from unused appropriations for salaries shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 608</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title III, § 3002(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1917.</num>
<heading> Interference with civil service examinations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever, being a member or employee of the United States Office of Personnel Management or an individual in the public service, willfully and corruptly—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> defeats, deceives, or obstructs an individual in respect of his right of examination according to the rules prescribed by the President under title 5 for the administration of the competitive service and the regulations prescribed by such Office under <ref>section 1302(a) of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> falsely marks, grades, estimates, or reports on the examination or proper standing of an individual examined;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> makes a false representation concerning the mark, grade, estimate, or report on the examination or proper standing of an individual examined, or concerning the individual examined; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> furnishes to an individual any special or secret information for the purpose of improving or injuring the prospects or chances of an individual examined, or to be examined, being appointed, employed, or promoted;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall, for each offense, be fined under this title not less than $100 or imprisoned not less than ten days nor more than one year, or both.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 609</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330010(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1918.</num>
<heading> Disloyalty and asserting the right to strike against the Government</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever violates the provision of <ref>section 7311 of title 5</ref> that an individual may not accept or hold a position in the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia if he—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> advocates the overthrow of our constitutional form of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is a member of an organization that he knows advocates the overthrow of our constitutional form of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> participates in a strike, or asserts the right to strike, against the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is a member of an organization of employees of the Government of the United States or of individuals employed by the government of the District of Columbia that he knows asserts the right to strike against the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year and a day, or both.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 609</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1919.</num>
<heading> False statement to obtain unemployment compensation for Federal service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes a false statement or representation of a material fact knowing it to be false, or knowingly fails to disclose a material fact, to obtain or increase for himself or for any other individual any payment authorized to be paid under chapter 85 of title 5 or under an agreement thereunder, shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1920.</num>
<heading> False statement or fraud to obtain Federal employees’ compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and willfully falsifies, conceals, or covers up a material fact, or makes a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation, or makes or uses a false statement or report knowing the same to contain any false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or entry in connection with the application for or receipt of compensation or other benefit or payment under subchapter I or III of chapter 81 of title 5, shall be guilty of perjury, and on conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine under this title, or by imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both; but if the amount of the benefits falsely obtained does not exceed $1,000, such person shall be punished by a fine under this title, or by imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–333, title I, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1921.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title X, § 1002(9)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2155</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1922.</num>
<heading> False or withheld report concerning Federal employees’ compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer or employee of the United States charged with the responsibility for making the reports of the immediate superior specified by <ref>section 8120 of title 5</ref>, willfully fails, neglects, or refuses to make any of the reports, or knowingly files a false report, or induces, compels, or directs an injured employee to forego filing of any claim for compensation or other benefits provided under subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5 or any extension or application thereof, or willfully retains any notice, report, claim, or paper which is required to be filed under that subchapter or any extension or application thereof, or regulations prescribed thereunder, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1923.</num>
<heading> Fraudulent receipt of payments of missing persons</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever obtains or receives any money, check, or allotment under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subchapter VII of chapter 55 of title 5; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> chapter 10 of title 37;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">without being entitled thereto, with intent to defraud, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 610</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1924.</num>
<heading> Unauthorized removal and retention of classified documents or material</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, being an officer, employee, contractor, or consultant of the United States, and, by virtue of his office, employment, position, or contract, becomes possessed of documents or materials containing classified information of the United States, knowingly removes such documents or materials without authority and with the intent to retain such documents or materials at an unauthorized location shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the provision of documents and materials to the Congress shall not constitute an offense under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “classified information of the United States” means information originated, owned, or possessed by the United States Government concerning the national defense or foreign relations of the United States that has been determined pursuant to law or Executive order to require protection against unauthorized disclosure in the interests of national security.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3453</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(d)(1)(C)(i)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1809</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–118, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2018-01-19">Jan. 19, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>