<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 73—</num>
<heading>OBSTRUCTION OF JUSTICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1501.</num>
<heading> Assault on process server</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and willfully obstructs, resists, or opposes any officer of the United States, or other person duly authorized, in serving, or attempting to serve or execute, any legal or judicial writ or process of any court of the United States, or United States magistrate judge; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever assaults, beats, or wounds any officer or other person duly authorized, knowing him to be such officer, or other person so duly authorized, in serving or executing any such writ, rule, order, process, warrant, or other legal or judicial writ or process—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall, except as otherwise provided by law, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1502.</num>
<heading> Resistance to extradition agent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and willfully obstructs, resists, or opposes an extradition agent of the United States in the execution of his duties, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 24, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1503.</num>
<heading> Influencing or injuring officer or juror generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever corruptly, or by threats or force, or by any threatening letter or communication, endeavors to influence, intimidate, or impede any grand or petit juror, or officer in or of any court of the United States, or officer who may be serving at any examination or other proceeding before any United States magistrate judge or other committing magistrate, in the discharge of his duty, or injures any such grand or petit juror in his person or property on account of any verdict or indictment assented to by him, or on account of his being or having been such juror, or injures any such officer, magistrate judge, or other committing magistrate in his person or property on account of the performance of his official duties, or corruptly or by threats or force, or by any threatening letter or communication, influences, obstructs, or impedes, or endeavors to influence, obstruct, or impede, the due administration of justice, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b). If the offense under this section occurs in connection with a trial of a criminal case, and the act in violation of this section involves the threat of physical force or physical force, the maximum term of imprisonment which may be imposed for the offense shall be the higher of that otherwise provided by law or the maximum term that could have been imposed for any offense charged in such case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The punishment for an offense under this section is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a killing, the punishment provided in sections 1111 and 1112;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an attempted killing, or a case in which the offense was committed against a petit juror and in which a class A or B felony was charged, imprisonment for not more than 20 years, a fine under this title, or both; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in any other case, imprisonment for not more than 10 years, a fine under this title, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–291, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60016</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1974</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 104–214, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1504.</num>
<heading> Influencing juror by writing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever attempts to influence the action or decision of any grand or petit juror of any court of the United States upon any issue or matter pending before such juror, or before the jury of which he is a member, or pertaining to his duties, by writing or sending to him any written communication, in relation to such issue or matter, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the communication of a request to appear before the grand jury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1505.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of proceedings before departments, agencies, and committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to avoid, evade, prevent, or obstruct compliance, in whole or in part, with any civil investigative demand duly and properly made under the Antitrust Civil Process Act, willfully withholds, misrepresents, removes from any place, conceals, covers up, destroys, mutilates, alters, or by other means falsifies any documentary material, answers to written interrogatories, or oral testimony, which is the subject of such demand; or attempts to do so or solicits another to do so; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever corruptly, or by threats or force, or by any threatening letter or communication influences, obstructs, or impedes or endeavors to influence, obstruct, or impede the due and proper administration of the law under which any pending proceeding is being had before any department or agency of the United States, or the due and proper exercise of the power of inquiry under which any inquiry or investigation is being had by either House, or any committee of either House or any joint committee of the Congress—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years or, if the offense involves international or domestic terrorism (as defined in section 2331), imprisoned not more than 8 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–664, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–435, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–291, § 4(d)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6703(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3766</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1506.</num>
<heading> Theft or alteration of record or process; false bail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever feloniously steals, takes away, alters, falsifies, or otherwise avoids any record, writ, process, or other proceeding, in any court of the United States, whereby any judgment is reversed, made void, or does not take effect; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever acknowledges, or procures to be acknowledged in any such court, any recognizance, bail, or judgment, in the name of any other person not privy or consenting to the same—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1507.</num>
<heading> Picketing or parading</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with the intent of interfering with, obstructing, or impeding the administration of justice, or with the intent of influencing any judge, juror, witness, or court officer, in the discharge of his duty, pickets or parades in or near a building housing a court of the United States, or in or near a building or residence occupied or used by such judge, juror, witness, or court officer, or with such intent uses any sound-truck or similar device or resorts to any other demonstration in or near any such building or residence, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall interfere with or prevent the exercise by any court of the United States of its power to punish for contempt.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024</ref>, title I, § 31(a), <ref>64 Stat. 1018</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1508.</num>
<heading> Recording, listening to, or observing proceedings of grand or petit juries while deliberating or voting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and willfully, by any means or device whatsoever—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> records, or attempts to record, the proceedings of any grand or petit jury in any court of the United States while such jury is deliberating or voting; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> listens to or observes, or attempts to listen to or observe, the proceedings of any grand or petit jury of which he is not a member in any court of the United States while such jury is deliberating or voting—</content>
</subsection>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</continuation>
<continuation class="indent0">Nothing in paragraph (a) of this section shall be construed to prohibit the taking of notes by a grand or petit juror in any court of the United States in connection with and solely for the purpose of assisting him in the performance of his duties as such juror.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Aug. 2, 1956, ch. 879, § 1</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 935</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(f)(13)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1509.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of court orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, by threats or force, willfully prevents, obstructs, impedes, or interferes with, or willfully attempts to prevent, obstruct, impede, or interfere with, the due exercise of rights or the performance of duties under any order, judgment, or decree of a court of the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">No injunctive or other civil relief against the conduct made criminal by this section shall be denied on the ground that such conduct is a crime.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–449, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1960-05-06">May 6, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 86</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1510.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of criminal investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever willfully endeavors by means of bribery to obstruct, delay, or prevent the communication of information relating to a violation of any criminal statute of the United States by any person to a criminal investigator shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whoever, being an officer of a financial institution, with the intent to obstruct a judicial proceeding, directly or indirectly notifies any other person about the existence or contents of a subpoena for records of that financial institution, or information that has been furnished in response to that subpoena, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever, being an officer of a financial institution, directly or indirectly notifies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a customer of that financial institution whose records are sought by a subpoena for records; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other person named in that subpoena;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">about the existence or contents of that subpoena or information that has been furnished in response to that subpoena, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “an officer of a financial institution” means an officer, director, partner, employee, agent, or attorney of or for a financial institution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the term “subpoena for records” means a Federal grand jury subpoena, a subpoena issued under <ref>section 3486 of this title</ref>, or an order or subpoena issued in accordance with <ref>section 3512 of this title</ref>, <ref>section 5318 of title 31</ref>, or <ref>section 1782 of title 28</ref>, for customer records that has been served relating to a violation of, or a conspiracy to violate—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> section 215, 656, 657, 1005, 1006, 1007, 1014, 1344, 1956, 1957, 1960, an offense against a foreign nation constituting specified unlawful activity under section 1956, a foreign offense for which enforcement of a foreign forfeiture judgment could be brought under <ref>section 2467 of title 28</ref>, or chapter 53 of title 31; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> section 1341 or 1343 affecting a financial institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “criminal investigator” means any individual duly authorized by a department, agency, or armed force of the United States to conduct or engage in investigations of or prosecutions for violations of the criminal laws of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acting as, or being, an officer, director, agent or employee of a person engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce or is involved (other than as an insured or beneficiary under a policy of insurance) in a transaction relating to the conduct of affairs of such a business,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">with intent to obstruct a judicial proceeding, directly or indirectly notifies any other person about the existence or contents of a subpoena for records of that person engaged in such business or information that has been furnished to a Federal grand jury in response to that subpoena, shall be fined as provided by this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As used in paragraph (1), the term “subpoena for records” means a Federal grand jury subpoena for records that has been served relating to a violation of, or a conspiracy to violate, <ref>section 1033 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Whoever, having been notified of the applicable disclosure prohibitions or confidentiality requirements of <ref>section 2709(c)(1) of this title</ref>, section 626(d)(1) or 627(c)(1) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1681u(d)(1)</ref> or 1681v(c)(1)), section 1114(a)(3)(A) or 1114(a)(5)(D)(i) of the Right to Financial Privacy Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002113">1</ref> (<ref>12 U.S.C. 3414(a)(3)(A)</ref> or 3414(a)(5)(D)(i)), or section 802(b)(1) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 436(b)(1)</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002114">2</ref> knowingly and with the intent to obstruct an investigation or judicial proceeding violates such prohibitions or requirements applicable by law to such person shall be imprisoned for not more than five years, fined under this title, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–123, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1967-11-03">Nov. 3, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 362</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–291, § 4(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 962(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1528</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320604(c)</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2119</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 248(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2020</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 217</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10606(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. F, title LXIII, § 6308(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1511.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of State or local law enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be unlawful for two or more persons to conspire to obstruct the enforcement of the criminal laws of a State or political subdivision thereof, with the intent to facilitate an illegal gambling business if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one or more of such persons does any act to effect the object of such a conspiracy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> one or more of such persons is an official or employee, elected, appointed, or otherwise, of such State or political subdivision; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> one or more of such persons conducts, finances, manages, supervises, directs, or owns all or part of an illegal gambling business.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “illegal gambling business” means a gambling business which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a violation of the law of a State or political subdivision in which it is conducted;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> involves five or more persons who conduct, finance, manage, supervise, direct, or own all or part of such business; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> has been or remains in substantially continuous operation for a period in excess of thirty days or has a gross revenue of $2,000 in any single day.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “gambling” includes but is not limited to pool-selling, bookmaking, maintaining slot machines, roulette wheels, or dice tables, and conducting lotteries, policy, bolita or numbers games, or selling chances therein.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to any bingo game, lottery, or similar game of chance conducted by an organization exempt from tax under paragraph (3) of subsection (c) of section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, if no part of the gross receipts derived from such activity inures to the benefit of any private shareholder, member, or employee of such organization, except as compensation for actual expenses incurred by him in the conduct of such activity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Whoever violates this section shall be punished by a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 936</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1512.</num>
<heading> Tampering with a witness, victim, or an informant</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever kills or attempts to kill another person, with intent to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prevent the attendance or testimony of any person in an official proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prevent the production of a record, document, or other object, in an official proceeding; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> prevent the communication by any person to a law enforcement officer or judge of the United States of information relating to the commission or possible commission of a Federal offense or a violation of conditions of probation, parole, or release pending judicial proceedings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in paragraph (3).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever uses physical force or the threat of physical force against any person, or attempts to do so, with intent to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> influence, delay, or prevent the testimony of any person in an official proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> cause or induce any person to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> withhold testimony, or withhold a record, document, or other object, from an official proceeding;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> alter, destroy, mutilate, or conceal an object with intent to impair the integrity or availability of the object for use in an official proceeding;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> evade legal process summoning that person to appear as a witness, or to produce a record, document, or other object, in an official proceeding; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> be absent from an official proceeding to which that person has been summoned by legal process; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> hinder, delay, or prevent the communication to a law enforcement officer or judge of the United States of information relating to the commission or possible commission of a Federal offense or a violation of conditions of probation, supervised release, parole, or release pending judicial proceedings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in paragraph (3).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The punishment for an offense under this subsection is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a killing, the punishment provided in sections 1111 and 1112;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an attempt to murder; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the use or attempted use of physical force against any person;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">imprisonment for not more than 30 years; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of the threat of use of physical force against any person, imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever knowingly uses intimidation, threatens, or corruptly persuades another person, or attempts to do so, or engages in misleading conduct toward another person, with intent to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> influence, delay, or prevent the testimony of any person in an official proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> cause or induce any person to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> withhold testimony, or withhold a record, document, or other object, from an official proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> alter, destroy, mutilate, or conceal an object with intent to impair the object’s integrity or availability for use in an official proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> evade legal process summoning that person to appear as a witness, or to produce a record, document, or other object, in an official proceeding; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> be absent from an official proceeding to which such person has been summoned by legal process; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> hinder, delay, or prevent the communication to a law enforcement officer or judge of the United States of information relating to the commission or possible commission of a Federal offense or a violation of conditions of probation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002115">1</ref> supervised release,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002115">1</ref> parole, or release pending judicial proceedings;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever corruptly—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> alters, destroys, mutilates, or conceals a record, document, or other object, or attempts to do so, with the intent to impair the object’s integrity or availability for use in an official proceeding; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> otherwise obstructs, influences, or impedes any official proceeding, or attempts to do so,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever intentionally harasses another person and thereby hinders, delays, prevents, or dissuades any person from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> attending or testifying in an official proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reporting to a law enforcement officer or judge of the United States the commission or possible commission of a Federal offense or a violation of conditions of probation <sup>1</sup> supervised release,,<sup>1</sup> parole, or release pending judicial proceedings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> arresting or seeking the arrest of another person in connection with a Federal offense; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> causing a criminal prosecution, or a parole or probation revocation proceeding, to be sought or instituted, or assisting in such prosecution or proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">or attempts to do so, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 3 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> In a prosecution for an offense under this section, it is an affirmative defense, as to which the defendant has the burden of proof by a preponderance of the evidence, that the conduct consisted solely of lawful conduct and that the defendant’s sole intention was to encourage, induce, or cause the other person to testify truthfully.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an official proceeding need not be pending or about to be instituted at the time of the offense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the testimony, or the record, document, or other object need not be admissible in evidence or free of a claim of privilege.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> In a prosecution for an offense under this section, no state of mind need be proved with respect to the circumstance—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the official proceeding before a judge, court, magistrate judge, grand jury, or government agency is before a judge or court of the United States, a United States magistrate judge, a bankruptcy judge, a Federal grand jury, or a Federal Government agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the judge is a judge of the United States or that the law enforcement officer is an officer or employee of the Federal Government or a person authorized to act for or on behalf of the Federal Government or serving the Federal Government as an adviser or consultant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> There is extraterritorial Federal jurisdiction over an offense under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A prosecution under this section or section 1503 may be brought in the district in which the official proceeding (whether or not pending or about to be instituted) was intended to be affected or in the district in which the conduct constituting the alleged offense occurred.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> If the offense under this section occurs in connection with a trial of a criminal case, the maximum term of imprisonment which may be imposed for the offense shall be the higher of that otherwise provided by law or the maximum term that could have been imposed for any offense charged in such case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> Whoever conspires to commit any offense under this section shall be subject to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense the commission of which was the object of the conspiracy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–291, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1249</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 61</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3614</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7029(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4397</ref>, 4398; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60018</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(O), (U), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1975</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–214, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(31)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title III, § 3001(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1803</ref>, 1804; <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1513.</num>
<heading> Retaliating against a witness, victim, or an informant</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever kills or attempts to kill another person with intent to retaliate against any person for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the attendance of a witness or party at an official proceeding, or any testimony given or any record, document, or other object produced by a witness in an official proceeding; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing to a law enforcement officer any information relating to the commission or possible commission of a Federal offense or a violation of conditions of probation, supervised release, parole, or release pending judicial proceedings,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in paragraph (2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The punishment for an offense under this subsection is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a killing, the punishment provided in sections 1111 and 1112; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an attempt, imprisonment for not more than 30 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever knowingly engages in any conduct and thereby causes bodily injury to another person or damages the tangible property of another person, or threatens to do so, with intent to retaliate against any person for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the attendance of a witness or party at an official proceeding, or any testimony given or any record, document, or other object produced by a witness in an official proceeding; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any information relating to the commission or possible commission of a Federal offense or a violation of conditions of probation, supervised release, parole, or release pending judicial proceedings given by a person to a law enforcement officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">or attempts to do so, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the retaliation occurred because of attendance at or testimony in a criminal case, the maximum term of imprisonment which may be imposed for the offense under this section shall be the higher of that otherwise provided by law or the maximum term that could have been imposed for any offense charged in such case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> There is extraterritorial Federal jurisdiction over an offense under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly, with the intent to retaliate, takes any action harmful to any person, including interference with the lawful employment or livelihood of any person, for providing to a law enforcement officer any truthful information relating to the commission or possible commission of any Federal offense, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Whoever conspires to commit any offense under this section shall be subject to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense the commission of which was the object of the conspiracy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> A prosecution under this section may be brought in the district in which the official proceeding (whether pending, about to be instituted, or completed) was intended to be affected, or in which the conduct constituting the alleged offense occurred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–291, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1250</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60017</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(U), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1975</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–214, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title XI, § 1107(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 810</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title III, § 3001(b)</ref>, (c)(2), title IV, § 4002(b)(4), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1804</ref>, 1807; <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title II</ref>, §§ 204, 206, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1514.</num>
<heading> Civil action to restrain harassment of a victim or witness</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A United States district court, upon application of the attorney for the Government, shall issue a temporary restraining order prohibiting harassment of a victim or witness in a Federal criminal case if the court finds, from specific facts shown by affidavit or by verified complaint, that there are reasonable grounds to believe that harassment of an identified victim or witness in a Federal criminal case exists or that such order is necessary to prevent and restrain an offense under <ref>section 1512 of this title</ref>, other than an offense consisting of misleading conduct, or under <ref>section 1513 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A temporary restraining order may be issued under this section without written or oral notice to the adverse party or such party’s attorney in a civil action under this section if the court finds, upon written certification of facts by the attorney for the Government, that such notice should not be required and that there is a reasonable probability that the Government will prevail on the merits.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A temporary restraining order issued without notice under this section shall be endorsed with the date and hour of issuance and be filed forthwith in the office of the clerk of the court issuing the order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A temporary restraining order issued under this section shall expire at such time, not to exceed 14 days from issuance, as the court directs; the court, for good cause shown before expiration of such order, may extend the expiration date of the order for up to 14 days or for such longer period agreed to by the adverse party.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> When a temporary restraining order is issued without notice, the motion for a protective order shall be set down for hearing at the earliest possible time and takes precedence over all matters except older matters of the same character, and when such motion comes on for hearing, if the attorney for the Government does not proceed with the application for a protective order, the court shall dissolve the temporary restraining order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> If on two days notice to the attorney for the Government, excluding intermediate weekends and holidays, or on such shorter notice as the court may prescribe, the adverse party appears and moves to dissolve or modify the temporary restraining order, the court shall proceed to hear and determine such motion as expeditiously as the ends of justice require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A temporary restraining order shall set forth the reasons for the issuance of such order, be specific in terms, and describe in reasonable detail (and not by reference to the complaint or other document) the act or acts being restrained.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A United States district court, upon motion of the attorney for the Government, or its own motion, shall issue a protective order prohibiting harassment of a victim or witness in a Federal criminal case or investigation if the court, after a hearing, finds by a preponderance of the evidence that harassment of an identified victim or witness in a Federal criminal case or investigation exists or that such order is necessary to prevent and restrain an offense under <ref>section 1512 of this title</ref>, other than an offense consisting of misleading conduct, or under <ref>section 1513 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a minor witness or victim, the court shall issue a protective order prohibiting harassment or intimidation of the minor victim or witness if the court finds evidence that the conduct at issue is reasonably likely to adversely affect the willingness of the minor witness or victim to testify or otherwise participate in the Federal criminal case or investigation. Any hearing regarding a protective order under this paragraph shall be conducted in accordance with paragraphs (1) and (3), except that the court may issue an ex parte emergency protective order in advance of a hearing if exigent circumstances are present. If such an ex parte order is applied for or issued, the court shall hold a hearing not later than 14 days after the date such order was applied for or is issued.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> At the hearing referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, any adverse party named in the complaint shall have the right to present evidence and cross-examine witnesses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A protective order shall set forth the reasons for the issuance of such order, be specific in terms, describe in reasonable detail the act or acts being restrained.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The court shall set the duration of effect of the protective order for such period as the court determines necessary to prevent harassment of the victim or witness but in no case for a period in excess of three years from the date of such order’s issuance. The attorney for the Government may, at any time within ninety days before the expiration of such order, apply for a new protective order under this section, except that in the case of a minor victim or witness, the court may order that such protective order expires on the later of 3 years after the date of issuance or the date of the eighteenth birthday of that minor victim or witness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly and intentionally violates or attempts to violate an order issued under this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “course of conduct” means a series of acts over a period of time, however short, indicating a continuity of purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the term “harassment” means a serious act or course of conduct directed at a specific person that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> causes substantial emotional distress in such person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> serves no legitimate purpose;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “immediate family member” has the meaning given that term in section 115 and includes grandchildren;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the term “intimidation” means a serious act or course of conduct directed at a specific person that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> causes fear or apprehension in such person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> serves no legitimate purpose;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the term “restricted personal information” has the meaning give <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002116">1</ref> that term in section 119;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the term “serious act” means a single act of threatening, retaliatory, harassing, or violent conduct that is reasonably likely to influence the willingness of a victim or witness to testify or participate in a Federal criminal case or investigation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the term “specific person” means a victim or witness in a Federal criminal case or investigation, and includes an immediate family member of such a victim or witness.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraphs (B)(ii) and (D)(ii) of paragraph (1), a court shall presume, subject to rebuttal by the person, that the distribution or publication using the Internet of a photograph of, or restricted personal information regarding, a specific person serves no legitimate purpose, unless that use is authorized by that specific person, is for news reporting purposes, is designed to locate that specific person (who has been reported to law enforcement as a missing person), or is part of a government-authorized effort to locate a fugitive or person of interest in a criminal, antiterrorism, or national security investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–291, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1250</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–16, § 3(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–206, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-07">Dec. 7, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1490</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1514A.</num>
<heading> Civil action to protect against retaliation in fraud cases</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Whistleblower Protection for Employees of Publicly Traded Companies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No company with a class of securities registered under section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>l</i>), or that is required to file reports under section 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>o</i>(d)) including any subsidiary or affiliate whose financial information is included in the consolidated financial statements of such company, or nationally recognized statistical rating organization (as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78c</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002117">1</ref> or any officer, employee, contractor, subcontractor, or agent of such company or nationally recognized statistical rating organization, may discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, harass, or in any other manner discriminate against an employee in the terms and conditions of employment because of any lawful act done by the employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to provide information, cause information to be provided, or otherwise assist in an investigation regarding any conduct which the employee reasonably believes constitutes a violation of section 1341, 1343, 1344, or 1348, any rule or regulation of the Securities and Exchange Commission, or any provision of Federal law relating to fraud against shareholders, when the information or assistance is provided to or the investigation is conducted by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Federal regulatory or law enforcement agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any Member of Congress or any committee of Congress; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a person with supervisory authority over the employee (or such other person working for the employer who has the authority to investigate, discover, or terminate misconduct); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to file, cause to be filed, testify, participate in, or otherwise assist in a proceeding filed or about to be filed (with any knowledge of the employer) relating to an alleged violation of section 1341, 1343, 1344, or 1348, any rule or regulation of the Securities and Exchange Commission, or any provision of Federal law relating to fraud against shareholders.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Enforcement Action.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person who alleges discharge or other discrimination by any person in violation of subsection (a) may seek relief under subsection (c), by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Secretary has not issued a final decision within 180 days of the filing of the complaint and there is no showing that such delay is due to the bad faith of the claimant, bringing an action at law or equity for de novo review in the appropriate district court of the United States, which shall have jurisdiction over such an action without regard to the amount in controversy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedure.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An action under paragraph (1)(A) shall be governed under the rules and procedures set forth in <ref>section 42121(b) of title 49</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notification made under <ref>section 42121(b)(1) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, shall be made to the person named in the complaint and to the employer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Burdens of proof</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An action brought under paragraph (1)(B) shall be governed by the legal burdens of proof set forth in <ref>section 42121(b) of title 49</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statute of limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An action under paragraph (1) shall be commenced not later than 180 days after the date on which the violation occurs, or after the date on which the employee became aware of the violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jury trial</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A party to an action brought under paragraph (1)(B) shall be entitled to trial by jury.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Remedies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An employee prevailing in any action under subsection (b)(1) shall be entitled to all relief necessary to make the employee whole.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensatory damages</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Relief for any action under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reinstatement with the same seniority status that the employee would have had, but for the discrimination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of back pay, with interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> compensation for any special damages sustained as a result of the discrimination, including litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable attorney fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rights Retained by Employee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any employee under any Federal or State law, or under any collective bargaining agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Nonenforceability of Certain Provisions Waiving Rights and Remedies or Requiring Arbitration of Disputes.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of rights and remedies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The rights and remedies provided for in this section may not be waived by any agreement, policy form, or condition of employment, including by a predispute arbitration agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Predispute arbitration agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No predispute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable, if the agreement requires arbitration of a dispute arising under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title VIII, § 806(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 802</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title IX</ref>, §§ 922(b), (c), 929A, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1848</ref>, 1852.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1515.</num>
<heading> Definitions for certain provisions; general provision</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> As used in sections 1512 and 1513 of this title and in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “official proceeding” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a proceeding before a judge or court of the United States, a United States magistrate judge, a bankruptcy judge, a judge of the United States Tax Court, a special trial judge of the Tax Court, a judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims, or a Federal grand jury;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a proceeding before the Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a proceeding before a Federal Government agency which is authorized by law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a proceeding involving the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce before any insurance regulatory official or agency or any agent or examiner appointed by such official or agency to examine the affairs of any person engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “physical force” means physical action against another, and includes confinement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “misleading conduct” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> knowingly making a false statement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> intentionally omitting information from a statement and thereby causing a portion of such statement to be misleading, or intentionally concealing a material fact, and thereby creating a false impression by such statement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> with intent to mislead, knowingly submitting or inviting reliance on a writing or recording that is false, forged, altered, or otherwise lacking in authenticity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with intent to mislead, knowingly submitting or inviting reliance on a sample, specimen, map, photograph, boundary mark, or other object that is misleading in a material respect; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> knowingly using a trick, scheme, or device with intent to mislead;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “law enforcement officer” means an officer or employee of the Federal Government, or a person authorized to act for or on behalf of the Federal Government or serving the Federal Government as an adviser or consultant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> authorized under law to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of an offense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serving as a probation or pretrial services officer under this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the term “bodily injury” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a cut, abrasion, bruise, burn, or disfigurement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> physical pain;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> illness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other injury to the body, no matter how temporary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “corruptly persuades” does not include conduct which would be misleading conduct but for a lack of a state of mind.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> As used in section 1505, the term “corruptly” means acting with an improper purpose, personally or by influencing another, including making a false or misleading statement, or withholding, concealing, altering, or destroying a document or other information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This chapter does not prohibit or punish the providing of lawful, bona fide, legal representation services in connection with or anticipation of an official proceeding.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–291, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1252</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 50(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3605</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7029(b)</ref>, (d), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320604(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–292, § 3</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(39)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1516.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of Federal audit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, with intent to deceive or defraud the United States, endeavors to influence, obstruct, or impede a Federal auditor in the performance of official duties relating to a person, entity, or program receiving in excess of $100,000, directly or indirectly, from the United States in any 1 year period under a contract or subcontract, grant, or cooperative agreement, or relating to any property that is security for a mortgage note that is insured, guaranteed, acquired, or held by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development pursuant to any Act administered by the Secretary, or relating to any property that is security for a loan that is made or guaranteed under title V of the Housing Act of 1949, shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Federal auditor” means any person employed on a full- or part-time or contractual basis to perform an audit or a quality assurance inspection for or on behalf of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “in any 1 year period” has the meaning given to the term “in any one-year period” in section 666.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7078(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4406</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320609</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(43)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–65, title V, § 564</ref>, <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–569, title VII, § 709(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 3018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 205(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1517.</num>
<heading> Obstructing examination of financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever corruptly obstructs or attempts to obstruct any examination of a financial institution by an agency of the United States with jurisdiction to conduct an examination of such financial institution shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2503(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4861</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1518.</num>
<heading> Obstruction of criminal investigations of health care offenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever willfully prevents, obstructs, misleads, delays or attempts to prevent, obstruct, mislead, or delay the communication of information or records relating to a violation of a Federal health care offense to a criminal investigator shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> As used in this section the term “criminal investigator” means any individual duly authorized by a department, agency, or armed force of the United States to conduct or engage in investigations for prosecutions for violations of health care offenses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 245(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1519.</num>
<heading> Destruction, alteration, or falsification of records in Federal investigations and bankruptcy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly alters, destroys, mutilates, conceals, covers up, falsifies, or makes a false entry in any record, document, or tangible object with the intent to impede, obstruct, or influence the investigation or proper administration of any matter within the jurisdiction of any department or agency of the United States or any case filed under title 11, or in relation to or contemplation of any such matter or case, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1520.</num>
<heading> Destruction of corporate audit records</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any accountant who conducts an audit of an issuer of securities to which section 10A(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78j–1(a)</ref>) applies, shall maintain all audit or review workpapers for a period of 5 years from the end of the fiscal period in which the audit or review was concluded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Securities and Exchange Commission shall promulgate, within 180 days, after adequate notice and an opportunity for comment, such rules and regulations, as are reasonably necessary, relating to the retention of relevant records such as workpapers, documents that form the basis of an audit or review, memoranda, correspondence, communications, other documents, and records (including electronic records) which are created, sent, or received in connection with an audit or review and contain conclusions, opinions, analyses, or financial data relating to such an audit or review, which is conducted by any accountant who conducts an audit of an issuer of securities to which section 10A(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78j–1(a)</ref>) applies. The Commission may, from time to time, amend or supplement the rules and regulations that it is required to promulgate under this section, after adequate notice and an opportunity for comment, in order to ensure that such rules and regulations adequately comport with the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly and willfully violates subsection (a)(1), or any rule or regulation promulgated by the Securities and Exchange Commission under subsection (a)(2), shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish or relieve any person of any other duty or obligation imposed by Federal or State law or regulation to maintain, or refrain from destroying, any document.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–204, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1521.</num>
<heading> Retaliating against a Federal judge or Federal law enforcement officer by false claim or slander of title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever files, attempts to file, or conspires to file, in any public record or in any private record which is generally available to the public, any false lien or encumbrance against the real or personal property of an individual described in section 1114, on account of the performance of official duties by that individual, knowing or having reason to know that such lien or encumbrance is false or contains any materially false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>