<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>CLAIMS AND SERVICES IN MATTERS AFFECTING GOVERNMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 281.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4304(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3503</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 282.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–849, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1126</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 283.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–849, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VIII, § 822(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1132</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 284.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–849, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1126</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 285.</num>
<heading> Taking or using papers relating to claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without authority, takes and carries away from the place where it was filed, deposited, or kept by authority of the United States, any certificate, affidavit, deposition, statement of facts, power of attorney, receipt, voucher, assignment, or other document, record, file, or paper prepared, fitted, or intended to be used or presented to procure the payment of money from or by the United States or any officer, employee, or agent thereof, or the allowance or payment of the whole or any part of any claim, account, or demand against the United States, whether the same has or has not already been so used or presented, and whether such claim, account, or demand, or any part thereof has or has not already been allowed or paid; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever presents, uses, or attempts to use any such document, record, file, or paper so taken and carried away, to procure the payment of any money from or by the United States, or any officer, employee, or agent thereof, or the allowance or payment of the whole or any part of any claim, account, or demand against the United States—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 286.</num>
<heading> Conspiracy to defraud the Government with respect to claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever enters into any agreement, combination, or conspiracy to defraud the United States, or any department or agency thereof, by obtaining or aiding to obtain the payment or allowance of any false, fictitious or fraudulent claim, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 287.</num>
<heading> False, fictitious or fraudulent claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes or presents to any person or officer in the civil, military, or naval service of the United States, or to any department or agency thereof, any claim upon or against the United States, or any department or agency thereof, knowing such claim to be false, fictitious, or fraudulent, shall be imprisoned not more than five years and shall be subject to a fine in the amount provided in this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–562, § 7</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3169</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 288.</num>
<heading> False claims for postal losses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes, alleges, or presents any claim or application for indemnity for the loss of any registered or insured letter, parcel, package, or other article or matter, or the contents thereof, knowing such claim or application to be false, fictitious, or fraudulent; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever for the purpose of obtaining or aiding to obtain the payment or approval of any such claim or application, makes or uses any false statement, certificate, affidavit, or deposition; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and willfully misrepresents, or misstates, or, for the purpose aforesaid, knowingly and willfully conceals any material fact or circumstance in respect of any such claim or application for indemnity—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Where the amount of such claim or application for indemnity is less than $1,000 only a fine shall be imposed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 289.</num>
<heading> False claims for pensions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and willfully makes, or presents any false, fictitious or fraudulent affidavit, declaration, certificate, voucher, endorsement, or paper or writing purporting to be such, concerning any claim for pension or payment thereof, or pertaining to any other matter within the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or knowingly or willfully makes or presents any paper required as a voucher in drawing a pension, which paper bears a date subsequent to that upon which it was actually signed or acknowledged by the pensioner; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly and falsely certifies that the declarant, affiant, or witness named in such declaration, affidavit, voucher, endorsement, or other paper or writing personally appeared before him and was sworn thereto, or acknowledged the execution thereof—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 699</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 290.</num>
<heading> Discharge papers withheld by claim agent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a claim agent, attorney, or other person engaged in the collection of claims for pay, pension, or other allowances for any soldier, sailor, or marine, or for any commissioned officer of the military or naval forces, or for any person who may have been a soldier, sailor, marine, or officer of the regular or volunteer forces of the United States, or for his dependents or beneficiaries, retains, without the consent of the owner or owners thereof, or refuses to deliver or account for the same upon demand duly made by the owner or owners thereof, or by their agent or attorney, the discharge papers of any such soldier, sailor, or marine, or commissioned officer, which may have been placed in his hands for the purpose of collecting said claims, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both; and shall be debarred from prosecuting any such claim in any department or agency of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 699</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 291.</num>
<heading> Purchase of claims for fees by court officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a judge, clerk, or deputy clerk of any court of the United States or a Territory or Possession thereof, or a United States district attorney, assistant attorney, marshal, deputy marshal, magistrate judge, or other person holding any office or employment, or position of trust or profit under the United States, directly or indirectly purchases at less than the full face value thereof, any claim against the United States for the fee, mileage, or expenses of any witness, juror, deputy marshal, or any other officer of such court, shall be fined under this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 699</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 292.</num>
<heading> Solicitation of employment and receipt of unapproved fees concerning Federal employees’ compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever solicits employment for himself or another in respect to a case, claim, or award for compensation under, or to be brought under, subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives a fee, other consideration, or gratuity on account of legal or other services furnished in respect to a case, claim, or award for compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5, unless the fee, consideration, or gratuity is approved by the Secretary of Labor—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall, for each offense, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 608</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 293.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–123, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-10-23">Oct. 23, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 760</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>