<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 235—</num>
<heading>APPEAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3731.</num>
<heading> Appeal by United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In a criminal case an appeal by the United States shall lie to a court of appeals from a decision, judgment, or order of a district court dismissing an indictment or information or granting a new trial after verdict or judgment, as to any one or more counts, or any part thereof, except that no appeal shall lie where the double jeopardy clause of the United States Constitution prohibits further prosecution.</p>
<p class="indent0">An appeal by the United States shall lie to a court of appeals from a decision or order of a district court suppressing or excluding evidence or requiring the return of seized property in a criminal proceeding, not made after the defendant has been put in jeopardy and before the verdict or finding on an indictment or information, if the United States attorney certifies to the district court that the appeal is not taken for purpose of delay and that the evidence is a substantial proof of a fact material in the proceeding.</p>
<p class="indent0">An appeal by the United States shall lie to a court of appeals from a decision or order, entered by a district court of the United States, granting the release of a person charged with or convicted of an offense, or denying a motion for revocation of, or modification of the conditions of, a decision or order granting release.</p>
<p class="indent0">The appeal in all such cases shall be taken within thirty days after the decision, judgment or order has been rendered and shall be diligently prosecuted.</p>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall be liberally construed to effectuate its purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 844</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 58</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 97</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–351, title VIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1968-06-19">June 19, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–644, title III, § 14(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1890</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II</ref>, §§ 205, 1206, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1986</ref>, 2153; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 32</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330008(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2142</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title III, § 3004</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3732.</num>
<heading> Taking of appeal; notice; time—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3733.</num>
<heading> Assignment of errors—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3734.</num>
<heading> Bill of exceptions abolished—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3735.</num>
<heading> Bail on appeal or certiorari—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3736.</num>
<heading> Certiorari—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3737.</num>
<heading> Record—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3738.</num>
<heading> Docketing appeal and record—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3739.</num>
<heading> Supervision—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3740.</num>
<heading> Argument—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3741.</num>
<heading> Harmless error and plain error—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3742.</num>
<heading> Review of a sentence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeal by a Defendant</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A defendant may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of an otherwise final sentence if the sentence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> was imposed in violation of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was imposed as a result of an incorrect application of the sentencing guidelines; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is greater than the sentence specified in the applicable guideline range to the extent that the sentence includes a greater fine or term of imprisonment, probation, or supervised release than the maximum established in the guideline range, or includes a more limiting condition of probation or supervised release under section 3563(b)(6) or (b)(11) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002276">1</ref> than the maximum established in the guideline range; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> was imposed for an offense for which there is no sentencing guideline and is plainly unreasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeal by the Government</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Government may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of an otherwise final sentence if the sentence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> was imposed in violation of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was imposed as a result of an incorrect application of the sentencing guidelines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is less than the sentence specified in the applicable guideline range to the extent that the sentence includes a lesser fine or term of imprisonment, probation, or supervised release than the minimum established in the guideline range, or includes a less limiting condition of probation or supervised release under section 3563(b)(6) or (b)(11) <sup>1</sup> than the minimum established in the guideline range; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> was imposed for an offense for which there is no sentencing guideline and is plainly unreasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Government may not further prosecute such appeal without the personal approval of the Attorney General, the Solicitor General, or a deputy solicitor general designated by the Solicitor General.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plea Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of a plea agreement that includes a specific sentence under rule 11(e)(1)(C) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a defendant may not file a notice of appeal under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (a) unless the sentence imposed is greater than the sentence set forth in such agreement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Government may not file a notice of appeal under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (b) unless the sentence imposed is less than the sentence set forth in such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Record on Review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a notice of appeal is filed in the district court pursuant to subsection (a) or (b), the clerk shall certify to the court of appeals—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that portion of the record in the case that is designated as pertinent by either of the parties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the presentence report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the information submitted during the sentencing proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon review of the record, the court of appeals shall determine whether the sentence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> was imposed in violation of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was imposed as a result of an incorrect application of the sentencing guidelines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> is outside the applicable guideline range, and</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the district court failed to provide the written statement of reasons required by section 3553(c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the sentence departs from the applicable guideline range based on a factor that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> does not advance the objectives set forth in section 3553(a)(2); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is not authorized under section 3553(b); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is not justified by the facts of the case; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the sentence departs to an unreasonable degree from the applicable guidelines range, having regard for the factors to be considered in imposing a sentence, as set forth in <ref>section 3553(a) of this title</ref> and the reasons for the imposition of the particular sentence, as stated by the district court pursuant to the provisions of section 3553(c); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> was imposed for an offense for which there is no applicable sentencing guideline and is plainly unreasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The court of appeals shall give due regard to the opportunity of the district court to judge the credibility of the witnesses, and shall accept the findings of fact of the district court unless they are clearly erroneous and, except with respect to determinations under subsection (3)(A) or (3)(B), shall give due deference to the district court’s application of the guidelines to the facts. With respect to determinations under subsection (3)(A) or (3)(B), the court of appeals shall review de novo the district court’s application of the guidelines to the facts.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Decision and Disposition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the court of appeals determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the sentence was imposed in violation of law or imposed as a result of an incorrect application of the sentencing guidelines, the court shall remand the case for further sentencing proceedings with such instructions as the court considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the sentence is outside the applicable guideline range and the district court failed to provide the required statement of reasons in the order of judgment and commitment, or the departure is based on an impermissible factor, or is to an unreasonable degree, or the sentence was imposed for an offense for which there is no applicable sentencing guideline and is plainly unreasonable, it shall state specific reasons for its conclusions and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if it determines that the sentence is too high and the appeal has been filed under subsection (a), it shall set aside the sentence and remand the case for further sentencing proceedings with such instructions as the court considers appropriate, subject to subsection (g);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if it determines that the sentence is too low and the appeal has been filed under subsection (b), it shall set aside the sentence and remand the case for further sentencing proceedings with such instructions as the court considers appropriate, subject to subsection (g);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the sentence is not described in paragraph (1) or (2), it shall affirm the sentence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sentencing Upon Remand</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A district court to which a case is remanded pursuant to subsection (f)(1) or (f)(2) shall resentence a defendant in accordance with section 3553 and with such instructions as may have been given by the court of appeals, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In determining the range referred to in subsection 3553(a)(4), the court shall apply the guidelines issued by the Sentencing Commission pursuant to <ref>section 994(a)(1) of title 28</ref>, United States Code, and that were in effect on the date of the previous sentencing of the defendant prior to the appeal, together with any amendments thereto by any act of Congress that was in effect on such date; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall not impose a sentence outside the applicable guidelines range except upon a ground that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> was specifically and affirmatively included in the written statement of reasons required by section 3553(c) in connection with the previous sentencing of the defendant prior to the appeal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was held by the court of appeals, in remanding the case, to be a permissible ground of departure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to a Sentence by a Magistrate Judge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An appeal of an otherwise final sentence imposed by a United States magistrate judge may be taken to a judge of the district court, and this section shall apply (except for the requirement of approval by the Attorney General or the Solicitor General in the case of a Government appeal) as though the appeal were to a court of appeals from a sentence imposed by a district court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guideline Not Expressed as a Range</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purpose of this section, the term “guideline range” includes a guideline range having the same upper and lower limits.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a factor is a “permissible” ground of departure if it—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advances the objectives set forth in section 3553(a)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is authorized under section 3553(b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is justified by the facts of the case; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a factor is an “impermissible” ground of departure if it is not a permissible factor within the meaning of subsection (j)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 213(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2011</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 73(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–182</ref>, §§ 4–6, <date date="1987-12-07">Dec. 7, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1266</ref>, 1267; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7103(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV</ref>, §§ 3501, 3503, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330002(k)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–21, title IV, § 401(d)</ref>–(f), <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 670</ref>, 671.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>