<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 315—</num>
<heading>DISCHARGE AND RELEASE PAYMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 4281.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 218(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2027</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4282.</num>
<heading> Arrested but unconvicted persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the release from custody of a person arrested on a charge of violating any law of the United States or of the Territory of Alaska, but not indicted nor informed against, or indicted or informed against but not convicted, and detained pursuant to chapter 207, or a person held as a material witness, the court in its discretion may direct the United States marshal for the district wherein he is released, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Attorney General, to furnish the person so released with transportation and subsistence to the place of his arrest, or, at his election, to the place of his bona fide residence if such cost is not greater than to the place of arrest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4283, 4284.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 218(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2027</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4285.</num>
<heading> Persons released pending further judicial proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any judge or magistrate judge of the United States, when ordering a person released under chapter 207 on a condition of his subsequent appearance before that court, any division of that court, or any court of the United States in another judicial district in which criminal proceedings are pending, may, when the interests of justice would be served thereby and the United States judge or magistrate judge is satisfied, after appropriate inquiry, that the defendant is financially unable to provide the necessary transportation to appear before the required court on his own, direct the United States marshal to arrange for that person’s means of noncustodial transportation or furnish the fare for such transportation to the place where his appearance is required, and in addition may direct the United States marshal to furnish that person with an amount of money for subsistence expenses to his destination, not to exceed the amount authorized as a per diem allowance for travel under <ref>section 5702(a) of title 5</ref>, United States Code. When so ordered, such expenses shall be paid by the marshal out of funds authorized by the Attorney General for such expenses.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–503, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-10-24">Oct. 24, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1704</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3599E</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>