<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 67—</num>
<heading>MILITARY AND NAVY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1381.</num>
<heading> Enticing desertion and harboring deserters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever entices or procures, or attempts or endeavors to entice or procure any person in the Armed Forces of the United States, or who has been recruited for service therein, to desert therefrom, or aids any such person in deserting or in attempting to desert from such service; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever harbors, conceals, protects, or assists any such person who may have deserted from such service, knowing him to have deserted therefrom, or refuses to give up and deliver such person on the demand of any officer authorized to receive him—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1382.</num>
<heading> Entering military, naval, or Coast Guard property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the jurisdiction of the United States, goes upon any military, naval, or Coast Guard reservation, post, fort, arsenal, yard, station, or installation, for any purpose prohibited by law or lawful regulation; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever reenters or is found within any such reservation, post, fort, arsenal, yard, station, or installation, after having been removed therefrom or ordered not to reenter by any officer or person in command or charge thereof—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1383.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title V, § 501(e)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1258</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1384.</num>
<heading> Prostitution near military and naval establishments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within such reasonable distance of any military or naval camp, station, fort, post, yard, base, cantonment, training or mobilization place as the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy, the Secretary of the Air Force, or any two or all of them shall determine to be needful to the efficiency, health, and welfare of the Army, the Navy, or the Air Force, and shall designate and publish in general orders or bulletins, whoever engages in prostitution or aids or abets prostitution or procures or solicits for purposes of prostitution, or keeps or sets up a house of ill fame, brothel, or bawdy house, or receives any person for purposes of lewdness, assignation, or prostitution into any vehicle, conveyance, place, structure, or building, or permits any person to remain for the purpose of lewdness, assignation, or prostitution in any vehicle, conveyance, place, structure, or building or leases or rents or contracts to lease or rent any vehicle, conveyance, place, structure or building, or part thereof, knowing or with good reason to know that it is intended to be used for any of the purposes herein prohibited shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Secretaries of the Army, Navy, and Air Force and the Federal Security Administrator shall take such steps as they deem necessary to suppress and prevent such violations thereof, and shall accept the cooperation of the authorities of States and their counties, districts, and other political subdivisions in carrying out the purpose of this section.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not be construed as conferring on the personnel of the Departments of the Army, Navy, or Air Force or the Federal Security Agency any authority to make criminal investigations, searches, seizures, or arrests of civilians charged with violations of this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 35</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 94</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1385.</num>
<heading> Use of Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, and Space Force as posse comitatus</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, except in cases and under circumstances expressly authorized by the Constitution or Act of Congress, willfully uses any part of the Army, the Navy, the Marine Corps, the Air Force, or the Space Force as a posse comitatus or otherwise to execute the laws shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 18(a)</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 626</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 17(d)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 144</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1045(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1386.</num>
<heading> Keys and keyways used in security applications by the Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whoever steals, purloins, embezzles, or obtains by false pretense any lock or key to any lock, knowing that such lock or key has been adopted by any part of the Department of Defense, including all Department of Defense agencies, military departments, and agencies thereof, for use in protecting conventional arms, ammunition or explosives, special weapons, and classified information or classified equipment shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> knowingly and unlawfully makes, forges, or counterfeits any key, knowing that such key has been adopted by any part of the Department of Defense, including all Department of Defense agencies, military departments, and agencies thereof, for use in protecting conventional arms, ammunition or explosives, special weapons, and classified information or classified equipment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> knowing that any lock or key has been adopted by any part of the Department of Defense, including all Department of Defense agencies, military departments, and agencies thereof, for use in protecting conventional arms, ammunition or explosives, special weapons, and classified information or classified equipment, possesses any such lock or key with the intent to unlawfully or improperly use, sell, or otherwise dispose of such lock or key or cause the same to be unlawfully or improperly used, sold, or otherwise disposed of,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whoever, being engaged as a contractor or otherwise in the manufacture of any lock or key knowing that such lock or key has been adopted by any part of the Department of Defense, including all Department of Defense agencies, military departments, and agencies thereof, for use in protecting conventional arms, ammunition or explosives, special weapons, and classified information or classified equipment, delivers any such finished or unfinished lock or any such key to any person not duly authorized by the Secretary of Defense or his designated representative to receive the same, unless the person receiving it is the contractor for furnishing the same or engaged in the manufacture thereof in the manner authorized by the contract, or the agent of such manufacturer, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever commits an offense under subsection (a) shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “key” means any key, keyblank, or keyway adopted by any part of the Department of Defense, including all Department of Defense agencies, military departments, and agencies thereof, for use in protecting conventional arms, ammunition or explosives, special weapons, and classified information or classified equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1090(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1387.</num>
<heading> Demonstrations at cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration and at Arlington National Cemetery</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever violates <ref>section 2413 of title 38</ref> shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–228, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-05-29">May 29, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1388.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on disruptions of funerals of members or former members of the Armed Forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For any funeral of a member or former member of the Armed Forces that is not located at a cemetery under the control of the National Cemetery Administration or part of Arlington National Cemetery, it shall be unlawful for any person to engage in an activity during the period beginning 120 minutes before and ending 120 minutes after such funeral, any part of which activity—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> takes place within the boundaries of the location of such funeral or takes place within 300 feet of the point of the intersection between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the boundary of the location of such funeral; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a road, pathway, or other route of ingress to or egress from the location of such funeral; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes any individual willfully making or assisting in the making of any noise or diversion—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is not part of such funeral and that disturbs or tends to disturb the peace or good order of such funeral; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with the intent of disturbing the peace or good order of such funeral;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is within 500 feet of the boundary of the location of such funeral; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes any individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> willfully and without proper authorization impeding or tending to impede the access to or egress from such location; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with the intent to impede the access to or egress from such location; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> is on or near the boundary of the residence, home, or domicile of any surviving member of the deceased person’s immediate family and includes any individual willfully making or assisting in the making of any noise or diversion—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that disturbs or tends to disturb the peace of the persons located at such location; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with the intent of disturbing such peace.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who violates subsection (a) shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Civil Remedies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">District courts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to prevent and restrain violations of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for the adjudication of any claims for relief under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attorney general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General may institute proceedings under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any person, including a surviving member of the deceased person’s immediate family, who suffers injury as a result of conduct that violates this section may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sue therefor in any appropriate United States district court or in any court of competent jurisdiction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recover damages as provided in subsection (d) and the cost of the suit, including reasonable attorneys’ fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Estoppel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A final judgment or decree rendered in favor of the United States in any criminal proceeding brought by the United States under this section shall estop the defendant from denying the essential allegations of the criminal offense in any subsequent civil proceeding brought by a person or by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Actual and Statutory Damages.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to any penalty imposed under subsection (b), a violator of this section is liable in an action under subsection (c) for actual or statutory damages as provided in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions by private persons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person bringing an action under subsection (c)(3) may elect, at any time before final judgment is rendered, to recover the actual damages suffered by him or her as a result of the violation or, instead of actual damages, an award of statutory damages for each violation involved in the action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions by attorney general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any action under subsection (c)(2), the Attorney General is entitled to recover an award of statutory damages for each violation involved in the action notwithstanding any recovery under subsection (c)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutory damages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A court may award, as the court considers just, statutory damages in a sum of not less than $25,000 or more than $50,000 per violation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rebuttable Presumption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It shall be a rebuttable presumption that the violation was committed willfully for purposes of determining relief under this section if the violator, or a person acting in concert with the violator, did not have reasonable grounds to believe, either from the attention or publicity sought by the violator or other circumstance, that the conduct of such violator or person would not disturb or tend to disturb the peace or good order of such funeral, impede or tend to impede the access to or egress from such funeral, or disturb or tend to disturb the peace of any surviving member of the deceased person’s immediate family who may be found on or near the residence, home, or domicile of the deceased person’s immediate family on the date of the service or ceremony.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Armed Forces” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 101 of title 10</ref> and includes members and former members of the National Guard who were employed in the service of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “immediate family” means, with respect to a person, the immediate family members of such person, as such term is defined in <ref>section 115 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–464, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3480</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–154, title VI, § 601(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1389.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on attacks on United States servicemen on account of service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever knowingly assaults or batters a United States serviceman or an immediate family member of a United States serviceman, or who knowingly destroys or injures the property of such serviceman or immediate family member, on account of the military service of that serviceman or status of that individual as a United States serviceman, or who attempts or conspires to do so, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a simple assault, or destruction or injury to property in which the damage or attempted damage to such property is not more than $500, be fined under this title in an amount not less than $500 nor more than $10,000 and imprisoned not more than 2 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of destruction or injury to property in which the damage or attempted damage to such property is more than $500, be fined under this title in an amount not less than $1000 nor more than $100,000 and imprisoned not more than 5 years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of a battery, or an assault resulting in bodily injury, be fined under this title in an amount not less than $2500 and imprisoned not less than 6 months nor more than 10 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not apply to conduct by a person who is subject to the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Armed Forces” has the meaning given that term in section 1388;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “immediate family member” has the meaning given that term in section 115; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “United States serviceman”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a member of the Armed Forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes a former member of the Armed Forces during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the discharge from the Armed Forces of that member of the Armed Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. E, § 4712(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>