<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 301—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4001.</num>
<heading> Limitation on detention; control of prisons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No citizen shall be imprisoned or otherwise detained by the United States except pursuant to an Act of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The control and management of Federal penal and correctional institutions, except military or naval institutions, shall be vested in the Attorney General, who shall promulgate rules for the government thereof, and appoint all necessary officers and employees in accordance with the civil-service laws, the Classification Act, as amended, and the applicable regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may establish and conduct industries, farms, and other activities and classify the inmates; and provide for their proper government, discipline, treatment, care, rehabilitation, and reformation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 847</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–128, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1971-09-25">Sept. 25, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 347</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4002.</num>
<heading> Federal prisoners in State institutions; employment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of providing suitable quarters for the safekeeping, care, and subsistence of all persons held under authority of any enactment of Congress, the Attorney General may contract, for a period not exceeding three years, with the proper authorities of any State, Territory, or political subdivision thereof, for the imprisonment, subsistence, care, and proper employment of such persons.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such Federal prisoners shall be employed only in the manufacture of articles for, the production of supplies for, the construction of public works for, and the maintenance and care of the institutions of, the State or political subdivision in which they are imprisoned.</p>
<p class="indent0">The rates to be paid for the care and custody of said persons shall take into consideration the character of the quarters furnished, sanitary conditions, and quality of subsistence and may be such as will permit and encourage the proper authorities to provide reasonably decent, sanitary, and healthful quarters and subsistence for such persons.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 847</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–624, § 8</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3463</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4003.</num>
<heading> Federal institutions in States without appropriate facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If by reason of the refusal or inability of the authorities having control of any jail, workhouse, penal, correctional, or other suitable institution of any State or Territory, or political subdivision thereof, to enter into a contract for the imprisonment, subsistence, care, or proper employment of United States prisoners, or if there are no suitable or sufficient facilities available at reasonable cost, the Attorney General may select a site either within or convenient to the State, Territory, or judicial district concerned and cause to be erected thereon a house of detention, workhouse, jail, prison-industries project, or camp, or other place of confinement, which shall be used for the detention of persons held under authority of any Act of Congress, and of such other persons as in the opinion of the Attorney General are proper subjects for confinement in such institutions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4004.</num>
<heading> Oaths and acknowledgments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The wardens and superintendents, associate wardens and superintendents, chief clerks, and record clerks, of Federal penal or correctional institutions, may administer oaths to and take acknowledgments of officers, employees, and inmates of such institutions, but shall not demand or accept any fee or compensation therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref>July 7, 1955, ch. 282</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 223</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4005.</num>
<heading> Medical relief; expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon request of the Attorney General and to the extent consistent with the Assisted Suicide Funding Restriction Act of 1997, the Federal Security Administrator shall detail regular and reserve commissioned officers of the Public Health Service, pharmacists, acting assistant surgeons, and other employees of the Public Health Service to the Department of Justice for the purpose of supervising and furnishing medical, psychiatric, and other technical and scientific services to the Federal penal and correctional institutions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The compensation, allowances, and expenses of the personnel detailed under this section may be paid from applicable appropriations of the Public Health Service in accordance with the law and regulations governing the personnel of the Public Health Service, such appropriations to be reimbursed from applicable appropriations of the Department of Justice; or the Attorney General may make allotments of funds and transfer of credit to the Public Health Service in such amounts as are available and necessary, for payment of compensation, allowances, and expenses of personnel so detailed, in accordance with the law and regulations governing the personnel of the Public Health Service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–12, § 9(k)</ref>, <date date="1997-04-30">Apr. 30, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 28</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4006.</num>
<heading> Subsistence for prisoners</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as applicable, shall allow and pay only the reasonable and actual cost of the subsistence of prisoners in the custody of any marshal of the United States, and shall prescribe such regulations for the government of the marshals as will enable him to determine the actual and reasonable expenses incurred.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Health Care Items and Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Payment for costs incurred for the provision of health care items and services for individuals in the custody of the United States Marshals Service, the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Department of Homeland Security shall be the amount billed, not to exceed the amount that would be paid for the provision of similar health care items and services under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full and final payment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any payment for a health care item or service made pursuant to this subsection, shall be deemed to be full and final payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(1) [title I, § 114]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–20; <ref>Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title VI, § 626]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–108; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1157</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3114</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4007.</num>
<heading> Expenses of prisoners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The expenses attendant upon the confinement of persons arrested or committed under the laws of the United States, as well as upon the execution of any sentence of a court thereof respecting them, shall be paid out of the Treasury of the United States in the manner provided by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4008.</num>
<heading> Transportation expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Prisoners shall be transported by agents designated by the Attorney General or his authorized representative.</p>
<p class="indent0">The reasonable expense of transportation, necessary subsistence, and hire and transportation of guards and agents shall be paid by the Attorney General from such appropriation for the Department of Justice as he shall direct.</p>
<p class="indent0">Upon conviction by a consular court or court martial the prisoner shall be transported from the court to the place of confinement by agents of the Department of State, the Army, Navy, or Air Force, as the case may be, the expense to be paid out of the Treasury of the United States in the manner provided by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 61</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 98</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4009.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for sites and buildings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may authorize the use of a sum not to exceed $100,000 in each instance, payable from any unexpended balance of the appropriation “Support of United States prisoners” for the purpose of leasing or acquiring a site, preparation of plans, and erection of necessary buildings under <ref>section 4003 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">If in any instance it shall be impossible or impracticable to secure a proper site and erect the necessary buildings within the above limitation the Attorney General may authorize the use of a sum not to exceed $10,000 in each instance, payable from any unexpended balance of the appropriation “Support of United States prisoners” for the purpose of securing options and making preliminary surveys or sketches.</p>
<p class="indent0">Upon selection of an appropriate site the Attorney General shall submit to Congress an estimate of the cost of purchasing same and of remodeling, constructing, and equipping the necessary buildings thereon.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 849</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4010.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of additional land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may, when authorized by law, acquire land adjacent to or in the vicinity of a Federal penal or correctional institution if he considers the additional land essential to the protection of the health or safety of the inmates of the institution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(f)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4011.</num>
<heading> Disposition of cash collections for meals, laundry, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Collections in cash for meals, laundry, barber service, uniform equipment, and other items for which payment is made originally from appropriations for the maintenance and operation of Federal penal and correctional institutions, may be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the appropriation currently available for those items when the collection is made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 3(f)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 610</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4012.</num>
<heading> Summary seizure and forfeiture of prison contraband</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer or employee of the Bureau of Prisons may, pursuant to rules and regulations of the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, summarily seize any object introduced into a Federal penal or correctional facility or possessed by an inmate of such a facility in violation of a rule, regulation or order promulgated by the Director, and such object shall be forfeited to the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1109(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4013.</num>
<heading> Support of United States prisoners in non-Federal institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General, in support of United States prisoners in non-Federal institutions, is authorized to make payments from funds appropriated for Federal prisoner detention for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> necessary clothing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> medical care and necessary guard hire; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the housing, care, and security of persons held in custody of a United States marshal pursuant to Federal law under agreements with State or local units of government or contracts with private entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General, in support of Federal prisoner detainees in non-Federal institutions, is authorized to make payments, from funds appropriated for State and local law enforcement assistance, for entering into contracts or cooperative agreements with any State, territory, or political subdivision thereof, for the necessary construction, physical renovation, acquisition of equipment, supplies, or materials required to establish acceptable conditions of confinement and detention services in any State or local jurisdiction which agrees to provide guaranteed bed space for Federal detainees within that correctional system, in accordance with regulations which are issued by the Attorney General and are comparable to the regulations issued under <ref>section 4006 of this title</ref>, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> amounts made available for purposes of this paragraph shall not exceed the average per-inmate cost of constructing similar confinement facilities for the Federal prison population,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the availability of such federally assisted facility shall be assured for housing Federal prisoners, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the per diem rate charged for housing such Federal prisoners shall not exceed allowable costs or other conditions specified in the contract or cooperative agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The United States Marshals Service may designate districts that need additional support from private detention entities under subsection (a)(3) based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of Federal detainees in the district; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the availability of appropriate Federal, State, and local government detention facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In order to be eligible for a contract for the housing, care, and security of persons held in custody of the United States Marshals pursuant to Federal law and funding under subsection (a)(3), a private entity shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be located in a district that has been designated as needing additional Federal detention facilities pursuant to paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meet the standards of the American Correctional Association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> comply with all applicable State and local laws and regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> have approved fire, security, escape, and riot plans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> comply with any other regulations that the Marshals Service deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States Marshals Service shall provide an opportunity for public comment on a contract under subsection (a)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Health Care Fees For Federal Prisoners in Non-Federal Institutions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding amounts paid under subsection (a)(3), a State or local government may assess and collect a reasonable fee from the trust fund account (or institutional equivalent) of a Federal prisoner for health care services, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the prisoner is confined in a non-Federal institution pursuant to an agreement between the Federal Government and the State or local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the fee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is authorized under State law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not exceed the amount collected from State or local prisoners for the same services; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the services—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are provided within or outside of the institution by a person who is licensed or certified under State law to provide health care services and who is operating within the scope of such license;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> constitute a health care visit within the meaning of <ref>section 4048(a)(4) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> are not preventative health care services, emergency services, prenatal care, diagnosis or treatment of chronic infectious diseases, mental health care, or substance abuse treatment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No refusal of treatment for financial reasons</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to permit any refusal of treatment to a prisoner on the basis that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the account of the prisoner is insolvent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the prisoner is otherwise unable to pay a fee assessed under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to prisoners of law</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each person who is or becomes a prisoner shall be provided with written and oral notices of the provisions of this subsection and the applicability of this subsection to the prisoner. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, a fee under this section may not be assessed against, or collected from, such person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> until the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which each prisoner in the prison system is provided with such notices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for services provided before the expiration of such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to prisoners of state or local implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The implementation of this subsection by the State or local government, and any amendment to that implementation, shall not take effect until the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which each prisoner in the prison system is provided with written and oral notices of the provisions of that implementation (or amendment, as the case may be). A fee under this subsection may not be assessed against, or collected from, a prisoner pursuant to such implementation (or amendments, as the case may be) for services provided before the expiration of such period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice before public comment period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before the beginning of any period a proposed implementation under this subsection is open to public comment, written and oral notice of the provisions of that proposed implementation shall be provided to groups that advocate on behalf of Federal prisoners and to each prisoner subject to such proposed implementation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comprehensive hiv/aids services required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any State or local government assessing or collecting a fee under this subsection shall provide comprehensive coverage for services relating to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) to each Federal prisoner in the custody of such State or local government when medically appropriate. The State or local government may not assess or collect a fee under this subsection for providing such coverage.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7608(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4516</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XVII, § 1701</ref>, title XXXV, § 3599, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4843</ref>, 4931; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330011</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2145</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–294, § 3</ref>, <date date="2000-10-12">Oct. 12, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1040</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title III, § 302(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1781</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4014.</num>
<heading> Testing for human immunodeficiency virus</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall cause each individual convicted of a Federal offense who is sentenced to incarceration for a period of 6 months or more to be tested for the presence of the human immunodeficiency virus, as appropriate, after the commencement of that incarceration, if such individual is determined to be at risk for infection with such virus in accordance with the guidelines issued by the Bureau of Prisons relating to infectious disease management.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If the Attorney General has a well-founded reason to believe that a person sentenced to a term of imprisonment for a Federal offense, or ordered detained before trial under section 3142(e), may have intentionally or unintentionally transmitted the human immunodeficiency virus to any officer or employee of the United States, or to any person lawfully present in a correctional facility who is not incarcerated there, the Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> cause the person who may have transmitted the virus to be tested promptly for the presence of such virus and communicate the test results to the person tested; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consistent with the guidelines issued by the Bureau of Prisons relating to infectious disease management, inform any person (in, as appropriate, confidential consultation with the person’s physician) who may have been exposed to such virus, of the potential risk involved and, if warranted by the circumstances, that prophylactic or other treatment should be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the results of a test under subsection (a) or (b) indicate the presence of the human immunodeficiency virus, the Attorney General shall provide appropriate access for counselling, health care, and support services to the affected officer, employee, or other person, and to the person tested.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The results of a test under this section are inadmissible against the person tested in any Federal or State civil or criminal case or proceeding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Attorney General shall issue rules to implement this section. Such rules shall require that the results of any test are communicated only to the person tested, and, if the results of the test indicate the presence of the virus, to correctional facility personnel consistent with guidelines issued by the Bureau of Prisons. Such rules shall also provide for procedures designed to protect the privacy of a person requesting that the test be performed and the privacy of the person tested.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–370, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-12">Nov. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>