<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 25—</num>
<heading>COUNTERFEITING AND FORGERY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 470.</num>
<heading> Counterfeit acts committed outside the United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person who, outside the United States, engages in the act of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> making, dealing, or possessing any counterfeit obligation or other security of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> making, dealing, or possessing any plate, stone, analog, digital, or electronic image, or other thing, or any part thereof, used to counterfeit such obligation or security,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if such act would constitute a violation of section 471, 473, or 474 if committed within the United States, shall be punished as is provided for the like offense within the United States.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XII, § 120003(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2021</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 340</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 471.</num>
<heading> Obligations or securities of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, falsely makes, forges, counterfeits, or alters any obligation or other security of the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 340</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 472.</num>
<heading> Uttering counterfeit obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, passes, utters, publishes, or sells, or attempts to pass, utter, publish, or sell, or with like intent brings into the United States or keeps in possession or conceals any falsely made, forged, counterfeited, or altered obligation or other security of the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 340</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 473.</num>
<heading> Dealing in counterfeit obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever buys, sells, exchanges, transfers, receives, or delivers any false, forged, counterfeited, or altered obligation or other security of the United States, with the intent that the same be passed, published, or used as true and genuine, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(d)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 340</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 474.</num>
<heading> Plates, stones, or analog, digital, or electronic images for counterfeiting obligations or securities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, having control, custody, or possession of any plate, stone, or other thing, or any part thereof, from which has been printed, or which may be prepared by direction of the Secretary of the Treasury for the purpose of printing, any obligation or other security of the United States, uses such plate, stone, or other thing, or any part thereof, or knowingly suffers the same to be used for the purpose of printing any such or similar obligation or other security, or any part thereof, except as may be printed for the use of the United States by order of the proper officer thereof; or<p class="indent0">Whoever makes or executes any plate, stone, or other thing in the likeness of any plate designated for the printing of such obligation or other security; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, makes, executes, acquires, scans, captures, records, receives, transmits, reproduces, sells, or has in such person’s control, custody, or possession, an analog, digital, or electronic image of any obligation or other security of the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever sells any such plate, stone, or other thing, or brings into the United States any such plate, stone, or other thing, except under the direction of the Secretary of the Treasury or other proper officer, or with any other intent, in either case, than that such plate, stone, or other thing be used for the printing of the obligations or other securities of the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever has in his control, custody, or possession any plate, stone, or other thing in any manner made after or in the similitude of any plate, stone, or other thing, from which any such obligation or other security has been printed, with intent to use such plate, stone, or other thing, or to suffer the same to be used in forging or counterfeiting any such obligation or other security, or any part thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever has in his possession or custody, except under authority from the Secretary of the Treasury or other proper officer, any obligation or other security made or executed, in whole or in part, after the similitude of any obligation or other security issued under the authority of the United States, with intent to sell or otherwise use the same; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever prints, photographs, or in any other manner makes or executes any engraving, photograph, print, or impression in the likeness of any such obligation or other security, or any part thereof, or sells any such engraving, photograph, print, or impression, except to the United States, or brings into the United States, any such engraving, photograph, print, or impression, except by direction of some proper officer of the United States—</p>
<p class="indent0">Is guilty of a class B felony.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “analog, digital, or electronic image” includes any analog, digital, or electronic method used for the making, execution, acquisition, scanning, capturing, recording, retrieval, transmission, or reproduction of any obligation or security, unless such use is authorized by the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary shall establish a system (pursuant to section 504) to ensure that the legitimate use of such electronic methods and retention of such reproductions by businesses, hobbyists, press and others shall not be unduly restricted.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1552</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4070</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 648(a)]</ref>, title II, § 2603(a), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–367, 3009–470; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(e)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 340</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 474A.</num>
<heading> Deterrents to counterfeiting of obligations and securities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever has in his control or possession, after a distinctive paper has been adopted by the Secretary of the Treasury for the obligations and other securities of the United States, any similar paper adapted to the making of any such obligation or other security, except under the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury, is guilty of a class B felony.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever has in his control or possession, after a distinctive counterfeit deterrent has been adopted by the Secretary of the Treasury for the obligations and other securities of the United States by publication in the Federal Register, any essentially identical feature or device adapted to the making of any such obligation or security, except under the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury, is guilty of a class B felony.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “distinctive paper” includes any distinctive medium of which currency is made, whether of wood pulp, rag, plastic substrate, or other natural or artificial fibers or materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “distinctive counterfeit deterrent” includes any ink, watermark, seal, security thread, optically variable device, or other feature or device;</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in which the United States has an exclusive property interest; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is not otherwise in commercial use or in the public domain and which the Secretary designates as being necessary in preventing the counterfeiting of obligations or other securities of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1553(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4070</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 648(a)]</ref>, title II, § 2603(a), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–367, 3009–470.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 475.</num>
<heading> Imitating obligations or securities; advertisements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever designs, engraves, prints, makes, or executes, or utters, issues, distributes, circulates, or uses any business or professional card, notice, placard, circular, handbill, or advertisement in the likeness or similitude of any obligation or security of the United States issued under or authorized by any Act of Congress or writes, prints, or otherwise impresses upon or attaches to any such instrument, obligation, or security, or any coin of the United States, any business or professional card, notice, or advertisement, or any notice or advertisement whatever, shall be fined under this title. Nothing in this section applies to evidence of postage payment approved by the United States Postal Service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>July 16, 1951, ch. 226, § 2</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1192</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3129</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 476.</num>
<heading> Taking impressions of tools used for obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without authority from the United States, takes, procures, or makes an impression, stamp, analog, digital, or electronic image, or imprint of, from or by the use of any tool, implement, instrument, or thing used or fitted or intended to be used in printing, stamping, or impressing, or in making other tools, implements, instruments, or things to be used or fitted or intended to be used in printing, stamping, or impressing any obligation or other security of the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 25 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(f)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 477.</num>
<heading> Possessing or selling impressions of tools used for obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, possesses, keeps, safeguards, or controls, without authority from the United States, any imprint, stamp, analog, digital, or electronic image, or impression, taken or made upon any substance or material whatsoever, of any tool, implement, instrument or thing, used, fitted or intended to be used, for any of the purposes mentioned in <ref>section 476 of this title</ref>; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, sells, gives, or delivers any such imprint, stamp, analog, digital, or electronic image, or impression to any other person—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 25 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(g)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 478.</num>
<heading> Foreign obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States, with intent to defraud, falsely makes, alters, forges, or counterfeits any bond, certificate, obligation, or other security of any foreign government, purporting to be or in imitation of any such security issued under the authority of such foreign government, or any treasury note, bill, or promise to pay, lawfully issued by such foreign government and intended to circulate as money, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 375(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 479.</num>
<heading> Uttering counterfeit foreign obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States, knowingly and with intent to defraud, utters, passes, or puts off, in payment or negotiation, any false, forged, or counterfeited bond, certificate, obligation, security, treasury note, bill, or promise to pay, mentioned in <ref>section 478 of this title</ref>, whether or not the same was made, altered, forged, or counterfeited within the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(J)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 375(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 480.</num>
<heading> Possessing counterfeit foreign obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States, knowingly and with intent to defraud, possesses or delivers any false, forged, or counterfeit bond, certificate, obligation, security, treasury note, bill, promise to pay, bank note, or bill issued by a bank or corporation of any foreign country, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 375(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 481.</num>
<heading> Plates, stones, or analog, digital, or electronic images for counterfeiting foreign obligations or securities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States except by lawful authority, controls, holds, or possesses any plate, stone, or other thing, or any part thereof, from which has been printed or may be printed any counterfeit note, bond, obligation, or other security, in whole or in part, of any foreign government, bank, or corporation, or uses such plate, stone, or other thing, or knowingly permits or suffers the same to be used in counterfeiting such foreign obligations, or any part thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, except by lawful authority, makes or engraves any plate, stone, or other thing in the likeness or similitude of any plate, stone, or other thing designated for the printing of the genuine issues of the obligations of any foreign government, bank, or corporation; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, makes, executes, acquires, scans, captures, records, receives, transmits, reproduces, sells, or has in such person’s control, custody, or possession, an analog, digital, or electronic image of any bond, certificate, obligation, or other security of any foreign government, or of any treasury note, bill, or promise to pay, lawfully issued by such foreign government and intended to circulate as money; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, except by lawful authority, prints, photographs, or makes, executes, or sells any engraving, photograph, print, or impression in the likeness of any genuine note, bond, obligation, or other security, or any part thereof, of any foreign government, bank, or corporation; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever brings into the United States any counterfeit plate, stone, or other thing, engraving, photograph, print, or other impressions of the notes, bonds, obligations, or other securities of any foreign government, bank, or corporation—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 25 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 375(d)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 482.</num>
<heading> Foreign bank notes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States, with intent to defraud, falsely makes, alters, forges, or counterfeits any bank note or bill issued by a bank or corporation of any foreign country, and intended by the law or usage of such foreign country to circulate as money, such bank or corporation being authorized by the laws of such country, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 375(e)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 342</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 483.</num>
<heading> Uttering counterfeit foreign bank notes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States, utters, passes, puts off, or tenders in payment, with intent to defraud, any such false, forged, altered, or counterfeited bank note or bill, mentioned in <ref>section 482 of this title</ref>, knowing the same to be so false, forged, altered, and counterfeited, whether or not the same was made, forged, altered, or counterfeited within the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 375(f)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 342</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 484.</num>
<heading> Connecting parts of different notes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever so places or connects together different parts of two or more notes, bills, or other genuine instruments issued under the authority of the United States, or by any foreign government, or corporation, as to produce one instrument, with intent to defraud, shall be guilty of forgery in the same manner as if the parts so put together were falsely made or forged, and shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(h)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 485.</num>
<heading> Coins or bars</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, forges, or counterfeits any coin or bar in resemblance or similitude of any coin of a denomination higher than 5 cents or any gold or silver bar coined or stamped at any mint or assay office of the United States, or in resemblance or similitude of any foreign gold or silver coin current in the United States or in actual use and circulation as money within the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever passes, utters, publishes, sells, possesses, or brings into the United States any false, forged, or counterfeit coin or bar, knowing the same to be false, forged, or counterfeit, with intent to defraud any body politic or corporate, or any person, or attempts the commission of any offense described in this paragraph—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than fifteen years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–81, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-23">July 23, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 257</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 486.</num>
<heading> Uttering coins of gold, silver or other metal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, except as authorized by law, makes or utters or passes, or attempts to utter or pass, any coins of gold or silver or other metal, or alloys of metals, intended for use as current money, whether in the resemblance of coins of the United States or of foreign countries, or of original design, shall be fined under this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002042">1</ref> or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 487.</num>
<heading> Making or possessing counterfeit dies for coins</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without lawful authority, makes any die, hub, or mold, or any part thereof, either of steel or plaster, or any other substance, in likeness or similitude, as to the design or the inscription thereon, of any die, hub, or mold designated for the coining or making of any of the genuine gold, silver, nickel, bronze, copper, or other coins coined at the mints of the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without lawful authority, possesses any such die, hub, or mold, or any part thereof, or permits the same to be used for or in aid of the counterfeiting of any such coins of the United States—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than fifteen years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 488.</num>
<heading> Making or possessing counterfeit dies for foreign coins</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States, without lawful authority, makes any die, hub, or mold, or any part thereof, either of steel or of plaster, or of any other substance, in the likeness or similitude, as to the design or the inscription thereon, of any die, hub, or mold designated for the coining of the genuine coin of any foreign government; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without lawful authority, possesses any such die, hub, or mold, or any part thereof, or conceals, or knowingly suffers the same to be used for the counterfeiting of any foreign coin—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 489.</num>
<heading> Making or possessing likeness of coins</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the United States, makes or brings therein from any foreign country, or possesses with intent to sell, give away, or in any other manner uses the same, except under authority of the Secretary of the Treasury or other proper officer of the United States, any token, disk, or device in the likeness or similitude as to design, color, or the inscription thereon of any of the coins of the United States or of any foreign country issued as money, either under the authority of the United States or under the authority of any foreign government shall be fined under this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>July 16, 1951, ch. 226, § 3</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 490.</num>
<heading> Minor coins</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, forges, or counterfeits any coin in the resemblance or similitude of any of the one-cent and 5-cent coins minted at the mints of the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever passes, utters, publishes, or sells, or brings into the United States, or possesses any such false, forged, or counterfeited coin, with intent to defraud any person, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–216, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-02-14">Feb. 14, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 491.</num>
<heading> Tokens or paper used as money</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, being 18 years of age or over, not lawfully authorized, makes, issues, or passes any coin, card, token, or device in metal, or its compounds, intended to be used as money, or whoever, being 18 years of age or over, with intent to defraud, makes, utters, inserts, or uses any card, token, slug, disk, device, paper, or other thing similar in size and shape to any of the lawful coins or other currency of the United States or any coin or other currency not legal tender in the United States, to procure anything of value, or the use or enjoyment of any property or service from any automatic merchandise vending machine, postage-stamp machine, turnstile, fare box, coinbox telephone, parking meter or other lawful receptacle, depository, or contrivance designed to receive or to be operated by lawful coins or other currency of the United States, shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever manufactures, sells, offers, or advertises for sale, or exposes or keeps with intent to furnish or sell any token, slug, disk, device, paper, or other thing similar in size and shape to any of the lawful coins or other currency of the United States, or any token, disk, paper, or other device issued or authorized in connection with rationing or food and fiber distribution by any agency of the United States, with knowledge or reason to believe that such tokens, slugs, disks, devices, papers, or other things are intended to be used unlawfully or fraudulently to procure anything of value, or the use or enjoyment of any property or service from any automatic merchandise vending machine, postage-stamp machine, turnstile, fare box, coinbox telephone, parking meter, or other lawful receptacle, depository, or contrivance designed to receive or to be operated by lawful coins or other currency of the United States shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall create immunity from criminal prosecution under the laws of any State, Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, territory, possession, or the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> “Knowledge or reason to believe”, within the meaning of paragraph (b) of this section, may be shown by proof that any law-enforcement officer has, prior to the commission of the offense with which the defendant is charged, informed the defendant that tokens, slugs, disks, or other devices of the kind manufactured, sold, offered, or advertised for sale by him or exposed or kept with intent to furnish or sell, are being used unlawfully or fraudulently to operate certain specified automatic merchandise vending machines, postage-stamp machines, turnstiles, fare boxes, coin-box telephones, parking meters, or other receptacles, depositories, or contrivances, designed to receive or to be operated by lawful coins of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–667</ref>, <date date="1962-09-19">Sept. 19, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 492.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture of counterfeit paraphernalia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All counterfeits of any coins or obligations or other securities of the United States or of any foreign government, or any articles, devices, and other things made, possessed, or used in violation of this chapter or of sections 331–333, 335, 336, 642 or 1720, of this title, or any material or apparatus used or fitted or intended to be used, in the making of such counterfeits, articles, devices or things, found in the possession of any person without authority from the Secretary of the Treasury or other proper officer, shall be forfeited to the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, having the custody or control of any such counterfeits, material, apparatus, articles, devices, or other things, fails or refuses to surrender possession thereof upon request by any authorized agent of the Treasury Department, or other proper officer, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Whenever, except as hereinafter in this section provided, any person interested in any article, device, or other thing, or material or apparatus seized under this section files with the Secretary of the Treasury, before the disposition thereof, a petition for the remission or mitigation of such forfeiture, the Secretary of the Treasury, if he finds that such forfeiture was incurred without willful negligence or without any intention on the part of the petitioner to violate the law, or finds the existence of such mitigating circumstances as to justify the remission or the mitigation of such forfeiture, may remit or mitigate the same upon such terms and conditions as he deems reasonable and just.</p>
<p class="indent0">If the seizure involves offenses other than offenses against the coinage, currency, obligations or securities of the United States or any foreign government, the petition for the remission or mitigation of forfeiture shall be referred to the Attorney General, who may remit or mitigate the forfeiture upon such terms as he deems reasonable and just.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(d)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 493.</num>
<heading> Bonds and obligations of certain lending agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, forges, counterfeits or alters any note, bond, debenture, coupon, obligation, instrument, or writing in imitation or purporting to be in imitation of, a note, bond, debenture, coupon, obligation, instrument or writing, issued by the Reconstruction Finance Corporation, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, National Credit Union Administration, Home Owners’ Loan Corporation, Farm Credit Administration, Department of Housing and Urban Development, or any land bank, intermediate credit bank, insured credit union, bank for cooperatives or any lending, mortgage, insurance, credit or savings and loan corporation or association authorized or acting under the laws of the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever passes, utters, or publishes, or attempts to pass, utter or publish any note, bond, debenture, coupon, obligation, instrument or document knowing the same to have been falsely made, forged, counterfeited or altered, contrary to the provisions of this section, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–353, § 3(p)</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–19, § 24(a)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–468, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-10-19">Oct. 19, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 374(i)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 494.</num>
<heading> Contractors’ bonds, bids, and public records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, alters, forges, or counterfeits any bond, bid, proposal, contract, guarantee, security, official bond, public record, affidavit, or other writing for the purpose of defrauding the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever utters or publishes as true or possesses with intent to utter or publish as true, any such false, forged, altered, or counterfeited writing, knowing the same to be false, forged, altered, or counterfeited; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever transmits to, or presents at any office or to any officer of the United States, any such false, forged, altered, or counterfeited writing, knowing the same to be false, forged, altered, or counterfeited—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 495.</num>
<heading> Contracts, deeds, and powers of attorney</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, alters, forges, or counterfeits any deed, power of attorney, order, certificate, receipt, contract, or other writing, for the purpose of obtaining or receiving, or of enabling any other person, either directly or indirectly, to obtain or receive from the United States or any officers or agents thereof, any sum of money; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever utters or publishes as true any such false, forged, altered, or counterfeited writing, with intent to defraud the United States, knowing the same to be false, altered, forged, or counterfeited; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever transmits to, or presents at any office or officer of the United States, any such writing in support of, or in relation to, any account or claim, with intent to defraud the United States, knowing the same to be false, altered, forged, or counterfeited—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 496.</num>
<heading> Customs matters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever forges, counterfeits or falsely alters any writing made or required to be made in connection with the entry or withdrawal of imports or collection of customs duties, or uses any such writing knowing the same to be forged, counterfeited or falsely altered, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 497.</num>
<heading> Letters patent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, forges, counterfeits, or alters any letters patent granted or purporting to have been granted by the President of the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever passes, utters, or publishes, or attempts to pass, utter, or publish as genuine, any such letters patent, knowing the same to be forged, counterfeited or falsely altered—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 498.</num>
<heading> Military or naval discharge certificates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever forges, counterfeits, or falsely alters any certificate of discharge from the military or naval service of the United States, or uses, unlawfully possesses or exhibits any such certificate, knowing the same to be forged, counterfeited, or falsely altered, shall be fined under this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002043">1</ref> or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 499.</num>
<heading> Military, naval, or official passes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, forges, counterfeits, alters, or tampers with any naval, military, or official pass or permit, issued by or under the authority of the United States, or with intent to defraud uses or possesses any such pass or permit, or personates or falsely represents himself to be or not to be a person to whom such pass or permit has been duly issued, or willfully allows any other person to have or use any such pass or permit, issued for his use alone, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 500.</num>
<heading> Money orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, falsely makes, forges, counterfeits, engraves, or prints any order in imitation of or purporting to be a blank money order or a money order issued by or under the direction of the Post Office Department or Postal Service; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever forges or counterfeits the signature or initials of any person authorized to issue money orders upon or to any money order, postal note, or blank therefor provided or issued by or under the direction of the Post Office Department or Postal Service, or post office department or corporation of any foreign country, and payable in the United States, or any material signature or indorsement thereon, or any material signature to any receipt or certificate of identification thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely alters, in any material respect, any such money order or postal note; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, passes, utters or publishes or attempts to pass, utter or publish any such forged or altered money order or postal note, knowing any material initials, signature, stamp impression or indorsement thereon to be false, forged, or counterfeited, or any material alteration therein to have been falsely made; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever issues any money order or postal note without having previously received or paid the full amount of money payable therefor, with the purpose of fraudulently obtaining or receiving, or fraudulently enabling any other person, either directly or indirectly, to obtain or receive from the United States or Postal Service, or any officer, employee, or agent thereof, any sum of money whatever; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever embezzles, steals, or knowingly converts to his own use or to the use of another, or without authority converts or disposes of any blank money order form provided by or under the authority of the Post Office Department or Postal Service; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives or possesses any such money order form with the intent to convert it to his own use or gain or use or gain of another knowing it to have been embezzled, stolen or converted; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud the United States, the Postal Service, or any person, transmits, presents, or causes to be transmitted or presented, any money order or postal note knowing the same—</p>
<p class="indent1">(1) to contain any forged or counterfeited signature, initials, or any stamped impression, or</p>
<p class="indent1">(2) to contain any material alteration therein unlawfully made, or</p>
<p class="indent1">(3) to have been unlawfully issued without previous payment of the amount required to be paid upon such issue, or</p>
<p class="indent1">(4) to have been stamped without lawful authority; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever steals, or with intent to defraud or without being lawfully authorized by the Post Office Department or Postal Service, receives, possesses, disposes of or attempts to dispose of any postal money order machine or any stamp, tool, or instrument specifically designed to be used in preparing or filling out the blanks on postal money order forms—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002044">1</ref> or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(5)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–430</ref>, <date date="1972-09-23">Sept. 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Postage stamps, postage meter stamps, and postal cards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever forges or counterfeits any postage stamp, postage meter stamp, or any stamp printed upon any stamped envelope, or postal card, or any die, plate, or engraving thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes or prints, or knowingly uses or sells, or possesses with intent to use or sell, any such forged or counterfeited postage stamp, postage meter stamp, stamped envelope, postal card, die, plate, or engraving; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes, or knowingly uses or sells, or possesses with intent to use or sell, any paper bearing the watermark of any stamped envelope, or postal card, or any fraudulent imitation thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes or prints, or authorizes to be made or printed, any postage stamp, postage meter stamp, stamped envelope, or postal card, of the kind authorized and provided by the Post Office Department or by the Postal Service, without the special authority and direction of the Department or Postal Service; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever after such postage stamp, postage meter stamp, stamped envelope, or postal card has been printed, with intent to defraud, delivers the same to any person not authorized by an instrument in writing, duly executed under the hand of the Postmaster General and the seal of the Post Office Department or the Postal Service, to receive it—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(6)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–448, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-14">Oct. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Postage and revenue stamps of foreign governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever forges, or counterfeits, or knowingly utters or uses any forged or counterfeit postage stamp or revenue stamp of any foreign government, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Postmarking stamps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever forges or counterfeits any postmarking stamp, or impression thereof with intent to make it appear that such impression is a genuine postmark, or makes or knowingly uses or sells, or possesses with intent to use or sell, any forged or counterfeited postmarking stamp, die, plate, or engraving, or such impression thereof, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Printing and filming of United States and foreign obligations and securities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the following are permitted:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The printing, publishing, or importation, or the making or importation of the necessary plates for such printing or publishing, of illustrations of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> postage stamps of the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> revenue stamps of the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other obligation or other security of the United States, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> postage stamps, revenue stamps, notes, bonds, and any other obligation or other security of any foreign government, bank, or corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Illustrations permitted by the foregoing provisions of this section shall be made in accordance with the following conditions—</continuation>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all illustrations shall be in black and white, except that illustrations of postage stamps issued by the United States or by any foreign government and stamps issued under the Migratory Bird Hunting Stamp Act of 1934 may be in color;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all illustrations (including illustrations of uncanceled postage stamps in color and illustrations of stamps issued under the Migratory Bird Hunting Stamp Act of 1934 in color) shall be of a size less than three-fourths or more than one and one-half, in linear dimension, of each part of any matter so illustrated which is covered by subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of this paragraph, except that black and white illustrations of postage and revenue stamps issued by the United States or by any foreign government and colored illustrations of canceled postage stamps issued by the United States may be in the exact linear dimension in which the stamps were issued; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the negatives and plates used in making the illustrations shall be destroyed after their final use in accordance with this section.<p class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe regulations to permit color illustrations of such currency of the United States as the Secretary determines may be appropriate for such purposes.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of this section shall not permit the reproduction of illustrations of obligations or other securities, by or through electronic methods used for the acquisition, recording, retrieval, transmission, or reproduction of any obligation or other security, unless such use is authorized by the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary shall establish a system to ensure that the legitimate use of such electronic methods and retention of such reproductions by businesses, hobbyists, press or others shall not be unduly restricted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The making or importation of motion-picture films, microfilms, or slides, for projection upon a screen or for use in telecasting, of postage and revenue stamps and other obligations and securities of the United States, and postage and revenue stamps, notes, bonds, and other obligations or securities of any foreign government, bank, or corporation. No prints or other reproductions shall be made from such films or slides, except for the purposes of paragraph (1), without the permission of the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0">For the purposes of this section the term “postage stamp” includes postage meter stamps.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–921, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–353, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-06-20">June 20, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–448, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-10-14">Oct. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title X, § 1077(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1554</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4071</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(e)</ref>, (f)(3), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Seals of courts; signatures of judges or court officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever forges the signature of any judge, register, or other officer of any court of the United States, or of any Territory thereof, or forges or counterfeits the seal of any such court, or knowingly concurs in using any such forged or counterfeit signature or seal, for the purpose of authenticating any proceeding or document, or tenders in evidence any such proceeding or document with a false or counterfeit signature of any such judge, register, or other officer, or a false or counterfeit seal of the court, subscribed or attached thereto, knowing such signature or seal to be false or counterfeit, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Seals of departments or agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> falsely makes, forges, counterfeits, mutilates, or alters the seal of any department or agency of the United States, or any facsimile thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly uses, affixes, or impresses any such fraudulently made, forged, counterfeited, mutilated, or altered seal or facsimile thereof to or upon any certificate, instrument, commission, document, or paper of any description; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with fraudulent intent, possesses, sells, offers for sale, furnishes, offers to furnish, gives away, offers to give away, transports, offers to transport, imports, or offers to import any such seal or facsimile thereof, knowing the same to have been so falsely made, forged, counterfeited, mutilated, or altered,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (a) or any other provision of law, if a forged, counterfeited, mutilated, or altered seal of a department or agency of the United States, or any facsimile thereof, is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> so forged, counterfeited, mutilated, or altered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> used, affixed, or impressed to or upon any certificate, instrument, commission, document, or paper of any description; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with fraudulent intent, possessed, sold, offered for sale, furnished, offered to furnish, given away, offered to give away, transported, offered to transport, imported, or offered to import,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">with the intent or effect of facilitating an alien’s application for, or receipt of, a Federal benefit to which the alien is not entitled, the penalties which may be imposed for each offense under subsection (a) shall be two times the maximum fine, and 3 times the maximum term of imprisonment, or both, that would otherwise be imposed for an offense under subsection (a).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “Federal benefit” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the issuance of any grant, contract, loan, professional license, or commercial license provided by any agency of the United States or by appropriated funds of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any retirement, welfare, Social Security, health (including treatment of an emergency medical condition in accordance with section 1903(v) of the Social Security Act (19 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002045">1</ref> U.S.C. 1396b(v))), disability, veterans, public housing, education, supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">2</ref> or unemployment benefit, or any similar benefit for which payments or assistance are provided by an agency of the United States or by appropriated funds of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> each instance of forgery, counterfeiting, mutilation, or alteration shall constitute a separate offense under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title V, § 561</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–681</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E)</ref>, (2)(M), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1096</ref>, 1097; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E), (2)(M), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1858.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507.</num>
<heading> Ship’s papers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, forges, counterfeits, or alters any instrument in imitation of or purporting to be, an abstract or official copy or certificate of the documentation of any vessel, or a certificate of ownership, pass, or clearance, granted for any vessel, under the authority of the United States, or a permit, debenture, or other official document granted by any officer of the customs by virtue of his office; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever utters, publishes, or passes, or attempts to utter, publish, or pass, as true, any such false, forged, counterfeited, or falsely altered instrument, abstract, official copy, certificate, pass, clearance, permit, debenture, or other official document herein specified, knowing the same to be false, forged, counterfeited, or falsely altered, with an intent to defraud—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 508.</num>
<heading> Transportation requests of Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever falsely makes, forges, or counterfeits in whole or in part, any form or request in similitude of the form or request provided by the Government for requesting a common carrier to furnish transportation on account of the United States or any department or agency thereof, or knowingly alters any form or request provided by the Government for requesting a common carrier to furnish transportation on account of the United States or any department or agency thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly passes, utters, publishes, or sells, or attempts to pass, utter, publish, or sell, any such false, forged, counterfeited, or altered form or request—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509.</num>
<heading> Possessing and making plates or stones for Government transportation requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, except by lawful authority, controls, holds or possesses any plate, stone, or other thing, or any part thereof, from which has been printed or may be printed any form or request for Government transportation, or uses such plate, stone, or other thing, or knowingly permits or suffers the same to be used in making any such form or request or any part of such a form or request; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes or engraves any plate, stone, or thing, in the likeness of any plate, stone, or thing designated for the printing of the genuine issues of the form or request for Government transportation; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever prints, photographs, or in any other manner makes, executes, or sells any engraving, photograph, print, or impression in the likeness of any genuine form or request for Government transportation, or any part thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever brings into the United States or any place subject to the jurisdiction thereof, any plate, stone, or other thing, or engraving, photograph, print, or other impression of the form or request for Government transportation—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 510.</num>
<heading> Forging endorsements on Treasury checks or bonds or securities of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever, with intent to defraud—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> falsely makes or forges any endorsement or signature on a Treasury check or bond or security of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> passes, utters, or publishes, or attempts to pass, utter, or publish, any Treasury check or bond or security of the United States bearing a falsely made or forged endorsement or signature;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever, with knowledge that such Treasury check or bond or security of the United States is stolen or bears a falsely made or forged endorsement or signature buys, sells, exchanges, receives, delivers, retains, or conceals any such Treasury check or bond or security of the United States shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the face value of the Treasury check or bond or security of the United States or the aggregate face value, if more than one Treasury check or bond or security of the United States, does not exceed $1,000, in any of the above-mentioned offenses, the penalty shall be a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–151, § 115(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-14">Nov. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 976</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3514</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (L), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI</ref>, §§ 602(e), 606(b), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3503</ref>, 3511; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 511.</num>
<heading> Altering or removing motor vehicle identification numbers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly removes, obliterates, tampers with, or alters an identification number for a motor vehicle or motor vehicle part; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with intent to further the theft of a motor vehicle, knowingly removes, obliterates, tampers with, or alters a decal or device affixed to a motor vehicle pursuant to the Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention Act,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) of this section does not apply to a removal, obliteration, tampering, or alteration by a person specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection (unless such person knows that the vehicle or part involved is stolen).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The persons referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a motor vehicle scrap processor or a motor vehicle demolisher who complies with applicable State law with respect to such vehicle or part;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a person who repairs such vehicle or part, if the removal, obliteration, tampering, or alteration is reasonably necessary for the repair;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a person who restores or replaces an identification number for such vehicle or part in accordance with applicable State law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> a person who removes, obliterates, tampers with, or alters a decal or device affixed to a motor vehicle pursuant to the Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention Act, if that person is the owner of the motor vehicle, or is authorized to remove, obliterate, tamper with or alter the decal or device by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the owner or his authorized agent;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> applicable State or local law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> regulations promulgated by the Attorney General to implement the Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention Act.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “identification number” means a number or symbol that is inscribed or affixed for purposes of identification under chapter 301 and part C of subtitle VI of title 49;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “motor vehicle” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 32101 of title 49</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “motor vehicle demolisher” means a person, including any motor vehicle dismantler or motor vehicle recycler, who is engaged in the business of reducing motor vehicles or motor vehicle parts to metallic scrap that is unsuitable for use as either a motor vehicle or a motor vehicle part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “motor vehicle scrap processor” means a person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who is engaged in the business of purchasing motor vehicles or motor vehicle parts for reduction to metallic scrap for recycling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who, from a fixed location, uses machinery to process metallic scrap into prepared grades; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whose principal product is metallic scrap for recycling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but such term does not include any activity of any such person relating to the recycling of a motor vehicle or a motor vehicle part as a used motor vehicle or a used motor vehicle part.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For purposes of subsection (a) of this section, the term “tampers with” includes covering a program decal or device affixed to a motor vehicle pursuant to the Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention Act for the purpose of obstructing its visibility.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–547, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-25">Oct. 25, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2768</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXII, § 220003(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2076</ref>, 2077; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 511A.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title X, § 1002(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2155</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 512.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture of certain motor vehicles and motor vehicle parts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> If an identification number for a motor vehicle or motor vehicle part is removed, obliterated, tampered with, or altered, such vehicle or part shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture to the United States unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a motor vehicle part, such part is attached to a motor vehicle and the owner of such motor vehicle does not know that the identification number has been removed, obliterated, tampered with, or altered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> such motor vehicle or part has a replacement identification number that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is authorized by the Secretary of Transportation under chapter 301 of title 49; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conforms to applicable State law;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such removal, obliteration, tampering, or alteration is caused by collision or fire or is carried out as described in <ref>section 511(b) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such motor vehicle or part is in the possession or control of a motor vehicle scrap processor who does not know that such identification number was removed, obliterated, tampered with, or altered in any manner other than by collision or fire or as described in <ref>section 511(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> All provisions of law relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the seizure and condemnation of vessels, vehicles, merchandise, and baggage for violation of customs laws, and procedures for summary and judicial forfeiture applicable to such violations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the disposition of such vessels, vehicles, merchandise, and baggage or the proceeds from such disposition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the remission or mitigation of such forfeiture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the compromise of claims and the award of compensation to informers with respect to such forfeiture;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall apply to seizures and forfeitures under this section, to the extent that such provisions are not inconsistent with this section. The duties of the collector of customs or any other person with respect to seizure and forfeiture under such provisions shall be performed under this section by such persons as may be designated by the Attorney General.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the terms “identification number”, “motor vehicle”, and “motor vehicle scrap processor” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 511 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–547, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-25">Oct. 25, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2769</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 513.</num>
<heading> Securities of the States and private entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever makes, utters or possesses a counterfeited security of a State or a political subdivision thereof or of an organization, or whoever makes, utters or possesses a forged security of a State or political subdivision thereof or of an organization, with intent to deceive another person, organization, or government shall be fined under this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002047">1</ref> or imprisoned for not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever makes, receives, possesses, sells or otherwise transfers an implement designed for or particularly suited for making a counterfeit or forged security with the intent that it be so used shall be punished by a fine under this title or by imprisonment for not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “counterfeited” means a document that purports to be genuine but is not, because it has been falsely made or manufactured in its entirety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “forged” means a document that purports to be genuine but is not because it has been falsely altered, com­pleted, signed, or endorsed, or contains a false addition thereto or insertion therein, or is a combination of parts of two or more genuine documents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “security” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a note, stock certificate, treasury stock certificate, bond, treasury bond, debenture, certificate of deposit, interest coupon, bill, check, draft, warrant, debit instrument as defined in section 916(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002048">2</ref> of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act, money order, traveler’s check, letter of credit, warehouse receipt, negotiable bill of lading, evidence of indebtedness, certificate of interest in or participation in any profit-sharing agreement, collateral-trust certificate, pre-reorganization certificate of subscription, transferable share, investment contract, voting trust certificate, or certificate of interest in tangible or intangible property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an instrument evidencing ownership of goods, wares, or merchandise;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other written instrument commonly known as a security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a certificate of interest in, certificate of participation in, certificate for, receipt for, or warrant or option or other right to subscribe to or purchase, any of the foregoing; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a blank form of any of the foregoing;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “organization” means a legal entity, other than a government, established or organized for any purpose, and includes a corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, joint stock company, foundation, institution, society, union, or any other association of persons which operates in or the activities of which affect interstate or foreign commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “State” includes a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1105(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2144</ref>, § 511; renumbered § 513, <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 31(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3598</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3515</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330008(1), 330016(2)(C), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2142</ref>, 2148.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 514.</num>
<heading> Fictitious obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever, with the intent to defraud—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> draws, prints, processes, produces, publishes, or otherwise makes, or attempts or causes the same, within the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> passes, utters, presents, offers, brokers, issues, sells, or attempts or causes the same, or with like intent possesses, within the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> utilizes interstate or foreign commerce, including the use of the mails or wire, radio, or other electronic communication, to transmit, transport, ship, move, transfer, or attempts or causes the same, to, from, or through the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">any false or fictitious instrument, document, or other item appearing, representing, purporting, or contriving through scheme or artifice, to be an actual security or other financial instrument issued under the authority of the United States, a foreign government, a State or other political subdivision of the United States, or an organization, shall be guilty of a class B felony.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, any term used in this section that is defined in section 513(c) has the same meaning given such term in section 513(c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The United States Secret Service, in addition to any other agency having such authority, shall have authority to investigate offenses under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 648(b)(1)]</ref>, title II, § 2603(b)(1), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–367, 3009–470.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>