<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11A—</num>
<heading>CHILD SUPPORT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 228.</num>
<heading> Failure to pay legal child support obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> willfully fails to pay a support obligation with respect to a child who resides in another State, if such obligation has remained unpaid for a period longer than 1 year, or is greater than $5,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> travels in interstate or foreign commerce with the intent to evade a support obligation, if such obligation has remained unpaid for a period longer than 1 year, or is greater than $5,000; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> willfully fails to pay a support obligation with respect to a child who resides in another State, if such obligation has remained unpaid for a period longer than 2 years, or is greater than $10,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in subsection (c).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presumption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The existence of a support obligation that was in effect for the time period charged in the indictment or information creates a rebuttable presumption that the obligor has the ability to pay the support obligation for that time period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Punishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The punishment for an offense under this section is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a first offense under subsection (a)(1), a fine under this title, imprisonment for not more than 6 months, or both; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an offense under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a), or a second or subsequent offense under subsection (a)(1), a fine under this title, imprisonment for not more than 2 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mandatory Restitution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon a conviction under this section, the court shall order restitution under section 3663A in an amount equal to the total unpaid support obligation as it exists at the time of sentencing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Venue</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to an offense under this section, an action may be inquired of and prosecuted in a district court of the United States for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the district in which the child who is the subject of the support obligation involved resided during a period during which a person described in subsection (a) (referred to in this subsection as an “obliger”) failed to meet that support obligation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the district in which the obliger resided during a period described in paragraph (1); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other district with jurisdiction otherwise provided for by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 479a</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “State” includes any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “support obligation” means any amount determined under a court order or an order of an administrative process pursuant to the law of a State or of an Indian tribe to be due from a person for the support and maintenance of a child or of a child and the parent with whom the child is living.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–521, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-25">Oct. 25, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3403</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 607</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–187, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-06-24">June 24, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>