<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 209—</num>
<heading>EXTRADITION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3181.</num>
<heading> Scope and limitation of chapter</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The provisions of this chapter relating to the surrender of persons who have committed crimes in foreign countries shall continue in force only during the existence of any treaty of extradition with such foreign government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of this chapter shall be construed to permit, in the exercise of comity, the surrender of persons, other than citizens, nationals, or permanent residents of the United States, who have committed crimes of violence against nationals of the United States in foreign countries without regard to the existence of any treaty of extradition with such foreign government if the Attorney General certifies, in writing, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evidence has been presented by the foreign government that indicates that had the offenses been committed in the United States, they would constitute crimes of violence as defined under <ref>section 16 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the offenses charged are not of a political nature.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “national of the United States” has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title IV, § 443(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3182.</num>
<heading> Fugitives from State or Territory to State, District, or Territory</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the executive authority of any State or Territory demands any person as a fugitive from justice, of the executive authority of any State, District, or Territory to which such person has fled, and produces a copy of an indictment found or an affidavit made before a magistrate of any State or Territory, charging the person demanded with having committed treason, felony, or other crime, certified as authentic by the governor or chief magistrate of the State or Territory from whence the person so charged has fled, the executive authority of the State, District, or Territory to which such person has fled shall cause him to be arrested and secured, and notify the executive authority making such demand, or the agent of such authority appointed to receive the fugitive, and shall cause the fugitive to be delivered to such agent when he shall appear. If no such agent appears within thirty days from the time of the arrest, the prisoner may be discharged.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(f)(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3183.</num>
<heading> Fugitives from State, Territory, or Possession into extraterritorial jurisdiction of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the executive authority of any State, Territory, District, or possession of the United States demands any American citizen or national as a fugitive from justice who has fled to a country in which the United States exercises extraterritorial jurisdiction, and produces a copy of an indictment found or an affidavit made before a magistrate of the demanding jurisdiction, charging the fugitive so demanded with having committed treason, felony, or other offense, certified as authentic by the Governor or chief magistrate of such demanding jurisdiction, or other person authorized to act, the officer or representative of the United States vested with judicial authority to whom the demand has been made shall cause such fugitive to be arrested and secured, and notify the executive authorities making such demand, or the agent of such authority appointed to receive the fugitive, and shall cause the fugitive to be delivered to such agent when he shall appear.</p>
<p class="indent0">If no such agent shall appear within three months from the time of the arrest, the prisoner may be discharged.</p>
<p class="indent0">The agent who receives the fugitive into his custody shall be empowered to transport him to the jurisdiction from which he has fled.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4004(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1812</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3184.</num>
<heading> Fugitives from foreign country to United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever there is a treaty or convention for extradition between the United States and any foreign government, or in cases arising under section 3181(b), any justice or judge of the United States, or any magistrate judge authorized so to do by a court of the United States, or any judge of a court of record of general jurisdiction of any State, may, upon complaint made under oath, charging any person found within his jurisdiction, with having committed within the jurisdiction of any such foreign government any of the crimes provided for by such treaty or convention, or provided for under section 3181(b), issue his warrant for the apprehension of the person so charged, that he may be brought before such justice, judge, or magistrate judge, to the end that the evidence of criminality may be heard and considered. Such complaint may be filed before and such warrant may be issued by a judge or magistrate judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia if the whereabouts within the United States of the person charged are not known or, if there is reason to believe the person will shortly enter the United States. If, on such hearing, he deems the evidence sufficient to sustain the charge under the provisions of the proper treaty or convention, or under section 3181(b), he shall certify the same, together with a copy of all the testimony taken before him, to the Secretary of State, that a warrant may issue upon the requisition of the proper authorities of such foreign government, for the surrender of such person, according to the stipulations of the treaty or convention; and he shall issue his warrant for the commitment of the person so charged to the proper jail, there to remain until such surrender shall be made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7087</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XVI, § 1605</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4843</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title IV, § 443(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3185.</num>
<heading> Fugitives from country under control of United States into the United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever any foreign country or territory, or any part thereof, is occupied by or under the control of the United States, any person who, having violated the criminal laws in force therein by the commission of any of the offenses enumerated below, departs or flees from justice therein to the United States, shall, when found therein, be liable to arrest and detention by the authorities of the United States, and on the written request or requisition of the military governor or other chief executive officer in control of such foreign country or territory shall be returned and surrendered as hereinafter provided to such authorities for trial under the laws in force in the place where such offense was committed.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Murder and assault with intent to commit murder;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Counterfeiting or altering money, or uttering or bringing into circulation counterfeit or altered money;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Counterfeiting certificates or coupons of public indebtedness, bank notes, or other instruments of public credit, and the utterance or circulation of the same;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Forgery or altering and uttering what is forged or altered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Embezzlement or criminal malversation of the public funds, committed by public officers, employees, or depositaries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Larceny or embezzlement of an amount not less than $100 in value;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Robbery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Burglary, defined to be the breaking and entering by nighttime into the house of another person with intent to commit a felony therein;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Breaking and entering the house or building of another, whether in the day or nighttime, with the intent to commit a felony therein;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Entering, or breaking and entering the offices of the Government and public authorities, or the offices of banks, banking houses, savings banks, trust companies, insurance or other companies, with the intent to commit a felony therein;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Perjury or the subornation of perjury;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> A felony under chapter 109A of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Arson;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Piracy by the law of nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Murder, assault with intent to kill, and manslaughter, committed on the high seas, on board a ship owned by or in control of citizens or residents of such foreign country or territory and not under the flag of the United States, or of some other government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Malicious destruction of or attempt to destroy railways, trams, vessels, bridges, dwellings, public edifices, or other buildings, when the act endangers human life.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0">This chapter, so far as applicable, shall govern proceedings authorized by this section. Such proceedings shall be had before a judge of the courts of the United States only, who shall hold such person on evidence establishing probable cause that he is guilty of the offense charged.</continuation>
<continuation class="indent0">No return or surrender shall be made of any person charged with the commission of any offense of a political nature.</continuation>
<continuation class="indent0">If so held, such person shall be returned and surrendered to the authorities in control of such foreign country or territory on the order of the Secretary of State of the United States, and such authorities shall secure to such a person a fair and impartial trial.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 49</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 96</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 87(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–654, § 3(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3663</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3186.</num>
<heading> Secretary of State to surrender fugitive</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State may order the person committed under sections 3184 or 3185 of this title to be delivered to any authorized agent of such foreign government, to be tried for the offense of which charged.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such agent may hold such person in custody, and take him to the territory of such foreign government, pursuant to such treaty.</p>
<p class="indent0">A person so accused who escapes may be retaken in the same manner as any person accused of any offense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3187.</num>
<heading> Provisional arrest and detention within extra­territorial jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisional arrest and detention of a fugitive, under sections 3042 and 3183 of this title, in advance of the presentation of formal proofs, may be obtained by telegraph upon the request of the authority competent to request the surrender of such fugitive addressed to the authority competent to grant such surrender. Such request shall be accompanied by an express statement that a warrant for the fugitive’s arrest has been issued within the jurisdiction of the authority making such request charging the fugitive with the commission of the crime for which his extradition is sought to be obtained.</p>
<p class="indent0">No person shall be held in custody under telegraphic request by virtue of this section for more than ninety days.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3188.</num>
<heading> Time of commitment pending extradition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any person who is committed for rendition to a foreign government to remain until delivered up in pursuance of a requisition, is not so delivered up and conveyed out of the United States within two calendar months after such commitment, over and above the time actually required to convey the prisoner from the jail to which he was committed, by the readiest way, out of the United States, any judge of the United States, or of any State, upon application made to him by or on behalf of the person so committed, and upon proof made to him that reasonable notice of the intention to make such application has been given to the Secretary of State, may order the person so committed to be discharged out of custody, unless sufficient cause is shown to such judge why such discharge ought not to be ordered.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3189.</num>
<heading> Place and character of hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Hearings in cases of extradition under treaty stipulation or convention shall be held on land, publicly, and in a room or office easily accessible to the public.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3190.</num>
<heading> Evidence on hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Depositions, warrants, or other papers or copies thereof offered in evidence upon the hearing of any extradition case shall be received and admitted as evidence on such hearing for all the purposes of such hearing if they shall be properly and legally authenticated so as to entitle them to be received for similar purposes by the tribunals of the foreign country from which the accused party shall have escaped, and the certificate of the principal diplomatic or consular officer of the United States resident in such foreign country shall be proof that the same, so offered, are authenticated in the manner required.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3191.</num>
<heading> Witnesses for indigent fugitives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the hearing of any case under a claim of extradition by a foreign government, upon affidavit being filed by the person charged setting forth that there are witnesses whose evidence is material to his defense, that he cannot safely go to trial without them, what he expects to prove by each of them, and that he is not possessed of sufficient means, and is actually unable to pay the fees of such witnesses, the judge or magistrate judge hearing the matter may order that such witnesses be subpenaed; and the costs incurred by the process, and the fees of witnesses, shall be paid in the same manner as in the case of witnesses subpenaed in behalf of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3192.</num>
<heading> Protection of accused</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any person is delivered by any foreign government to an agent of the United States, for the purpose of being brought within the United States and tried for any offense of which he is duly accused, the President shall have power to take all necessary measures for the transportation and safekeeping of such accused person, and for his security against lawless violence, until the final conclusion of his trial for the offenses specified in the warrant of extradition, and until his final discharge from custody or imprisonment for or on account of such offenses, and for a reasonable time thereafter, and may employ such portion of the land or naval forces of the United States, or of the militia thereof, as may be necessary for the safe-keeping and protection of the accused.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3193.</num>
<heading> Receiving agent’s authority over offenders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A duly appointed agent to receive, in behalf of the United States, the delivery, by a foreign government, of any person accused of crime committed within the United States, and to convey him to the place of his trial, shall have all the powers of a marshal of the United States, in the several districts through which it may be necessary for him to pass with such prisoner, so far as such power is requisite for the prisoner’s safe-keeping.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3194.</num>
<heading> Transportation of fugitive by receiving agent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agent appointed as provided in <ref>section 3182 of this title</ref> who receives the fugitive into his custody is empowered to transport him to the State or Territory from which he has fled.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3195.</num>
<heading> Payment of fees and costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All costs or expenses incurred in any extradition proceeding in apprehending, securing, and transmitting a fugitive shall be paid by the demanding authority.</p>
<p class="indent0">All witness fees and costs of every nature in cases of international extradition, including the fees of the magistrate judge, shall be certified by the judge or magistrate judge before whom the hearing shall take place to the Secretary of State of the United States, and the same shall be paid out of appropriations to defray the expenses of the judiciary or the Department of Justice as the case may be.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall certify to the Secretary of State the amounts to be paid to the United States on account of said fees and costs in extradition cases by the foreign government requesting the extradition, and the Secretary of State shall cause said amounts to be collected and transmitted to the Attorney General for deposit in the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3196.</num>
<heading> Extradition of United States citizens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the applicable treaty or convention does not obligate the United States to extradite its citizens to a foreign country, the Secretary of State may, nevertheless, order the surrender to that country of a United States citizen whose extradition has been requested by that country if the other requirements of that treaty or convention are met.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–623, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-21">Nov. 21, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>