<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 305—</num>
<heading>COMMITMENT AND TRANSFER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4081.</num>
<heading> Classification and treatment of prisoners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal penal and correctional institutions shall be so planned and limited in size as to facilitate the development of an integrated system which will assure the proper classification and segregation of Federal prisoners according to the nature of the offenses committed, the character and mental condition of the prisoners, and such other factors as should be considered in providing an individualized system of discipline, care, and treatment of the persons committed to such institutions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 850</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4082.</num>
<heading> Commitment to Attorney General; residential treatment centers; extension of limits of confinement; work furlough</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The willful failure of a prisoner to remain within the extended limits of his confinement, or to return within the time prescribed to an institution or facility designated by the Attorney General, shall be deemed an escape from the custody of the Attorney General punishable as provided in chapter 35 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General shall, upon the request of the head of any law enforcement agency of a State or of a unit of local government in a State, make available as expeditiously as possible to such agency, with respect to prisoners who have been convicted of felony offenses against the United States and who are confined at a facility which is a residential community treatment center located in the geographical area in which such agency has jurisdiction, the following information maintained by the Bureau of Prisons (to the extent that the Bureau of Prisons maintains such information)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the names of such prisoners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the community treatment center addresses of such prisoners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the dates of birth of such prisoners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation numbers assigned to such prisoners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> photographs and fingerprints of such prisoners; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the nature of the offenses against the United States of which each such prisoner has been convicted and the factual circumstances relating to such offenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any law enforcement agency which receives information under this subsection shall not disseminate such information outside of such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section—<p class="indent1" role="listItem">the term “facility” shall include a residential community treatment center; and</p>
<p class="indent1" role="listItem">the term “relative” shall mean a spouse, child (including stepchild, adopted child or child as to whom the prisoner, though not a natural parent, has acted in the place of a parent), parent (including a person who, though not a natural parent, has acted in the place of a parent), brother, or sister.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 850</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–176, § 1</ref>, <date date="1965-09-10">Sept. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–209</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 218(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 57(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4083.</num>
<heading> Penitentiary imprisonment; consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Persons convicted of offenses against the United States or by courts-martial punishable by imprisonment for more than one year may be confined in any United States penitentiary.</p>
<p class="indent0">A sentence for an offense punishable by imprisonment for one year or less shall not be served in a penitentiary without the consent of the defendant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 850</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–256</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4084, 4085.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 218(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2027</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4086.</num>
<heading> Temporary safe-keeping of federal offenders by marshals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States marshals shall provide for the safe-keeping of any person arrested, or held under authority of any enactment of Congress pending commitment to an institution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>