<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 110A—</num>
<heading>DOMESTIC VIOLENCE AND STALKING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2261.</num>
<heading> Interstate domestic violence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Offenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel or conduct of offender</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who travels in interstate or foreign commerce or enters or leaves Indian country or is present within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States with the intent to kill, injure, harass, or intimidate a spouse, intimate partner, or dating partner, and who, in the course of or as a result of such travel or presence, commits or attempts to commit a crime of violence against that spouse, intimate partner, or dating partner, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Causing travel of victim</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who causes a spouse, intimate partner, or dating partner to travel in interstate or foreign commerce or to enter or leave Indian country by force, coercion, duress, or fraud, and who, in the course of, as a result of, or to facilitate such conduct or travel, commits or attempts to commit a crime of violence against that spouse, intimate partner, or dating partner, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person who violates this section or section 2261A shall be fined under this title, imprisoned—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for life or any term of years, if death of the victim results;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for not more than 20 years if permanent disfigurement or life threatening bodily injury to the victim results;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for not more than 10 years, if serious bodily injury to the victim results or if the offender uses a dangerous weapon during the offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> as provided for the applicable conduct under chapter 109A if the offense would constitute an offense under chapter 109A (without regard to whether the offense was committed in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States or in a Federal prison); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> for not more than 5 years, in any other case,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">or both fined and imprisoned.</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Whoever commits the crime of stalking in violation of a temporary or permanent civil or criminal injunction, restraining order, no-contact order, or other order described in <ref>section 2266 of title 18</ref>, United States Code, shall be punished by imprisonment for not less than 1 year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40221(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1926</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1069(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2656</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title I, § 1107(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I</ref>, §§ 114(b), 116(a), 117(a), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2988</ref>, 2989; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 77</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2261A.</num>
<heading> Stalking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whoever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> travels in interstate or foreign commerce or is present within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or enters or leaves Indian country, with the intent to kill, injure, harass, intimidate, or place under surveillance with intent to kill, injure, harass, or intimidate another person, and in the course of, or as a result of, such travel or presence engages in conduct that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> places that person in reasonable fear of the death of, or serious bodily injury to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an immediate family member (as defined in section 115) of that person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a spouse or intimate partner of that person; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse of that person; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> causes, attempts to cause, or would be reasonably expected to cause substantial emotional distress to a person described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> with the intent to kill, injure, harass, intimidate, or place under surveillance with intent to kill, injure, harass, or intimidate another person, uses the mail, any interactive computer service or electronic communication service or electronic communication system of interstate commerce, or any other facility of interstate or foreign commerce to engage in a course of conduct that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> places that person in reasonable fear of the death of or serious bodily injury to a person, a pet, a service animal, an emotional support animal, or a horse described in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv) of paragraph (1)(A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> causes, attempts to cause, or would be reasonably expected to cause substantial emotional distress to a person described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of paragraph (1)(A),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in section 2261(b) or section 2261B, as the case may be.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1069(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2655</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title I, § 1107(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 114(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2987</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4982</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–249, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-22">Dec. 22, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2261B.</num>
<heading> Enhanced penalty for stalkers of children</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), if the victim of an offense under section 2261A is under the age of 18 years, the maximum imprisonment for the offense is 5 years greater than the maximum term of imprisonment otherwise provided for that offense in section 2261.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a person who violates section 2261A if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the person is subject to a sentence under section 2261(b)(5); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the person is under the age of 18 at the time the offense occurred; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the victim of the offense is not less than 15 nor more than 17 years of age and not more than 3 years younger than the person who committed the offense at the time the offense occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–249, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-22">Dec. 22, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2262.</num>
<heading> Interstate violation of protection order</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Offenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel or conduct of offender</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who travels in interstate or foreign commerce, or enters or leaves Indian country or is present within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, with the intent to engage in conduct that violates the portion of a protection order that prohibits or provides protection against violence, threats, or harassment against, contact or communication with, or physical proximity to, another person or the pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse of that person, or that would violate such a portion of a protection order in the jurisdiction in which the order was issued, and subsequently engages in such conduct, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Causing travel of victim</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who causes another person to travel in interstate or foreign commerce or to enter or leave Indian country by force, coercion, duress, or fraud, and in the course of, as a result of, or to facilitate such conduct or travel engages in conduct that violates the portion of a protection order that prohibits or provides protection against violence, threats, or harassment against, contact or communication with, or physical proximity to, another person or the pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse of that person, or that would violate such a portion of a protection order in the jurisdiction in which the order was issued, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person who violates this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for life or any term of years, if death of the victim results;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for not more than 20 years if permanent disfigurement or life threatening bodily injury to the victim results;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for not more than 10 years, if serious bodily injury to the victim results or if the offender uses a dangerous weapon during the offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> as provided for the applicable conduct under chapter 109A if the offense would constitute an offense under chapter 109A (without regard to whether the offense was committed in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States or in a Federal prison); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> for not more than 5 years, in any other case, including any case in which the offense is committed against a pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">or both fined and imprisoned.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40221(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1927</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1069(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2656</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 605(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title I, § 1107(c)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2989</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 107(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 78</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12502(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4982</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2263.</num>
<heading> Pretrial release of defendant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any proceeding pursuant to section 3142 for the purpose of determining whether a defendant charged under this chapter shall be released pending trial, or for the purpose of determining conditions of such release, the alleged victim shall be given an opportunity to be heard regarding the danger posed by the defendant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40221(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2264.</num>
<heading> Restitution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding section 3663 or 3663A, and in addition to any other civil or criminal penalty authorized by law, the court shall order restitution for any offense under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Scope and Nature of Order.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Directions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The order of restitution under this section shall direct the defendant to pay the victim (through the appropriate court mechanism) the full amount of the victim’s losses as determined by the court pursuant to paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An order of restitution under this section shall be issued and enforced in accordance with section 3664 in the same manner as an order under section 3663A.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, the term “full amount of the victim’s losses” includes any costs incurred by the victim for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> medical services relating to physical, psychiatric, or psychological care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> physical and occupational therapy or rehabilitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> necessary transportation, temporary housing, and child care expenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> lost income;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> attorneys’ fees, plus any costs incurred in obtaining a civil protection order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> veterinary services relating to physical care for the victim’s pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other losses suffered by the victim as a proximate result of the offense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order mandatory</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The issuance of a restitution order under this section is mandatory.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A court may not decline to issue an order under this section because of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the economic circumstances of the defendant; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the fact that a victim has, or is entitled to, receive compensation for his or her injuries from the proceeds of insurance or any other source.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Victim Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, the term “victim” means the individual harmed as a result of a commission of a crime under this chapter, including, in the case of a victim who is under 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased, the legal guardian of the victim or representative of the victim’s estate, another family member, or any other person appointed as suitable by the court, but in no event shall the defendant be named as such representative or guardian.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40221(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1928</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 205(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1231</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12502(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4983</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2265.</num>
<heading> Full faith and credit given to protection orders</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full Faith and Credit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any protection order issued that is consistent with subsection (b) of this section by the court of one State, Indian tribe, or territory (the issuing State, Indian tribe, or territory) shall be accorded full faith and credit by the court of another State, Indian tribe, or territory (the enforcing State, Indian tribe, or territory) and enforced by the court and law enforcement personnel of the other State, Indian tribal government or Territory <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002163">1</ref> as if it were the order of the enforcing State or tribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection Order</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A protection order issued by a State, tribal, or territorial court is consistent with this subsection if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such court has jurisdiction over the parties and matter under the law of such State, Indian tribe, or territory; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reasonable notice and opportunity to be heard is given to the person against whom the order is sought sufficient to protect that person’s right to due process. In the case of ex parte orders, notice and opportunity to be heard must be provided within the time required by State, tribal, or territorial law, and in any event within a reasonable time after the order is issued, sufficient to protect the respondent’s due process rights.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cross or Counter Petition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A protection order issued by a State, tribal, or territorial court against one who has petitioned, filed a complaint, or otherwise filed a written pleading for protection against abuse by a spouse or intimate partner is not entitled to full faith and credit if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no cross or counter petition, complaint, or other written pleading was filed seeking such a protection order; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a cross or counter petition has been filed and the court did not make specific findings that each party was entitled to such an order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notification and Registration.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State, Indian tribe, or territory according full faith and credit to an order by a court of another State, Indian tribe, or territory shall not notify or require notification of the party against whom a protection order has been issued that the protection order has been registered or filed in that enforcing State, tribal, or territorial jurisdiction unless requested to do so by the party protected under such order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No prior registration or filing as prerequisite for enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any protection order that is otherwise consistent with this section shall be accorded full faith and credit, notwithstanding failure to comply with any requirement that the order be registered or filed in the enforcing State, tribal, or territorial jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limits on internet publication of registration information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A State, Indian tribe, or territory shall not make available publicly on the Internet any information regarding the registration, filing of a petition for, or issuance of a protection order, restraining order, or injunction in either the issuing or enforcing State, tribal or territorial jurisdiction, if such publication would be likely to publicly reveal the identity or location of the party protected under such order. A State, Indian tribe, or territory may share court-generated and law enforcement-generated information contained in secure, governmental registries for protection order enforcement purposes. The prohibition under this paragraph applies to all protection orders for the protection of a person residing within a State, territorial, or Tribal jurisdiction, whether or not the protection order was issued by that State, territory, or Tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tribal Court Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, a court of an Indian tribe shall have full civil jurisdiction to issue and enforce protection orders involving any person, including the authority to enforce any orders through civil contempt proceedings, to exclude violators from Indian land, and to use other appropriate mechanisms, in matters arising anywhere in the Indian country of the Indian tribe (as defined in section 1151) or otherwise within the authority of the Indian tribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40221(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1930</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title I, § 1101(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 106(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2981</ref>, 2982; <ref>Pub. L. 109–271, § 2(n)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 754</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 124</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2265A.</num>
<heading> Repeat offenders</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum Term of Imprisonment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The maximum term of imprisonment for a violation of this chapter after a prior domestic violence or stalking offense shall be twice the term otherwise provided under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “prior domestic violence or stalking offense” means a conviction for an offense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under section 2261, 2261A, or 2262 of this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under State or tribal law for an offense consisting of conduct that would have been an offense under a section referred to in subparagraph (A) if the conduct had occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or in interstate or foreign commerce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2988</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title IX, § 906(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2266.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bodily injury</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “bodily injury” means any act, except one done in self-defense, that results in physical injury or sexual abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Course of conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “course of conduct” means a pattern of conduct composed of 2 or more acts, evidencing a continuity of purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enter or leave indian country</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “enter or leave Indian country” includes leaving the jurisdiction of 1 tribal government and entering the jurisdiction of another tribal government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indian country</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Indian country” has the meaning stated in <ref>section 1151 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection order</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “protection order” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any injunction, restraining order, or any other order issued by a civil or criminal court for the purpose of preventing violent or threatening acts or harassment against, sexual violence, or contact or communication with or physical proximity to, another person, including any temporary or final order issued by a civil or criminal court whether obtained by filing an independent action or as a pendente lite order in another proceeding so long as any civil or criminal order was issued in response to a complaint, petition, or motion filed by or on behalf of a person seeking protection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any support, child custody or visitation provisions, orders, remedies or relief issued as part of a protection order, restraining order, or injunction pursuant to State, tribal, territorial, or local law authorizing the issuance of protection orders, restraining orders, or injunctions for the protection of victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, dating violence, or stalking.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Serious bodily injury</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “serious bodily injury” has the meaning stated in section 2119(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Spouse or intimate partner</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “spouse or intimate partner” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> sections other than 2261A—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a spouse or former spouse of the abuser, a person who shares a child in common with the abuser, and a person who cohabits or has cohabited as a spouse with the abuser; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a person who is or has been in a social relationship of a romantic or intimate nature with the abuser, as determined by the length of the relationship, the type of relationship, and the frequency of interaction between the persons involved in the relationship; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> section 2261A—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a spouse or former spouse of the target of the stalking, a person who shares a child in common with the target of the stalking, and a person who cohabits or has cohabited as a spouse with the target of the stalking; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a person who is or has been in a social relationship of a romantic or intimate nature with the target of the stalking, as determined by the length of the relationship, the type of the relationship, and the frequency of interaction between the persons involved in the relationship.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002164">1</ref></content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other person similarly situated to a spouse who is protected by the domestic or family violence laws of the State or tribal jurisdiction in which the injury occurred or where the victim resides.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” includes a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and a commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel in interstate or foreign commerce</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “travel in interstate or foreign commerce” does not include travel from 1 State to another by an individual who is a member of an Indian tribe and who remains at all times in the territory of the Indian tribe of which the individual is a member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dating partner</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “dating partner” refers to a person who is or has been in a social relationship of a romantic or intimate nature with the abuser. The existence of such a relationship is based on a consideration of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the length of the relationship; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the type of relationship; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the frequency of interaction between the persons involved in the relationship.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pet</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “pet” means a domesticated animal, such as a dog, cat, bird, rodent, fish, turtle, or other animal that is kept for pleasure rather than for commercial purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emotional support animal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “emotional support animal” means an animal that is covered by the exclusion specified in section 5.303 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), and that is not a service animal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service animal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “service animal” has the meaning given the term in section 36.104 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40221(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1931</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title I, § 1107(d)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I</ref>, §§ 106(d), 116(b), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2982</ref>, 2988; <ref>Pub. L. 109–271, § 2(c)</ref>, (i), <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12502(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4983</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>