<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 35—</num>
<heading>ESCAPE AND RESCUE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 751.</num>
<heading> Prisoners in custody of institution or officer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever escapes or attempts to escape from the custody of the Attorney General or his authorized representative, or from any institution or facility in which he is confined by direction of the Attorney General, or from any custody under or by virtue of any process issued under the laws of the United States by any court, judge, or magistrate judge, or from the custody of an officer or employee of the United States pursuant to lawful arrest, shall, if the custody or confinement is by virtue of an arrest on a charge of felony, or conviction of any offense, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; or if the custody or confinement is for extradition, or for exclusion or expulsion proceedings under the immigration laws, or by virtue of an arrest or charge of or for a misdemeanor, and prior to conviction, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever escapes or attempts to escape from the custody of the Attorney General or his authorized representative, or from any institution or facility in which he is confined by direction of the Attorney General, or from any custody under or by virtue of any process issued under the laws of the United States by any court, judge, or magistrate judge, or from the custody of an officer or employee of the United States pursuant to lawful arrest, shall, if the custody or confinement is by virtue of a lawful arrest for a violation of any law of the United States not punishable by death or life imprisonment and committed before such person’s eighteenth birthday, and as to whom the Attorney General has not specifically directed the institution of criminal proceedings, or by virtue of a commitment as a juvenile delinquent under <ref>section 5034 of this title</ref>, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to affect the discretionary authority vested in the Attorney General pursuant to <ref>section 5032 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 734</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–251, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-12-30">Dec. 30, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–176, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-09-10">Sept. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 675</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7055</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 752.</num>
<heading> Instigating or assisting escape</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever rescues or attempts to rescue or instigates, aids or assists the escape, or attempt to escape, of any person arrested upon a warrant or other process issued under any law of the United States, or committed to the custody of the Attorney General or to any institution or facility by his direction, shall, if the custody or confinement is by virtue of an arrest on a charge of felony, or conviction of any offense, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; or, if the custody or confinement is for extradition, or for exclusion or expulsion proceedings under the immigration laws, or by virtue of an arrest or charge of or for a misdemeanor, and prior to conviction, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever rescues or attempts to rescue or instigates, aids, or assists the escape or attempted escape of any person in the custody of the Attorney General or his authorized representative, or of any person arrested upon a warrant or other process issued under any law of the United States or from any institution or facility in which he is confined by direction of the Attorney General, shall, if the custody or confinement is by virtue of a lawful arrest for a violation of any law of the United States not punishable by death or life imprisonment and committed before such person’s eighteenth birthday, and as to whom the Attorney General has not specifically directed the institution of criminal proceedings, or by virtue of a commitment as a juvenile delinquent under <ref>section 5034 of this title</ref>, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>May 28, 1956, ch. 331</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–251, § 2</ref>, <date date="1963-12-30">Dec. 30, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–176, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-09-10">Sept. 10, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 675</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7055</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(d)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 753.</num>
<heading> Rescue to prevent execution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, by force, sets at liberty or rescues any person found guilty in any court of the United States of any capital crime, while going to execution or during execution, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty-five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(O)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 754.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330004(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2141</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 755.</num>
<heading> Officer permitting escape</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, having in his custody any prisoner by virtue of process issued under the laws of the United States by any court, judge, or magistrate judge, voluntarily suffers such prisoner to escape, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both; or if he negligently suffers such person to escape, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, (I), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 705(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 756.</num>
<heading> Internee of belligerent nation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the jurisdiction of the United States, aids or entices any person belonging to the armed forces of a belligerent nation or faction who is interned in the United States in accordance with the law of nations, to escape or attempt to escape from the jurisdiction of the United States or from the limits of internment prescribed, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 705(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 757.</num>
<heading> Prisoners of war or enemy aliens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever procures the escape of any prisoner of war held by the United States or any of its allies, or the escape of any person apprehended or interned as an enemy alien by the United States or any of its allies, or advises, connives at, aids, or assists in such escape, or aids, relieves, transports, harbors, conceals, shelters, protects, holds correspondence with, gives intelligence to, or otherwise assists any such prisoner of war or enemy alien, after his escape from custody, knowing him to be such prisoner of war or enemy alien, or attempts to commit or conspires to commit any of the above acts, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall be in addition to and not in substitution for any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 758.</num>
<heading> High speed flight from immigration checkpoint</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever flees or evades a checkpoint operated by the Immigration and Naturalization Service, or any other Federal law enforcement agency, in a motor vehicle and flees Federal, State, or local law enforcement agents in excess of the legal speed limit shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I, § 108(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>