<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 212A—</num>
<heading>EXTRATERRITORIAL JURISDICTION OVER CERTAIN OFFENSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3271.</num>
<heading> Trafficking in persons offenses committed by persons employed by or accompanying the Federal Government outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, while employed by or accompanying the Federal Government outside the United States, engages in conduct outside the United States that would constitute an offense under chapter 77 or 117 of this title if the conduct had been engaged in within the United States or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States shall be punished as provided for that offense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No prosecution may be commenced against a person under this section if a foreign government, in accordance with jurisdiction recognized by the United States, has prosecuted or is prosecuting such person for the conduct constituting such offense, except upon the approval of the Attorney General or the Deputy Attorney General (or a person acting in either such capacity), which function of approval may not be delegated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3272.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “employed by the Federal Government outside the United States” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> employed as a civilian employee of the Federal Government, as a Federal contractor (including a subcontractor at any tier), or as an employee of a Federal contractor (including a subcontractor at any tier);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> present or residing outside the United States in connection with such employment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not a national of or ordinarily resident in the host nation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “accompanying the Federal Government outside the United States” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a dependant of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a civilian employee of the Federal Government; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a Federal contractor (including a subcontractor at any tier) or an employee of a Federal contractor (including a subcontractor at any tier);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> residing with such civilian employee, contractor, or contractor employee outside the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not a national of or ordinarily resident in the host nation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3273.</num>
<heading> Offenses committed by certain United States personnel stationed in Canada in furtherance of border security initiatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever, while employed by the Department of Homeland Security or the Department of Justice and stationed or deployed in Canada pursuant to a treaty, executive agreement, or bilateral memorandum in furtherance of a border security initiative, engages in conduct (or conspires or attempts to engage in conduct) in Canada that would constitute an offense for which a person may be prosecuted in a court of the United States had the conduct been engaged in within the United States or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States shall be fined or imprisoned, or both, as provided for that offense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “employed by the Department of Homeland Security or the Department of Justice” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> being employed as a civilian employee, a contractor (including a subcontractor at any tier), or an employee of a contractor (or a subcontractor at any tier) of the Department of Homeland Security or the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> being present or residing in Canada in connection with such employment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not being a national of or ordinarily resident in Canada.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–316, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>