<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 41—</num>
<heading>EXTORTION AND THREATS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 871.</num>
<heading> Threats against President and successors to the Presidency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly and willfully deposits for conveyance in the mail or for a delivery from any post office or by any letter carrier any letter, paper, writing, print, missive, or document containing any threat to take the life of, to kidnap, or to inflict bodily harm upon the President of the United States, the President-elect, the Vice President or other officer next in the order of succession to the office of President of the United States, or the Vice President-elect, or knowingly and willfully otherwise makes any such threat against the President, President-elect, Vice President or other officer next in the order of succession to the office of President, or Vice President-elect, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The terms “President-elect” and “Vice President-elect” as used in this section shall mean such persons as are the apparent successful candidates for the offices of President and Vice President, respectively, as ascertained from the results of the general elections held to determine the electors of President and Vice President in accordance with title 3, United States Code, sections 1 and 2. The phrase “other officer next in the order of succession to the office of President” as used in this section shall mean the person next in the order of succession to act as President in accordance with title 3, United States Code, sections 19 and 20.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>June 1, 1955, ch. 115, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–829, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 956</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–297, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 872.</num>
<heading> Extortion by officers or employees of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, or employee of the United States or any department or agency thereof, or representing himself to be or assuming to act as such, under color or pretense of office or employment commits or attempts an act of extortion, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both; but if the amount so extorted or demanded does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 24(b)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 873.</num>
<heading> Blackmail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, under a threat of informing, or as a consideration for not informing, against any violation of any law of the United States, demands or receives any money or other valuable thing, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 874.</num>
<heading> Kickbacks from public works employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, by force, intimidation, or threat of procuring dismissal from employment, or by any other manner whatsoever induces any person employed in the construction, prosecution, completion or repair of any public building, public work, or building or work financed in whole or in part by loans or grants from the United States, to give up any part of the compensation to which he is entitled under his contract of employment, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 875.</num>
<heading> Interstate communications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever transmits in interstate or foreign commerce any communication containing any demand or request for a ransom or reward for the release of any kidnapped person, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever, with intent to extort from any person, firm, association, or corporation, any money or other thing of value, transmits in interstate or foreign commerce any communication containing any threat to kidnap any person or any threat to injure the person of another, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whoever transmits in interstate or foreign commerce any communication containing any threat to kidnap any person or any threat to injure the person of another, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Whoever, with intent to extort from any person, firm, association, or corporation, any money or other thing of value, transmits in interstate or foreign commerce any communication containing any threat to injure the property or reputation of the addressee or of another or the reputation of a deceased person or any threat to accuse the addressee or any other person of a crime, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 63</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3614</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, (H), (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 876.</num>
<heading> Mailing threatening communications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly deposits in any post office or authorized depository for mail matter, to be sent or delivered by the Postal Service or knowingly causes to be delivered by the Postal Service according to the direction thereon, any communication, with or without a name or designating mark subscribed thereto, addressed to any other person, and containing any demand or request for ransom or reward for the release of any kidnapped person, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever, with intent to extort from any person any money or other thing of value, so deposits, or causes to be delivered, as aforesaid, any communication containing any threat to kidnap any person or any threat to injure the person of the addressee or of another, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly so deposits or causes to be delivered as aforesaid, any communication with or without a name or designating mark subscribed thereto, addressed to any other person and containing any threat to kidnap any person or any threat to injure the person of the addressee or of another, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both. If such a communication is addressed to a United States judge, a Federal law enforcement officer, or an official who is covered by section 1114, the individual shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Whoever, with intent to extort from any person any money or other thing of value, knowingly so deposits or causes to be delivered, as aforesaid, any communication, with or without a name or designating mark subscribed thereto, addressed to any other person and containing any threat to injure the property or reputation of the addressee or of another, or the reputation of a deceased person, or any threat to accuse the addressee or any other person of a crime, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both. If such a communication is addressed to a United States judge, a Federal law enforcement officer, or an official who is covered by section 1114, the individual shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(7)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330016(1)(G), (H), (K), 330021(2), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2150; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11008(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 877.</num>
<heading> Mailing threatening communications from foreign country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly deposits in any post office or authorized depository for mail matter of any foreign country any communication addressed to any person within the United States, for the purpose of having such communication delivered by the post office establishment of such foreign country to the Postal Service and by it delivered to such addressee in the United States, and as a result thereof such communication is delivered by the post office establishment of such foreign country to the Postal Service and by it delivered to the address to which it is directed in the United States, and containing any demand or request for ransom or reward for the release of any kidnapped person, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to extort from any person any money or other thing of value, so deposits as aforesaid, any communication for the purpose aforesaid, containing any threat to kidnap any person or any threat to injure the person of the addressee or of another, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly so deposits as aforesaid, any communication, for the purpose aforesaid, containing any threat to kidnap any person or any threat to injure the person of the addressee or of another, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to extort from any person any money or other thing of value, knowingly so deposits as aforesaid, any communication, for the purpose aforesaid, containing any threat to injure the property or reputation of the addressee or of another, or the reputation of a deceased person, or any threat to accuse the addressee or any other person of a crime, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(8)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330016(1)(G), (H), (K), 330021(2), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2150.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 878.</num>
<heading> Threats and extortion against foreign officials, official guests, or internationally protected persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly and willfully threatens to violate section 112, 1116, or 1201 shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both, except that imprisonment for a threatened assault shall not exceed three years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever in connection with any violation of subsection (a) or actual violation of section 112, 1116, or 1201 makes any extortionate demand shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section “foreign official”, “internationally protected person”, “national of the United States”, and “official guest” shall have the same meanings as those provided in <ref>section 1116(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If the victim of an offense under subsection (a) is an internationally protected person outside the United States, the United States may exercise jurisdiction over the offense if (1) the victim is a representative, officer, employee, or agent of the United States, (2) an offender is a national of the United States, or (3) an offender is afterwards found in the United States. As used in this subsection, the United States includes all areas under the jurisdiction of the United States including any of the places within the provisions of sections 5 and 7 of this title and <ref>section 46501(2) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–467, § 8</ref>, <date date="1976-10-08">Oct. 8, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2000</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–163, § 17(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–504, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-24">Oct. 24, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, (N), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII</ref>, §§ 705(a)(4), 721(e), <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1295</ref>, 1299.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 879.</num>
<heading> Threats against former Presidents and certain other persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever knowingly and willfully threatens to kill, kidnap, or inflict bodily harm upon—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a former President or a member of the immediate family of a former President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a member of the immediate family of the President, the President-elect, the Vice President, or the Vice President-elect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a major candidate for the office of President or Vice President, or a member of the immediate family of such candidate; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a person protected by the Secret Service under section 3056(a)(6);</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “immediate family” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to subsection (a)(1) of this section, the spouse of a former President during a former President’s lifetime, the surviving spouse of a former President until the surviving spouse’s death or remarriage, and minor children of a former President until they reach sixteen years of age; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to subsection (a)(2) and (a)(3) of this section, a person to whom the President, President-elect, Vice President, Vice President-elect, or major candidate for the office of President or Vice President—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is related by blood, marriage, or adoption; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> stands in loco parentis;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “major candidate for the office of President or Vice President” means a candidate referred to in subsection (a)(7) of <ref>section 3056 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the terms “President-elect” and “Vice President-elect” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 871(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–297, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1317</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–587, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3111</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–544, § 2(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–272, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 880.</num>
<heading> Receiving the proceeds of extortion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person who receives, possesses, conceals, or disposes of any money or other property which was obtained from the commission of any offense under this chapter that is punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year, knowing the same to have been unlawfully obtained, shall be imprisoned not more than 3 years, fined under this title, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320601(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>