<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 3—</num>
<heading>ANIMALS, BIRDS, FISH, AND PLANTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 41.</num>
<heading> Hunting, fishing, trapping; disturbance or injury on wildlife refuges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, except in compliance with rules and regulations promulgated by authority of law, hunts, traps, captures, willfully disturbs or kills any bird, fish, or wild animal of any kind whatever, or takes or destroys the eggs or nest of any such bird or fish, on any lands or waters which are set apart or reserved as sanctuaries, refuges or breeding grounds for such birds, fish, or animals under any law of the United States or willfully injures, molests, or destroys any property of the United States on any such lands or waters, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 42.</num>
<heading> Importation or shipment of injurious mammals, birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibia, and reptiles; permits, specimens for museums; regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The importation into the United States, any territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any possession of the United States, or any shipment between the continental United States, the District of Columbia, Hawaii, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any possession of the United States, of the mongoose of the species Herpestes auropunctatus; of the species of so-called “flying foxes” or fruit bats of the genus Pteropus; of the zebra mussel of the species Dreissena polymorpha; of the quagga mussel of the species Dreissena rostriformis or Dreissena bugensis; of the bighead carp of the species Hypophthalmichthys nobilis; and such other species of wild mammals, wild birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibians, reptiles, brown tree snakes, or the offspring or eggs of any of the foregoing which the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe by regulation to be injurious to human beings, to the interests of agriculture, horticulture, forestry, or to wildlife or the wildlife resources of the United States, is hereby prohibited. All such prohibited mammals, birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibians, and reptiles, and the eggs or offspring therefrom, shall be promptly exported or destroyed at the expense of the importer or consignee. Nothing in this section shall be construed to repeal or modify any provision of the Public Health Service Act or Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Also, this section shall not authorize any action with respect to the importation of any plant pest as defined in the Federal Plant Pest Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref> insofar as such importation is subject to regulation under that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As used in this subsection, the term “wild” relates to any creatures that, whether or not raised in captivity, normally are found in a wild state; and the terms “wildlife” and “wildlife resources” include those resources that comprise wild mammals, wild birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), and all other classes of wild creatures whatsoever, and all types of aquatic and land vegetation upon which such wildlife resources are dependent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Secretary of the Interior, when he finds that there has been a proper showing of responsibility and continued protection of the public interest and health, shall permit the importation for zoological, educational, medical, and scientific purposes of any mammals, birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibia, and reptiles, or the offspring or eggs thereof, where such importation would be prohibited otherwise by or pursuant to this Act, and this Act shall not restrict importations by Federal agencies for their own use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall restrict the importation of dead natural-history specimens for museums or for scientific collections, or the importation of domesticated canaries, parrots (including all other species of psittacine birds), or such other cage birds as the Secretary of the Interior may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of the Interior shall enforce the provisions of this subsection, including any regulations issued hereunder, and, if requested by the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Treasury may require the furnishing of an appropriate bond when desirable to insure compliance with such provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever violates this section, or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Interior within one hundred and eighty days of the enactment of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 shall prescribe such requirements and issue such permits as he may deem necessary for the transportation of wild animals and birds under humane and healthful conditions, and it shall be unlawful for any person, including any importer, knowingly to cause or permit any wild animal or bird to be transported to the United States, or any Territory or district thereof, under inhumane or unhealthful conditions or in violation of such requirements. In any criminal prosecution for violation of this subsection and in any administrative proceeding for the suspension of the issuance of further permits—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the condition of any vessel or conveyance, or the enclosures in which wild animals or birds are confined therein, upon its arrival in the United States, or any Territory or district thereof, shall constitute relevant evidence in determining whether the provisions of this subsection have been violated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the presence in such vessel or conveyance at such time of a substantial ratio of dead, crippled, diseased, or starving wild animals or birds shall be deemed prima facie evidence of the violation of the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 2</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 89</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–702, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 753</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–79, § 9(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-11-16">Nov. 16, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–646, title I, § 1208</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1013(e)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 4091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–307, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-12-14">Dec. 14, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title IX, § 903(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 43.</num>
<heading> Force, violence, and threats involving animal enterprises</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever travels in interstate or foreign commerce, or uses or causes to be used the mail or any facility of interstate or foreign commerce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the purpose of damaging or interfering with the operations of an animal enterprise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in connection with such purpose—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> intentionally damages or causes the loss of any real or personal property (including animals or records) used by an animal enterprise, or any real or personal property of a person or entity having a connection to, relationship with, or transactions with an animal enterprise;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> intentionally places a person in reasonable fear of the death of, or serious bodily injury to that person, a member of the immediate family (as defined in section 115) of that person, or a spouse or intimate partner of that person by a course of conduct involving threats, acts of vandalism, property damage, criminal trespass, harassment, or intimidation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> conspires or attempts to do so;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided for in subsection (b).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The punishment for a violation of section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002017">1</ref> (a) or an attempt or conspiracy to violate subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a fine under this title or imprisonment not <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">2</ref> more than 1 year, or both, if the offense does not instill in another the reasonable fear of serious bodily injury or death and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the offense results in no economic damage or bodily injury; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offense results in economic damage that does not exceed $10,000;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both, if no bodily injury occurs and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the offense results in economic damage exceeding $10,000 but not exceeding $100,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offense instills in another the reasonable fear of serious bodily injury or death;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the offense results in economic damage exceeding $100,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offense results in substantial bodily injury to another individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than 20 years, or both, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the offense results in serious bodily injury to another individual; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the offense results in economic damage exceeding $1,000,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> imprisonment for life or for any terms of years, a fine under this title, or both, if the offense results in death of another individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restitution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An order of restitution under section 3663 or 3663A of this title with respect to a violation of this section may also include restitution—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the reasonable cost of repeating any experimentation that was interrupted or invalidated as a result of the offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the loss of food production or farm income reasonably attributable to the offense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for any other economic damage, including any losses or costs caused by economic disruption, resulting from the offense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “animal enterprise” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a commercial or academic enterprise that uses or sells animals or animal products for profit, food or fiber production, agriculture, education, research, or testing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a zoo, aquarium, animal shelter, pet store, breeder, furrier, circus, or rodeo, or other lawful competitive animal event; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any fair or similar event intended to advance agricultural arts and sciences;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “course of conduct” means a pattern of conduct composed of 2 or more acts, evidencing a continuity of purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “economic damage”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the replacement costs of lost or damaged property or records, the costs of repeating an interrupted or invalidated experiment, the loss of profits, or increased costs, including losses and increased costs resulting from threats, acts or vandalism, property damage, trespass, harassment, or intimidation taken against a person or entity on account of that person’s or entity’s connection to, relationship with, or transactions with the animal enterprise; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include any lawful economic disruption (including a lawful boycott) that results from lawful public, governmental, or business reaction to the disclosure of information about an animal enterprise;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “serious bodily injury” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> injury posing a substantial risk of death;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> extreme physical pain;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> protracted and obvious disfigurement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> protracted loss or impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the term “substantial bodily injury” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> deep cuts and serious burns or abrasions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> short-term or nonobvious disfigurement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fractured or dislocated bones, or torn members of the body;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> significant physical pain;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> illness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> short-term loss or impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other significant injury to the body.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rules of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to prohibit any expressive conduct (including peaceful picketing or other peaceful demonstration) protected from legal prohibition by the First Amendment to the Constitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to create new remedies for interference with activities protected by the free speech or free exercise clauses of the First Amendment to the Constitution, regardless of the point of view expressed, or to limit any existing legal remedies for such interference; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide exclusive criminal penalties or civil remedies with respect to the conduct prohibited by this action, or to preempt State or local laws that may provide such penalties or remedies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–346, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-08-26">Aug. 26, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 928</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(r)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–188, title III, § 336</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 681</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–374, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-11-27">Nov. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2652</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 44.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–79, § 9(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-11-16">Nov. 16, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1079</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 45.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XII, § 1206(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4832</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 46.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title X, § 1002(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2155</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 47.</num>
<heading> Use of aircraft or motor vehicles to hunt certain wild horses or burros; pollution of watering holes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever uses an aircraft or a motor vehicle to hunt, for the purpose of capturing or killing, any wild unbranded horse, mare, colt, or burro running at large on any of the public land or ranges shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever pollutes or causes the pollution of any watering hole on any of the public land or ranges for the purpose of trapping, killing, wounding, or maiming any of the animals referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> As used in subsection (a) of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “aircraft” means any contrivance used for flight in the air; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “motor vehicle” includes an automobile, automobile truck, automobile wagon, motorcycle, or any other self-propelled vehicle designed for running on land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–234, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 470</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 48.</num>
<heading> Animal crushing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Offenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crushing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It shall be unlawful for any person to purposely engage in animal crushing in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Creation of animal crush videos</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly create an animal crush video, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the person intends or has reason to know that the animal crush video will be distributed in, or using a means or facility of, interstate or foreign commerce; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the animal crush video is distributed in, or using a means or facility of, interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution of animal crush videos</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, market, advertise, exchange, or distribute an animal crush video in, or using a means or facility of, interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extraterritorial Application</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies to the knowing sale, marketing, advertising, exchange, distribution, or creation of an animal crush video outside of the United States, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the person engaging in such conduct intends or has reason to know that the animal crush video will be transported into the United States or its territories or possessions; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the animal crush video is transported into the United States or its territories or possessions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 7 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply with regard to any conduct, or a visual depiction of that conduct, that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a customary and normal veterinary, agricultural husbandry, or other animal management practice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the slaughter of animals for food;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> hunting, trapping, fishing, a sporting activity not otherwise prohibited by Federal law, predator control, or pest control;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> medical or scientific research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> necessary to protect the life or property of a person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> performed as part of euthanizing an animal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Good-faith distribution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section does not apply to the good-faith distribution of an animal crush video to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a law enforcement agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a third party for the sole purpose of analysis to determine if referral to a law enforcement agency is appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unintentional conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to unintentional conduct that injures or kills an animal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consistency with rfra</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall be enforced in a manner that is consistent with section 3 of the Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000bb–1</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Preemption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt the law of any State or local subdivision thereof to protect animals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “animal crushing” means actual conduct in which one or more living non-human mammals, birds, reptiles, or amphibians is purposely crushed, burned, drowned, suffocated, impaled, or otherwise subjected to serious bodily injury (as defined in section 1365 and including conduct that, if committed against a person and in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, would violate section 2241 or 2242);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “animal crush video” means any photograph, motion-picture film, video or digital recording, or electronic image that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> depicts animal crushing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is obscene; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “euthanizing an animal” means the humane destruction of an animal accomplished by a method that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> produces rapid unconsciousness and subsequent death without evidence of pain or distress; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> uses anesthesia produced by an agent that causes painless loss of consciousness and subsequent death.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–152, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1732</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–294, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-09">Dec. 9, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3178</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–72, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-25">Nov. 25, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 49.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of animal fighting prohibitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates subsection (a)(1), (b), (c), or (d) of section 26 of the Animal Welfare Act shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both, for each violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attending an Animal Fighting Venture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates subsection (a)(2)(A) of section 26 of the Animal Welfare Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2156</ref>) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both, for each violation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Causing an Individual Who Has Not Attained the Age of </inline>16<inline class="small-caps"> To Attend an Animal Fighting Venture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever violates subsection (a)(2)(B) of section 26 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 2156</ref>) of the Animal Welfare Act shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both, for each violation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–22, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-05-03">May 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 88</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14207(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1462</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIV, § 14207(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2224; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12308(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12616(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>