<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 201—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3001.</num>
<heading> Procedure governed by rules; scope, purpose and effect; definition of terms; local rules; forms—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3002.</num>
<heading> Courts always open—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3003.</num>
<heading> Calendars—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3004.</num>
<heading> Decorum in court room—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3005.</num>
<heading> Counsel and witnesses in capital cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever is indicted for treason or other capital crime shall be allowed to make his full defense by counsel; and the court before which the defendant is to be tried, or a judge thereof, shall promptly, upon the defendant’s request, assign 2 such counsel, of whom at least 1 shall be learned in the law applicable to capital cases, and who shall have free access to the accused at all reasonable hours. In assigning counsel under this section, the court shall consider the recommendation of the Federal Public Defender organization, or, if no such organization exists in the district, of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts. The defendant shall be allowed, in his defense to make any proof that he can produce by lawful witnesses, and shall have the like process of the court to compel his witnesses to appear at his trial, as is usually granted to compel witnesses to appear on behalf of the prosecution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title VI, § 60026</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1982</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3006.</num>
<heading> Assignment of counsel—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3006A.</num>
<heading> Adequate representation of defendants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Choice of Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each United States district court, with the approval of the judicial council of the circuit, shall place in operation throughout the district a plan for furnishing representation for any person financially unable to obtain adequate representation in accordance with this section. Representation under each plan shall include counsel and investigative, expert, and other services necessary for adequate representation. Each plan shall provide the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Representation shall be provided for any financially eligible person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is charged with a felony or a Class A misdemeanor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a juvenile alleged to have committed an act of juvenile delinquency as defined in <ref>section 5031 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is charged with a violation of probation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is under arrest, when such representation is required by law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> is charged with a violation of supervised release or faces modification, reduction, or enlargement of a condition, or extension or revocation of a term of supervised release;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> is subject to a mental condition hearing under chapter 313 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> is in custody as a material witness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> is entitled to appointment of counsel under the sixth amendment to the Constitution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> faces loss of liberty in a case, and Federal law requires the appointment of counsel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> is entitled to the appointment of counsel under <ref>section 4109 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever the United States magistrate judge or the court determines that the interests of justice so require, representation may be provided for any financially eligible person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is charged with a Class B or C misdemeanor, or an infraction for which a sentence to confinement is authorized; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is seeking relief under section 2241, 2254, or 2255 of title 28.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Private attorneys shall be appointed in a substantial proportion of the cases. Each plan may include, in addition to the provisions for private attorneys, either of the following or both:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Attorneys furnished by a bar association or a legal aid agency,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Attorneys furnished by a defender organization established in accordance with the provisions of subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Prior to approving the plan for a district, the judicial council of the circuit shall supplement the plan with provisions for representation on appeal. The district court may modify the plan at any time with the approval of the judicial council of the circuit. It shall modify the plan when directed by the judicial council of the circuit. The district court shall notify the Administrative Office of the United States Courts of any modification of its plan.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Counsel furnishing representation under the plan shall be selected from a panel of attorneys designated or approved by the court, or from a bar association, legal aid agency, or defender organization furnishing representation pursuant to the plan. In every case in which a person entitled to representation under a plan approved under subsection (a) appears without counsel, the United States magistrate judge or the court shall advise the person that he has the right to be represented by counsel and that counsel will be appointed to represent him if he is financially unable to obtain counsel. Unless the person waives representation by counsel, the United States magistrate judge or the court, if satisfied after appropriate inquiry that the person is financially unable to obtain counsel, shall appoint counsel to represent him. Such appointment may be made retroactive to include any representation furnished pursuant to the plan prior to appointment. The United States magistrate judge or the court shall appoint separate counsel for persons having interests that cannot properly be represented by the same counsel, or when other good cause is shown.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration and Substitution of Appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person for whom counsel is appointed shall be represented at every stage of the proceedings from his initial appearance before the United States magistrate judge or the court through appeal, including ancillary matters appropriate to the proceedings. If at any time after the appointment of counsel the United States magistrate judge or the court finds that the person is financially able to obtain counsel or to make partial payment for the representation, it may terminate the appointment of counsel or authorize payment as provided in subsection (f), as the interests of justice may dictate. If at any stage of the proceedings, including an appeal, the United States magistrate judge or the court finds that the person is financially unable to pay counsel whom he had retained, it may appoint counsel as provided in subsection (b) and authorize payment as provided in subsection (d), as the interests of justice may dictate. The United States magistrate judge or the court may, in the interests of justice, substitute one appointed counsel for another at any stage of the proceedings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Payment for Representation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hourly Rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any attorney appointed pursuant to this section, or the attorney’s law firm, or a bar association or legal aid agency or community defender organization which has provided the appointed attorney shall, at the conclusion of the representation or any segment thereof, be compensated at a rate not exceeding $60 per hour for time expended in court or before a United States magistrate judge and $40 per hour for time reasonably expended out of court, unless the Judicial Conference determines that a higher rate of not in excess of $75 per hour is justified for a circuit or for particular districts within a circuit, for time expended in court or before a United States magistrate judge and for time expended out of court. The Judicial Conference shall develop guidelines for determining the maximum hourly rates for each circuit in accordance with the preceding sentence, with variations by district, where appropriate, taking into account such factors as the minimum range of the prevailing hourly rates for qualified attorneys in the district in which the representation is provided and the recommendations of the judicial councils of the circuits. Not less than 3 years after the effective date of the Criminal Justice Act Revision of 1986, the Judicial Conference is authorized to raise the maximum hourly rates specified in this paragraph up to the aggregate of the overall average percentages of the adjustments in the rates of pay under the General Schedule made pursuant to section 5305 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002213">1</ref> of title 5 on or after such effective date. After the rates are raised under the preceding sentence, such maximum hourly rates may be raised at intervals of not less than 1 year each, up to the aggregate of the overall average percentages of such adjustments made since the last raise was made under this paragraph. Attorneys may be reimbursed for expenses reasonably incurred, including the costs of transcripts authorized by the United States magistrate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002214">2</ref> or the court, and the costs of defending actions alleging malpractice of counsel in furnishing representational services under this section. No reimbursement for expenses in defending against malpractice claims shall be made if a judgment of malpractice is rendered against the counsel furnishing representational services under this section. The United States magistrate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002214">2</ref> or the court shall make determinations relating to reimbursement of expenses under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For representation of a defendant before the United States magistrate judge or the district court, or both, the compensation to be paid to an attorney, or the attorney’s law firm, or to a bar association or legal aid agency or community defender organization shall not exceed $7,000 for each attorney in a case in which one or more felonies are charged, and $2,000 for each attorney in a case in which only misdemeanors are charged. For representation of a defendant in an appellate court, the compensation to be paid to an attorney, or the attorney’s law firm, or to a bar association or legal aid agency or community defender organization shall not exceed $5,000 for each attorney in each court. For representation of a petitioner in a non-capital habeas corpus proceeding, the compensation for each attorney shall not exceed the amount applicable to a felony in this paragraph for representation of a defendant before a judicial officer of the district court. For representation of such petitioner in an appellate court, the compensation for each attorney shall not exceed the amount applicable for representation of a defendant in an appellate court. For representation of an offender before the United States Parole Commission in a proceeding under <ref>section 4106A of this title</ref>, the compensation shall not exceed $1,500 for each attorney in each proceeding; for representation of an offender in an appeal from a determination of such Commission under such section, the compensation shall not exceed $5,000 for each attorney in each court. For any other representation required or authorized by this section, the compensation shall not exceed $1,500 for each attorney in each proceeding. The compensation maximum amounts provided in this paragraph shall increase simultaneously by the same percentage, rounded to the nearest multiple of $100, as the aggregate percentage increases in the maximum hourly compensation rate paid pursuant to paragraph (1) for time expended since the case maximum amounts were last adjusted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiving Maximum Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Payment in excess of any maximum amount provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection may be made for extended or complex representation whenever the court in which the representation was rendered, or the United States magistrate judge if the representation was furnished exclusively before him, certifies that the amount of the excess payment is necessary to provide fair compensation and the payment is approved by the chief judge of the circuit. The chief judge of the circuit may delegate such approval authority to an active or senior circuit judge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of fees.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subparagraphs (B) through (E), the amounts paid under this subsection for services in any case shall be made available to the public by the court upon the court’s approval of the payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pre-trial or trial in progress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a trial is in pre-trial status or still in progress and after considering the defendant’s interests as set forth in subparagraph (D), the court shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> redact any detailed information on the payment voucher provided by defense counsel to justify the expenses to the court; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> make public only the amounts approved for payment to defense counsel by dividing those amounts into the following categories:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Arraignment and or plea.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> Bail and detention hearings.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> Motions.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> Hearings.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> Interviews and conferences.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> Obtaining and reviewing records.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> Legal research and brief writing.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(VIII)</num>
<content> Travel time.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IX)</num>
<content> Investigative work.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(X)</num>
<content> Experts.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(XI)</num>
<content> Trial and appeals.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(XII)</num>
<content> Other.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Trial completed.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a request for payment is not submitted until after the completion of the trial and subject to consideration of the defendant’s interests as set forth in subparagraph (D), the court shall make available to the public an unredacted copy of the expense voucher.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of the rights of the defendant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the court determines that defendant’s interests as set forth in subparagraph (D) require a limited disclosure, the court shall disclose amounts as provided in subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The interests referred to in subparagraphs (B) and (C) are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to protect any person’s 5th amendment right against self-incrimination;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to protect the defendant’s 6th amendment rights to effective assistance of counsel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the defendant’s attorney-client privilege;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the work product privilege of the defendant’s counsel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the safety of any person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any other interest that justice may require, except that the amount of the fees shall not be considered a reason justifying any limited disclosure under <ref>section 3006A(d)(4) of title 18</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court shall provide reasonable notice of disclosure to the counsel of the defendant prior to the approval of the payments in order to allow the counsel to request redaction based on the considerations set forth in subparagraph (D). Upon completion of the trial, the court shall release unredacted copies of the vouchers provided by defense counsel to justify the expenses to the court. If there is an appeal, the court shall not release unredacted copies of the vouchers provided by defense counsel to justify the expenses to the court until such time as the appeals process is completed, unless the court determines that none of the defendant’s interests set forth in subparagraph (D) will be compromised.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amendment made by paragraph (4) shall become effective 60 days after enactment of this Act, will apply only to cases filed on or after the effective date, and shall be in effect for no longer than 24 months after the effective date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A separate claim for compensation and reimbursement shall be made to the district court for representation before the United States magistrate judge and the court, and to each appellate court before which the attorney provided representation to the person involved. Each claim shall be supported by a sworn written statement specifying the time expended, services rendered, and expenses incurred while the case was pending before the United States magistrate judge and the court, and the compensation and reimbursement applied for or received in the same case from any other source. The court shall fix the compensation and reimbursement to be paid to the attorney, or the attorney’s law firm or to the bar association or legal aid agency or community defender organization which provided the appointed attorney. In cases where representation is furnished exclusively before a United States magistrate judge, the claim shall be submitted to him and he shall fix the compensation and reimbursement to be paid. In cases where representation is furnished other than before the United States magistrate judge, the district court, or an appellate court, claims shall be submitted to the district court which shall fix the compensation and reimbursement to be paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">New Trials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of compensation and other payments authorized by this section, an order by a court granting a new trial shall be deemed to initiate a new case.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proceedings Before Appellate Courts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a person for whom counsel is appointed under this section appeals to an appellate court or petitions for a writ of certiorari, he may do so without prepayment of fees and costs or security therefor and without filing the affidavit required by <ref>section 1915(a) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Services Other Than Counsel.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Upon Request</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Counsel for a person who is financially unable to obtain investigative, expert, or other services necessary for adequate representation may request them in an ex parte application. Upon finding, after appropriate inquiry in an ex parte proceeding, that the services are necessary and that the person is financially unable to obtain them, the court, or the United States magistrate judge if the services are required in connection with a matter over which he has jurisdiction, shall authorize counsel to obtain the services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Without Prior Request</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Counsel appointed under this section may obtain, subject to later review, investigative, expert, and other services without prior authorization if necessary for adequate representation. Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the total cost of services obtained without prior authorization may not exceed $800 and expenses reasonably incurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The court, or the United States magistrate judge (if the services were rendered in a case disposed of entirely before the United States magistrate judge), may, in the interest of justice, and upon the finding that timely procurement of necessary services could not await prior authorization, approve payment for such services after they have been obtained, even if the cost of such services exceeds $800.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Compensation to be paid to a person for services rendered by him to a person under this subsection, or to be paid to an organization for services rendered by an employee thereof, shall not exceed $2,400, exclusive of reimbursement for expenses reasonably incurred, unless payment in excess of that limit is certified by the court, or by the United States magistrate judge if the services were rendered in connection with a case disposed of entirely before him, as necessary to provide fair compensation for services of an unusual character or duration, and the amount of the excess payment is approved by the chief judge of the circuit. The chief judge of the circuit may delegate such approval authority to an active or senior circuit judge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amounts paid under this subsection for services in any case shall be made available to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The dollar amounts provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) shall be adjusted simultaneously by an amount, rounded to the nearest multiple of $100, equal to the percentage of the cumulative adjustments taking effect under <ref>section 5303 of title 5</ref> in the rates of pay under the General Schedule since the date the dollar amounts provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively, were last enacted or adjusted by statute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receipt of Other Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the United States magistrate judge or the court finds that funds are available for payment from or on behalf of a person furnished representation, it may authorize or direct that such funds be paid to the appointed attorney, or the attorney’s law firm, to the bar association or legal aid agency or community defender organization which provided the appointed attorney, to any person or organization authorized pursuant to subsection (e) to render investigative, expert, or other services, or to the court for deposit in the Treasury as a reimbursement to the appropriation, current at the time of payment, to carry out the provisions of this section. Except as so authorized or directed, no such person or organization may request or accept any payment or promise of payment for representing a defendant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Defender Organization.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A district or a part of a district in which at least two hundred persons annually require the appointment of counsel may establish a defender organization as provided for either under subparagraphs (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) of this subsection or both. Two adjacent districts or parts of districts may aggregate the number of persons required to be represented to establish eligibility for a defender organization to serve both areas. In the event that adjacent districts or parts of districts are located in different circuits, the plan for furnishing representation shall be approved by the judicial council of each circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Types of Defender Organizations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Public Defender Organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Federal Public Defender Organization shall consist of one or more full-time salaried attorneys. An organization for a district or part of a district or two adjacent districts or parts of districts shall be supervised by a Federal Public Defender appointed by the court of appeals of the circuit, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, after considering recommendations from the district court or courts to be served. Nothing contained herein shall be deemed to authorize more than one Federal Public Defender within a single judicial district. The Federal Public Defender shall be appointed for a term of four years, unless sooner removed by the court of appeals of the circuit for incompetency, misconduct in office, or neglect of duty. Upon the expiration of his term, a Federal Public Defender may, by a majority vote of the judges of the court of appeals, continue to perform the duties of his office until his successor is appointed, or until one year after the expiration of such Defender’s term, whichever is earlier. The compensation of the Federal Public Defender shall be fixed by the court of appeals of the circuit at a rate not to exceed the compensation received by the United States attorney for the district where representation is furnished or, if two districts or parts of districts are involved, the compensation of the higher paid United States attorney of the districts. The Federal Public Defender may appoint, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, full-time attorneys in such number as may be approved by the court of appeals of the circuit and other personnel in such number as may be approved by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts. Compensation paid to such attorneys and other personnel of the organization shall be fixed by the Federal Public Defender at a rate not to exceed that paid to attorneys and other personnel of similar qualifications and experience in the Office of the United States attorney in the district where representation is furnished or, if two districts or parts of districts are involved, the higher compensation paid to persons of similar qualifications and experience in the districts. Neither the Federal Public Defender nor any attorney so appointed by him may engage in the private practice of law. Each organization shall submit to the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, at the time and in the form prescribed by him, reports of its activities and financial position and its proposed budget. The Director of the Administrative Office shall submit, in accordance with <ref>section 605 of title 28</ref>, a budget for each organization for each fiscal year and shall out of the appropriations therefor make payments to and on behalf of each organization. Payments under this subparagraph to an organization shall be in lieu of payments under subsection (d) or (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Community Defender Organization</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A Community Defender Organization shall be a non-profit defense counsel service established and administered by any group authorized by the plan to provide representation. The organization shall be eligible to furnish attorneys and receive payments under this section if its bylaws are set forth in the plan of the district or districts in which it will serve. Each organization shall submit to the Judicial Conference of the United States an annual report setting forth its activities and financial position and the anticipated caseload and expenses for the next fiscal year. Upon application an organization may, to the extent approved by the Judicial Conference of the United States:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> receive an initial grant for expenses necessary to establish the organization; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in lieu of payments under subsection (d) or (e), receive periodic sustaining grants to provide representation and other expenses pursuant to this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Malpractice and Negligence Suits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall, to the extent the Director considers appropriate, provide representation for and hold harmless, or provide liability insurance for, any person who is an officer or employee of a Federal Public Defender Organization established under this subsection, or a Community Defender Organization established under this subsection which is receiving periodic sustaining grants, for money damages for injury, loss of liberty, loss of property, or personal injury or death arising from malpractice or negligence of any such officer or employee in furnishing representational services under this section while acting within the scope of that person’s office or employment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rules and Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each district court and court of appeals of a circuit shall submit a report on the appointment of counsel within its jurisdiction to the Administrative Office of the United States Courts in such form and at such times as the Judicial Conference of the United States may specify. The Judicial Conference of the United States may, from time to time, issue rules and regulations governing the operation of plans formulated under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the United States courts, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, sums necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, including funds for the continuing education and training of persons providing representational services under this section. When so specified in appropriation acts, such appropriations shall remain available until expended. Payments from such appropriations shall be made under the supervision of the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Districts Included</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As used in this section, the term “district court” means each district court of the United States created by chapter 5 of title 28, the District Court of the Virgin Islands, the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands, and the District Court of Guam.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability in the District of Columbia</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of this section shall apply in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia and the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 88–455, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 552</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–447, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-10-14">Oct. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 916</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–412, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 53</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II</ref>, §§ 223(e), 405, 1901, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2028</ref>, 2067, 2185; <ref>Pub. L. 99–651, title I</ref>, §§ 102, 103, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3642</ref>, 3645; <ref>Pub. L. 100–182, § 19</ref>, <date date="1987-12-07">Dec. 7, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7101(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title IX, § 903(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–119, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(1) [title III, § 308(a)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–37; <ref>Pub. L. 106–518, title II</ref>, §§ 210, 211, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. B, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2894</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–406</ref>, §§ 11–12(b), <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4293</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 111–174, § 7</ref>, <date date="2010-05-27">May 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1217</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–47, div. B, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 542</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3007.</num>
<heading> Motions—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3008.</num>
<heading> Service and filing of papers—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3009.</num>
<heading> Records—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–578, title III, § 301(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3010.</num>
<heading> Exceptions unnecessary—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3011.</num>
<heading> Computation of time—(Rule)</heading>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3012.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 218(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2027</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3013.</num>
<heading> Special assessment on convicted persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The court shall assess on any person convicted of an offense against the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an infraction or a misdemeanor—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> if the defendant is an individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of $5 in the case of an infraction or a class C misdemeanor;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount of $10 in the case of a class B misdemeanor; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the amount of $25 in the case of a class A misdemeanor; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if the defendant is a person other than an individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of $25 in the case of an infraction or a class C misdemeanor;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount of $50 in the case of a class B misdemeanor; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the amount of $125 in the case of a class A misdemeanor;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a felony—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount of $100 if the defendant is an individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of $400 if the defendant is a person other than an individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Such amount so assessed shall be collected in the manner that fines are collected in criminal cases.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The obligation to pay an assessment ceases five years after the date of the judgment. This subsection shall apply to all assessments irrespective of the date of imposition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, an offense under <ref>section 13 of this title</ref> is an offense against the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1405(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2174</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–185, § 3</ref>, <date date="1987-12-11">Dec. 11, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7082(b), 7085, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4407</ref>, 4408; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3569</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(r)(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3014.</num>
<heading> Additional special assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Beginning on the date of enactment of the Justice for Victims of Trafficking Act of 2015 and ending on <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>, in addition to the assessment imposed under section 3013, the court shall assess an amount of $5,000 on any non-indigent person or entity convicted of an offense under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> chapter 77 (relating to peonage, slavery, and trafficking in persons);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> chapter 109A (relating to sexual abuse);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> chapter 110 (relating to sexual exploitation and other abuse of children);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> chapter 117 (relating to transportation for illegal sexual activity and related crimes); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1324</ref>) (relating to human smuggling), unless the person induced, assisted, abetted, or aided only an individual who at the time of such action was the alien’s spouse, parent, son, or daughter (and no other individual) to enter the United States in violation of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Satisfaction of Other Court-Ordered Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assessment under subsection (a) shall not be payable until the person subject to the assessment has satisfied all outstanding court-ordered fines, orders of restitution, and any other obligation related to victim-compensation arising from the criminal convictions on which the special assessment is based.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Domestic Trafficking Victims’ Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the “Domestic Trafficking Victims’ Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Fund”), to be administered by the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In a manner consistent with <ref>section 3302(b) of title 31</ref>, there shall be transferred to the Fund from the General Fund of the Treasury an amount equal to the amount of the assessments collected under this section, which shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>From amounts in the Fund, in addition to any other amounts available, and without further appropriation, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2027, use amounts available in the Fund to award grants or enhance victims’ programming under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 204 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<ref>34 U.S.C. 20705</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subsections (b)(2) and (f) of section 107 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 7105</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> section 214(b) of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<ref>34 U.S.C. 20304</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002215">1</ref> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> section 106 of the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008 (<ref>34 U.S.C. 21116</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (h)(2), none of the amounts in the Fund may be used to provide health care or medical items or services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection Method</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount assessed under subsection (a) shall, subject to subsection (b), be collected in the manner that fines are collected in criminal cases, including the mandatory imposition of civil remedies for satisfaction of an unpaid fine as authorized under section 3613, where appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to section 3613(b), the obligation to pay an assessment imposed on or after the date of enactment of the Justice for Victims of Trafficking Act of 2015 shall not cease until the assessment is paid in full.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Health or Medical Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>From amounts appropriated under section 10503(b)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 254b–2(b)(1)</ref>) for fiscal year 2015 and each subsequent fiscal year (or period thereof), there shall be transferred to the Fund an amount equal to the amount transferred under subsection (d) for each fiscal year, except that the amount transferred under this paragraph shall not be less than $5,000,000 or more than $30,000,000 in each such fiscal year, and such amounts shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall use amounts transferred to the Fund under paragraph (1) to award grants that may be used for the provision of health care or medical items or services to victims of trafficking under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sections 202, 203, and 204 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 14044a</ref>, 14044b, and 14044c); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002216">2</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subsections (b)(2) and (f) of section 107 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 7105</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> section 214(b) of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 13002(b)</ref>).<sup>2</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the amounts in the Fund used under paragraph (1), not less than $2,000,000, if such amounts are available in the Fund during the relevant fiscal year, shall be used for grants to provide services for child pornography victims and child victims of a severe form of trafficking (as defined in section 103 of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 7102</ref>)) under section 214(b) of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 13002(b)</ref>).<sup>2</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of provision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The application of the provisions of section 221(c) of the Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015, section 50901(e) of the Advancing Chronic Care, Extenders, and Social Services Act, section 3831 of the CARES Act, section 2101 of the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2021 and Other Extensions Act, section 1201(d) of the Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2021, and Other Extensions Act, section 301(d) of division BB of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021, section 2321(d) of the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2024 and Other Extensions Act, section 201(d) of the Further Continuing Appropriations and Other Extensions Act, 2024, section 101(d) of the Further Additional Continuing Appropriations and Other Extensions Act, 2024, section 101(d) of division G of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2024, section 3101(d) of the Health Extensions and Other Matters Act, 2025, and section 2101(d) of division B of the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025 shall continue to apply to the amounts transferred pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, title IX, § 905, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 228</ref>, 266; <ref>Pub. L. 115–96, div. C, title I, § 3101(e)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2049</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–123, div. E, title IX, § 50901(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–392, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–59, div. B, title I, § 1101(e)</ref>, <date date="2019-09-27">Sept. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–69, div. B, title I, § 1101(e)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-21">Nov. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1136</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. N, title I, § 401(e)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3113</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III, § 3831(e)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–159, div. C, title I, § 2101(e)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-01">Oct. 1, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–215, div. B, title II, § 1201(e)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-11">Dec. 11, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1044</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title III, § 301(e)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–43, div. D, title I, § 3103</ref>, <date date="2021-09-30">Sept. 30, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–70, div. C, title I, § 2102</ref>, <date date="2021-12-03">Dec. 3, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–86, div. B, title I, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2022-02-18">Feb. 18, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. O, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 788</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–177, § 1</ref>, <date date="2022-09-16">Sept. 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2109</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–180, div. C, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2022-09-30">Sept. 30, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2133</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–229, div. B, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2022-12-16">Dec. 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. X, § 101</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6204</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–15, div. B, title III, § 2321(e)</ref>, <date date="2023-09-30">Sept. 30, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–22, div. B, title II, § 201(e)</ref>, <date date="2023-11-17">Nov. 17, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–35, div. B, title I, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="2024-01-19">Jan. 19, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–42, div. G, title I, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–158, div. C, title I, § 3101(e)</ref>, div. E, § 5103, <date date="2024-12-21">Dec. 21, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1763</ref>, 1771; <ref>Pub. L. 119–4, div. B, title I, § 2101(e)</ref>, div. C, § 3103, <date date="2025-03-15">Mar. 15, 2025</date>, <ref>139 Stat. 41</ref>, 46.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>