<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 319—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF CORRECTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4351.</num>
<heading> Establishment; Advisory Board; appointment of members; compensation; officers; committees; delegation of powers; Director, appointment and powers <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002288">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is hereby established within the Bureau of Prisons a National Institute of Corrections.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The overall policy and operations of the National Institute of Corrections shall be under the supervision of an Advisory Board. The Board shall consist of sixteen members. The following six individuals shall serve as members of the Commission ex officio: the Director of the Federal Bureau of Prisons or his designee, the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance or his designee, Chairman of the United States Sentencing Commission or his designee, the Director of the Federal Judicial Center or his designee, the Associate Administrator for the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002289">2</ref> or his designee, and the Assistant Secretary for Human Development of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare or his designee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The remaining ten members of the Board shall be selected as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Five shall be appointed initially by the Attorney General of the United States for staggered terms; one member shall serve for one year, one member for two years, and three members for three years. Upon the expiration of each member’s term, the Attorney General shall appoint successors who will each serve for a term of three years. Each member selected shall be qualified as a practitioner (Federal, State, or local) in the field of corrections, probation, or parole.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Five shall be appointed initially by the Attorney General of the United States for staggered terms, one member shall serve for one year, three members for two years, and one member for three years. Upon the expiration of each member’s term the Attorney General shall appoint successors who will each serve for a term of three years. Each member selected shall be from the private sector, such as business, labor, and education, having demonstrated an active interest in corrections, probation, or parole.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The members of the Board shall not, by reason of such membership, be deemed officers or employees of the United States. Members of the Commission who are full-time officers or employees of the United States shall serve without additional compensation, but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the perform­ance of the duties vested in the Board. Other members of the Board shall, while attending meetings of the Board or while engaged in duties related to such meetings or in other activities of the Commission pursuant to this title, be entitled to receive compensation at the rate not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate authorized for GS–18 by <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, including traveltime, and while away from their homes or regular places of business may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence equal to that authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Board shall elect a chairman from among its members who shall serve for a term of one year. The members of the Board shall also elect one or more members as a vice-chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Board is authorized to appoint, without regard to the civil service laws, technical, or other advisory committees to advise the Institute with respect to the administration of this title as it deems appropriate. Members of these committees not otherwise employed by the United States, while engaged in advising the Institute or attending meetings of the committees, shall be entitled to receive compensation at the rate fixed by the Board but not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate authorized for GS–18 by <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, and while away from their homes or regular places of business may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence equal to that authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Board is authorized to delegate its powers under this title to such persons as it deems appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Institute shall be under the supervision of an officer to be known as the Director, who shall be appointed by the Attorney General after consultation with the Board. The Director shall have authority to supervise the organization, employees, enrollees, financial affairs, and all other operations of the Institute and may employ such staff, faculty, and administrative personnel, subject to the civil service and classification laws, as are necessary to the functioning of the Institute. The Director shall have the power to acquire and hold real and personal property for the Institute and may receive gifts, donations, and trusts on behalf of the Institute. The Director shall also have the power to appoint such technical or other advisory councils comprised of consultants to guide and advise the Board. The Director is authorized to delegate his powers under this title to such persons as he deems appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–415, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1139</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–115, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-03">Oct. 3, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1060</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 223</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2030</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330001(i)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4352.</num>
<heading> Authority of Institute; time; records of recipients; access; scope of section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002290">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the other powers, express and implied, the National Institute of Corrections shall have authority—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to receive from or make grants to and enter into contracts with Federal, State, tribal, and general units of local government, public and private agencies, educational institutions, organizations, and individuals to carry out the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to serve as a clearinghouse and information center for the collection, preparation, and dissemination of information on corrections, including, but not limited to, programs for prevention of crime and recidivism, training of corrections personnel, and rehabilitation and treatment of criminal and juvenile offenders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to assist and serve in a consulting capacity to Federal, State, tribal, and local courts, departments, and agencies in the development, maintenance, and coordination of programs, facilities, and services, training, treatment, and rehabilitation with respect to criminal and juvenile offenders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to encourage and assist Federal, State, tribal, and local government programs and services, and programs and services of other public and private agencies, institutions, and organizations in their efforts to develop and implement improved corrections programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to devise and conduct, in various geographical locations, seminars, workshops, and training programs for law enforcement officers, judges, and judicial personnel, probation and parole personnel, correctional personnel, welfare workers, and other persons, including lay ex-offenders, and paraprofessional personnel, connected with the treatment and rehabilitation of criminal and juvenile offenders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to develop technical training teams to aid in the development of seminars, workshops, and training programs within the several States and tribal communities, and with the State, tribal, and local agencies which work with prisoners, parolees, probationers, and other offenders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to conduct, encourage, and coordinate research relating to corrections, including the causes, prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of criminal offenders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to formulate and disseminate correctional policy, goals, standards, and recommendations for Federal, State, tribal, and local correctional agencies, organizations, institutions, and personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to conduct evaluation programs which study the effectiveness of new approaches, techniques, systems, programs, and devices employed to improve the corrections system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to receive from any Federal department or agency such statistics, data, program reports, and other material as the Institute deems necessary to carry out its functions. Each such department or agency is authorized to cooperate with the Institute and shall, to the maximum extent practicable, consult with and furnish information to the Institute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> to arrange with and reimburse the heads of Federal departments and agencies for the use of personnel, facilities, or equipment of such departments and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> to confer with and avail itself of the assistance, services, records, and facilities of State, tribal, and local governments or other public or private agencies, organizations, or individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> to enter into contracts with public or private agencies, organizations, or individuals, for the performance of any of the functions of the Institute; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> to procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> of the United States Code, at rates of compensation not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate authorized for GS–18 by <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> of the United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(b)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–375, title I, § 109(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1820</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each recipient of assistance under this chapter shall keep such records as the Institute shall prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such assistance, the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which such assistance is given or used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Institute, and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for purposes of audit and examinations to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipients that are pertinent to the grants received under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The provision of this section shall apply to all recipients of assistance under this title, whether by direct grant or contract from the Institute or by subgrant or subcontract from primary grantees or contractors of the Institute.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–415, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1140</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–375, title I, § 109(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1820</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3599F</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 261(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2299</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4353.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1780</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>