<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 7—</num>
<heading>ASSAULT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 111.</num>
<heading> Assaulting, resisting, or impeding certain officers or employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> forcibly assaults, resists, opposes, impedes, intimidates, or interferes with any person designated in <ref>section 1114 of this title</ref> while engaged in or on account of the performance of official duties; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> forcibly assaults or intimidates any person who formerly served as a person designated in section 1114 on account of the performance of official duties during such person’s term of service,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall, where the acts in violation of this section constitute only simple assault, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both, and where such acts involve physical contact with the victim of that assault or the intent to commit another felony, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 8 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enhanced Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever, in the commission of any acts described in subsection (a), uses a deadly or dangerous weapon (including a weapon intended to cause death or danger but that fails to do so by reason of a defective component) or inflicts bodily injury, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extraterritorial Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is extraterritorial jurisdiction over the conduct prohibited by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6487(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4386</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320101(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 727(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11008(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1818</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title II, § 208(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–59, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-18">Nov. 18, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1469</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112.</num>
<heading> Protection of foreign officials, official guests, and internationally protected persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever assaults, strikes, wounds, imprisons, or offers violence to a foreign official, official guest, or internationally protected person or makes any other violent attack upon the person or liberty of such person, or, if likely to endanger his person or liberty, makes a violent attack upon his official premises, private accommodation, or means of transport or attempts to commit any of the foregoing shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both. Whoever in the commission of any such act uses a deadly or dangerous weapon, or inflicts bodily injury, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever willfully—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> intimidates, coerces, threatens, or harasses a foreign official or an official guest or obstructs a foreign official in the performance of his duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> attempts to intimidate, coerce, threaten, or harass a foreign official or an official guest or obstruct a foreign official in the performance of his duties; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> within the United States and within one hundred feet of any building or premises in whole or in part owned, used, or occupied for official business or for diplomatic, consular, or residential purposes by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a foreign government, including such use as a mission to an international organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an international organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a foreign official; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an official guest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">congregates with two or more other persons with intent to violate any other provision of this section;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section “foreign government”, “foreign official”, “internationally protected person”, “international organization”, “national of the United States”, and “official guest” shall have the same meanings as those provided in <ref>section 1116(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this section shall be construed or applied so as to abridge the exercise of rights guaranteed under the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the victim of an offense under subsection (a) is an internationally protected person outside the United States, the United States may exercise jurisdiction over the offense if (1) the victim is a representative, officer, employee, or agent of the United States, (2) an offender is a national of the United States, or (3) an offender is afterwards found in the United States. As used in this subsection, the United States includes all areas under the jurisdiction of the United States including any of the places within the provisions of sections 5 and 7 of this title and <ref>section 46501(2) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In the course of enforcement of subsection (a) and any other sections prohibiting a conspiracy or attempt to violate subsection (a), the Attorney General may request assistance from any Federal, State, or local agency, including the Army, Navy, and Air Force, any statute, rule, or regulation to the contrary, notwithstanding.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–493, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-08-27">Aug. 27, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–539, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1072</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–467, § 5</ref>, <date date="1976-10-08">Oct. 8, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1999</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–163, § 17(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–504, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-24">Oct. 24, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6478</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320101(b)</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G), (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2108</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 721(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(12)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 113.</num>
<heading> Assaults within maritime and territorial jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever, within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, is guilty of an assault shall be punished as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Assault with intent to commit murder or a violation of section 2241 or 2242, by a fine under this title, imprisonment for not more than 20 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Assault with intent to commit any felony, except murder or a violation of section 2241 or 2242, by a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Assault with a dangerous weapon, with intent to do bodily harm, by a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Assault by striking, beating, or wounding, by a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Simple assault, by a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than six months, or both, or if the victim of the assault is an individual who has not attained the age of 16 years, by fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Assault resulting in serious bodily injury, by a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Assault resulting in substantial bodily injury to a spouse or intimate partner, a dating partner, or an individual who has not attained the age of 16 years, by a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Assault of a spouse, intimate partner, or dating partner by strangling, suffocating, or attempting to strangle or suffocate, by a fine under this title, imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “substantial bodily injury” means bodily injury which involves—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a temporary but substantial disfigurement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a temporary but substantial loss or impairment of the function of any bodily member, organ, or mental faculty;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “serious bodily injury” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1365 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the terms “dating partner” and “spouse or intimate partner” have the meanings <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">1</ref> given those terms in section 2266;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “strangling” means intentionally, knowingly, or recklessly impeding the normal breathing or circulation of the blood of a person by applying pressure to the throat or neck, regardless of whether that conduct results in any visible injury or whether there is any intent to kill or protractedly injure the victim; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “suffocating” means intentionally, knowingly, or recklessly impeding the normal breathing of a person by covering the mouth of the person, the nose of the person, or both, regardless of whether that conduct results in any visible injury or whether there is any intent to kill or protractedly injure the victim.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 689</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–297, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-05-29">May 29, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 87(c)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–654, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3663</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XVII, § 170201(a)</ref>–(d), title XXXII, § 320101(c), title XXXIII, § 330016(2)(B), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2042</ref>, 2043, 2108, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(7)</ref>, (12)(B), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title IX, § 906(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 114.</num>
<heading> Maiming within maritime and territorial jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, and with intent to torture (as defined in section 2340), maim, or disfigure, cuts, bites, or slits the nose, ear, or lip, or cuts out or disables the tongue, or puts out or destroys an eye, or cuts off or disables a limb or any member of another person; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, and with like intent, throws or pours upon another person, any scalding water, corrosive acid, or caustic substance—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 689</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 3</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 90</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1009A</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3507</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(O)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 705(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 115.</num>
<heading> Influencing, impeding, or retaliating against a Federal official by threatening or injuring a family member</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assaults, kidnaps, or murders, or attempts or conspires to kidnap or murder, or threatens to assault, kidnap or murder a member of the immediate family of a United States official, a United States judge, a Federal law enforcement officer, or an official whose killing would be a crime under <ref>section 1114 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> threatens to assault, kidnap, or murder, a United States official, a United States judge, a Federal law enforcement officer, or an official whose killing would be a crime under such section,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">with intent to impede, intimidate, or interfere with such official, judge, or law enforcement officer while engaged in the performance of official duties, or with intent to retaliate against such official, judge, or law enforcement officer on account of the performance of official duties, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whoever assaults, kidnaps, or murders, or attempts or conspires to kidnap or murder, or threatens to assault, kidnap, or murder, any person who formerly served as a person designated in paragraph (1), or a member of the immediate family of any person who formerly served as a person designated in paragraph (1), with intent to retaliate against such person on account of the performance of official duties during the term of service of such person, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The punishment for an assault in violation of this section is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a fine under this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if the assault consists of a simple assault, a term of imprisonment for not more than 1 year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the assault involved physical contact with the victim of that assault or the intent to commit another felony, a term of imprisonment for not more than 10 years;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the assault resulted in bodily injury, a term of imprisonment for not more than 20 years; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> if the assault resulted in serious bodily injury (as that term is defined in <ref>section 1365 of this title</ref>, and including any conduct that, if the conduct occurred in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, would violate section 2241 or 2242 of this title) or a dangerous weapon was used during and in relation to the offense, a term of imprisonment for not more than 30 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A kidnapping, attempted kidnapping, or conspiracy to kidnap in violation of this section shall be punished as provided in <ref>section 1201 of this title</ref> for the kidnapping or attempted kidnapping of, or a conspiracy to kidnap, a person described in <ref>section 1201(a)(5) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A murder, attempted murder, or conspiracy to murder in violation of this section shall be punished as provided in sections 1111, 1113, and 1117 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A threat made in violation of this section shall be punished by a fine under this title or imprisonment for a term of not more than 10 years, or both, except that imprisonment for a threatened assault shall not exceed 6 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Federal law enforcement officer” means any officer, agent, or employee of the United States authorized by law or by a Government agency to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of Federal criminal law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “immediate family member” of an individual means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> his spouse, parent, brother or sister, child or person to whom he stands in loco parentis; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other person living in his household and related to him by blood or marriage;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “United States judge” means any judicial officer of the United States, and includes a justice of the Supreme Court and a United States magistrate judge; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “United States official” means the President, President-elect, Vice President, Vice President-elect, a Member of Congress, a member-elect of Congress, a member of the executive branch who is the head of a department listed in <ref>5 U.S.C. 101</ref>, or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> This section shall not interfere with the investigative authority of the United States Secret Service, as provided under sections 3056, 871, and 879 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> There is extraterritorial jurisdiction over the conduct prohibited by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1008(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2140</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–646</ref>, §§ 37(a), 60, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3599</ref>, 3613; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6487(f)[b]</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4386</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3508</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330016(2)(C), 330021(1), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>, 2150; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title VII</ref>, §§ 723(a), 727(b), <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1300</ref>, 1302; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(b)(9)</ref>, div. C, title I, § 11008(c), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1808</ref>, 1818; <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–59, § 3(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-18">Nov. 18, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1469</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 116.</num>
<heading> Female genital mutilation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), whoever, in any circumstance described in subsection (d), knowingly—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> performs, attempts to perform, or conspires to perform female genital mutilation on another person who has not attained the age of 18 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> being the parent, guardian, or caretaker of a person who has not attained the age of 18 years facilitates or consents to the female genital mutilation of such person; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> transports a person who has not attained the age of 18 years for the purpose of the performance of female genital mutilation on such person,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A surgical operation is not a violation of this section if the operation is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> necessary to the health of the person on whom it is performed, and is performed by a person licensed in the place of its performance as a medical practitioner; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> performed on a person in labor or who has just given birth and is performed for medical purposes connected with that labor or birth by a person licensed in the place it is performed as a medical practitioner, midwife, or person in training to become such a practitioner or midwife.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> It shall not be a defense to a prosecution under this section that female genital mutilation is required as a matter of religion, custom, tradition, ritual, or standard practice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the defendant or victim traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the defendant used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the defendant transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any instrument, item, substance, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, the term “female genital mutilation” means any procedure performed for non-medical reasons that involves partial or total removal of, or other injury to, the external female genitalia, and includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a clitoridectomy or the partial or total removal of the clitoris or the prepuce or clitoral hood;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> excision or the partial or total removal (with or without excision of the clitoris) of the labia minora or the labia majora, or both;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> infibulation or the narrowing of the vaginal opening (with or without excision of the clitoris); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> other procedures that are harmful to the external female genitalia, including pricking, incising, scraping, or cauterizing the genital area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title VI, § 645(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–709</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1088</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1970</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–309, § 3</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 117.</num>
<heading> Domestic assault by an habitual offender</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any person who commits a domestic assault within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States or Indian country and who has a final conviction on at least 2 separate prior occasions in Federal, State, or Indian tribal court proceedings for offenses that would be, if subject to Federal jurisdiction—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any assault, sexual abuse, or serious violent felony against a spouse or intimate partner, or against a child of or in the care of the person committing the domestic assault; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an offense under chapter 110A,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for a term of not more than 5 years, or both, except that if substantial bodily injury results from violation under this section, the offender shall be imprisoned for a term of not more than 10 years.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Domestic Assault Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “domestic assault” means an assault committed by a current or former spouse, parent, child, or guardian of the victim, by a person with whom the victim shares a child in common, by a person who is cohabitating with or has cohabitated with the victim as a spouse, parent, child, or guardian, or by a person similarly situated to a spouse, parent, child, or guardian of the victim.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title IX, § 909</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3084</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–104, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-05-20">May 20, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1156</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 118.</num>
<heading> Interference with certain protective functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who knowingly and willfully obstructs, resists, or interferes with a Federal law enforcement agent engaged, within the United States or the special maritime territorial jurisdiction of the United States, in the performance of the protective functions authorized under section 37 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2709</ref>) or section 103 of the Diplomatic Security Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4802</ref>) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–472, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-11">Jan. 11, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 119.</num>
<heading> Protection of individuals performing certain official duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever knowingly makes restricted personal information about a covered person, or a member of the immediate family of that covered person, publicly available—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with the intent to threaten, intimidate, or incite the commission of a crime of violence against that covered person, or a member of the immediate family of that covered person; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with the intent and knowledge that the restricted personal information will be used to threaten, intimidate, or facilitate the commission of a crime of violence against that covered person, or a member of the immediate family of that covered person,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “restricted personal information” means, with respect to an individual, the Social Security number, the home address, home phone number, mobile phone number, personal email, or home fax number of, and identifiable to, that individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “covered person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual designated in section 1114;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a grand or petit juror, witness, or other officer in or of, any court of the United States, or an officer who may be, or was, serving at any examination or other proceeding before any United States magistrate judge or other committing magistrate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an informant or witness in a Federal criminal investigation or prosecution; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a State or local officer or employee whose restricted personal information is made publicly available because of the participation in, or assistance provided to, a Federal criminal investigation by that officer or employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “crime of violence” has the meaning given the term in section 16; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “immediate family” has the meaning given the term in section 115(c)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>