<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 238—</num>
<heading>SEXUAL ASSAULT SURVIVORS’ RIGHTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3772.</num>
<heading> Sexual assault survivors’ rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rights of Sexual Assault Survivors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to those rights provided in section 3771, a sexual assault survivor has the following rights:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The right not to be prevented from, or charged for, receiving a medical forensic examination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The right to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (3), have a sexual assault evidence collection kit or its probative contents preserved, without charge, for the duration of the maximum applicable statute of limitations or 20 years, whichever is shorter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be informed of any result of a sexual assault evidence collection kit, including a DNA profile match, toxicology report, or other information collected as part of a medical forensic examination, if such disclosure would not impede or compromise an ongoing investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be informed in writing of policies governing the collection and preservation of a sexual assault evidence collection kit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> be informed of the status and location of a sexual assault evidence collection kit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The right to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> upon written request, receive written notification from the appropriate official with custody not later than 60 days before the date of the intended destruction or disposal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon written request, be granted further preservation of the kit or its probative contents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The right to be informed of the rights under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (b) through (f) of section 3771 shall apply to sexual assault survivors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Sexual Assault</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “sexual assault” means any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, tribal, or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section, other than paragraphs (2)(A) and (3)(B) of subsection (a), shall be carried out using funds made available under section 1402(d)(3)(A)(i) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 10601(d)(3)(A)(i)</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002278">1</ref> No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–236, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 966</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XV, § 1505</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 956</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>