<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 53—</num>
<heading>INDIANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1151.</num>
<heading> Indian country defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in sections 1154 and 1156 of this title, the term “Indian country”, as used in this chapter, means (a) all land within the limits of any Indian reservation under the jurisdiction of the United States Government, notwithstanding the issuance of any patent, and, including rights-of-way running through the reservation, (b) all dependent Indian communities within the borders of the United States whether within the original or subsequently acquired territory thereof, and whether within or without the limits of a state, and (c) all Indian allotments, the Indian titles to which have not been extinguished, including rights-of-way running through the same.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 757</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 25</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 94</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1152.</num>
<heading> Laws governing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, the general laws of the United States as to the punishment of offenses committed in any place within the sole and exclusive jurisdiction of the United States, except the District of Columbia, shall extend to the Indian country.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not extend to offenses committed by one Indian against the person or property of another Indian, nor to any Indian committing any offense in the Indian country who has been punished by the local law of the tribe, or to any case where, by treaty stipulations, the exclusive jurisdiction over such offenses is or may be secured to the Indian tribes respectively.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 757</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1153.</num>
<heading> Offenses committed within Indian country</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any Indian who commits against the person or property of another Indian or other person any of the following offenses, namely, murder, manslaughter, kidnapping, maiming, a felony under chapter 109A, incest, a felony assault under section 113, an assault against an individual who has not attained the age of 16 years, felony child abuse or neglect, arson, burglary, robbery, and a felony under <ref>section 661 of this title</ref> within the Indian country, shall be subject to the same law and penalties as all other persons committing any of the above offenses, within the exclusive jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any offense referred to in subsection (a) of this section that is not defined and punished by Federal law in force within the exclusive jurisdiction of the United States shall be defined and punished in accordance with the laws of the State in which such offense was committed as are in force at the time of such offense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 26</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 94</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–707, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–284, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–297, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-05-29">May 29, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 585</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1009</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–303</ref>, <date date="1986-05-15">May 15, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 87(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–654, § 3(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3663</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7027</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XVII, § 170201(e)</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330021(1), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2043</ref>, 2150; <ref>Pub. L. 109–248, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title IX, § 906(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1154.</num>
<heading> Intoxicants dispensed in Indian country</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever sells, gives away, disposes of, exchanges, or barters any malt, spirituous, or vinous liquor, including beer, ale, and wine, or any ardent or other intoxicating liquor of any kind whatsoever, except for scientific, sacramental, medicinal or mechanical purposes, or any essence, extract, bitters, preparation, compound, composition, or any article whatsoever, under any name, label, or brand, which produces intoxication, to any Indian to whom an allotment of land has been made while the title to the same shall be held in trust by the Government, or to any Indian who is a ward of the Government under charge of any Indian superintendent, or to any Indian, including mixed bloods, over whom the Government, through its departments, exercises guardianship, and whoever introduces or attempts to introduce any malt, spirituous, or vinous liquor, including beer, ale, and wine, or any ardent or intoxicating liquor of any kind whatsoever into the Indian country, shall, for the first offense, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and, for each subsequent offense, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> It shall be a sufficient defense to any charge of introducing or attempting to introduce ardent spirits, ale, beer, wine, or intoxicating liquors into the Indian country that the acts charged were done under authority, in writing, from the Department of the Army or any officer duly authorized thereunto by the Department of the Army, but this subsection shall not bar the prosecution of any officer, soldier, sutler or storekeeper, attaché, or employee of the Army of the United States who barters, donates, or furnishes in any manner whatsoever liquors, beer, or any intoxicating beverage whatsoever to any Indian.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The term “Indian country” as used in this section does not include fee-patented lands in non-Indian communities or rights-of-way through Indian reservations, and this section does not apply to such lands or rights-of-way in the absence of a treaty or statute extending the Indian liquor laws thereto.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 27</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 94</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, (I), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1155.</num>
<heading> Intoxicants dispensed on school site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, on any tract of land in the former Indian country upon which is located any Indian school maintained by or under the supervision of the United States, manufactures, sells, gives away, or in any manner, or by any means furnishes to anyone, either for himself or another, any vinous, malt, or fermented liquors, or any other intoxicating drinks of any kind whatsoever, except for scientific, sacramental, medicinal or mechanical purposes, whether medicated or not, or who carries, or in any manner has carried, into such area any such liquors or drinks, or who shall be interested in such manufacture, sale, giving away, furnishing to anyone, or carrying into such area any of such liquors or drinks, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1156.</num>
<heading> Intoxicants possessed unlawfully</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, except for scientific, sacramental, medicinal or mechanical purposes, possesses intoxicating liquors in the Indian country or where the introduction is prohibited by treaty or an Act of Congress, shall, for the first offense, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and, for each subsequent offense, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">The term “Indian country” as used in this section does not include fee-patented lands in non-Indian communities or rights-of-way through Indian reservations, and this section does not apply to such lands or rights-of-way in the absence of a treaty or statute extending the Indian liquor laws thereto.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 28</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 94</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, (I), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1157.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 85–86</ref>, <date date="1957-07-10">July 10, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 277</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1158.</num>
<heading> Counterfeiting Indian Arts and Crafts Board trade mark</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever counterfeits or colorably imitates any Government trade mark used or devised by the Indian Arts and Crafts Board in the Department of the Interior as provided in <ref>section 305a of Title 25</ref>, or, except as authorized by the Board, affixes any such Government trade mark, or knowingly, willfully, and corruptly affixes any reproduction, counterfeit, copy, or colorable imitation thereof upon any products, or to any labels, signs, prints, packages, wrappers, or receptacles intended to be used upon or in connection with the sale of such products; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly makes any false statement for the purpose of obtaining the use of any such Government trade mark—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall (1) in the case of a first violation, if an individual, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both, and, if a person other than an individual, be fined not more than $1,000,000; and (2) in the case of subsequent violations, if an individual, be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned not more than fifteen years, or both, and, if a person other than an individual, be fined not more than $5,000,000; and (3) shall be enjoined from further carrying on the act or acts complained of.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–644, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4665</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(U)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1159.</num>
<heading> Misrepresentation of Indian produced goods and products</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> It is unlawful to offer or display for sale or sell any good, with or without a Government trademark, in a manner that falsely suggests it is Indian produced, an Indian product, or the product of a particular Indian or Indian tribe or Indian arts and crafts organization, resident within the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any person that knowingly violates subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a first violation by that person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> if the applicable goods are offered or displayed for sale at a total price of $1,000 or more, or if the applicable goods are sold for a total price of $1,000 or more—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual, be fined not more than $250,000, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a person other than an individual, be fined not more than $1,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> if the applicable goods are offered or displayed for sale at a total price of less than $1,000, or if the applicable goods are sold for a total price of less than $1,000—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual, be fined not more than $25,000, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a person other than an individual, be fined not more than $100,000; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a subsequent violation by that person, regardless of the amount for which any good is offered or displayed for sale or sold—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual, be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 15 years, or both; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a person other than an individual, be fined not more than $5,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Indian” means any individual who is a member of an Indian tribe, or for the purposes of this section is certified as an Indian artisan by an Indian tribe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “Indian product” and “product of a particular Indian tribe or Indian arts and crafts organization” has the meaning given such term in regulations which may be promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “Indian tribe”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 450b</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002102">1</ref> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes, for purposes of this section only, an Indian group that has been formally recognized as an Indian tribe by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a State legislature;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a State commission; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> another similar organization vested with State legislative tribal recognition authority; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Indian arts and crafts organization” means any legally established arts and crafts marketing organization composed of members of Indian tribes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In the event that any provision of this section is held invalid, it is the intent of Congress that the remaining provisions of this section shall continue in full force and effect.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–644, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4663</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1160.</num>
<heading> Property damaged in committing offense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever a non-Indian, in the commission of an offense within the Indian country takes, injures or destroys the property of any friendly Indian the judgment of conviction shall include a sentence that the defendant pay to the Indian owner a sum equal to twice the just value of the property so taken, injured, or destroyed.</p>
<p class="indent0">If such offender shall be unable to pay a sum at least equal to the just value or amount, whatever such payment shall fall short of the same shall be paid out of the Treasury of the United States. If such offender cannot be apprehended and brought to trial, the amount of such property shall be paid out of the Treasury. But no Indian shall be entitled to any payment out of the Treasury of the United States, for any such property, if he, or any of the nation to which he belongs, have sought private revenge, or have attempted to obtain satisfaction by any force or violence.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330004(9)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1161.</num>
<heading> Application of Indian liquor laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of sections 1154, 1156, 3113, 3488, and 3669, of this title, shall not apply within any area that is not Indian country, nor to any act or transaction within any area of Indian country provided such act or transaction is in conformity both with the laws of the State in which such act or transaction occurs and with an ordinance duly adopted by the tribe having jurisdiction over such area of Indian country, certified by the Secretary of the Interior, and published in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Aug. 15, 1953, ch. 502, § 2</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 586</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 223(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2028</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1162.</num>
<heading> State jurisdiction over offenses committed by or against Indians in the Indian country</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each of the States or Territories listed in the following table shall have jurisdiction over offenses committed by or against Indians in the areas of Indian country listed opposite the name of the State or Territory to the same extent that such State or Territory has jurisdiction over offenses committed elsewhere within the State or Territory, and the criminal laws of such State or Territory shall have the same force and effect within such Indian country as they have elsewhere within the State or Territory:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><i>State or Territory of</i></p></th><th><p><i>Indian country affected</i></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Alaska</span></p></td><td><p>All Indian country within the State, except that on Annette Islands, the Metlakatla Indian community may exercise jurisdiction over offenses committed by Indians in the same manner in which such jurisdiction may be exercised by Indian tribes in Indian country over which State jurisdiction has not been extended.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>California</span></p></td><td><p>All Indian country within the State.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Minnesota</span></p></td><td><p>All Indian country within the State, except the Red Lake Reservation.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Nebraska</span></p></td><td><p>All Indian country within the State.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Oregon</span></p></td><td><p>All Indian country within the State, except the Warm Springs Reservation.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Wisconsin</span></p></td><td><p>All Indian country within the State.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall authorize the alienation, encumbrance, or taxation of any real or personal property, including water rights, belonging to any Indian or any Indian tribe, band, or community that is held in trust by the United States or is subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States; or shall authorize regulation of the use of such property in a manner inconsistent with any Federal treaty, agreement, or statute or with any regulation made pursuant thereto; or shall deprive any Indian or any Indian tribe, band, or community of any right, privilege, or immunity afforded under Federal treaty, agreement, or statute with respect to hunting, trapping, or fishing or the control, licensing, or regulation thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The provisions of sections 1152 and 1153 of this chapter shall not be applicable within the areas of Indian country listed in subsection (a) of this section as areas over which the several States have exclusive jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (c), at the request of an Indian tribe, and after consultation with and consent by the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sections 1152 and 1153 shall apply in the areas of the Indian country of the Indian tribe; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> jurisdiction over those areas shall be concurrent among the Federal Government, State governments, and, where applicable, tribal governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Aug. 15, 1953, ch. 505, § 2</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 588</ref>; amended <ref>Aug. 24, 1954, ch. 910, § 1</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 795</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–615, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-08-08">Aug. 8, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–523</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1970-11-25">Nov. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1163.</num>
<heading> Embezzlement and theft from Indian tribal organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever embezzles, steals, knowingly converts to his use or the use of another, willfully misapplies, or willfully permits to be misapplied, any of the moneys, funds, credits, goods, assets, or other property belonging to any Indian tribal organization or intrusted to the custody or care of any officer, employee, or agent of an Indian tribal organization; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, knowing any such moneys, funds, credits, goods, assets, or other property to have been so embezzled, stolen, converted, misapplied or permitted to be misapplied, receives, conceals, or retains the same with intent to convert it to his use or the use of another—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; but if the value of such property does not exceed the sum of $1,000, he shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “Indian tribal organization” means any tribe, band, or community of Indians which is subject to the laws of the United States relating to Indian affairs or any corporation, association, or group which is organized under any of such laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 822, § 2</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 792</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1164.</num>
<heading> Destroying boundary and warning signs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever willfully destroys, defaces, or removes any sign erected by an Indian tribe, or a Government agency (1) to indicate the boundary of an Indian reservation or of any Indian country as defined in <ref>section 1151 of this title</ref> or (2) to give notice that hunting, trapping, or fishing is not permitted thereon without lawful authority or permission, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–634, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 469</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1165.</num>
<heading> Hunting, trapping, or fishing on Indian land</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without lawful authority or permission, willfully and knowingly goes upon any land that belongs to any Indian or Indian tribe, band, or group and either are held by the United States in trust or are subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States, or upon any lands of the United States that are reserved for Indian use, for the purpose of hunting, trapping, or fishing thereon, or for the removal of game, peltries, or fish therefrom, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ninety days, or both, and all game, fish, and peltries in his possession shall be forfeited.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–634, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 469</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1166.</num>
<heading> Gambling in Indian country</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (c), for purposes of Federal law, all State laws pertaining to the licensing, regulation, or prohibition of gambling, including but not limited to criminal sanctions applicable thereto, shall apply in Indian country in the same manner and to the same extent as such laws apply elsewhere in the State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever in Indian country is guilty of any act or omission involving gambling, whether or not conducted or sanctioned by an Indian tribe, which, although not made punishable by any enactment of Congress, would be punishable if committed or omitted within the jurisdiction of the State in which the act or omission occurred, under the laws governing the licensing, regulation, or prohibition of gambling in force at the time of such act or omission, shall be guilty of a like offense and subject to a like punishment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section, the term “gambling” does not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> class I gaming or class II gaming regulated by the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> class III gaming conducted under a Tribal-State compact approved by the Secretary of the Interior under section 11(d)(8) of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act that is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction over criminal prosecutions of violations of State gambling laws that are made applicable under this section to Indian country, unless an Indian tribe pursuant to a Tribal-State compact approved by the Secretary of the Interior under section 11(d)(8) of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, or under any other provision of Federal law, has consented to the transfer to the State of criminal jurisdiction with respect to gambling on the lands of the Indian tribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 23</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2487</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1167.</num>
<heading> Theft from gaming establishments on Indian lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever abstracts, purloins, willfully misapplies, or takes and carries away with intent to steal, any money, funds, or other property of a value of $1,000 or less belonging to an establishment operated by or for or licensed by an Indian tribe pursuant to an ordinance or resolution approved by the National Indian Gaming Commission shall be fined under this title or be imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever abstracts, purloins, willfully misapplies, or takes and carries away with intent to steal, any money, funds, or other property of a value in excess of $1,000 belonging to a gaming establishment operated by or for or licensed by an Indian tribe pursuant to an ordinance or resolution approved by the National Indian Gaming Commission shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned for not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 23</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2487</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(S)</ref>, (U), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1168.</num>
<heading> Theft by officers or employees of gaming establishments on Indian lands</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, being an officer, employee, or individual licensee of a gaming establishment operated by or for or licensed by an Indian tribe pursuant to an ordinance or resolution approved by the National Indian Gaming Commission, embezzles, abstracts, purloins, willfully misapplies, or takes and carries away with intent to steal, any moneys, funds, assets, or other property of such establishment of a value of $1,000 or less shall be fined not more than $250,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever, being an officer, employee, or individual licensee of a gaming establishment operated by or for or licensed by an Indian tribe pursuant to an ordinance or resolution approved by the National Indian Gaming Commission, embezzles, abstracts, purloins, willfully misapplies, or takes and carries away with intent to steal, any moneys, funds, assets, or other property of such establishment of a value in excess of $1,000 shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned for not more than twenty years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–497, § 23</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2487</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3537</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4925</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1169.</num>
<heading> Reporting of child abuse</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> is a—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> physician, surgeon, dentist, podiatrist, chiropractor, nurse, dental hygienist, optometrist, medical examiner, emergency medical technician, paramedic, or health care provider,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> teacher, school counselor, instructional aide, teacher’s aide, teacher’s assistant, or bus driver employed by any tribal, Federal, public or private school,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> administrative officer, supervisor of child welfare and attendance, or truancy officer of any tribal, Federal, public or private school,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> child day care worker, headstart teacher, public assistance worker, worker in a group home or residential or day care facility, or social worker,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> psychiatrist, psychologist, or psychological assistant,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> licensed or unlicensed marriage, family, or child counselor,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> person employed in the mental health profession, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> law enforcement officer, probation officer, worker in a juvenile rehabilitation or detention facility, or person employed in a public agency who is responsible for enforcing statutes and judicial orders;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> knows, or has reasonable suspicion, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a child was abused in Indian country, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> actions are being taken, or are going to be taken, that would reasonably be expected to result in abuse of a child in Indian country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> fails to immediately report such abuse or actions described in paragraph (2) to the local child protective services agency or local law enforcement agency,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 6 months or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> supervises, or has authority over, a person described in subsection (a)(1), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inhibits or prevents that person from making the report described in subsection (a),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 6 months or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “abuse” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any case in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a child is dead or exhibits evidence of skin bruising, bleeding, malnutrition, failure to thrive, burns, fracture of any bone, subdural hematoma, soft tissue swelling, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such condition is not justifiably explained or may not be the product of an accidental occurrence; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any case in which a child is subjected to sexual assault, sexual molestation, sexual exploitation, sexual contact, or prostitution;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “child” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not married, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has not attained 18 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “local child protective services agency” means that agency of the Federal Government, of a State, or of an Indian tribe that has the primary responsibility for child protection on any Indian reservation or within any community in Indian country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “local law enforcement agency” means that Federal, tribal, or State law enforcement agency that has the primary responsibility for the investigation of an instance of alleged child abuse within the portion of Indian country involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any person making a report described in subsection (a) which is based upon their reasonable belief and which is made in good faith shall be immune from civil or criminal liability for making that report.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–630, title IV, § 404(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4547</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330011(d), 330016(1)(K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2144</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(25)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1170.</num>
<heading> Illegal trafficking in Native American human remains and cultural items</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly sells, purchases, uses for profit, or transports for sale or profit, the human remains of a Native American without the right of possession to those remains as provided in the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act shall be fined in accordance with this title, or imprisoned not more than 1 year and 1 day, or both, and in the case of a second or subsequent violation, be fined in accordance with this title, or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly sells, purchases, uses for profit, or transports for sale or profit any Native American cultural items obtained in violation of the Native American Grave Protection and Repatriation Act shall be fined in accordance with this title, imprisoned not more than one year, or both, and in the case of a second or subsequent violation, be fined in accordance with this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–601, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3052</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330010(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–258, § 4</ref>, <date date="2022-12-21">Dec. 21, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>