<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>EMBEZZLEMENT AND THEFT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 641.</num>
<heading> Public money, property or records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever embezzles, steals, purloins, or knowingly converts to his use or the use of another, or without authority, sells, conveys or disposes of any record, voucher, money, or thing of value of the United States or of any department or agency thereof, or any property made or being made under contract for the United States or any department or agency thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives, conceals, or retains the same with intent to convert it to his use or gain, knowing it to have been embezzled, stolen, purloined or converted—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the value of such property in the aggregate, combining amounts from all the counts for which the defendant is convicted in a single case, does not exceed the sum of $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">The word “value” means face, par, or market value, or cost price, either wholesale or retail, whichever is greater.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (L), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–275, § 4</ref>, <date date="2004-07-15">July 15, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 642.</num>
<heading> Tools and materials for counterfeiting purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without authority from the United States, secretes within, or embezzles, or takes and carries away from any building, room, office, apartment, vault, safe, or other place where the same is kept, used, employed, placed, lodged, or deposited by authority of the United States, any tool, implement, or thing used or fitted to be used in stamping or printing, or in making some other tool or implement used or fitted to be used in stamping or printing any kind or description of bond, bill, note, certificate, coupon, postage stamp, revenue stamp, fractional currency note, or other paper, instrument, obligation, device, or document, authorized by law to be printed, stamped, sealed, prepared, issued, uttered, or put in circulation on behalf of the United States; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without such authority, so secretes, embezzles, or takes and carries away any paper, parchment, or other material prepared and intended to be used in the making of any such papers, instruments, obligations, devices, or documents; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without such authority, so secretes, embezzles, or takes and carries away any paper, parchment, or other material printed or stamped, in whole or part, and intended to be prepared, issued, or put in circulation on behalf of the United States as one of such papers, instruments, or obligations, or printed or stamped, in whole or part, in the similitude of any such paper, instrument, or obligation, whether intended to issue or put the same in circulation or not—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 643.</num>
<heading> Accounting generally for public money</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, employee or agent of the United States or of any department or agency thereof, having received public money which he is not authorized to retain as salary, pay, or emolument, fails to render his accounts for the same as provided by law is guilty of embezzlement, and shall be fined under this title or in a sum equal to the amount of the money embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 644.</num>
<heading> Banker receiving unauthorized deposit of public money</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, not being an authorized depositary of public moneys, knowingly receives from any disbursing officer, or collector of internal revenue, or other agent of the United States, any public money on deposit, or by way of loan or accommodation, with or without interest, or otherwise than in payment of a debt against the United States, or uses, transfers, converts, appropriates, or applies any portion of the public money for any purpose not prescribed by law is guilty of embezzlement and shall be fined under this title or not more than the amount so embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(2)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 645.</num>
<heading> Court officers generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a United States marshal, clerk, receiver, referee, trustee, or other officer of a United States court, or any deputy, assistant, or employee of any such officer, retains or converts to his own use or to the use of another or after demand by the party entitled thereto, unlawfully retains any money coming into his hands by virtue of his official relation, position or employment, is guilty of embezzlement and shall, where the offense is not otherwise punishable by enactment of Congress, be fined under this title or not more than double the value of the money so embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be a defense that the accused person had any interest in such moneys or fund.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 646.</num>
<heading> Court officers depositing registry moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a clerk or other officer of a court of the United States, fails to deposit promptly any money belonging in the registry of the court, or paid into court or received by the officers thereof, with the Treasurer or a designated depositary of the United States, in the name and to the credit of such court, or retains or converts to his own use or to the use of another any such money, is guilty of embezzlement and shall be fined under this title or not more than the amount embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not prevent the delivery of any such money upon security, according to agreement of parties, under the direction of the court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(H), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 647.</num>
<heading> Receiving loan from court officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever knowingly receives, from a clerk or other officer of a court of the United States, as a deposit, loan, or otherwise, any money belonging in the registry of such court, is guilty of embezzlement, and shall be fined under this title or not more than the amount embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 648.</num>
<heading> Custodians, generally, misusing public funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer or other person charged by any Act of Congress with the safe-keeping of the public moneys, loans, uses, or converts to his own use, or deposits in any bank, including any branch or agency of a foreign bank (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978), or exchanges for other funds, except as specially allowed by law, any portion of the public moneys intrusted to him for safe-keeping, is guilty of embezzlement of the money so loaned, used, converted, deposited, or exchanged, and shall be fined under this title or in a sum equal to the amount of money so embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2597(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649.</num>
<heading> Custodians failing to deposit moneys; persons affected</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, having money of the United States in his possession or under his control, fails to deposit it with the Treasurer or some public depositary of the United States, when required so to do by the Secretary of the Treasury or the head of any other proper department or agency or by the Government Accountability Office, is guilty of embezzlement, and shall be fined under this title or in a sum equal to the amount of money embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled is $1,000 or less, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section and sections 643, 648, 650 and 653 of this title shall apply to all persons charged with the safe-keeping, transfer, or disbursement of the public money, whether such persons be charged as receivers or depositaries of the same.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 650.</num>
<heading> Depositaries failing to safeguard deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Treasurer of the United States or any public depositary fails to keep safely all moneys deposited by any disbursing officer or disbursing agent, as well as all moneys deposited by any receiver, collector, or other person having money of the United States, he is guilty of embezzlement, and shall be fined under this title or in a sum equal to the amount of money so embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 651.</num>
<heading> Disbursing officer falsely certifying full payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer charged with the disbursement of the public moneys, accepts, receives, or transmits to the Government Accountability Office to be allowed in his favor any receipt or voucher from a creditor of the United States without having paid the full amount specified therein to such creditor in such funds as the officer received for disbursement, or in such funds as he may be authorized by law to take in exchange, shall be fined under this title or in double the amount so withheld, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than two years, or both; but if the amount withheld does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 652.</num>
<heading> Disbursing officer paying lesser in lieu of lawful amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, clerk, agent, employee, or other person charged with the payment of any appropriation made by Congress, pays to any clerk or other employee of the United States, or of any department or agency thereof, a sum less than that provided by law, and requires such employee to receipt or give a voucher for an amount greater than that actually paid to and received by him, is guilty of embezzlement, and shall be fined under this title or in double the amount so withheld, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than two years, or both; but if the amount embezzled is $1,000 or less, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 653.</num>
<heading> Disbursing officer misusing public funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a disbursing officer of the United States, or any department or agency thereof, or a person acting as such, in any manner converts to his own use, or loans with or without interest, or deposits in any place or in any manner, except as authorized by law, any public money intrusted to him; or, for any purpose not prescribed by law, withdraws from the Treasury or any authorized depositary, or transfers, or applies, any portion of the public money intrusted to him, is guilty of embezzlement of the money so converted, loaned, deposited, withdrawn, transferred, or applied, and shall be fined under this title or not more than the amount embezzled, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the amount embezzled is $1,000 or less, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 654.</num>
<heading> Officer or employee of United States converting property of another</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer or employee of the United States or of any department or agency thereof, embezzles or wrongfully converts to his own use the money or property of another which comes into his possession or under his control in the execution of such office or employment, or under color or claim of authority as such officer or employee, shall be fined under this title or not more than the value of the money and property thus embezzled or converted, whichever is greater, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; but if the sum embezzled is $1,000 or less, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (2)(H), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 655.</num>
<heading> Theft by bank examiner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a bank examiner or assistant examiner, steals, or unlawfully takes, or unlawfully conceals any money, note, draft, bond, or security or any other property of value in the possession of any bank or banking institution which is a member of the Federal Reserve System, which is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, which is a branch or agency of a foreign bank (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978), or which is an organization operating under section 25 or section 25(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002051">1</ref> of the Federal Reserve Act, or from any safe deposit box in or adjacent to the premises of such bank, branch, agency, or organization, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; but if the amount taken or concealed does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and shall be disqualified from holding office as a national bank examiner or Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation examiner.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to all public examiners and assistant examiners who examine member banks of the Federal Reserve System, banks the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, branches or agencies of foreign banks (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978), or organizations operating under section 25 or section 25(a) <sup>1</sup> of the Federal Reserve Act, whether appointed by the Comptroller of the Currency, by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, by a Federal Reserve Agent, by a Federal Reserve bank, or by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or appointed or elected under the laws of any State; but shall not apply to private examiners or assistant examiners employed only by a clearing-house association or by the directors of a bank.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2597(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 656.</num>
<heading> Theft, embezzlement, or misapplication by bank officer or employee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, director, agent or employee of, or connected in any capacity with any Federal Reserve bank, member bank, depository institution holding company, national bank, insured bank, branch or agency of a foreign bank, or organization operating under section 25 or section 25(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002052">1</ref> of the Federal Reserve Act, or a receiver of a national bank, insured bank, branch, agency, or organization or any agent or employee of the receiver, or a Federal Reserve Agent, or an agent or employee of a Federal Reserve Agent or of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, embezzles, abstracts, purloins or willfully misapplies any of the moneys, funds or credits of such bank, branch, agency, or organization or holding company or any moneys, funds, assets or securities intrusted to the custody or care of such bank, branch, agency, or organization, or holding company or to the custody or care of any such agent, officer, director, employee or receiver, shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 30 years, or both; but if the amount embezzled, abstracted, purloined or misapplied does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “national bank” is synonymous with “national banking association”; “member bank” means and includes any national bank, state bank, or bank and trust company which has become a member of one of the Federal Reserve banks; “insured bank” includes any bank, banking association, trust company, savings bank, or other banking institution, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and the term “branch or agency of a foreign bank” means a branch or agency described in <ref>section 20(9) of this title</ref>. For purposes of this section, the term “depository institution holding company” has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 961(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV</ref>, §§ 2504(b), 2595(a)(1), 2597(f), <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4861</ref>, 4906, 4909; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI</ref>, §§ 601(f)(1), 606(a), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3499</ref>, 3511.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 657.</num>
<heading> Lending, credit and insurance institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, agent or employee of or connected in any capacity with the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, National Credit Union Administration, any Federal home loan bank, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, Farm Credit Administration, Department of Housing and Urban Development, Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, the Secretary of Agriculture acting through the Farmers Home Administration or successor agency, the Rural Development Administration or successor agency, or the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation, a Farm Credit Bank, a bank for cooperatives or any lending, mortgage, insurance, credit or savings and loan corporation or association authorized or acting under the laws of the United States or any institution, other than an insured bank (as defined in section 656), the accounts of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or by the National Credit Union Administration Board or any small business investment company, or any community development financial institution receiving financial assistance under the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994, and whoever, being a receiver of any such institution, or agent or employee of the receiver, embezzles, abstracts, purloins or willfully misapplies any moneys, funds, credits, securities or other things of value belonging to such institution, or pledged or otherwise intrusted to its care, shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 30 years, or both; but if the amount or value embezzled, abstracted, purloined or misapplied does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 11</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 90</ref>; <ref>July 28, 1956, ch. 773, § 1</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–699, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1958-08-21">Aug. 21, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–353, § 3(q)</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–19, § 24(a)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–468, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-10-19">Oct. 19, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–73, title IX</ref>, §§ 961(c), 962(a)(7), (8)(A), <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 499</ref>, 502; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2303(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XVI, § 1603</ref>, title XXV, §§ 2504(c), 2595(a)(2), <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4843</ref>, 4861, 4907; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330004(6), 330016(1)(H), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2141</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 119(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2188</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 767</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1174</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title II, § 1216(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 377(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 658.</num>
<heading> Property mortgaged or pledged to farm credit agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with intent to defraud, knowingly conceals, removes, disposes of, or converts to his own use or to that of another, any property mortgaged or pledged to, or held by, the Farm Credit Administration, any Federal intermediate credit bank, or the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, the Secretary of Agriculture acting through the Farmers Home Administration or successor agency, the Rural Development Administration or successor agency, any production credit association organized under sections 1131–1134m of Title 12, any regional agricultural credit corporation, or any bank for cooperatives, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; but if the value of such property does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 12</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 91</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 21</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 718</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1956, ch. 741</ref>, title I, § 109, <ref>70 Stat. 667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–353, § 3(r)</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2303(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330004(7), 330016(1)(H), (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2141</ref>, 2147; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 767</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 659.</num>
<heading> Interstate or foreign shipments by carrier; State prosecutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever embezzles, steals, or unlawfully takes, carries away, or conceals, or by fraud or deception obtains from any pipeline system, railroad car, wagon, motortruck, trailer, or other vehicle, or from any tank or storage facility, station, station house, platform or depot or from any steamboat, vessel, or wharf, or from any aircraft, air cargo container, air terminal, airport, aircraft terminal or air navigation facility, or from any intermodal container, trailer, container freight station, warehouse, or freight consolidation facility, with intent to convert to his own use any goods or chattels moving as or which are a part of or which constitute an interstate or foreign shipment of freight, express, or other property; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever buys or receives or has in his possession any such goods or chattels, knowing the same to have been embezzled or stolen; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever embezzles, steals, or unlawfully takes, carries away, or by fraud or deception obtains with intent to convert to his own use any baggage which shall have come into the possession of any common carrier for transportation in interstate or foreign commerce or breaks into, steals, takes, carries away, or conceals any of the contents of such baggage, or buys, receives, or has in his possession any such baggage or any article therefrom of whatever nature, knowing the same to have been embezzled or stolen; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever embezzles, steals, or unlawfully takes by any fraudulent device, scheme, or game, from any railroad car, bus, vehicle, steamboat, vessel, or aircraft operated by any common carrier moving in interstate or foreign commerce or from any passenger thereon any money, baggage, goods, or chattels, or whoever buys, receives, or has in his possession any such money, baggage, goods, or chattels, knowing the same to have been embezzled or stolen—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both, but if the amount or value of such money, baggage, goods, or chattels is less than $1,000, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both. If the offense involves a pre-retail medical product (as defined in section 670), it shall be punished under section 670 unless the penalties provided for under this section are greater.</p>
<p class="indent0">The offense shall be deemed to have been committed not only in the district where the violation first occurred, but also in any district in which the defendant may have taken or been in possession of the said money, baggage, goods, or chattels.</p>
<p class="indent0">The carrying or transporting of any such money, freight, express, baggage, goods, or chattels in interstate or foreign commerce, knowing the same to have been stolen, shall constitute a separate offense and subject the offender to the penalties under this section for unlawful taking, and the offense shall be deemed to have been committed in any district into which such money, freight, express, baggage, goods, or chattels shall have been removed or into which the same shall have been brought by such offender.</p>
<p class="indent0">To establish the interstate or foreign commerce character of any shipment in any prosecution under this section the waybill or other shipping document of such shipment shall be prima facie evidence of the place from which and to which such shipment was made. For purposes of this section, goods and chattel shall be construed to be moving as an interstate or foreign shipment at all points between the point of origin and the final destination (as evidenced by the waybill or other shipping document of the shipment), regardless of any temporary stop while awaiting transshipment or otherwise. The removal of property from a pipeline system which extends interstate shall be prima facie evidence of the interstate character of the shipment of the property.</p>
<p class="indent0">A judgment of conviction or acquittal on the merits under the laws of any State shall be a bar to any prosecution under this section for the same act or acts. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as indicating an intent on the part of Congress to occupy the field in which provisions of this section operate to the exclusion of State laws on the same subject matter, nor shall any provision of this section be construed as invalidating any provision of State law unless such provision is inconsistent with any of the purposes of this section or any provision thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 13</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 91</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–654, § 1(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="1966-10-14">Oct. 14, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 904</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title III, § 307(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–186, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-10-05">Oct. 5, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 660.</num>
<heading> Carrier’s funds derived from commerce; State prosecutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a president, director, officer, or manager of any firm, association, or corporation engaged in commerce as a common carrier, or whoever, being an employee of such common carrier riding in or upon any railroad car, motortruck, steamboat, vessel, aircraft or other vehicle of such carrier moving in interstate commerce, embezzles, steals, abstracts, or willfully misapplies, or willfully permits to be misapplied, any of the moneys, funds, credits, securities, property, or assets of such firm, association, or corporation arising or accruing from, or used in, such commerce, in whole or in part, or willfully or knowingly converts the same to his own use or to the use of another, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">The offense shall be deemed to have been committed not only in the district where the violation first occurred but also in any district in which the defendant may have taken or had possession of such moneys, funds, credits, securities, property or assets.</p>
<p class="indent0">A judgment of conviction or acquittal on the merits under the laws of any State shall be a bar to any prosecution hereunder for the same act or acts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 661.</num>
<heading> Within special maritime and territorial jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, takes and carries away, with intent to steal or purloin, any personal property of another shall be punished as follows:</p>
<p class="indent0">If the property taken is of a value exceeding $1,000, or is taken from the person of another, by a fine under this title, or imprisonment for not more than five years, or both; in all other cases, by a fine under this title or by imprisonment not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">If the property stolen consists of any evidence of debt, or other written instrument, the amount of money due thereon, or secured to be paid thereby and remaining unsatisfied, or which in any contingency might be collected thereon, or the value of the property the title to which is shown thereby, or the sum which might be recovered in the absence thereof, shall be the value of the property stolen.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI</ref>, §§ 601(a)(3), 606(a), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>, 3511.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 662.</num>
<heading> Receiving stolen property within special maritime and territorial jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, buys, receives, or conceals any money, goods, bank notes, or other thing which may be the subject of larceny, which has been feloniously taken, stolen, or embezzled, from any other person, knowing the same to have been so taken, stolen, or embezzled, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both; but if the amount or value of thing so taken, stolen or embezzled does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 663.</num>
<heading> Solicitation or use of gifts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever solicits any gift of money or other property, and represents that such gift is being solicited for the use of the United States, with the intention of embezzling, stealing, or purloining such gift, or converting the same to any other use or purpose, or whoever, having come into possession of any money or property which has been donated by the owner thereof for the use of the United States, embezzles, steals or purloins such money or property, or converts the same to any other use or purpose, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 664.</num>
<heading> Theft or embezzlement from employee benefit plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who embezzles, steals, or unlawfully and willfully abstracts or converts to his own use or to the use of another, any of the moneys, funds, securities, premiums, credits, property, or other assets of any employee welfare benefit plan or employee pension benefit plan, or of any fund connected therewith, shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “any employee welfare benefit plan or employee pension benefit plan” means any employee benefit plan subject to any provision of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–420, § 17(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-03-20">Mar. 20, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 41</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 112(a)(2)(A)</ref>, formerly § 111(a)(2)(A), <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 851</ref>, renumbered § 112(a)(2)(A), <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. T, title III, § 320(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5354</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 665.</num>
<heading> Theft or embezzlement from employment and training funds; improper inducement; obstruction of investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever, being an officer, director, agent, or employee of, or connected in any capacity with any agency or organization receiving financial assistance or any funds under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act or title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 knowingly enrolls an ineligible participant, embezzles, willfully misapplies, steals, or obtains by fraud any of the moneys, funds, assets, or property which are the subject of a financial assistance agreement or contract pursuant to such Act shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both; but if the amount so embezzled, misapplied, stolen, or obtained by fraud does not exceed $1,000, such person shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever, by threat or procuring dismissal of any person from employment or of refusal to employ or refusal to renew a contract of employment in connection with a financial assistance agreement or contract under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act or title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 induces any person to give up any money or thing of any value to any person (including such organization or agency receiving funds) shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whoever willfully obstructs or impedes or willfully endeavors to obstruct or impede, an investigation or inquiry under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act or title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, or the regulations thereunder, shall be punished by a fine under this title, or by imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–203, title VII, § 711(a)</ref>, formerly title VI, § 611(a), <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 881</ref>; renumbered title VII, § 711(a), <ref>Pub. L. 93–567, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1845</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–524, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–300, title I, § 182</ref>, <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3517</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (L), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(13)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–421; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1809</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(ee)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 666.</num>
<heading> Theft or bribery concerning programs receiving Federal funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever, if the circumstance described in subsection (b) of this section exists—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> being an agent of an organization, or of a State, local, or Indian tribal government, or any agency thereof—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> embezzles, steals, obtains by fraud, or otherwise without authority knowingly converts to the use of any person other than the rightful owner or intentionally misapplies, property that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is valued at $5,000 or more, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is owned by, or is under the care, custody, or control of such organization, government, or agency; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> corruptly solicits or demands for the benefit of any person, or accepts or agrees to accept, anything of value from any person, intending to be influenced or rewarded in connection with any business, transaction, or series of transactions of such organization, government, or agency involving any thing of value of $5,000 or more; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> corruptly gives, offers, or agrees to give anything of value to any person, with intent to influence or reward an agent of an organization or of a State, local or Indian tribal government, or any agency thereof, in connection with any business, transaction, or series of transactions of such organization, government, or agency involving anything of value of $5,000 or more;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The circumstance referred to in subsection (a) of this section is that the organization, government, or agency receives, in any one year period, benefits in excess of $10,000 under a Federal program involving a grant, contract, subsidy, loan, guarantee, insurance, or other form of Federal assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to bona fide salary, wages, fees, or other compensation paid, or expenses paid or reimbursed, in the usual course of business.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “agent” means a person authorized to act on behalf of another person or a government and, in the case of an organization or government, includes a servant or employee, and a partner, director, officer, manager, and representative;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “government agency” means a subdivision of the executive, legislative, judicial, or other branch of government, including a department, independent establishment, commission, administration, authority, board, and bureau, and a corporation or other legal entity established, and subject to control, by a government or governments for the execution of a governmental or intergovernmental program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “local” means of or pertaining to a political subdivision within a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “State” includes a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “in any one-year period” means a continuous period that commences no earlier than twelve months before the commission of the offense or that ends no later than twelve months after the commission of the offense. Such period may include time both before and after the commission of the offense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2143</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 59(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XII</ref>, §§ 1205(d), 1209, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4831</ref>, 4832; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330003(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 667.</num>
<heading> Theft of livestock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever obtains or uses the property of another which has a value of $10,000 or more in connection with the marketing of livestock in interstate or foreign commerce with intent to deprive the other of a right to the property or a benefit of the property or to appropriate the property to his own use or the use of another shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both. The term “livestock” has the meaning set forth in <ref>section 2311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1111</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2149</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330009(b), 330016(1)(L), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2143</ref>, 2147.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 668.</num>
<heading> Theft of major artwork</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “museum” means an organized and permanent institution, the activities of which affect interstate or foreign commerce, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is situated in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is established for an essentially educational or aesthetic purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has a professional staff; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> owns, utilizes, and cares for tangible objects that are exhibited to the public on a regular schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “object of cultural heritage” means an object that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> over 100 years old and worth in excess of $5,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> worth at least $100,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> steals or obtains by fraud from the care, custody, or control of a museum any object of cultural heritage; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowing that an object of cultural heritage has been stolen or obtained by fraud, if in fact the object was stolen or obtained from the care, custody, or control of a museum (whether or not that fact is known to the person), receives, conceals, exhibits, or disposes of the object,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320902(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2123</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(18)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 669.</num>
<heading> Theft or embezzlement in connection with health care</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly and willfully embezzles, steals, or otherwise without authority converts to the use of any person other than the rightful owner, or intentionally misapplies any of the moneys, funds, securities, premiums, credits, property, or other assets of a health care benefit program, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both; but if the value of such property does not exceed the sum of $100 the defendant shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “health care benefit program” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 24(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 243(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 670.</num>
<heading> Theft of medical products</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever, in, or using any means or facility of, interstate or foreign commerce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> embezzles, steals, or by fraud or deception obtains, or knowingly and unlawfully takes, carries away, or conceals a pre-retail medical product;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly and falsely makes, alters, forges, or counterfeits the labeling or documentation (including documentation relating to origination or shipping) of a pre-retail medical product;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> knowingly possesses, transports, or traffics in a pre-retail medical product that was involved in a violation of paragraph (1) or (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> with intent to defraud, buys, or otherwise obtains, a pre-retail medical product that has expired or been stolen;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> with intent to defraud, sells, or distributes, a pre-retail medical product that is expired or stolen; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> attempts or conspires to violate any of paragraphs (1) through (5);</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in subsection (c) and subject to the other sanctions provided in this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aggravated Offenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An offense under this section is an aggravated offense if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the defendant is employed by, or is an agent of, an organization in the supply chain for the pre-retail medical product; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the violation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> involves the use of violence, force, or a threat of violence or force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> involves the use of a deadly weapon;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> results in serious bodily injury or death, including serious bodily injury or death resulting from the use of the medical product involved; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is subsequent to a prior conviction for an offense under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever violates subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the offense is an aggravated offense under subsection (b)(2)(C), shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 30 years, or both;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the value of the medical products involved in the offense is $5,000 or greater, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 15 years, or both, but if the offense is an aggravated offense other than one under subsection (b)(2)(C), the maximum term of imprisonment is 20 years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in any other case, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both, but if the offense is an aggravated offense other than one under subsection (b)(2)(C), the maximum term of imprisonment is 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever violates subsection (a) is subject to a civil penalty in an amount not more than the greater of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> three times the economic loss attributable to the violation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $1,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “pre-retail medical product” means a medical product that has not yet been made available for retail purchase by a consumer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “medical product” means a drug, biological product, device, medical food, or infant formula;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the terms “device”, “drug”, “infant formula”, and “labeling” have, respectively, the meanings given those terms in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “biological product” has the meaning given the term in section 351 of the Public Health Service Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “medical food” has the meaning given the term in section 5(b) of the Orphan Drug Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “supply chain” includes manufacturer, wholesaler, repacker, own-labeled distributor, private-label distributor, jobber, broker, drug trader, transportation company, hospital, pharmacy, or security company.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–186, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-10-05">Oct. 5, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1427</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>