<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 204—</num>
<heading>REWARDS FOR INFORMATION CONCERNING TERRORIST ACTS AND ESPIONAGE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3071.</num>
<heading> Information for which rewards authorized</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to acts of terrorism primarily within the territorial jurisdiction of the United States, the Attorney General may reward any individual who furnishes information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for the commission of an act of terrorism against a United States person or United States property; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for conspiring or attempting to commit an act of terrorism against a United States person or property; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> leading to the prevention, frustration, or favorable resolution of an act of terrorism against a United States person or property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to acts of espionage involving or directed at the United States, the Attorney General may reward any individual who furnishes information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for commission of an act of espionage against the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for conspiring or attempting to commit an act of espionage against the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> leading to the prevention or frustration of an act of espionage against the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–533, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2706</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3072.</num>
<heading> Determination of entitlement; maximum amount; Presidential approval; conclusiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall determine whether an individual furnishing information described in section 3071 is entitled to a reward and the amount to be paid.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–533, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2707</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title III, § 301(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1781</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3073.</num>
<heading> Protection of identity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any reward granted under this chapter shall be certified for payment by the Attorney General. If it is determined that the identity of the recipient of a reward or of the members of the recipient’s immediate family must be protected, the Attorney General may take such measures in connection with the payment of the reward as deemed necessary to effect such protection.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–533, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3074.</num>
<heading> Exception of governmental officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No officer or employee of any governmental entity who, while in the performance of his or her official duties, furnishes the information described in section 3071 shall be eligible for any monetary reward under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–533, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3075.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title III, § 301(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1781</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3076.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for witness security program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any individual (and the immediate family of such individual) who furnishes information which would justify a reward by the Attorney General under this chapter or by the Secretary of State under section 36 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 may, in the discretion of the Attorney General, participate in the Attorney General’s witness security program authorized under chapter 224 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–533, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2707</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 45</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3077.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “act of terrorism” means an act of domestic or international terrorism as defined in section 2331;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “United States person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a national of the United States as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States as defined in section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any person within the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any employee or contractor of the United States Government, regardless of nationality, who is the victim or intended victim of an act of terrorism by virtue of that employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a sole proprietorship, partnership, company, or association composed principally of nationals or permanent resident aliens of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a corporation organized under the laws of the United States, any State, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States, and a foreign subsidiary of such corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “United States property” means any real or personal property which is within the United States or, if outside the United States, the actual or beneficial ownership of which rests in a United States person or any Federal or State governmental entity of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, includes Puerto Rico and all territories and possessions of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “State” includes any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other possession or territory of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “government entity” includes the Government of the United States, any State or political subdivision thereof, any foreign country, and any state, provincial, municipal, or other political subdivision of a foreign country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “Attorney General” means the Attorney General of the United States or that official designated by the Attorney General to perform the Attorney General’s responsibilities under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> “act of espionage” means an activity that is a violation of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 793, 794, or 798 of this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 4 of the Subversive Activities Control Act of 1950.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–533, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2707</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7051</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3572</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330021(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title VIII, § 803(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 605(g)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 802(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>