<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>CONTEMPTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 401.</num>
<heading> Power of court</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A court of the United States shall have power to punish by fine or imprisonment, or both, at its discretion, such contempt of its authority, and none other, as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Misbehavior of any person in its presence or so near thereto as to obstruct the administration of justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Misbehavior of any of its officers in their official transactions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Disobedience or resistance to its lawful writ, process, order, rule, decree, or command.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 701</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title III, § 3002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 402.</num>
<heading> Contempts constituting crimes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person, corporation or association willfully disobeying any lawful writ, process, order, rule, decree, or command of any district court of the United States, including the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review established by section 103 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1803</ref>), or any court of the District of Columbia, by doing any act or thing therein, or thereby forbidden, if the act or thing so done be of such character as to constitute also a criminal offense under any statute of the United States or under the laws of any State in which the act was committed, shall be prosecuted for such contempt as provided in <ref>section 3691 of this title</ref> and shall be punished by a fine under this title or imprisonment, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such fine shall be paid to the United States or to the complainant or other party injured by the act constituting the contempt, or may, where more than one is so damaged, be divided or apportioned among them as the court may direct, but in no case shall the fine to be paid to the United States exceed, in case the accused is a natural person, the sum of $1,000, nor shall such imprisonment exceed the term of six months.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not be construed to relate to contempts committed in the presence of the court, or so near thereto as to obstruct the administration of justice, nor to contempts committed in disobedience of any lawful writ, process, order, rule, decree, or command entered in any suit or action brought or prosecuted in the name of, or on behalf of, the United States, but the same, and all other cases of contempt not specifically embraced in this section may be punished in conformity to the prevailing usages at law.</p>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “State” includes a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 701</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 8(c)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 90</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XII, § 1205(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4830</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII</ref>, §§ 330011(f), 330016(2)(E), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2145</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 118–49, § 14(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-04-20">Apr. 20, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 882</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 403.</num>
<heading> Protection of the privacy of child victims and child witnesses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A knowing or intentional violation of the privacy protection accorded by <ref>section 3509 of this title</ref> is a criminal contempt punishable by not more than one year’s imprisonment, or a fine under this title, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title II, § 225(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>