<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29—</num>
<heading>ELECTIONS AND POLITICAL ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 591.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 96–187, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1367</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 592.</num>
<heading> Troops at polls</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer of the Army or Navy, or other person in the civil, military, or naval service of the United States, orders, brings, keeps, or has under his authority or control any troops or armed men at any place where a general or special election is held, unless such force be necessary to repel armed enemies of the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; and be disqualified from holding any office of honor, profit, or trust under the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not prevent any officer or member of the armed forces of the United States from exercising the right of suffrage in any election district to which he may belong, if otherwise qualified according to the laws of the State in which he offers to vote.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 593.</num>
<heading> Interference by armed forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer or member of the Armed Forces of the United States, prescribes or fixes or attempts to prescribe or fix, whether by proclamation, order or otherwise, the qualifications of voters at any election in any State; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being such officer or member, prevents or attempts to prevent by force, threat, intimidation, advice or otherwise any qualified voter of any State from fully exercising the right of suffrage at any general or special election; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being such officer or member, orders or compels or attempts to compel any election officer in any State to receive a vote from a person not legally qualified to vote; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being such officer or member, imposes or attempts to impose any regulations for conducting any general or special election in a State, different from those prescribed by law; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being such officer or member, interferes in any manner with an election officer’s discharge of his duties—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; and disqualified from holding any office of honor, profit or trust under the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not prevent any officer or member of the Armed Forces from exercising the right of suffrage in any district to which he may belong, if otherwise qualified according to the laws of the State of such district.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 594.</num>
<heading> Intimidation of voters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever intimidates, threatens, coerces, or attempts to intimidate, threaten, or coerce, any other person for the purpose of interfering with the right of such other person to vote or to vote as he may choose, or of causing such other person to vote for, or not to vote for, any candidate for the office of President, Vice President, Presidential elector, Member of the Senate, Member of the House of Representatives, Delegate from the District of Columbia, or Resident Commissioner, at any election held solely or in part for the purpose of electing such candidate, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–405, title II, § 204(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="1970-09-22">Sept. 22, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 853</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 595.</num>
<heading> Interference by administrative employees of Federal, State, or Territorial Governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a person employed in any administrative position by the United States, or by any department or agency thereof, or by the District of Columbia or any agency or instrumentality thereof, or by any State, Territory, or Possession of the United States, or any political subdivision, municipality, or agency thereof, or agency of such political subdivision or municipality (including any corporation owned or controlled by any State, Territory, or Possession of the United States or by any such political subdivision, municipality, or agency), in connection with any activity which is financed in whole or in part by loans or grants made by the United States, or any department or agency thereof, uses his official authority for the purpose of interfering with, or affecting, the nomination or the election of any candidate for the office of President, Vice President, Presidential elector, Member of the Senate, Member of the House of Representatives, Delegate from the District of Columbia, or Resident Commissioner, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not prohibit or make unlawful any act by any officer or employee of any educational or research institution, establishment, agency, or system which is supported in whole or in part by any state or political subdivision thereof, or by the District of Columbia or by any Territory or Possession of the United States; or by any recognized religious, philanthropic or cultural organization.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–405, title II, § 204(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="1970-09-22">Sept. 22, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 853</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (L), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 596.</num>
<heading> Polling armed forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, within or without the Armed Forces of the United States, polls any member of such forces, either within or without the United States, either before or after he executes any ballot under any Federal or State law, with reference to his choice of or his vote for any candidate, or states, publishes, or releases any result of any purported poll taken from or among the members of the Armed Forces of the United States or including within it the statement of choice for such candidate or of such votes cast by any member of the Armed Forces of the United States, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">The word “poll” means any request for information, verbal or written, which by its language or form of expression requires or implies the necessity of an answer, where the request is made with the intent of compiling the result of the answers obtained, either for the personal use of the person making the request, or for the purpose of reporting the same to any other person, persons, political party, unincorporated association or corporation, or for the purpose of publishing the same orally, by radio, or in written or printed form.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 597.</num>
<heading> Expenditures to influence voting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever makes or offers to make an expenditure to any person, either to vote or withhold his vote, or to vote for or against any candidate; and</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever solicits, accepts, or receives any such expenditure in consideration of his vote or the withholding of his vote—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and if the violation was willful, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 598.</num>
<heading> Coercion by means of relief appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever uses any part of any appropriation made by Congress for work relief, relief, or for increasing employment by providing loans and grants for public-works projects, or exercises or administers any authority conferred by any Appropriation Act for the purpose of interfering with, restraining, or coercing any individual in the exercise of his right to vote at any election, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 599.</num>
<heading> Promise of appointment by candidate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a candidate, directly or indirectly promises or pledges the appointment, or the use of his influence or support for the appointment of any person to any public or private position or employment, for the purpose of procuring support in his candidacy shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and if the violation was willful, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (L), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 600.</num>
<heading> Promise of employment or other benefit for political activity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, directly or indirectly, promises any employment, position, compensation, contract, appointment, or other benefit, provided for or made possible in whole or in part by any Act of Congress, or any special consideration in obtaining any such benefit, to any person as consideration, favor, or reward for any political activity or for the support of or opposition to any candidate or any political party in connection with any general or special election to any political office, or in connection with any primary election or political convention or caucus held to select candidates for any political office, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–225, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1972-02-07">Feb. 7, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–453, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-10-02">Oct. 2, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1517</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 601.</num>
<heading> Deprivation of employment or other benefit for political contribution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whoever, directly or indirectly, knowingly causes or attempts to cause any person to make a contribution of a thing of value (including services) for the benefit of any candidate or any political party, by means of the denial or deprivation, or the threat of the denial or deprivation, of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any employment, position, or work in or for any agency or other entity of the Government of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or any compensation or benefit of such employment, position, or work; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any payment or benefit of a program of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if such employment, position, work, compensation, payment, or benefit is provided for or made possible in whole or in part by an Act of Congress, shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “candidate” means an individual who seeks nomination for election, or election, to Federal, State, or local office, whether or not such individual is elected, and, for purposes of this paragraph, an individual shall be deemed to seek nomination for election, or election, to Federal, State, or local office, if he has (A) taken the action necessary under the law of a State to qualify himself for nomination for election, or election, or (B) received contributions or made expenditures, or has given his consent for any other person to receive contributions or make expenditures, with a view to bringing about his nomination for election, or election, to such office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “election” means (A) a general, special primary, or runoff election, (B) a convention or caucus of a political party held to nominate a candidate, (C) a primary election held for the selection of delegates to a nominating convention of a political party, (D) a primary election held for the expression of a preference for the nomination of persons for election to the office of President, and (E) the election of delegates to a constitutional convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution of the United States or of any State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–453, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-10-02">Oct. 2, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 602.</num>
<heading> Solicitation of political contributions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be unlawful for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a candidate for the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an individual elected to or serving in the office of Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an officer or employee of the United States or any department or agency thereof; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a person receiving any salary or compensation for services from money derived from the Treasury of the United States; to knowingly solicit any contribution within the meaning of section 301(8) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 from any other such officer, employee, or person. Any person who violates this section shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 3 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to any activity of an employee (as defined in <ref>section 7322(1) of title 5</ref>) or any individual employed in or under the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission, unless that activity is prohibited by section 7323 or 7324 of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–187, title II, § 201(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 603.</num>
<heading> Making political contributions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for an officer or employee of the United States or any department or agency thereof, or a person receiving any salary or compensation for services from money derived from the Treasury of the United States, to make any contribution within the meaning of section 301(8) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to any other such officer, employee or person or to any Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress, if the person receiving such contribution is the employer or employing authority of the person making the contribution. Any person who violates this section shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, a contribution to an authorized committee as defined in section 302(e)(1) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 shall be considered a contribution to the individual who has authorized such committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to any activity of an employee (as defined in <ref>section 7322(1) of title 5</ref>) or any individual employed in or under the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission, unless that activity is prohibited by section 7323 or 7324 of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 20(b)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 718</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–187, title II, § 201(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 604.</num>
<heading> Solicitation from persons on relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever solicits or receives or is in any manner concerned in soliciting or receiving any assessment, subscription, or contribution for any political purpose from any person known by him to be entitled to, or receiving compensation, employment, or other benefit provided for or made possible by any Act of Congress appropriating funds for work relief or relief purposes, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 605.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of names of persons on relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, for political purposes, furnishes or discloses any list or names of persons receiving compensation, employment or benefits provided for or made possible by any Act of Congress appropriating, or authorizing the appropriation of funds for work relief or relief purposes, to a political candidate, committee, campaign manager, or to any person for delivery to a political candidate, committee, or campaign manager; and</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives any such list or names for political purposes—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 606.</num>
<heading> Intimidation to secure political contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being one of the officers or employees of the United States mentioned in <ref>section 602 of this title</ref>, discharges, or promotes, or degrades, or in any manner changes the official rank or compensation of any other officer or employee, or promises or threatens so to do, for giving or withholding or neglecting to make any contribution of money or other valuable thing for any political purpose, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 607.</num>
<heading> Place of solicitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It shall be unlawful for any person to solicit or receive a donation of money or other thing of value in connection with a Federal, State, or local election from a person who is located in a room or building occupied in the discharge of official duties by an officer or employee of the United States. It shall be unlawful for an individual who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government, including the President, Vice President, and Members of Congress, to solicit or receive a donation of money or other thing of value in connection with a Federal, State, or local election, while in any room or building occupied in the discharge of official duties by an officer or employee of the United States, from any person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who violates this section shall be fined not more than $5,000, imprisoned not more than 3 years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to the receipt of contributions by persons on the staff of a Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress or Executive Office of the President, provided, that such contributions have not been solicited in any manner which directs the contributor to mail or deliver a contribution to any room, building, or other facility referred to in subsection (a), and provided that such contributions are transferred within seven days of receipt to a political committee within the meaning of section 302(e) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–187, title II, § 201(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–155, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2002-03-27">Mar. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 96</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608.</num>
<heading> Absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly deprives or attempts to deprive any person of a right under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act shall be fined in accordance with this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever knowingly gives false information for the purpose of establishing the eligibility of any person to register or vote under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, or pays or offers to pay, or accepts payment for registering or voting under such Act shall be fined in accordance with this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–410, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-28">Aug. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 609.</num>
<heading> Use of military authority to influence vote of member of Armed Forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, being a commissioned, noncommissioned, warrant, or petty officer of an Armed Force, uses military authority to influence the vote of a member of the Armed Forces or to require a member of the Armed Forces to march to a polling place, or attempts to do so, shall be fined in accordance with this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both. Nothing in this section shall prohibit free discussion of political issues or candidates for public office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–410, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-28">Aug. 28, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 610.</num>
<heading> Coercion of political activity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to intimidate, threaten, command, or coerce, or attempt to intimidate, threaten, command, or coerce, any employee of the Federal Government as defined in <ref>section 7322(1) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, to engage in, or not to engage in, any political activity, including, but not limited to, voting or refusing to vote for any candidate or measure in any election, making or refusing to make any political contribution, or working or refusing to work on behalf of any candidate. Any person who violates this section shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1005</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 611.</num>
<heading> Voting by aliens</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be unlawful for any alien to vote in any election held solely or in part for the purpose of electing a candidate for the office of President, Vice President, Presidential elector, Member of the Senate, Member of the House of Representatives, Delegate from the District of Columbia, or Resident Commissioner, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the election is held partly for some other purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> aliens are authorized to vote for such other purpose under a State constitution or statute or a local ordinance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> voting for such other purpose is conducted independently of voting for a candidate for such Federal offices, in such a manner that an alien has the opportunity to vote for such other purpose, but not an opportunity to vote for a candidate for any one or more of such Federal offices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any person who violates this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) does not apply to an alien if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each natural parent of the alien (or, in the case of an adopted alien, each adoptive parent of the alien) is or was a citizen (whether by birth or naturalization);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the alien permanently resided in the United States prior to attaining the age of 16; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the alien reasonably believed at the time of voting in violation of such subsection that he or she was a citizen of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title II, § 216(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–572</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–395, title II, § 201(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1635</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 612 to 617.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 496</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>