<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 113—</num>
<heading>STOLEN PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2311.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</p>
<p class="indent0">“Aircraft” means any contrivance now known or hereafter invented, used, or designed for navigation of or for flight in the air;</p>
<p class="indent0">“Cattle” means one or more bulls, steers, oxen, cows, heifers, or calves, or the carcass or carcasses thereof;</p>
<p class="indent0">“Livestock” means any domestic animals raised for home use, consumption, or profit, such as horses, pigs, llamas, goats, fowl, sheep, buffalo, and cattle, or the carcasses thereof;</p>
<p class="indent0">“Money” means the legal tender of the United States or of any foreign country, or any counterfeit thereof;</p>
<p class="indent0">“Motor vehicle” includes an automobile, automobile truck, automobile wagon, motorcycle, or any other self-propelled vehicle designed for running on land but not on rails;</p>
<p class="indent0">“Securities” includes any note, stock certificate, bond, debenture, check, draft, warrant, traveler’s check, letter of credit, warehouse receipt, negotiable bill of lading, evidence of indebtedness, certificate of interest or participation in any profit-sharing agreement, collateral-trust certificate, preorganization certificate or subscription, transferable share, investment contract, voting-trust certificate; valid or blank motor vehicle title; certificate of interest in property, tangible or intangible; instrument or document or writing evidencing ownership of goods, wares, and merchandise, or transferring or assigning any right, title, or interest in or to goods, wares, and merchandise; or, in general, any instrument commonly known as a “security”, or any certificate of interest or participation in, temporary or interim certificate for, receipt for, warrant, or right to subscribe to or purchase any of the foregoing, or any forged, counterfeited, or spurious representation of any of the foregoing;</p>
<p class="indent0">“Tax stamp” includes any tax stamp, tax token, tax meter imprint, or any other form of evidence of an obligation running to a State, or evidence of the discharge thereof;</p>
<p class="indent0">“Value” means the face, par, or market value, whichever is the greatest, and the aggregate value of all goods, wares, and merchandise, securities, and money referred to in a single indictment shall constitute the value thereof.</p>
<p class="indent0">“Vessel” means any watercraft or other contrivance used or designed for transportation or navigation on, under, or immediately above, water.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 805</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–371, § 1</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–547, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1984-10-25">Oct. 25, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320912</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(20)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title III, § 307(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2312.</num>
<heading> Transportation of stolen vehicles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever transports in interstate or foreign commerce a motor vehicle, vessel, or aircraft, knowing the same to have been stolen, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–519, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1992-10-25">Oct. 25, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title III, § 307(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2313.</num>
<heading> Sale or receipt of stolen vehicles</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever receives, possesses, conceals, stores, barters, sells, or disposes of any motor vehicle, vessel, or aircraft, which has crossed a State or United States boundary after being stolen, knowing the same to have been stolen, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “State” includes a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–547, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1984-10-25">Oct. 25, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XII, § 1205</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4831</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–519, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1992-10-25">Oct. 25, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title III, § 307(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2314.</num>
<heading> Transportation of stolen goods, securities, moneys, fraudulent State tax stamps, or articles used in counterfeiting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever transports, transmits, or transfers in interstate or foreign commerce any goods, wares, merchandise, securities or money, of the value of $5,000 or more, knowing the same to have been stolen, converted or taken by fraud; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, having devised or intending to devise any scheme or artifice to defraud, or for obtaining money or property by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises, transports or causes to be transported, or induces any person or persons to travel in, or to be transported in interstate or foreign commerce in the execution or concealment of a scheme or artifice to defraud that person or those persons of money or property having a value of $5,000 or more; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with unlawful or fraudulent intent, transports in interstate or foreign commerce any falsely made, forged, altered, or counterfeited securities or tax stamps, knowing the same to have been falsely made, forged, altered, or counterfeited; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with unlawful or fraudulent intent, transports in interstate or foreign commerce any traveler’s check bearing a forged countersignature; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, with unlawful or fraudulent intent, transports in interstate or foreign commerce, any tool, implement, or thing used or fitted to be used in falsely making, forging, altering, or counterfeiting any security or tax stamps, or any part thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever transports, transmits, or transfers in interstate or foreign commerce any veterans’ memorial object, knowing the same to have been stolen, converted or taken by fraud—</p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both. If the offense involves a pre-retail medical product (as defined in section 670) the punishment for the offense shall be the same as the punishment for an offense under section 670 unless the punishment under this section is greater. If the offense involves the transportation, transmission, or transfer in interstate or foreign commerce of veterans’ memorial objects with a value, in the aggregate, of less than $1,000, the defendant shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any falsely made, forged, altered, counterfeited or spurious representation of an obligation or other security of the United States, or of an obligation, bond, certificate, security, treasury note, bill, promise to pay or bank note issued by any foreign government. This section also shall not apply to any falsely made, forged, altered, counterfeited, or spurious representation of any bank note or bill issued by a bank or corporation of any foreign country which is intended by the laws or usage of such country to circulate as money.</p>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section the term “veterans’ memorial object” means a grave marker, headstone, monument, or other object, intended to permanently honor a veteran or mark a veteran’s grave, or any monument that signifies an event of national military historical significance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 45</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 96</ref>; <ref>July 9, 1956, ch. 519</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–371, § 2</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–535</ref>, <date date="1968-09-28">Sept. 28, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7057, 7080, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4402</ref>, 4406; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XII, § 1208</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, (L), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–186, § 4(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-10-05">Oct. 5, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1084(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2315.</num>
<heading> Sale or receipt of stolen goods, securities, moneys, or fraudulent State tax stamps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives, possesses, conceals, stores, barters, sells, or disposes of any goods, wares, or merchandise, securities, or money of the value of $5,000 or more, or pledges or accepts as security for a loan any goods, wares, or merchandise, or securities, of the value of $500 or more, which have crossed a State or United States boundary after being stolen, unlawfully converted, or taken, knowing the same to have been stolen, unlawfully converted, or taken; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives, possesses, conceals, stores, barters, sells, or disposes of any falsely made, forged, altered, or counterfeited securities or tax stamps, or pledges or accepts as security for a loan any falsely made, forged, altered, or counterfeited securities or tax stamps, moving as, or which are a part of, or which constitute interstate or foreign commerce, knowing the same to have been so falsely made, forged, altered, or counterfeited; or</p>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives in interstate or foreign commerce, or conceals, stores, barters, sells, or disposes of, any tool, implement, or thing used or intended to be used in falsely making, forging, altering, or counterfeiting any security or tax stamp, or any part thereof, moving as, or which is a part of, or which constitutes interstate or foreign commerce, knowing that the same is fitted to be used, or has been used, in falsely making, forging, altering, or counterfeiting any security or tax stamp, or any part thereof; or</p>
<p class="indent0">‘Whoever <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002182">1</ref> receives, possesses, conceals, stores, barters, sells, or disposes of any veterans’ memorial object which has crossed a State or United States boundary after being stolen, unlawfully converted, or taken, knowing the same to have been stolen, unlawfully converted, or taken—’ <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002182">1</ref></p>
<p class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both. If the offense involves a pre-retail medical product (as defined in section 670) the punishment for the offense shall be the same as the punishment for an offense under section 670 unless the punishment under this section is greater. If the offense involves the receipt, possession, concealment, storage, barter, sale, or disposal of veterans’ memorial objects with a value, in the aggregate, of less than $1,000, the defendant shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any falsely made, forged, altered, counterfeited, or spurious representation of an obligation or other security of the United States or of an obligation, bond, certificate, security, treasury note, bill, promise to pay, or bank note, issued by any foreign government. This section also shall not apply to any falsely made, forged, altered, counterfeited, or spurious representation of any bank note or bill issued by a bank or corporation of any foreign country which is intended by the laws or usage of such country to circulate as money.</p>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “State” includes a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States. For purposes of this section the term “veterans’ memorial object” means a grave marker, headstone, monument, or other object, intended to permanently honor a veteran or mark a veteran’s grave, or any monument that signifies an event of national military historical significance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–371, § 3</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 76</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7048, 7057(b), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4401</ref>, 4402; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XII, § 1205(m)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4831</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–186, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-10-05">Oct. 5, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1084(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2316.</num>
<heading> Transportation of livestock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever transports in interstate or foreign commerce any livestock, knowing the same to have been stolen, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1113</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2317.</num>
<heading> Sale or receipt of livestock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever receives, conceals, stores, barters, buys, sells, or disposes of any livestock, moving in or constituting a part of interstate or foreign commerce, knowing the same to have been stolen, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1114</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2318.</num>
<heading> Trafficking in counterfeit labels, illicit labels, or counterfeit documentation or packaging</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002183">1</ref> Whoever, in any of the circumstances described in subsection (c), knowingly traffics in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a counterfeit label or illicit label affixed to, enclosing, or accompanying, or designed to be affixed to, enclose, or accompany—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a phonorecord;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a copy of a computer program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a copy of a motion picture or other audiovisual work;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a copy of a literary work;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a copy of a pictorial, graphic, or sculptural work;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a work of visual art; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> documentation or packaging; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> counterfeit documentation or packaging,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “counterfeit label” means an identifying label or container that appears to be genuine, but is not;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “traffic” has the same meaning as in <ref>section 2320(f) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the terms “copy”, “phonorecord”, “motion picture”, “computer program”, “audiovisual work”, “literary work”, “pictorial, graphic, or sculptural work”, “sound recording”, “work of visual art”, and “copyright owner” have, respectively, the meanings given those terms in section 101 (relating to definitions) of title 17;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “illicit label” means a genuine certificate, licensing document, registration card, or similar labeling component—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that is used by the copyright owner to verify that a phonorecord, a copy of a computer program, a copy of a motion picture or other audiovisual work, a copy of a literary work, a copy of a pictorial, graphic, or sculptural work, a work of visual art, or documentation or packaging is not counterfeit or infringing of any copyright; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> that is, without the authorization of the copyright owner—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> distributed or intended for distribution not in connection with the copy, phonorecord, or work of visual art to which such labeling component was intended to be affixed by the respective copyright owner; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in connection with a genuine certificate or licensing document, knowingly falsified in order to designate a higher number of licensed users or copies than authorized by the copyright owner, unless that certificate or document is used by the copyright owner solely for the purpose of monitoring or tracking the copyright owner’s distribution channel and not for the purpose of verifying that a copy or phonorecord is noninfringing;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “documentation or packaging” means documentation or packaging, in physical form, for a phonorecord, copy of a computer program, copy of a motion picture or other audiovisual work, copy of a literary work, copy of a pictorial, graphic, or sculptural work, or work of visual art; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “counterfeit documentation or packaging” means documentation or packaging that appears to be genuine, but is not.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The circumstances referred to in subsection (a) of this section are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the offense is committed within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States; or within the special aircraft jurisdiction of the United States (as defined in <ref>section 46501 of title 49</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the mail or a facility of interstate or foreign commerce is used or intended to be used in the commission of the offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the counterfeit label or illicit label is affixed to, encloses, or accompanies, or is designed to be affixed to, enclose, or accompany—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a phonorecord of a copyrighted sound recording or copyrighted musical work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a copy of a copyrighted computer program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a copy of a copyrighted motion picture or other audiovisual work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a copy of a literary work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a copy of a pictorial, graphic, or sculptural work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a work of visual art; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> copyrighted documentation or packaging; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the counterfeited documentation or packaging is copyrighted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture and Destruction of Property; Restitution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Forfeiture, destruction, and restitution relating to this section shall be subject to section 2323, to the extent provided in that section, in addition to any other similar remedies provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Civil Remedies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any copyright owner who is injured, or is threatened with injury, by a violation of subsection (a) may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discretion of court</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In any action brought under paragraph (1), the court—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may grant 1 or more temporary or permanent injunctions on such terms as the court determines to be reasonable to prevent or restrain a violation of subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at any time while the action is pending, may order the impounding, on such terms as the court determines to be reasonable, of any article that is in the custody or control of the alleged violator and that the court has reasonable cause to believe was involved in a violation of subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> may award to the injured party—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reasonable attorney fees and costs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> actual damages and any additional profits of the violator, as provided in paragraph (3); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> statutory damages, as provided in paragraph (4).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Actual damages and profits.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The injured party is entitled to recover—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the actual damages suffered by the injured party as a result of a violation of subsection (a), as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any profits of the violator that are attributable to a violation of subsection (a) and are not taken into account in computing the actual damages.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Calculation of damages</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The court shall calculate actual damages by multiplying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the value of the phonorecords, copies, or works of visual art which are, or are intended to be, affixed with, enclosed in, or accompanied by any counterfeit labels, illicit labels, or counterfeit documentation or packaging, by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of phonorecords, copies, or works of visual art which are, or are intended to be, affixed with, enclosed in, or accompanied by any counterfeit labels, illicit labels, or counterfeit documentation or packaging.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this paragraph, the “value” of a phonorecord, copy, or work of visual art is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a copyrighted sound recording or copyrighted musical work, the retail value of an authorized phonorecord of that sound recording or musical work;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a copyrighted computer program, the retail value of an authorized copy of that computer program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of a copyrighted motion picture or other audiovisual work, the retail value of an authorized copy of that motion picture or audiovisual work;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> in the case of a copyrighted literary work, the retail value of an authorized copy of that literary work;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> in the case of a pictorial, graphic, or sculptural work, the retail value of an authorized copy of that work; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> in the case of a work of visual art, the retail value of that work.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statutory damages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The injured party may elect, at any time before final judgment is rendered, to recover, instead of actual damages and profits, an award of statutory damages for each violation of subsection (a) in a sum of not less than $2,500 or more than $25,000, as the court considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsequent violation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court may increase an award of damages under this subsection by 3 times the amount that would otherwise be awarded, as the court considers appropriate, if the court finds that a person has subsequently violated subsection (a) within 3 years after a final judgment was entered against that person for a violation of that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A civil action may not be commenced under this subsection unless it is commenced within 3 years after the date on which the claimant discovers the violation of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–773, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 775</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–573, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1873</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–553, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–180, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-05-24">May 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 91</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3567</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(e)(10)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1374</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(U)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–153, § 4(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1996-07-02">July 2, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1386</ref>, 1387; <ref>Pub. L. 108–482, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3912</ref>, 3914; <ref>Pub. L. 109–181, § 2(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-16">Mar. 16, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4260</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–295, § 6(i)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-09">Dec. 9, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–154, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2319.</num>
<heading> Criminal infringement of a copyright</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any person who violates section 506(a) (relating to criminal offenses) of title 17 shall be punished as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (d) and such penalties shall be in addition to any other provisions of title 17 or any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who commits an offense under <ref>section 506(a)(1)(A) of title 17</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 5 years, or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both, if the offense consists of the reproduction or distribution, including by electronic means, during any 180-day period, of at least 10 copies or phonorecords, of 1 or more copyrighted works, which have a total retail value of more than $2,500;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 10 years, or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both, if the offense is a felony and is a second or subsequent offense under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 1 year, or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both, in any other case.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who commits an offense under <ref>section 506(a)(1)(B) of title 17</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 3 years, or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both, if the offense consists of the reproduction or distribution of 10 or more copies or phonorecords of 1 or more copyrighted works, which have a total retail value of $2,500 or more;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 6 years, or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both, if the offense is a felony and is a second or subsequent offense under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 1 year, or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both, if the offense consists of the reproduction or distribution of 1 or more copies or phonorecords of 1 or more copyrighted works, which have a total retail value of more than $1,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Any person who commits an offense under <ref>section 506(a)(1)(C) of title 17</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 3 years, fined under this title, or both;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 5 years, fined under this title, or both, if the offense was committed for purposes of commercial advantage or private financial gain;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 6 years, fined under this title, or both, if the offense is a felony and is a second or subsequent offense under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall be imprisoned not more than 10 years, fined under this title, or both, if the offense is a felony and is a second or subsequent offense under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During preparation of the presentence report pursuant to Rule 32(c) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, victims of the offense shall be permitted to submit, and the probation officer shall receive, a victim impact statement that identifies the victim of the offense and the extent and scope of the injury and loss suffered by the victim, including the estimated economic impact of the offense on that victim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Persons permitted to submit victim impact statements shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> producers and sellers of legitimate works affected by conduct involved in the offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> holders of intellectual property rights in such works; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the legal representatives of such producers, sellers, and holders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “phonorecord” and “copies” have, respectively, the meanings set forth in section 101 (relating to definitions) of title 17;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “reproduction” and “distribution” refer to the exclusive rights of a copyright owner under clauses (1) and (3) respectively of section 106 (relating to exclusive rights in copyrighted works), as limited by sections 107 through 122, of title 17;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “financial gain” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 101 of title 17</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “work being prepared for commercial distribution” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 506(a) of title 17</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–180, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-05-24">May 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 92</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–561</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–80, § 12(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-13">Nov. 13, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1536</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–147, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1997-12-16">Dec. 16, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2678</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13211(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1910</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–9, title I, § 103(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-27">Apr. 27, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2319A.</num>
<heading> Unauthorized fixation of and trafficking in sound recordings and music videos of live musical performances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever, without the consent of the performer or performers involved, knowingly and for purposes of commercial advantage or private financial gain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fixes the sounds or sounds and images of a live musical performance in a copy or phonorecord, or reproduces copies or phonorecords of such a performance from an unauthorized fixation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transmits or otherwise communicates to the public the sounds or sounds and images of a live musical performance; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> distributes or offers to distribute, sells or offers to sell, rents or offers to rent, or traffics in any copy or phonorecord fixed as described in paragraph (1), regardless of whether the fixations occurred in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be imprisoned for not more than 5 years or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both, or if the offense is a second or subsequent offense, shall be imprisoned for not more than 10 years or fined in the amount set forth in this title, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture and Destruction of Property; Restitution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Forfeiture, destruction, and restitution relating to this section shall be subject to section 2323, to the extent provided in that section, in addition to any other similar remedies provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seizure and Forfeiture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If copies or phonorecords of sounds or sounds and images of a live musical performance are fixed outside of the United States without the consent of the performer or performers involved, such copies or phonorecords are subject to seizure and forfeiture in the United States in the same manner as property imported in violation of the customs laws. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue regulations by which any performer may, upon payment of a specified fee, be entitled to notification by United States Customs and Border Protection of the importation of copies or phonorecords that appear to consist of unauthorized fixations of the sounds or sounds and images of a live musical performance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Victim Impact Statement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During preparation of the presentence report pursuant to Rule 32(c) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, victims of the offense shall be permitted to submit, and the probation officer shall receive, a victim impact statement that identifies the victim of the offense and the extent and scope of the injury and loss suffered by the victim, including the estimated economic impact of the offense on that victim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Persons permitted to submit victim impact statements shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> producers and sellers of legitimate works affected by conduct involved in the offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> holders of intellectual property rights in such works; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the legal representatives of such producers, sellers, and holders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “copy”, “fixed”, “musical work”, “phonorecord”, “reproduce”, “sound recordings”, and “transmit” mean those terms within the meaning of title 17; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “traffic” has the same meaning as in section 2320(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002184">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall apply to any Act or Acts that occur on or after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 513(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4974</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–147, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="1997-12-16">Dec. 16, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2679</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–181, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-16">Mar. 16, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2319B.</num>
<heading> Unauthorized recording of Motion pictures in a Motion picture exhibition facility</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any person who, without the authorization of the copyright owner, knowingly uses or attempts to use an audiovisual recording device to transmit or make a copy of a motion picture or other audiovisual work protected under title 17, or any part thereof, from a performance of such work in a motion picture exhibition facility, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be imprisoned for not more than 3 years, fined under this title, or both; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the offense is a second or subsequent offense, be imprisoned for no more than 6 years, fined under this title, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The possession by a person of an audiovisual recording device in a motion picture exhibition facility may be considered as evidence in any proceeding to determine whether that person committed an offense under this subsection, but shall not, by itself, be sufficient to support a conviction of that person for such offense.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture and Destruction of Property; Restitution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Forfeiture, destruction, and restitution relating to this section shall be subject to section 2323, to the extent provided in that section, in addition to any other similar remedies provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not prevent any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, or intelligence activity by an officer, agent, or employee of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or by a person acting under a contract with the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Immunity for Theaters</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With reasonable cause, the owner or lessee of a motion picture exhibition facility where a motion picture or other audiovisual work is being exhibited, the authorized agent or employee of such owner or lessee, the licensor of the motion picture or other audiovisual work being exhibited, or the agent or employee of such licensor—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may detain, in a reasonable manner and for a reasonable time, any person suspected of a violation of this section with respect to that motion picture or audiovisual work for the purpose of questioning or summoning a law enforcement officer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall not be held liable in any civil or criminal action arising out of a detention under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Victim Impact Statement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>During the preparation of the presentence report under rule 32(c) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, victims of an offense under this section shall be permitted to submit to the probation officer a victim impact statement that identifies the victim of the offense and the extent and scope of the injury and loss suffered by the victim, including the estimated economic impact of the offense on that victim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A victim impact statement submitted under this subsection shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> producers and sellers of legitimate works affected by conduct involved in the offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> holders of intellectual property rights in the works described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the legal representatives of such producers, sellers, and holders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Law Not Preempted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to annul or limit any rights or remedies under the laws of any State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title 17 definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The terms “audiovisual work”, “copy”, “copyright owner”, “motion picture”, “motion picture exhibition facility”, and “transmit” have, respectively, the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 101 of title 17</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audiovisual recording device</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “audiovisual recording device” means a digital or analog photographic or video camera, or any other technology or device capable of enabling the recording or transmission of a copyrighted motion picture or other audiovisual work, or any part thereof, regardless of whether audiovisual recording is the sole or primary purpose of the device.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–9, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-27">Apr. 27, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 218</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2319C.</num>
<heading> Illicit digital transmission services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “audiovisual work”, “computer program”, “copies”, “copyright owner”, “digital transmission”, “financial gain”, “motion picture”, “motion picture exhibition facility”, “perform”, “phonorecords”, “publicly” (with respect to performing a work), “sound recording”, and “transmit” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 101 of title 17</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “digital transmission service” means a service that has the primary purpose of publicly performing works by digital transmission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the terms “publicly perform” and “public performance” refer to the exclusive rights of a copyright owner under paragraphs (4) and (6) of section 106 (relating to exclusive rights in copyrighted works) of title 17, as limited by sections 107 through 122 of title 17; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “work being prepared for commercial public performance” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a computer program, a musical work, a motion picture or other audiovisual work, or a sound recording, if, at the time of unauthorized public performance—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the copyright owner has a reasonable expectation of commercial public performance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the copies or phonorecords of the work have not been commercially publicly performed in the United States by or with the authorization of the copyright owner; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a motion picture, if, at the time of unauthorized public performance, the motion picture—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> has been made available for viewing in a motion picture exhibition facility; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has not been made available in copies for sale to the general public in the United States by or with the authorization of the copyright owner in a format intended to permit viewing outside a motion picture exhibition facility; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> had not been commercially publicly performed in the United States by or with the authorization of the copyright owner more than 24 hours before the unauthorized public performance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Act</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It shall be unlawful for a person to willfully, and for purposes of commercial advantage or private financial gain, offer or provide to the public a digital transmission service that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is primarily designed or provided for the purpose of publicly performing works protected under title 17 by means of a digital transmission without the authority of the copyright owner or the law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has no commercially significant purpose or use other than to publicly perform works protected under title 17 by means of a digital transmission without the authority of the copyright owner or the law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is intentionally marketed by or at the direction of that person to promote its use in publicly performing works protected under title 17 by means of a digital transmission without the authority of the copyright owner or the law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any person who violates subsection (b) shall be, in addition to any penalties provided for under title 17 or any other law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 3 years, or both;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the offense was committed in connection with 1 or more works being prepared for commercial public performance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the person knew or should have known that the work was being prepared for commercial public performance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both, if the offense is a second or subsequent offense under this section or section 2319(a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> affect the interpretation of any other provision of civil copyright law, including the limitations of liability set forth in <ref>section 512 of title 17</ref>, or principles of secondary liability; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prevent any Federal or State authority from enforcing cable theft or theft of service laws that are not subject to preemption under <ref>section 301 of title 17</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. Q, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2320.</num>
<heading> Trafficking in counterfeit goods or services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever intentionally—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> traffics in goods or services and knowingly uses a counterfeit mark on or in connection with such goods or services,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> traffics in labels, patches, stickers, wrappers, badges, emblems, medallions, charms, boxes, containers, cans, cases, hangtags, documentation, or packaging of any type or nature, knowing that a counterfeit mark has been applied thereto, the use of which is likely to cause confusion, to cause mistake, or to deceive,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> traffics in goods or services knowing that such good or service is a counterfeit military good or service the use, malfunction, or failure of which is likely to cause serious bodily injury or death, the disclosure of classified information, impairment of combat operations, or other significant harm to a combat operation, a member of the Armed Forces, or to national security, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> traffics in a drug and knowingly uses a counterfeit mark on or in connection with such drug,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">or attempts or conspires to violate any of paragraphs (1) through (4) shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Penalties.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever commits an offense under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if an individual, shall be fined not more than $2,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both, and, if a person other than an individual, shall be fined not more than $5,000,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a second or subsequent offense under subsection (a), if an individual, shall be fined not more than $5,000,000 or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both, and if other than an individual, shall be fined not more than $15,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Serious bodily injury or death.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Serious bodily injury</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever knowingly or recklessly causes or attempts to cause serious bodily injury from conduct in violation of subsection (a), if an individual, shall be fined not more than $5,000,000 or imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both, and if other than an individual, shall be fined not more than $15,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Death</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever knowingly or recklessly causes or attempts to cause death from conduct in violation of subsection (a), if an individual, shall be fined not more than $5,000,000 or imprisoned for any term of years or for life, or both, and if other than an individual, shall be fined not more than $15,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Counterfeit military goods or services and counterfeit drugs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whoever commits an offense under subsection (a) involving a counterfeit military good or service or drug that uses a counterfeit mark on or in connection with the drug—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if an individual, shall be fined not more than $5,000,000, imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both, and if other than an individual, be fined not more than $15,000,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a second or subsequent offense, if an individual, shall be fined not more than $15,000,000, imprisoned not more than 30 years, or both, and if other than an individual, shall be fined not more than $30,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture and Destruction of Property; Restitution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Forfeiture, destruction, and restitution relating to this section shall be subject to section 2323, to the extent provided in that section, in addition to any other similar remedies provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All defenses, affirmative defenses, and limitations on remedies that would be applicable in an action under the Lanham Act shall be applicable in a prosecution under this section. In a prosecution under this section, the defendant shall have the burden of proof, by a preponderance of the evidence, of any such affirmative defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presentence Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During preparation of the presentence report pursuant to Rule 32(c) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, victims of the offense shall be permitted to submit, and the probation officer shall receive, a victim impact statement that identifies the victim of the offense and the extent and scope of the injury and loss suffered by the victim, including the estimated economic impact of the offense on that victim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Persons permitted to submit victim impact statements shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> producers and sellers of legitimate goods or services affected by conduct involved in the offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> holders of intellectual property rights in such goods or services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the legal representatives of such producers, sellers, and holders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “counterfeit mark” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a spurious mark—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is used in connection with trafficking in any goods, services, labels, patches, stickers, wrappers, badges, emblems, medallions, charms, boxes, containers, cans, cases, hangtags, documentation, or packaging of any type or nature;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that is identical with, or substantially indistinguishable from, a mark registered on the principal register in the United States Patent and Trademark Office and in use, whether or not the defendant knew such mark was so registered;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that is applied to or used in connection with the goods or services for which the mark is registered with the United States Patent and Trademark Office, or is applied to or consists of a label, patch, sticker, wrapper, badge, emblem, medallion, charm, box, container, can, case, hangtag, documentation, or packaging of any type or nature that is designed, marketed, or otherwise intended to be used on or in connection with the goods or services for which the mark is registered in the United States Patent and Trademark Office; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the use of which is likely to cause confusion, to cause mistake, or to deceive; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a spurious designation that is identical with, or substantially indistinguishable from, a designation as to which the remedies of the Lanham Act are made available by reason of <ref>section 220506 of title 36</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but such term does not include any mark or designation used in connection with goods or services, or a mark or designation applied to labels, patches, stickers, wrappers, badges, emblems, medallions, charms, boxes, containers, cans, cases, hangtags, documentation, or packaging of any type or nature used in connection with such goods or services, of which the manufacturer or producer was, at the time of the manufacture or production in question, authorized to use the mark or designation for the type of goods or services so manufactured or produced, by the holder of the right to use such mark or designation;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “financial gain” includes the receipt, or expected receipt, of anything of value;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Lanham Act” means the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1946-07-05">July 5, 1946</date> (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1051</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the term “counterfeit military good or service” means a good or service that uses a counterfeit mark on or in connection with such good or service and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is falsely identified or labeled as meeting military specifications, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is intended for use in a military or national security application;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “traffic” means to transport, transfer, or otherwise dispose of, to another, for purposes of commercial advantage or private financial gain, or to make, import, export, obtain control of, or possess, with intent to so transport, transfer, or otherwise dispose of; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “drug” means a drug, as defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 321</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Cause of Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall entitle the United States to bring a criminal cause of action under this section for the repackaging of genuine goods or services not intended to deceive or confuse.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Beginning with the first year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Attorney General shall include in the report of the Attorney General to Congress on the business of the Department of Justice prepared pursuant to <ref>section 522 of title 28</ref>, an accounting, on a district by district basis, of the following with respect to all actions taken by the Department of Justice that involve trafficking in counterfeit labels for phonorecords, copies of computer programs or computer program documentation or packaging, copies of motion pictures or other audiovisual works (as defined in <ref>section 2318 of this title</ref>), criminal infringement of copyrights (as defined in <ref>section 2319 of this title</ref>), unauthorized fixation of and trafficking in sound recordings and music videos of live musical performances (as defined in <ref>section 2319A of this title</ref>), or trafficking in goods or services bearing counterfeit marks (as defined in <ref>section 2320 of this title</ref>):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The number of open investigations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The number of cases referred by the United States Customs Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The number of cases referred by other agencies or sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The number and outcome, including settlements, sentences, recoveries, and penalties, of all prosecutions brought under sections 2318, 2319, 2319A, and 2320 of title 18.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The report under paragraph (1), with respect to criminal infringement of copyright, shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The number of infringement cases in these categories: audiovisual (videos and films); audio (sound recordings); literary works (books and musical compositions); computer programs; video games; and, others.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The number of online infringement cases.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The number and dollar amounts of fines assessed in specific categories of dollar amounts. These categories shall be: no fines ordered; fines under $500; fines from $500 to $1,000; fines from $1,000 to $5,000; fines from $5,000 to $10,000; and fines over $10,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The total amount of restitution ordered in all copyright infringement cases.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In this paragraph, the term “online infringement cases” as used in paragraph (2) means those cases where the infringer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> advertised or publicized the infringing work on the Internet; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> made the infringing work available on the Internet for download, reproduction, performance, or distribution by other persons.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The information required under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in the report required in fiscal year 2005 and thereafter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transshipment and Exportation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No goods or services, the trafficking in of which is prohibited by this section, shall be transshipped through or exported from the United States. Any such transshipment or exportation shall be deemed a violation of section 42 of an Act to provide for the registration of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes, approved <date date="1946-07-05">July 5, 1946</date> (commonly referred to as the “Trademark Act of 1946” or the “Lanham Act”).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1502(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2178</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320104(a)</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(U), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2110</ref>, 2148; <ref>Pub. L. 104–153, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-07-02">July 2, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–147, § 2(f)</ref>, <date date="1997-12-16">Dec. 16, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2679</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–225, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–354, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–140, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-02-08">Feb. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 12</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 205(e)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–181</ref>, §§ 1(b), 2(b), <date date="2006-03-16">Mar. 16, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 285</ref>, 288; <ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4261</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 818(h)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–144, title VII, § 717(a)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2012-07-09">July 9, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1076</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–154, § 3(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2321.</num>
<heading> Trafficking in certain motor vehicles or motor vehicle parts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whoever buys, receives, possesses, or obtains control of, with intent to sell or otherwise dispose of, a motor vehicle or motor vehicle part, knowing that an identification number for such motor vehicle or part has been removed, obliterated, tampered with, or altered, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) does not apply if the removal, obliteration, tampering, or alteration—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is caused by collision or fire; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is not a violation of <ref>section 511 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the terms “identification number” and “motor vehicle” have the meaning given those terms in <ref>section 511 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–547, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-25">Oct. 25, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2770</ref>, § 2320; renumbered § 2321, <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 42(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3601</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(N)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2322.</num>
<heading> Chop shops</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unlawful action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who knowingly owns, operates, maintains, or controls a chop shop or conducts operations in a chop shop shall be punished by a fine under this title or by imprisonment for not more than 15 years, or both. If a conviction of a person under this paragraph is for a violation committed after the first conviction of such person under this paragraph, the maximum punishment shall be doubled with respect to any fine and imprisonment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Injunctions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General shall, as appropriate, in the case of any person who violates paragraph (1), commence a civil action for permanent or temporary injunction to restrain such violation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, the term “chop shop” means any building, lot, facility, or other structure or premise where one or more persons engage in receiving, concealing, destroying, disassembling, dismantling, reassembling, or storing any passenger motor vehicle or passenger motor vehicle part which has been unlawfully obtained in order to alter, counterfeit, deface, destroy, disguise, falsify, forge, obliterate, or remove the identity, including the vehicle identification number or derivative thereof, of such vehicle or vehicle part and to distribute, sell, or dispose of such vehicle or vehicle part in interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–519, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-25">Oct. 25, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3385</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2323.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture, destruction, and restitution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Civil Forfeiture.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Property subject to forfeiture</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following property is subject to forfeiture to the United States Government:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any article, the making or trafficking of which is, prohibited under <ref>section 506 of title 17</ref>, or section 2318, 2319, 2319A, 2319B, or 2320, or chapter 90, of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any property used, or intended to be used, in any manner or part to commit or facilitate the commission of an offense referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any property constituting or derived from any proceeds obtained directly or indirectly as a result of the commission of an offense referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of chapter 46 relating to civil forfeitures shall extend to any seizure or civil forfeiture under this section. For seizures made under this section, the court shall enter an appropriate protective order with respect to discovery and use of any records or information that has been seized. The protective order shall provide for appropriate procedures to ensure that confidential, private, proprietary, or privileged information contained in such records is not improperly disclosed or used. At the conclusion of the forfeiture proceedings, unless otherwise requested by an agency of the United States, the court shall order that any property forfeited under paragraph (1) be destroyed, or otherwise disposed of according to law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Criminal Forfeiture.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Property subject to forfeiture</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court, in imposing sentence on a person convicted of an offense under <ref>section 506 of title 17</ref>, or section 2318, 2319, 2319A, 2319B, or 2320, or chapter 90, of this title, shall order, in addition to any other sentence imposed, that the person forfeit to the United States Government any property subject to forfeiture under subsection (a) for that offense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The forfeiture of property under paragraph (1), including any seizure and disposition of the property and any related judicial or administrative proceeding, shall be governed by the procedures set forth in section 413 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<ref>21 U.S.C. 853</ref>), other than subsection (d) of that section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Destruction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the conclusion of the forfeiture proceedings, the court, unless otherwise requested by an agency of the United States shall order that any—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> forfeited article or component of an article bearing or consisting of a counterfeit mark be destroyed or otherwise disposed of according to law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> infringing items or other property described in subsection (a)(1)(A) and forfeited under paragraph (1) of this subsection be destroyed or otherwise disposed of according to law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restitution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When a person is convicted of an offense under <ref>section 506 of title 17</ref> or section 2318, 2319, 2319A, 2319B, or 2320, or chapter 90, of this title, the court, pursuant to sections 3556, 3663A, and 3664 of this title, shall order the person to pay restitution to any victim of the offense as an offense against property referred to in <ref>section 3663A(c)(1)(A)(ii) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>