<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 12—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN AND EXCHANGE STUDENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 221.</num>
<heading> Instructions of citizens from American republics; Government maintained professional educational institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized, in his discretion and under such regulations as he may prescribe by Executive order, to permit citizens of the American republics to receive instruction, with or without charge therefor, at professional educational institutions and schools maintained and administered by the Government of the United States or by departments or agencies thereof: <i>Provided</i>, That such citizens shall agree to comply with all regulations for the government of the institutions and schools at which they may be under instruction and to exert every effort to accomplish successfully the courses of instruction prescribed: <i>And provided further</i>, That the regulations prescribed by the President under the authority of this section shall contain provisions limiting the admission of citizens of the American republics to primary schools maintained and administered by the Government of the United States so that there will under no circumstances be any curtailment of the admission of citizens of the United States eligible to receive instruction therein.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 24, 1938, ch. 644</ref>, <ref>52 Stat. 1034</ref>; <ref>July 14, 1941, ch. 292</ref>, <ref>55 Stat. 589</ref>; <ref>June 26, 1946, ch. 493, § 1</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 221a.</num>
<heading> Instructions of citizens from American republics; United States Military Academy; restrictions; saving provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After <date date="1946-06-26">June 26, 1946</date>, no person shall have authority to permit citizens of the American Republics to receive instruction at the United States Military Academy under the provisions of <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>. Any person who is receiving instruction at the United States Military Academy on <date date="1946-06-26">June 26, 1946</date>, under authority of <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>, may, in the discretion of the President, be permitted to continue to receive such instruction and, if so permitted, shall thereafter be deemed to be receiving instruction under the provisions of <ref>section 347 of title 10</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 26, 1946, ch. 493, § 2</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 312</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 222 to 224.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–256, § 111(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1961-09-21">Sept. 21, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 538</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 225.</num>
<heading> Fund for education of Iranian students in United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated, out of any funds in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, the sum of $110,000, which sum shall be expended by the Secretary of State in his discretion for the education of Iranian students in the United States, in accordance with the obligation of the United States arising out of the agreement contained in an exchange of notes between this Government and the Iranian Government of July 25, July 29, November 9, and <date date="1924-11-15">November 15, 1924</date>, which agreement settled a claim asserted by the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">The said sum of $110,000 shall be deemed a trust fund received by the Secretary of State under the provisions of <ref>section 2668a of title 22</ref>, and shall be expended as therein provided. The said sum shall be deemed to constitute the fund of $110,000 received by the United States from the Iranian Government in four installments between <date date="1924-12-24">December 24, 1924</date>, and <date date="1925-03-29">March 29, 1925</date>, pursuant to the afore-mentioned notes, and deposited in the Treasury of the United States on <date date="1925-06-24">June 24, 1925</date>, which fund shall be deemed, insofar as the same may be necessary, to have been heretofore appropriated as a trust fund under <ref>section 2668a of title 22</ref> and sections 1321 and 1322(a) of title 31. The Secretary of the Treasury shall make payments out of the said fund to or for the account of such persons, in such amounts, at such times, and on such terms, as the Secretary of State or his designee shall certify and the certificates of the Secretary of State or his designee issued hereunder shall be conclusive as to the propriety of payments so made. The expenditure of the said sum by the United States shall constitute full performance of the obligation of the United States to the Iranian Government or any other person arising out of the said notes and shall discharge the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury with respect to any accountability therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 29, 1950, ch. 1110</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref>64 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 226.</num>
<heading> Cooperative public and private sector program for providing scholarships to students from the Caribbean and Central America</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this section to encourage the establishment of partnerships between State governments, universities, community colleges, and businesses to support scholarships for talented socially and economically disadvantaged students from eligible countries in the Caribbean and Central America to study in the United States in order to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve the diversity and quality of educational opportunities for such students;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist the development efforts of eligible countries by providing training and educational assistance to persons who can help address the social and economic needs of these countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> expand opportunities for cross-cultural studies and exchanges and improve the exchange of understanding and principles of democracy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> promote positive and productive relationships between the United States and its neighbor countries in the Caribbean and Central American regions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> give added visibility and focus to the “scholarship diplomacy” efforts of the United States Government by leveraging the monies available for this purpose through the development of partnerships among Federal, State, and local governments and the business and academic communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> promote community involvement with the scholarship program as a tool for broadening and strengthening the “American experience” for foreign students.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of scholarship program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall establish and administer a program of scholarship assistance, in cooperation with State governments, universities, community colleges, and businesses, to provide scholarships to enable socially and economically disadvantaged students from eligible countries in the Caribbean and Central America to study in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants to States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Administrator may make grants to States to provide scholarship assistance for undergraduate degree programs and for training programs of one year or longer in study areas related to the critical development needs of the students’ respective countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement with States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator and each participating State shall agree on a program regarding the educational opportunities available within the State, the selection and assignment of scholarship recipients, and related issues. To the maximum extent practicable, each State shall be given flexibility in designing its program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal share for each year for which a State receives payments under this section shall be not less than 50 percent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The non-Federal share of payments under this section may be in cash, including the waiver of tuition or the offering of in-State tuition or housing waivers or subsidies, or in-kind fairly evaluated, including the provision of books or supplies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forgiveness of scholarship assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The obligation of any recipient to reimburse any entity for any or all scholarship assistance provided under this section shall be forgiven upon the recipient’s prompt return to his or her country of domicile for a period which is at least one year longer than the period spent studying in the United States with scholarship assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private sector participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, each participating State shall enlist the assistance of the private sector to enable the State to meet the non-Federal share of payments under this section. Wherever appropriate, each participating State shall encourage the private sector to offer internships or other opportunities consistent with the purposes of this section to students receiving scholarships under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any funds used in carrying out this section shall be derived from funds allocated for Latin American and Caribbean regional programs under chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> and following; relating to the economic support fund).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “eligible country” means any country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which is receiving assistance under chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> and following; relating to development assistance) or chapter 4 of part II of that Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> and following; relating to the economic support fund); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is designated by the President as a beneficiary country pursuant to the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–382, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 661</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>