<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 77—</num>
<heading>FINANCIAL LITERACY AND EDUCATION IMPROVEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Chairperson” means the Chairperson of the Financial Literacy and Education Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Commission” means the Financial Literacy and Education Commission established under <ref>section 9702 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2003</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9702.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Financial Literacy and Education Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a commission to be known as the “Financial Literacy and Education Commission”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall serve to improve the financial literacy and education of persons in the United States through development of a national strategy to promote financial literacy and education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the respective head of each of the Federal banking agencies (as defined in <ref>section 1813 of title 12</ref>), the National Credit Union Administration, the Securities and Exchange Commission, each of the Departments of Education, Agriculture, Defense, Health and Human Services, Housing and Urban Development, Labor, and Veterans Affairs, the Federal Trade Commission, the General Services Administration, the Small Business Administration, the Social Security Administration, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, and the Office of Personnel Management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> at the discretion of the President, not more than 5 individuals appointed by the President from among the administrative heads of any other Federal agencies, departments, or other Federal Government entities, whom the President determines to be engaged in a serious effort to improve financial literacy and education.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member of the Commission may designate an alternate if the member is unable to attend a meeting of the Commission. Such alternate shall be an individual who exercises significant decisionmaking authority.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall serve as the Chairperson. The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall serve as the Vice Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall hold, at the call of the Chairperson, at least 1 meeting every 4 months. All such meetings shall be open to the public. The Commission may hold, at the call of the Chairperson, such other meetings as the Chairperson sees fit to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial meeting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall hold its first meeting not later than 60 days after <date date="2003-12-04">December 4, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 513</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2003</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1013(d)(5)</ref>, (6), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9703.</num>
<heading> Duties of the Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission, through the authority of the members referred to in <ref>section 9702(c) of this title</ref>, shall take such actions as it deems necessary to streamline, improve, or augment the financial literacy and education programs, grants, and materials of the Federal Government, including curricula for all Americans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Areas of emphasis</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To improve financial literacy and education, the Commission shall emphasize, among other elements, basic personal income and household money management and planning skills, including how to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> create household budgets, initiate savings plans, and make strategic investment decisions for education, retirement, home ownership, wealth building, or other savings goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> manage spending, credit, and debt, including credit card debt, effectively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increase awareness of the availability and significance of credit reports and credit scores in obtaining credit, the importance of their accuracy (and how to correct inaccuracies), their effect on credit terms, and the effect common financial decisions may have on credit scores;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ascertain fair and favorable credit terms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> avoid abusive, predatory, or deceptive credit offers and financial products;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> understand, evaluate, and compare financial products, services, and opportunities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> understand resources that ought to be easily accessible and affordable, and that inform and educate investors as to their rights and avenues of recourse when an investor believes his or her rights have been violated by unprofessional conduct of market intermediaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> increase awareness of the particular financial needs and financial transactions (such as the sending of remittances) of consumers who are targeted in multilingual financial literacy and education programs and improve the development and distribution of multilingual financial literacy and education materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> promote bringing individuals who lack basic banking services into the financial mainstream by opening and maintaining an account with a financial institution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> improve financial literacy and education through all other related skills, including personal finance and related economic education, with the primary goal of programs not simply to improve knowledge, but rather to improve consumers’ financial choices and outcomes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Best practices for teaching financial literacy</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">After soliciting public comments and consulting with and receiving input from relevant parties, including a diverse set of institutions of higher education and other parties, the Commission shall, by not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, establish best practices for institutions of higher education regarding methods to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> teach financial literacy skills; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide useful and necessary information to assist students at institutions of higher education when making financial decisions related to student borrowing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Best practices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The best practices described in subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Methods to ensure that each student has a clear sense of the student’s total borrowing obligations, including monthly payments, and repayment options.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The most effective ways to engage students in financial literacy education, including frequency and timing of communication with students.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Information on how to target different student populations, including part-time students, first-time students, and other nontraditional students.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Ways to clearly communicate the importance of graduating on a student’s ability to repay student loans.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of best practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall maintain and periodically update the best practices information required under this paragraph and make the best practices available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require an institution of higher education to adopt the best practices required under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Website</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall establish and maintain a website, such as the domain name “FinancialLiteracy.gov”, or a similar domain name.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The website established under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> serve as a clearinghouse of information about Federal financial literacy and education programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide a coordinated entry point for accessing information about all Federal publications, grants, and materials promoting enhanced financial literacy and education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> offer information on all Federal grants to promote financial literacy and education, and on how to target, apply for, and receive a grant that is most appropriate under the circumstances;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> as the Commission considers appropriate, feature website links to efforts that have no commercial content and that feature information about financial literacy and education programs, materials, or campaigns; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> offer such other information as the Commission finds appropriate to share with the public in the fulfillment of its purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Toll-free hotline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall establish a toll-free telephone number that shall be made available to members of the public seeking information about issues pertaining to financial literacy and education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development and dissemination of materials</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop materials to promote financial literacy and education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disseminate such materials to the general public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall take such steps as are necessary to coordinate and promote financial literacy and education efforts at the State and local level, including promoting partnerships among Federal, State, and local governments, nonprofit organizations, and private enterprises.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National strategy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than 18 months after <date date="2003-12-04">December 4, 2003</date>, develop a national strategy to promote basic financial literacy and education among all American consumers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinate Federal efforts to implement the strategy developed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The strategy to promote basic financial literacy and education required to be developed under paragraph (1) shall provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> participation by State and local governments and private, nonprofit, and public institutions in the creation and implementation of such strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the development of methods—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to increase the general financial education level of current and future consumers of financial services and products; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to enhance the general understanding of financial services and products;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> review of Federal activities designed to promote financial literacy and education, and development of a plan to improve coordination of such activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the identification of areas of overlap and duplication among Federal financial literacy and education activities and proposed means of eliminating any such overlap and duplication.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National strategy review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall, not less than annually, review the national strategy developed under this subsection and make such changes and recommendations as it deems necessary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall actively consult with a variety of representatives from private and nonprofit organizations and State and local agencies, as determined appropriate by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 18 months after the date of the first meeting of the Commission, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall issue a report, the Strategy for Assuring Financial Empowerment (“SAFE Strategy”), to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on the progress of the Commission in carrying out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the national strategy for financial literacy and education, as described under subsection (f);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information concerning the implementation of the duties of the Commission under subsections (a) through (g);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of the success of the Commission in implementing the national strategy developed under subsection (f);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an assessment of the availability, utilization, and impact of Federal financial literacy and education materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> information concerning the content and public use of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the website established under subsection (b); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the toll-free telephone number established under subsection (c);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a brief survey of the financial literacy and education materials developed under subsection (d), and data regarding the dissemination and impact of such materials, as measured by improved financial decisionmaking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a brief summary of any hearings conducted by the Commission, including a list of witnesses who testified at such hearings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> information about the activities of the Commission planned for the next fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a summary of all Federal financial literacy and education activities targeted to communities that have historically lacked access to financial literacy materials and education, and have been underserved by the mainstream financial systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> such other materials relating to the duties of the Commission as the Commission deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The initial report under paragraph (1) shall include information regarding all Federal programs, materials, and grants which seek to improve financial literacy, and assess the effectiveness of such programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Testimony</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall annually provide testimony by the Chairperson to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 514</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–174, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1367</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9704.</num>
<heading> Powers of the Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission deems appropriate to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In hearings held under this subsection, the Commission shall consider inviting witnesses from, among other groups—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> other Federal Government officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> State and local government officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> consumer and community groups;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> nonprofit financial literacy and education groups (such as those involved in personal finance and economic education); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the financial services industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out this chapter. Upon request of the Chairperson, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may conduct periodic studies regarding the state of financial literacy and education in the United States, as the Commission determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multilingual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may take any action to develop and promote financial literacy and education materials in languages other than English, as the Commission deems appropriate, including for the website established under <ref>section 9703(b) of this title</ref>, at the toll-free number established under <ref>section 9703(c) of this title</ref>, and in the materials developed and disseminated under <ref>section 9703(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2007</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9705.</num>
<heading> Commission personnel matters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of the Commission shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for their service as an officer or employee of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Office of Financial Education of the Department of the Treasury shall provide assistance to the Commission, upon request of the Commission, without reimbursement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of Government employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 516</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9706.</num>
<heading> Studies by the Comptroller General</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effectiveness study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2003-12-04">December 4, 2003</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to Congress assessing the effectiveness of the Commission in promoting financial literacy and education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study and report on the need and means for improving financial literacy among consumers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to assess the extent of consumers’ knowledge and awareness of credit reports, credit scores, and the dispute resolution process, and on methods for improving financial literacy among consumers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors to be included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The study required under paragraph (1) shall include the following issues:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The number of consumers who view their credit reports.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Under what conditions and for what purposes do consumers primarily obtain a copy of their consumer report (such as for the purpose of ensuring the completeness and accuracy of the contents, to protect against fraud, in response to an adverse action based on the report, or in response to suspected identity theft) and approximately what percentage of the total number of consumers who obtain a copy of their consumer report do so for each such primary purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The extent of consumers’ knowledge of the data collection process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The extent to which consumers know how to get a copy of a consumer report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The extent to which consumers know and understand the factors that positively or negatively impact credit scores.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before the end of the 12-month period beginning on <date date="2003-12-04">December 4, 2003</date>, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to Congress on the findings and conclusions of the Comptroller General pursuant to the study conducted under this subsection, together with such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Comptroller General may determine to be appropriate, including recommendations on methods for improving financial literacy among consumers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 517</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9707.</num>
<heading> The national public service multimedia campaign to enhance the state of financial literacy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), after review of the recommendations of the Commission, as part of the national strategy, shall develop, implement, and conduct a pilot national public service multimedia campaign to enhance the state of financial literacy and education in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public service campaign</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, after review of the recommendations of the Commission, shall select and work with a nonprofit organization or organizations that are especially well-qualified in the distribution of public service campaigns, and have secured private sector funds to produce the pilot national public service multimedia campaign.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of multimedia campaign</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, after review of the recommendations of the Commission, shall develop, in consultation with nonprofit, public, or private organizations, especially those that are well qualified by virtue of their experience in the field of financial literacy and education, to develop the financial literacy national public service multimedia campaign.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Focus of campaign</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The pilot national public service multimedia campaign shall be consistent with the national strategy, and shall promote the toll-free telephone number and the website developed under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multilingual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may develop the multimedia campaign in languages other than English, as the Secretary deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance measures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall develop measures to evaluate the effectiveness of the pilot national public service multimedia campaign, as measured by improved financial decision making among individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year for which there are appropriations pursuant to the authorization in subsection (e),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002253">1</ref> the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, describing the status and implementation of the provisions of this section and the state of financial literacy and education in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, not to exceed $3,000,000 for fiscal years 2004, 2005, and 2006, for the development, production, and distribution of a pilot national public service multimedia campaign under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 518</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2009</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9708.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as may be necessary to carry out this chapter, including administrative expenses of the Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 519</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2010</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9709.</num>
<heading> Coordinated education efforts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), in coordination with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Agriculture (with respect to land-grant colleges and universities), and any other appropriate agency that is a member of the Financial Literacy and Education Commission established under the Financial Literacy and Education Improvement Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 9701</ref> et seq.), shall seek to enhance financial literacy among students at covered educational institutions through—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the development of initiatives, programs, and curricula that improve student awareness of the short- and long-term costs associated with education loans and other debt assumed while in college, their repayment obligations, and their rights as borrowers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assisting such students in navigating the financial aid process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the Secretary, working in conjunction with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Financial Literacy and Education Commission, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify programs that promote or enhance financial literacy for college students, with specific emphasis on programs that impart the knowledge and ability for students to best navigate the financial aid process, including those that involve partnerships between nonprofit organizations, colleges and universities, State and local governments, and student organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> evaluate the effectiveness of such programs in terms of measured results, including positive behavioral change among college students;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote the programs identified as being the most effective; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage covered educational institutions to implement financial education programs for their students, including those that have the highest evaluations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2008-08-14">August 14, 2008</date>, the Financial Literacy and Education Commission shall submit a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Health Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives on the state of financial education among students at covered educational institutions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required by this subsection shall include a description of progress made in enhancing financial education with respect to student understanding of financial aid, including the programs and evaluations required by this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appearance before Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall, upon request, provide testimony before the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives concerning the report required by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–315, title X, § 1042</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3489</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>