<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 79—</num>
<heading>STEM-TRAINING GRANT PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9901.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to replicate and implement programs at institutions of higher education that provide integrated courses of study in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics, and teacher education, that lead to a baccalaureate degree in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics with concurrent teacher certification.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 551</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9902.</num>
<heading> Program requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director shall replicate and implement undergraduate degree programs under this chapter that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are designed to recruit and prepare students who pursue a baccalaureate degree in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics to become certified as elementary and secondary teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require the education department (or its equivalent) and the departments or division responsible for preparation of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics majors at an institution of higher education to collaborate in establishing and implementing the program at that institution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> require students participating in the program to enter the program through a field-based course and to continue to complete field-based courses supervised by master teachers throughout the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> hire sufficient teachers so that the ratio of students to master teachers in the program does not exceed 100 to 1;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> include instruction in the use of scientifically-based instructional materials and methods, assessments, pedagogical content knowledge (including the interaction between mathematics and science), the use of instructional technology, and how to incorporate State and local standards into the classroom curriculum;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> restrict to students participating in the program those courses that are specifically designed for the needs of teachers of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> require students participating in the program to successfully complete a final evaluation of their teaching proficiency, based on their classroom teaching performance, conducted by multiple trained observers, and a portfolio of their accomplishments.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 552</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9903.</num>
<heading> Grant program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall establish a grant program to support programs at institutions of higher education to carry out the purpose of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Geographical considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the administration of this chapter, the Director shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that grants are equitably distributed across all regions of the United States, taking into account population density and other geographic and demographic considerations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of grant</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the requirements of subsection (d), the Director may award grants annually on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education in the amount of $2,000,000, per institution of which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> $1,500,000 shall be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to design, implement, and evaluate a program that meets the requirements of <ref>section 9902 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to employ master teachers at the institution to oversee field experiences;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to provide a stipend to mentor teachers participating in the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to support curriculum development and implementation strategies for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics content courses taught through the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> up to $500,000 shall be set aside by the grantee for technical support and evaluation services from the institution whose programs will be replicated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible to apply for a grant under this section, an institution of higher education shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> include former secondary school science, technology, engineering, or mathematics master teachers as faculty in its science department for this program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> grant terminal degrees in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have a process to be used in establishing partnerships with local educational agencies for placement of participating students in their field experiences, including a process for identifying mentor teachers working in local schools to supervise classroom field experiences in cooperation with university-based master teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maintain policies allowing flexible entry to the program throughout the undergraduate coursework;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> require that master teachers employed by the institution will supervise field experiences of students in the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> require that the program complies with State certification or licensing requirements and the requirements under section 9101(23) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002257">1</ref> of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 7801(23)</ref>) for highly qualified teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> develop during the course of the grant a plan for long-term support and assessment of its graduates, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> induction support for graduates in their first one to two years of teaching;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> systems to determine the teaching status of graduates and thereby determine retention rates; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> methods to analyze the achievement of students taught by graduates, and methods to analyze classroom practices of graduates; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> be able upon completion of the grant at the end of 5 years to fund essential program costs, including salaries of master teachers and other necessary personnel, from recurring university budgets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An institution of higher education seeking a grant under the program shall submit an application to the Director in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Director may require, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the current rate at which individuals majoring in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics become certified as elementary and secondary teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description for the institution’s plan for increasing the numbers of students enrolled in and graduating from the program supported under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the institution’s capacity to develop a program in which individuals majoring in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics can become certified as elementary and secondary teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identification of the organizational unit within the department or division of arts and sciences or the science department at the institution that will adopt teacher certification for elementary and secondary teachers as its primary mission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> identification of core faculty within the department or division of arts and sciences or the science department at the institution to champion teacher preparation in their departments by teaching courses dedicated to preparing future elementary and secondary school teachers, helping create new degree plans, advising prospective students within their major, and assisting as needed with program administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> identification of core faculty in the education department or its equivalent at the institution to champion teacher preparation by creating and teaching courses specific to the preparation of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics and working closely with colleagues in the department or division of arts and sciences or the science department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a description of involving practical, field-based experience in teaching and degree plans enabling students to graduate in 4 years with a major in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics and elementary or secondary school teacher certification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An institution of higher education may not receive a grant under this section unless it provides, from non-federal sources, to carry out the activities supported by the grant, an amount that is not less than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 35 percent of the amount of the grant for the first fiscal year of the grant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 55 percent of the amount of the grant for the second and third fiscal years of the grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 75 percent of the amount of the grant for the fourth and fifth fiscal years of the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 90 days after <date date="2011-01-04">January 4, 2011</date>, the Director shall initiate a proceeding to promulgate guidance for the administration of the grant program established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9904.</num>
<heading> Grant oversight and administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director may execute a contract for program oversight and fiscal management with an organization at an institution of higher education, a non-profit organization, or other entity that demonstrates capacity for and experience in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> replicating 1 or more similar programs at regional or national levels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> providing programmatic and technical implementation assistance for the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> performing data collection and analysis to ensure proper implementation and continuous program improvement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> providing accountability for results by measuring and monitoring achievement of programmatic milestones.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight responsibilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Director executes a contract under subsection (a) with an organization for program oversight and fiscal management, the organization shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that a grant recipient faithfully replicates and implements the program or programs for which the grant is awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that grant funds are used for the purposes authorized and that a grant recipient has a system in place to track and account for all Federal grant funds provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance to grant recipients;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> collect and analyze data and report to the Director annually on the effects of the program on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the progress of participating students in achieving teaching competence and teaching certification;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the participation of students in the program by major, compared with local and State needs on secondary teachers by discipline; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the participation of students in the program by demographic subgroup;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> collect and analyze data and report to the Director annually on the effects of the program on the academic achievement of elementary and secondary school students taught by graduates of programs funded by grants under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> submit an annual report to the Director demonstrating compliance with the requirements of subparagraphs (A) through (E).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of the Director, the organization under contract under subsection (a) may assist the Director in evaluating grant applications.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall submit a copy of the annual report required by subsection (b)(1)(F) to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the House of Representatives Committee on Science and Technology, and the House of Representatives Committee on Education and Labor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4024</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9905.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Field-based course</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “field-based course” means a course of instruction offered by an institution of higher education that includes a requirement that students teach a minimum of 3 lessons or sequences of lessons to elementary or secondary students.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term by <ref>section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Master teacher</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “master teacher” means an individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who has been awarded a master’s or doctoral degree by an institution of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whose graduate coursework included courses in mathematics, science, computer science, or engineering;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> who has at least 3 years teaching experience in K–12 settings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whose teaching has been recognized for exceptional accomplishments in educating students, or is demonstrated to have resulted in improved student achievement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mentor teacher</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “mentor teacher” means an elementary or secondary school classroom teacher who assists with the training of students participating in a field-based course.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 555</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9906.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director to carry out this chapter $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2013.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 556</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4026</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>