<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 57—</num>
<heading>JAMES MADISON MEMORIAL FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4501.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to establish the James Madison Fellowship Program which is designed to encourage graduate study of the American Constitution, its roots, its formation, its principles, and its development.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 802]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–76, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 802]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–76.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4502.</num>
<heading> Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to commemorate the bicentennial of the Constitution, there is established, as an independent establishment of the executive branch, the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of Trustees; membership; term of office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Foundation shall be subject to the supervision and direction of a Board of Trustees. The Board shall be composed of thirteen members, as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Two Members of the Senate, of different political parties, shall be appointed by the President upon the recommendation of the President pro tempore of the Senate, in consultation with the Majority Leader and Minority Leader of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Two Members of the House of Representatives, of different political parties, shall be appointed by the President upon the recommendation of the Speaker of the House, in consultation with the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Two members of the Federal judiciary shall be appointed by the President upon the recommendation of the Chief Justice of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Six members, not more than three of whom shall be of the same political party, shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate, of whom one shall be a chief executive officer of a State, two shall be members of the general public, and three shall be members of the academic community, appointed upon the recommendation of the Librarian of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Education or his designate shall serve ex officio as a member of the Board, but shall not be eligible to serve as Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term of office of each member of the Board shall be six years; except that (A) the members first taking office shall serve as designated by the President, four for terms of two years, five for terms of four years, and four for terms of six years, and (B) any member appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the remainder of the term for which his predecessor was appointed, and shall be appointed in the same manner as the original appointment for that vacancy was made. This provision shall not apply to members ex officio.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the Board whose term has expired may continue to serve until the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date on which a successor has taken office; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the Congress adjourns sine die to end the session of Congress that commences after the date on which the member’s term expired.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Board shall elect from the members of the Board a Chairman and such other officers as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the Foundation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for expenses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), members of the Board shall serve without pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the Board and the President, Executive Secretary, and other personnel of the Foundation shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties at rates applicable to judges of the United States under <ref>section 456(a) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 803]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–76, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 803]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–76; <ref>Pub. L. 101–208, § 1</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–221, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-11">Dec. 11, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1676</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503.</num>
<heading> Fellowship recipients</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Foundation is authorized to award fellowships to outstanding students and teachers who will pursue graduate study leading to the degree of Master of Arts in teaching or other appropriate masters degree for teachers, with a major in social studies or American history. Each recipient must take at least twelve semester hours, or its equivalent in topics directly related to the Constitution of the United States, as determined by the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> James Madison fellowships shall be awarded to individuals who are, or who desire to become, social studies and American history teachers in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Junior fellowships shall be awarded to graduate students who are about to complete or have recently completed their undergraduate course of study, and plan to begin graduate work on a relatively full-time basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Senior fellowships shall be awarded to experienced teachers who wish to undertake work for a graduate degree on a part-time basis during summers or in evening programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 804]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–77, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 804]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–77.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4504.</num>
<heading> Period for award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Junior fellowships shall be granted for such periods as the Foundation may prescribe but not to exceed two academic years. Senior fellowship shall be granted for such periods as the Foundation may prescribe, but not to exceed five calendar years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 805]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–77, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 805]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–77.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4505.</num>
<heading> Recipient’s choice of institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Fellowship recipients may attend any institution of higher education in the United States with an accredited graduate program which offers courses of study or training which emphasize the origins of the Constitution of the United States, its principles, its development, and its comparison with other forms of government, as determined according to criteria established by the Foundation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 806]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–77, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 806]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–77.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4506.</num>
<heading> Recipient’s eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each student awarded a fellowship under this chapter shall demonstrate the potential, and a serious intention, to follow a career of educating students in secondary schools. Each institution of higher education at which such a student is in attendance shall make reasonable efforts to encourage such a student to meet the objectives of this section.</p>
<p class="indent0">Each student receiving a Fellowship under this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002171">1</ref> shall enter into an agreement under which the recipient shall:</p>
<p class="indent1">(a) within a 5-year period after completing the education for which the fellowship was awarded, teach on a full-time basis students in secondary school for a period of not less than one year for each year for which asistance <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002172">2</ref> was received;</p>
<p class="indent1">(b) repay all of the Fellowship assistance received plus interest at the rate of 6% per annum and, if applicable, reasonable collection fees for each school year for which assistance was received for which such recipient failed to teach as provided in paragraph (a); and</p>
<p class="indent1">(c) not be considered to be in violation of the agreement entered into during any period during which the recipient:</p>
<p class="indent2">(1) is pursuing a full-time course of study related to the field of teaching at an eligible institution;</p>
<p class="indent2">(2) is serving, not in excess of 3 years, as a member of the armed services of the United States;</p>
<p class="indent2">(3) is temporarily totally disabled for a period of time not to exceed 3 years as established by sworn affidavit of a qualified physician;</p>
<p class="indent2">(4) is unable to secure employment for a period not to exceed 12 months by reason of the care required by a spouse who is disabled;</p>
<p class="indent2">(5) is seeking and unable to find full-time employment for a single period not to exceed 12 months; or</p>
<p class="indent2">(6) is seeking and unable to find full-time employment as a teacher.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 807]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–77, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 807]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–77.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4507.</num>
<heading> Selection of fellowship recipients</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for selection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Madison Fellows shall be selected for their academic achievements and their potential to become secondary school teachers of social studies and American history.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Competition for selection; application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Foundation is authorized, either directly or by contract, to provide for the conduct of a nationwide competition for the selection of fellowship recipients. Each applicant must have a demonstrated interest in pursuing a course of study which emphasizes the Constitution, its principles, and its history, and have a demonstrated record of willingness to devote themselves to civil responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each application shall be accompanied by an essay explaining the importance of the study of the Constitution both to the applicant’s career aspirations and contributions to public service, and to citizenship generally in a constitutional regime.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each application shall include a description of a program of study for the graduate program, designating the courses to be taken, and the proposed Master’s thesis, where appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this paragraph, the Board of Trustees of the Foundation shall establish general criteria for programs in constitutional studies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional selection of recipients</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation shall adopt selection procedures which shall assure that at least one Madison Fellow shall be selected each year from each State, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and considered as a single entity, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Trust Territories of the Pacific Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas in which there are at least two resident applicants who meet the minimum criteria established by the Foundation; and, if sufficient funding is available, to invite applications from scholars overseas for study in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 808]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–78, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 808]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–78.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4508.</num>
<heading> Amount of fellowships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each student awarded a fellowship shall receive a stipend which shall not exceed the cost to the student for tuition, fees, books, room and board, or $12,000, whichever is less, for each academic year of study.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 809]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–78, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 809]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–78.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4509.</num>
<heading> Fellowship conditions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A student awarded a Madison Fellowship shall continue to receive payments only during such periods as the Foundation finds that the student is maintaining satisfactory progress in an approved program of study or research. Recipients of junior fellowships shall devote essentially full time to their program of study.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Foundation is authorized to require reports from any fellowship recipient containing such information, in such form, and to be filed at such times as the Foundation determines to be necessary. Such reports shall be accompanied by a certificate from an appropriate official at the institution of higher education, approved by the Foundation, stating that such student is making satisfactory progress in a program of study or research, with such exceptions as the Foundation may establish.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 810]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–79, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 810]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–79.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4510.</num>
<heading> James Madison Memorial Fellowship Trust Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund consisting of appropriations and amounts contributed by the Foundation for the Commemoration of the Constitution and other private sources to be available, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment of amounts appropriated</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> At the request of the Trust Fund, it shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury to invest in full the amounts appropriated and contributed to the fund. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States issued directly to the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of special obligations directly to the fund. Such special obligations shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average rate of interest, computed as to the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of such issue, borne by all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt; except that where such average rate is not a multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum, the rate of interest of such special obligations shall be the multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum next lower than such average rate. All requests of the Trust Fund to the Secretary of the Treasury provided for in this section shall be binding upon the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of obligations acquired by fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of the Trust Fund, the Secretary of the Treasury shall redeem any obligation issued directly to the fund. Obligations issued to the fund under subsection (b)(2) shall be redeemed at par plus accrued interest. Any other obligations issued directly to the fund shall be redeemed at the market price.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest and proceeds from sale or redemption of obligations credited to fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The interest on, and the proceeds from, the sale or redemption of any obligations held in the fund shall be credited to and form a part of the fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 811]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–79, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 811]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–79; <ref>Pub. L. 102–221, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-11">Dec. 11, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1676</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. J, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4511.</num>
<heading> Expenditures and audit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to pay to the Foundation from the interest and earnings of the fund such sums as the Board determines are necessary and appropriate to enable the Foundation to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The activities of the Foundation under this chapter may be audited by the Government Accountability Office under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. The representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, and files and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the Foundation, pertaining to such activities and necessary to facilitate the audit.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 812]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–80, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 812]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–80; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4512.</num>
<heading> President and Executive Secretary of Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Board may appoint a President of the Foundation to serve full-time or part-time and for such a term as the Board shall determine.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President shall carry out such of the functions and duties of the Foundation as the Board may determine, subject to the supervision and direction of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President shall be compensated at a rate to be determined by the Board without regard to subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, not to exceed the rate for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of that title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Sections 5532,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002173">1</ref> 8344, and 8468 of title 5 shall not apply to a person while such person is serving as President of the Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be an Executive Secretary of the Foundation who shall be appointed by the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Executive Secretary shall be the chief operating officer of the Foundation and shall carry out the functions of the Foundation subject to the supervision and direction of the Board or the President, as determined by the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Executive Secretary shall be compensated at the rate specified for employees placed in grade GS–18 of the General Schedule set forth in <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 813]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–80, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 813]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–80; <ref>Pub. L. 101–208, § 2</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–557, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–589, title II, § 253</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4513.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Foundation is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary to carry out this chapter,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002174">1</ref> without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, but at General Schedule pay rates not in excess of the maximum rate for grade GS–15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of that title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to procure temporary and intermittent services of such experts and consultants as are necessary to the extent authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, but at rates not to exceed the rate specified at the time of such service for grade GS–18 in section 5332 of such title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to prescribe such regulations as it deems necessary governing the manner in which its functions shall be carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to receive money and other property donated, bequeathed, or devised, without condition or restriction other than it be used for the purposes of the Foundation; and to use, sell, or otherwise dispose of such property for the purpose of carrying out its functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to accept and utilize the services of voluntary and noncompensated personnel and reimburse them for travel expenses, including per diem, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to enter into contracts, grants, or other arrangements, or modifications thereof, to carry out the provisions of this chapter,<sup>1</sup> and such contracts or modifications thereof may, with the concurrence of two-thirds of the members of the Board, be entered into without performance or other bonds, and without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to make advances, progress, and other payments which the Board deems necessary under this chapter without regard to the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to rent office space in the District of Columbia or its environs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to conduct programs in addition to or in conjunction with the Fellowship program which shall further the Foundation’s purpose of encouraging research and study of constitutionalism in America;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> to expend not more than 5 percent of its annual operating budget to pay the costs of fundraising activities, including public and private gatherings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> to make other necessary expenditures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The foundation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002175">2</ref> shall submit to the President and to the Congress an annual report of its operations under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detailing of agency personnel to Foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On request of the Chairman of the Foundation, the head of a Federal agency may detail personnel of the agency to the Foundation to assist the Foundation in carrying out this chapter.<sup>1</sup> Details under this subsection shall be without reimbursement by the Foundation to the agency from which personnel are detailed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 814]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–80, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 814]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–80; <ref>Pub. L. 101–208, § 3</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4514.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Board” means the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Foundation” means the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “institution of higher education” has the same meaning given that term by <ref>section 1001 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “secondary school” has the same meaning given that term by <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 815]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–81, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 815]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–81; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(6)(G)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076(m)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2092</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(vv)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4515.</num>
<heading> Appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are appropriated to the James Madison Memorial Trust Fund $20,000,000 to carry out the provisions of this chapter, $10,000,000 of which shall be available on <date date="1987-11-01">November 1, 1987</date>, and to remain available until expended; and $10,000,000 of which shall be available on <date date="1988-11-01">November 1, 1988</date>, and to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 816]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–81, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 816]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–81.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4516.</num>
<heading> Constitutional Law Resource Centers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this section to establish four centers where nationally recognized distinguished experts in Constitutional law will produce, on a periodic basis, articles of current interest relating to the Constitution of the United States which are suitable for use by James Madison scholars, educational institutions, law school reviews, bar associations, and the news media.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Endowments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to encourage recipient universities to provide such a continuing service, four endowments shall be established with funds from appropriations provided herein and such other amounts as may be contributed from other sources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair for Professor of Constitutional Law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The income from each endowment shall be used to help support a chair for a Professor of Constitutional law.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002176">1</ref> Each endowment shall be held in trust with the income from the portion provided herein used exclusively to contribute toward the salary and related costs of the professor filling the chair and for services directly related to the support of such professor such as secretarial and research services. The recipient university shall from sources other than that portion of the endowment funded herein furnish the office, classroom and related services suitable to such a member of the faculty.</p>
<p class="indent0">The professor holding each chair shall file a copy of such articles with the Library of Congress, which shall make them available to libraries in the usual manner and the recipient of the endowment shall also make a copy available upon request by accredited educational institutions, bar associations, and general news media without royalty or charge other than the costs associated with printing or reprinting, handling and distribution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment of endowment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">That portion of each endowment provided by this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002177">2</ref> and any accumulations attributable to such grant shall be invested by the recipient university in interest bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed both as to principal and interest by the United States and shall be subject to audit by the Government Accountability Office for the sole purpose of determining that such funds are accounted for or have been used as provided herein. If a grantee university elects to discontinue such chair and support services, the corpus of the endowment attributable to the Federal grant shall revert to the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application for grant of endowment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The application for the grant for an endowment shall require only such information and supporting material as is reasonably necessary to assure that the funds will be used for the purposes described herein. Acceptance of the grant by each university shall constitute an agreement and obligation of that university to fulfill the obligations set forth in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of grant of endowment; recipients of offer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The grants for each endowment shall be for $800,000 and shall be offered to Howard University School of Law in Washington, D.C., Drake University School of Law in Des Moines, Iowa, the University of Akron School of Law in Akron, Ohio, and the University of South Carolina School of Law at Columbia, South Carolina.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 817]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–81, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 817]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–81; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4517.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for universities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby appropriated to each recipient University named above or to the trustee of the fund designated by the President of the University the sum of $800,000 to carry out the provisions of <ref>section 4516 of this title</ref>, to be available on <date date="1987-11-01">November 1, 1987</date>, and to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 818]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–82, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 818]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–82.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>