<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 52—</num>
<heading>EDUCATION FOR ECONOMIC SECURITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3901.</num>
<heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to improve the quality of mathematics and science teaching and instruction in the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3902.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “area career and technical education school” has the same meaning given that term under <ref>section 2302(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Director” means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “elementary school” has the same meaning given that term under <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Governor” means the chief executive of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “Foundation” means the National Science Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “institution of higher education” has the same meaning given that term by <ref>section 1001 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “local educational agency” has the same meaning given that term under <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “secondary school” has the same meaning given that term under <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The term “State agency for higher education” means the State board of higher education or other agency or officer primarily responsible for the State supervision of higher education, or, if there is no such officer or agency, an officer or agency designated for the purpose of this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002155">1</ref> by the Governor or by State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The term “State educational agency” has the meaning given that term under <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1267</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(6)(F)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2092</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–270, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 747</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(dd)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING EDUCATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3911.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress declares that the science and engineering education responsibilities of the National Science Foundation are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to improve the quality of instruction in the fields of mathematics, science, and engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support research, fellowships, teacher-faculty-business exchange programs in mathematics, science, and engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to improve the quality and availability of instrumentation for mathematics, science, and engineering instruction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to encourage partnerships in education between local and State education agencies, business and industry, colleges and universities, and cultural and professional institutions and societies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to improve the quality of education at all levels in the fields of mathematics, science, and engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In exercising its responsibilities to strengthen scientific and engineering research potential and science and engineering education programs at all levels, the Foundation shall avoid undue concentration of support for research and education activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 101</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3912.</num>
<heading> Functional objectives; uses of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In carrying out its science and engineering education responsibilities, the Foundation shall have the following functional objectives: public understanding of science and technology, faculty enhancement, student education and training, instructional development and instrumentation, and materials development and dissemination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Funds under this subchapter shall, consistent with such functional objectives, be used for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhancement of public understanding of science and engineering through informal education activities using a variety of mediums such as broadcasting, museums, clubs, and amateur science societies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> development of new science and engineering faculty resources and talents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enhancement of the quality of science and engineering instruction in colleges of teacher education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> development of four-year college faculty and instructors in high technology fields;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> development of two-year community college faculty and instructors especially in high technology fields;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> development of precollege mathematics, science and engineering education and training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> encouragement of potential students, including underrepresented and underserved populations, to pursue careers in mathematics, science, engineering, and critical foreign languages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> development of instructional instrumentation and systems for postsecondary technical, engineering, and scientific education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> development of science, engineering, and education networks to aid in the development and dissemination of successful curricula, methods, and materials.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 102</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3913.</num>
<heading> Teacher institutes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to make competitive grants; covered institutions, businesses, etc.; purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation shall, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, make competitive grants to institutions of higher education, businesses, nonprofit private organizations (including schools), local education agencies, professional engineering and scientific associations, museums, libraries, public broadcasting entities (as defined in <ref>section 397(11) of title 47</ref>), and appropriate State agencies to support institutes and workshops for supervisors and teachers in public and private elementary and secondary schools for the purpose of improving the subject knowledge and teaching skills of such teachers in the areas of mathematics and science.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equitable distribution of grants; awards in each State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making grants under this section, the Foundation shall assure that there is an equitable distribution among States of institutes established and operated with funds made available under this section. The Foundation shall award not less than one institute in each State, except that the Foundation may waive this requirement if there is no proposal from a State which meets the requirements of this subchapter. Proposals which exceed $300,000 in any fiscal year incorporating the services or resources of more than two entities in the design and operation of the institute, may be funded at the discretion of the Director of the Foundation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation of advanced technology businesses and other businesses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Institutes assisted under this subchapter may, to the extent possible, involve the cooperation of advanced technology businesses and other businesses which are able to supply assistance in the teaching of mathematics and science.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of involvement in planning and development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making grants under this subchapter, the Foundation shall require assurances that local education agencies will be involved in the planning and development of the institute in the case of applications submitted by other eligible applicants described in subsection (a) of this section, or that one or more such applicants will be involved in the planning and development of the institute in the case of applications submitted by State or local education agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 103</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3914.</num>
<heading> Materials development and methods research for mathematics, science, and engineering</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to award competitive grants; covered institutions, businesses, etc.; purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Foundation is authorized, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education, businesses, nonprofit private organizations, local education agencies, professional engineering and scientific associations, museums, libraries, public broadcasting entities (as defined in <ref>section 397(11) of title 47</ref>), and appropriate State agencies—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for instructional curriculum improvement and faculty development in mathematics, science, and engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for programs designed to enhance public understanding of mathematics, science, and engineering, including the use of public broadcasting entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for research on methods of instruction and educational programs in mathematics, science, engineering, and critical foreign languages.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of studies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Studies conducted under subsection (a)(3) may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> teaching and learning research and its application to local and private sector instructional materials development and to improved teacher training programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> research on the use of local and informal science education activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> research on recruitment, retention, and improvement of mathematics, science, engineering, and critical languages faculties; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> analysis of materials and methods for mathematics, science, and engineering education used in other countries and their potential application in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching grant requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds awarded for such competitive grants shall be expended through a system requiring matching of the grant. The minimum amount required as a match shall be equal to a percentage of the grant that is determined by the Foundation. Funds made available for matching purposes may include in-kind services or other resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Materials or methods research application requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making grant applications for materials or methods research for the purposes described in subsections (a)(1) and (a)(3), the Foundation shall assure the involvement of appropriate State or local education agencies in the case of applications submitted by other entities described in subsection (a), or that one or more of such other entities will be consulted in the case of applications submitted by State or local education agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 104</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3915.</num>
<heading> Graduate fellowships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation is authorized, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, to establish and carry out a program of graduate fellowships for the purpose of encouraging and assisting promising students to continue their education and research in mathematics, science, and engineering.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 105</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3916.</num>
<heading> Other functional activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Foundation is authorized to expend up to 15 per centum of the funds available for science and engineering education for applications which the Foundation determines will meet one or more of the functional objectives described in <ref>section 3912(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Such programs may include a program for the exchange of mathematics, science, or engineering faculty between institutions of higher education (particularly institutions having nationally recognized research facilities) and eligible institutions. For the purposes of this section, the term “eligible institution” means an institution of higher education which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has an enrollment which includes a substantial percentage of students who are members of a minority group, or who are economically or educationally disadvantaged; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is located in a community that is not within commuting distance of a major institution of higher education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> demonstrates a commitment to meet the special educational needs of students who are members of a minority group or are economically or educationally disadvantaged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 106</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3917.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2141(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 731</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3918.</num>
<heading> Approval of proposals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation shall adopt approval procedures designed to assure that awards are made on the basis of the scientific and educational merit as determined by the peer review process. To the maximum extent possible, the Foundation shall assure that there is an equitable distribution of resources with respect to institutions and geographical areas.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 108</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3919.</num>
<heading> Special consideration of underrepresented and underserved population</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing financial assistance under this subchapter, the Foundation shall make every effort to ensure that consideration is given to proposals which contain provisions designed to meet the needs of underrepresented and underserved populations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 109</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3920.</num>
<heading> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds to carry out this subchapter for any fiscal year shall be made available from amounts appropriated pursuant to annual authorizations of appropriations for the National Science Foundation for Science and Engineering Education. For fiscal year 1986, funds to carry out this subchapter shall be available from amounts authorized by section 102(a)(8) of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act for fiscal year 1986.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 110</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3921.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against the Federal control of education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of section 1232a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002156">1</ref> of this title, relating to prohibition against Federal control of education, shall apply to each program and award authorized by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 111</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3922.</num>
<heading> Participation of teachers from private schools</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation shall, after consultation with appropriate private school representatives, make provision for the benefit of teachers in private elementary and secondary schools in the programs authorized by this subchapter, in order to assure equitable participation of such teachers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 112</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EDUCATION FOR ECONOMIC SECURITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 3961 to 3973.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title II, § 2303</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 324</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PARTNERSHIPS IN EDUCATION FOR MATHEMATICS, SCIENCE, AND ENGINEERING</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Higher Education Partnerships</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3981.</num>
<heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this part to supplement State and local resources to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve the quality of instruction in the fields of mathematics, science, and engineering in the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> furnish additional resources and support for research, student scholarships, and faculty exchange programs in the fields of mathematics, science, and engineering; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage partnerships in education between the business community, institutions of higher education, and elementary and secondary schools in the community.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3982.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this part—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “applicant” means with respect to activities described in <ref>section 3984(a) of this title</ref> an institution of higher education and the other participants described in paragraph (3) of <ref>section 3984(a) of this title</ref>, and with respect to activities described in <ref>section 3984(b) of this title</ref> a local educational agency and the other participants described in paragraph (3) of <ref>section 3984(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “equipment” includes machinery, utilities, and built-in equipment and any necessary enclosures or structures to house them, and includes all other items necessary for the functioning of a particular facility as a facility for the provision of educational services, including items such as instructional equipment and necessary furniture, printed, published, and audio-visual instructional materials, and books, periodicals, documents, and other related materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “State agency for higher education” means the State board of higher education or other agency or officer primarily responsible for the State supervision of higher education, or if there is no such officer or agency, an officer or agency designated by the Governor or by State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 232</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3983.</num>
<heading> Program authorized</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized, in accordance with the provisions of this part, to make grants to applicants to pay the Federal share of the costs of the activities described in <ref>section 3984 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1986 and 1987. There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this part $15,000,000 for fiscal year 1989 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1990, 1991, 1992, and 1993.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II</ref>, §§ 231, 233, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 900</ref>, 901; <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title II, § 2301</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 319</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3984.</num>
<heading> Authorized activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Higher education partnership in education programs and activities; eligible applicants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An applicant may use payments received under this part in any fiscal year for higher education programs and activities described in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Grants under this subsection may be used for partnership in education programs—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the improvement of instruction in mathematics, science, computer science, and engineering education at the postsecondary level;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for awarding scholarships to students at institutions of higher education in the fields of mathematics, science, computer science, and engineering;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for the operation of faculty exchange programs by the institutions of higher education and business concerns within the State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for research in the fields of mathematics, science, computer science, and engineering;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> for the acquisition, rehabilitation, and renovation of equipment and instrumentation for use in instruction in the fields of mathematics, science, computer science, and engineering; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to promote public understanding of science, mathematics, and computer science.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Education partnerships under this subsection may include institutions of higher education, business concerns, nonprofit private organizations, local educational agencies, professional mathematic and scientific associations, museums, libraries, educational television stations, and if the State so desires, appropriate State agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elementary and secondary partnership in education programs and activities; eligible applicants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An applicant may use payments received under this part in any fiscal year for programs and activities described in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A local educational agency may carry out an elementary and secondary school partnership in education program under which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> elementary and secondary school teachers in the schools of local educational agencies who teach mathematics, science, or computer science are made available to local business concerns and business concerns with establishments located in the community to serve in such concerns or establishments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personnel of local business concerns and business concerns with establishments located in the community serve as consultants, lecturers, teaching assistants, or teachers of mathematics, science, or computer science in the elementary and secondary schools within the State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> training and retraining is furnished to elementary and secondary school teachers of mathematics, science, and computer science under a cooperative arrangement between the State or local educational agency and appropriate business concerns;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> secondary school students observe, participate, and work in local business concerns and business concerns with establishments located in the community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> computer clubs and extracurricular activities involving modern technologies are established in elementary and secondary schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Partnerships under this subsection may include local educational agencies, business concerns, nonprofit private organizations, institutions of higher education, professional mathematic and scientific associations, museums, libraries, educational television stations, and, if the State so desires, appropriate State agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3985.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements; terms, assurances, and conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any applicant which desires to receive a grant under this part shall submit an application approved under <ref>section 3986 of this title</ref> to the Secretary, at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such additional information as the Secretary may reasonably require. Each such application shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describe the activities for which assistance under this part is sought;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide assurances that not more than 5 per centum of the amount received by the applicant in any fiscal year may be expended on administrative expenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to each program for which assistance is sought, provide assurances that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 30 per centum of the funds for each such project will be furnished by business concerns within the community;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> 20 per centum of the funds will be supplied by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the State,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the institution of higher education or the local educational agency, as the case may be, participating in the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the other parties participating in the program;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> no stipend will be paid directly to employees of a profitmaking business concern; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> teachers participating in the exchange program may not be employed by the participating business concern with which the teacher served within three years after the end of the exchange program unless the teacher repays the full cost of the exchange program to the State and local educational agency, as the case may be; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide assurances that whenever the program for which assistance is sought includes scholarships, the scholarships be awarded to undergraduate students at institutions of higher education within the State who wish to pursue a course of study in mathematics or science, engineering or computer science, and that each student awarded a scholarship under this part will receive a stipend which shall not exceed the cost of tuition at the institution of higher education plus a stipend of not to exceed $750 for each academic year of study for which the scholarship is awarded;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> set forth policies and procedures to assure that whenever the application includes a local educational agency, to the extent consistent with the number and location of children in the school district of such agency who are enrolled in private elementary and secondary schools, provision is made for the participation of such children in the program assisted under this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide assurances that consideration is given to programs and activities designed to meet the needs of underrepresented and underserved populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide assurances that in the consideration of applications submitted under <ref>section 3986(a) of this title</ref> that equitable consideration is given to applications submitted by private and public institutions of higher education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> provide such additional assurances as the Secretary determines essential to ensure compliance with the requirements of this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional joint application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A regional consortium of applicants in two or more States may file a joint application under the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3986.</num>
<heading> Submission of applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each applicant within a State which desires to receive a grant under this part shall submit the application prepared in accordance with <ref>section 3985 of this title</ref> to the State agency on <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002157">1</ref> higher education or the State educational agency, as the case may be, for approval and shall submit the approved application to the Secretary under <ref>section 3985 of this title</ref>. Each such application shall be submitted jointly by the local educational agency in the case of activities described in <ref>section 3984(a) of this title</ref>, or an institution of higher education in the case of activities described in <ref>section 3984(b) of this title</ref>, and each business concern or other party that is to participate in the program for which assistance is sought.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3987.</num>
<heading> Approval of applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria; consistency of applications with State plans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish criteria for approval of applications under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No application may be approved by the Secretary unless the State educational agency or the State agency for higher education, as the case may be, determines that the application is consistent with State plans for elementary and secondary education or State plans for higher education, as the case may be, in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures for equitable distribution of grants among States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall adopt approval procedures designed to assure that there is equitable distribution of grants among the States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3988.</num>
<heading> Payments; Federal share; limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal and non-Federal shares</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall pay, to each applicant having an application approved under <ref>section 3987 of this title</ref>, the Federal share of the cost of the program described in the application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Federal share for each fiscal year shall be 50 per centum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The non-Federal share of payments under this part may be in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal year State limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 15 per centum of the funds appropriated under this part in any fiscal year may be paid to applicants in any single State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Elementary and Secondary Education Partnerships</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3991.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this part to supplement State and local resources to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve the quality of instruction in the fields of mathematics and science in elementary and secondary schools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> furnish additional resources and support for the acquisition of equipment, and instructional and reference materials and improvement of laboratory facilities in elementary and secondary schools; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage partnerships in science and mathematics education between the business community, museums, libraries, professional mathematics and scientific associations, private nonprofit organizations, appropriate State agencies and elementary and secondary schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 321</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3992.</num>
<heading> Programs authorized</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make grants to States to pay the Federal share of the cost of the programs described in <ref>section 3994 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for purposes of carrying out this part <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002158">1</ref> $20,000,000 for fiscal year 1988.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 322</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3993.</num>
<heading> Amendment to State application</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State shall be eligible to receive a grant under this part if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the State submits to the Secretary as part of its application under section 209 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002159">1</ref> such information and assurances as the Secretary may require at such time as the Secretary shall establish; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary approves such application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall require each application to include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the State’s procedures relating to the use of funds from grants received under this part, including the approval process for local applications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assurance that not more than 1 percent of the amount received shall be used for administrative expenses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an assurance that the State will, to the extent possible, assist local school districts in economically depressed areas to obtain matching funds from business concerns.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 323</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3994.</num>
<heading> Eligible programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State may use funds from grants received in any fiscal year under this part for elementary and secondary programs described in this section. The State educational agency shall administer such funds, which shall be awarded to such programs on a competitive basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds from grants received under this part may be used for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Improvement of elementary and secondary resources</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Such funds may be used for acquisition of equipment, instructional and reference materials, and partnership in education programs designed to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve instruction in mathematics and science education at the elementary and secondary level;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improve laboratory facilities, classroom and library resources in elementary and secondary mathematics and science education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> attract matching dollars and in kind contributions of equipment, learning resources or shared time from business concerns, libraries, museums, nonprofit private organizations, professional mathematics and scientific associations, and appropriate State agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advanced placement programs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Such funds may be used for advanced placement programs operated by local educational agencies that are designed to allow qualified secondary students to attend college preparatory schools, colleges, or universities on a part-time or full-time basis with respect to science and mathematics instruction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A local educational agency that receives funds from a grant under this part for an advanced placement program described in subparagraph (A) shall allocate to such program a percentage of funds received from the State on a per student basis according to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of students participating in the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the instruction time such students receive under the program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 324</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3995.</num>
<heading> Local applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An applicant that desires to receive a grant under this part shall submit an application to the State educational agency, at such time, and in such manner, as the State may require. Such application may take the form of an amendment to an assessment submitted by the local educational agency under section 210,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002160">1</ref> if appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The State shall require each application to include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the activities for which assistance under this part is sought;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assurances that not more than 5 percent of the amount received by the applicant in any fiscal year shall be expended on administrative expenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> if the funds are to be used for improvement of elementary and secondary resources as described in subsection (b)(1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an estimate of the amount to be spent on equipment, facilities improvement, library resources, and classroom instructional material;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an estimate of the number of elementary and secondary students who will be aided by activities and expenditures under the grant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> assurances that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> except as provided in subsection (c), a minimum of 25 percent of the funds for each project will be supplied by business concerns within the community;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> no stipend shall be paid directly to employees of a profitmaking business concern;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provision shall be made for the equitable participation in the project of children who are enrolled in private elementary and secondary schools; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> consideration will be given to programs and activities designed to meet the needs of educationally disadvantaged and other traditionally underserved populations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> if the funds are to be used for advanced placement programs as described in subsection (b)(2), a commitment as to the percentage of funds received from the State on a per student basis that shall be used by the local educational agency to defray costs of the advanced placement program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The State may waive or reduce the amount of matching funds required under subsection (b)(3)(C)(i) if the State determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> substantial need exists in the area served by the applicant for a grant under this part; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the required amount of matching funds cannot be made available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A regional consortium of applicants in 2 or more local school districts may file a joint application under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 325</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3996.</num>
<heading> Submission of applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An applicant within a State that desires to receive a grant under this part <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002161">1</ref> shall submit an application prepared in accordance with <ref>section 3995 of this title</ref> to the State educational agency for approval. Each application with respect to funds for improvement of elementary and secondary resources under <ref>section 3994(b)(1) of this title</ref> shall be submitted jointly by the local educational agency and each business concern or other party that is to participate in the activities for which assistance is sought.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 326</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3997.</num>
<heading> Approval of applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The State shall establish criteria for approval of applications under this section. Such criteria shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consideration of the local district’s need for, and inability to locally provide for, the activities, equipment, library and instructional materials requested;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number and nature of elementary and secondary students who will benefit from the planned program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the expressed level of financial and in-kind commitment from other parties to the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The State shall adopt approval procedures designed to ensure that grants are equitably distributed among—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> rural, urban, and suburban areas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> small, medium, and large local educational agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 327</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3998.</num>
<heading> Computation of grant amounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments to grantees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment by State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State shall pay to the extent of amounts received by it from the Secretary under this part, to each applicant having an application approved under <ref>section 3997 of this title</ref>, the Federal share of the cost of the program described in the application.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Federal share for each fiscal year shall be 75 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of an applicant that receives a waiver under <ref>section 3995(c) of this title</ref>, the Federal share for each fiscal year may be as much as 100 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The non-Federal share of payments under this part may be in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments to States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), each State shall receive under this part the greater of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an amount equal to its share of funds appropriated under chapter 1 of the Education Consolidation and Improvement Act; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $225,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction for insufficient funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If sums appropriated to carry out this part are not sufficient to permit the Secretary to pay in full the grants which States may receive under subsection (b), the amount of such grants shall be ratably reduced.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title III, § 328</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title VI, § 6031(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1482</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>PRESIDENTIAL AWARDS FOR TEACHING EXCELLENCE IN MATHEMATICS AND SCIENCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 4001 to 4003.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title II, § 2303</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 324</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>ASBESTOS SCHOOL HAZARD ABATEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4011.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> exposure to asbestos fibers has been identified over a long period of time and by reputable medical and scientific evidence as significantly increasing the incidence of cancer and other severe or fatal diseases, such as asbestosis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> medical evidence has suggested that children may be particularly vulnerable to environmentally induced cancers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> medical science has not established any minimum level of exposure to asbestos fibers which is considered to be safe to individuals exposed to the fibers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> substantial amounts of asbestos, particularly in sprayed form, have been used in school buildings, especially during the period 1946 through 1972;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> partial surveys in some States have indicated that (A) in a number of school buildings materials containing asbestos fibers have become damaged or friable, causing asbestos fibers to be dislodged into the air, and (B) asbestos concentration far exceeding normal ambient air levels have been found in school buildings containing such damaged materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the presence in school buildings of friable or easily damaged asbestos creates an unwarranted hazard to the health of the school children and school employees who are exposed to such materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Department of Health and Human Services and the Environmental Protection Agency, as well as several States, have attempted to publicize the potential hazards to school children and employees from exposure to asbestos fibers, but there is no systematic program for remedying hazardous conditions in schools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> because there is no Federal health standard regulating the concentration of asbestos fibers in noncommercial workplace environments such as schools, school employees and students may be exposed to hazardous concentrations of asbestos fibers in the school buildings which they use each day;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> without a program of information distribution, technical and scientific assistance, and financial support, many local educational agencies and States will not be able to mitigate the potential asbestos hazards in their schools; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the effective regulation of interstate commerce for the protection of the public health requires the establishment of programs under this subchapter to mitigate hazards from exposure to asbestos fibers and materials emitting such fibers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to assist States and local educational agencies to ascertain the extent of the danger to the health of school children and employees from asbestos materials in schools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide continuing scientific and technical assistance to State and local agencies to enable them to identify and abate asbestos hazards in schools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide financial assistance for the abatement of asbestos threats to the health and safety of school children or employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assure that no employee of any local educational agency suffers any disciplinary action as a result of calling attention to potential asbestos hazards which may exist in schools.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637, § 14(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(1), (2), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4594</ref>, 4595.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4012.</num>
<heading> Asbestos hazard abatement program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abatement program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established a program within the Environmental Protection Agency to be known as the Asbestos Hazards Abatement Program (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as “Program”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The duties of the Administrator in implementing and effectuating the Program shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the compilation of medical, scientific, and technical information including, but not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the health and safety hazards associated with asbestos materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the means of identifying, sampling, and testing materials suspected of emitting asbestos fibers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the means of abating the threat posed by asbestos and asbestos containing materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the distribution of the information described in paragraph (1) (in any appropriate form such as pamphlets, reports, or instructions) to State and local educational agencies and to other institutions, including parent and employee organizations, for the purpose of carrying out activities described in this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not later than November 15 of each year for which this subchapter is authorized, the development and distribution of applications, or notifications to all local educational agencies of the availability of application forms including information for obtaining such forms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the review of applications for financial assistance, and the approval or disapproval of such applications, in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 4014 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 4, 14(a)(3), (b)(3), (4), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4590</ref>, 4594, 4595.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4013.</num>
<heading> State records and priority lists</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Governor of each State shall maintain records on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the presence of asbestos materials in school buildings of local educational agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the asbestos detection and abatement activities and other response actions conducted by local educational agencies (including activities relating to the replacement of the asbestos materials removed from school buildings with other appropriate building materials); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> repairs made to restore school buildings to conditions comparable to those which existed before the abatement activities referred to in paragraph (2) were undertaken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority list</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each year, in accordance with procedures established by the Administrator, the Governor of each State shall:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submit to the Administrator a priority list of all schools under the authority of a local educational agency within the State, without regard to the public or private nature of the school involved, that are candidates for abatement activities and other response actions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> forward to the Administrator for each candidate for abatement activities and other response actions all applications for financial assistance prepared by the local educational agencies in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 4014 of this title</ref>; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002162">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The priority list shall rank the potential candidates for abatement action based on the nature and magnitude of the existing and potential exposure presented by the asbestos materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For each school listed, the Governor shall certify that the statement of need contained in the application for assistance accurately reflects the financial resources available to the local educational agency for the asbestos abatement program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of determining the adequacy of the financial resources available to a local educational agency for the abatement of asbestos threats the Governor shall, to the extent practicable, consider the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A measure of financial need used by the State in which the local educational agency is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The estimated per capita income of the locality of such agency or of those directly or indirectly providing financial support for such agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The extent to which the local school millage rate falls above or below (i) the millage rate average of the State and (ii) the millage rate of other local educational agencies with comparable enrollment, per capita income, and resource base.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The ratio, expressed as a percentage, of the estimated cost of the project to the total budget of the local educational agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The borrowing capacity of the local educational agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any additional costs to the local educational agency of meeting the special needs of disadvantaged students.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Any other factor that demonstrates that the local educational agency has limited financial resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 5, 14(a)(4), (b)(5), (6), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4590</ref>, 4594, 4595.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4014.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established within the Environmental Protection Agency an Asbestos Hazards Abatement Assistance Program (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Assistance Program”), which shall be administered in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application submission</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Applications for financial assistance shall be submitted by a local educational agency to the Governor, or the Governor’s designee, who shall establish a priority list based on the criteria of <ref>section 4013(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Pursuant to <ref>section 4013 of this title</ref>, the Governor shall submit applications, together with the Governor’s report and priority list, to the Administrator who shall review and rank such applications pursuant to subsection (c)(2) and propose financing pursuant to the criteria of <ref>section 4013(b)(4) of this title</ref>. The Administrator shall approve or disapprove applications for financial assistance no later than April 30 of each year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Administrator shall provide financial assistance on a school-by-school basis to local educational agencies in accordance with other provisions of this section to carry out projects for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> abating the threat posed by materials containing asbestos to the health and safety of children or employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> replacing the asbestos materials removed from school buildings with other appropriate building materials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> restoring school buildings to conditions comparable to those existing before abatement activities were undertaken pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Administrator shall review and list in priority order applications for financial assistance. In ranking applications, the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the priority assigned to the abatement program by the Governor pursuant to <ref>section 4013(b)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the likelihood of release of asbestos fibers into a school environment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other evidence of the risk caused by the presence of asbestos including, but not limited to, situations in which there is a substantial quantity of dry loose asbestos-containing material on horizontal surfaces or asbestos-containing material is substantially deteriorated or damaged, and there is asbestos-containing material in an air plenum or in a high traffic area, confined space, or within easy reach of a passerby;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the extent to which the corrective action proposed by the applicant will reduce the exposure of school children and school employees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the extent to which the corrective action proposed by the applicant uses the least burdensome methods which protect human health and the environment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In determining whether an applicant is eligible for assistance, and the nature and amount of financial assistance, the Administrator shall consider the financial resources available to the applicant as certified by the Governor pursuant to <ref>section 4013(b)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In no event shall financial assistance be provided under this subchapter to an applicant if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Administrator determines that such applicant has resources adequate to support an appropriate asbestos materials abatement program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the applicant is not in compliance with title II of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2641</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of loan or grant</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An applicant for financial assistance may be granted a loan of up to 100 percent of the costs of an abatement program or, if the Administrator determines the applicant is unable to undertake and complete an asbestos materials abatement program with a loan, such applicant may also receive a grant (alone or in combination with a loan) not to exceed 50 percent of the total costs of abatement, in the amount which the Administrator deems necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In approving any grant, the Administrator shall state with particularity the reasons why the applicant is unable to undertake and complete the abatement program with loan funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Loans under this section shall be made pursuant to agreements which shall provide for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the loan shall not bear interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the loan shall have a maturity period of not more than twenty years (as determined by the Administrator) and shall be repayable during such period at such times and in such amounts as the Administrator may specify in the loan agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> repayment shall be made to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit in the Asbestos Trust Fund established by <ref>section 4022 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such other terms and conditions that the Administrator determines necessary to protect the financial interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No financial assistance may be provided under this section unless an application has been submitted to the Administrator in accordance with such procedures as may be developed by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Administrator shall not approve an application unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the application contains such information as the Administrator may require, including but not limited to information describing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the nature and extent of the asbestos problem for which the assistance is sought;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the asbestos content of the material to be abated;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the methods which will be used to abate the asbestos materials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the amount and type of financial assistance requested;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a description of the financial resources of the local educational agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a justification for the type and amount of the financial assistance requested.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the application contains a certification that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the local educational agency has prepared and is implementing an asbestos management plan, as required under title II of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2641</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all activities to be conducted with the financial assistance will be performed by individuals trained and accredited in conformance with title II of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2641</ref> et seq.) and regulations promulgated under that title;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the application contains assurances that the local educational agency will furnish such information as is necessary for the Administrator to make the report required by <ref>section 4016 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No financial assistance may be provided by the Administrator under this section for projects described in subsection (a)(2) on which abatement action was completed prior to <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 4021(b)(1) of this title</ref>, in approving applications the Administrator shall provide assistance to the local educational agencies having the highest priority among applications being considered in order of ranking until the appropriated funds are expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–519, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2988</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–368, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-18">July 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 6, 14(a)(5), (b)(7), (c)(1)–(4), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4591</ref>, 4594–4596.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4015.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall promulgate rules and regulations as necessary to implement the authorities and requirements of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator also shall establish procedures to be used by local educational agencies, in programs for which financial assistance is made available under <ref>section 4014 of this title</ref>, for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> abating asbestos materials in school buildings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> replacing the asbestos materials removed from school buildings with other appropriate building materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> restoring such school buildings to conditions comparable to those existing before asbestos containment or removal activities were undertaken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed, interpreted, or applied to diminish in any way the level of protection required under any other State or Federal worker protection or other applicable laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to effectuate the purposes of this subchapter, the Administrator may also adopt such other procedures, standards, and regulations as the Administrator deems necessary, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> procedures for testing the level of asbestos fibers in schools, including safety measures to be followed in conducting such tests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> standards for evaluating (on the basis of such tests) the likelihood of the leakage of asbestos fibers into the school environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> periodic reporting with respect to the activities that have taken place using funds loaned or granted under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 7, 14(a)(6), (b)(8), (9), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4592</ref>, 4594, 4595.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4016.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">During each calendar year until 1999, the Administrator shall prepare and submit, not later than June 1 of each year, to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the loan and grant program authorized by <ref>section 4014 of this title</ref>.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describe the number of applications received;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describe the number of loans and grants made in the preceding calendar year and specify each applicant for and recipient of a loan or grant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specify the number of loan or grant applications which were disapproved during the preceding calendar year and describe the reasons for such disapprovals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> describe the types of programs for which loans or grants were made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> specify the estimated total costs of such programs to the recipients of loans or grants and specify the amount of loans or grants made under the program authorized by this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> estimate the number of schools still in need of assistance and the amount of resources needed by such schools, categorized by State, to abate all remaining asbestos hazards.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 8, 14(a)(7), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4592</ref>, 4594.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4017.</num>
<heading> Recovery of costs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan condition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As a condition of the award of any financial assistance under <ref>section 4014 of this title</ref>, the recipient of any such loan or grant shall permit the United States to sue on behalf of such recipient any person determined by the Attorney General to be liable to the recipient for the costs of any activities undertaken by the recipient under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The proceeds from any judgment recovered in any suit brought by the United States under paragraph (1) (or, if the recipient files a similar suit on its own behalf, the proceeds from a judgment recovered by the recipient in such suit) shall be used to repay to the United States, by deposit in the Asbestos Trust Fund established by <ref>section 4022 of this title</ref>, to the extent that the proceeds are sufficient to provide for such repayment, an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount (i) outstanding on any loan and (ii) of any grant made to the recipient; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an amount equal to the interest which would have been charged on such loan were the loan made by a commercial lender at prevailing interest rates (as determined by the Administrator).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expeditious recovery</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall, where appropriate, proceed in an expeditious manner to recover the amounts expended by the United States to carry out this subchapter from the persons identified by the Attorney General as being liable for such costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 508</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 9, 14(a)(8), (b)(10), (11), (c)(5), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4592</ref>, 4594–4596.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4018.</num>
<heading> Employee protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No State or local educational agency receiving assistance under this subchapter may discharge any employee or otherwise discriminate against any employee with respect to the employee’s compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment because the employee has brought to the attention of the public information concerning any asbestos problem in the school buildings within the jurisdiction of such agency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637, § 14(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4019.</num>
<heading> Affect on rights under other laws</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in <ref>section 4017 of this title</ref>, nothing in this subchapter shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> affect the right of any party to seek legal redress in connection with the purchase or installation of asbestos materials in schools or any claim of disability or death related to exposure to asbestos in a school setting; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> affect the rights of any party under any other law.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 510</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637, § 14(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4020.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “asbestos” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> chrysotile, amosite, or crocidolite; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in fibrous form, tremolite, anthophyllite, or actinolite.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Attorney General” means the Attorney General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “threat” or “hazard” means that an asbestos material is friable or easily damaged, or within reach of students or employees or otherwise susceptible to damage (including damage from water, vibration, or air circulation) which could result in the dispersal of asbestos fibers into the school environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “local educational agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any local educational agency as defined in <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the governing authority of any nonprofit elementary or secondary school.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “nonprofit elementary or secondary school” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any elementary school or secondary school as defined in <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref> owned and operated by one or more nonprofit corporations or associations no part of the net earnings of which inures, or may lawfully inure, to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any school of any agency of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “school buildings” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> structures suitable for use as classrooms, laboratories, libraries, school eating facilities, or facilities used for the preparation of food;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any gymnasium or other facility which is specially designed for athletic or recreational activities for an academic course in physical education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other facilities used for the instruction of students, for research, or for the administration of educational or research programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> maintenance, storage, or utility facilities essential to the operation of the facilities described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, or the Administrator’s designee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “response action” has the meaning given such term by <ref>section 2642(11) of title 15</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 10, 14(a)(11), (c)(6), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4592</ref>, 4594, 4596; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 394(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2), <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2092</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(dd)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4021.</num>
<heading> Authorization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount; availability until expended</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the asbestos abatement program not more than $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1991, 1992, 1993, 1994, and 1995. In addition, for such purposes and for each of such fiscal years there are authorized to be appropriated out of the Asbestos Trust Fund established by <ref>section 4022 of this title</ref> such sums as are contained in such trust fund in each of such fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The sums appropriated under this subchapter shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum State amount; fiscal year obligation requirement; reserved funds for administration and asbestos abatement oriented program expenditures; appropriations out of Asbestos Trust Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A State with qualified applicants shall receive no less than one-half of 1 per centum of the sums appropriated under this subchapter or the total of the amounts requested by such applicants, whichever is less. Those amounts available in each fiscal year under this paragraph shall be obligated before the end of that fiscal year. For the purposes of this paragraph the term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Bureau of Indian Affairs and, taken together, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Of those sums appropriated for the implementation of this subchapter, not more than 5 percent may be reserved during each fiscal year for the administration of this subchapter and for programs including (but not limited to) the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The establishment of training centers for contractors, engineers, school employees, parents, and other personnel to provide instruction, in accordance with title II of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2641</ref> et seq.), on asbestos assessment and abatement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The development and dissemination of abatement guidance documents to assist in evaluation of potential hazards and the determination of proper abatement programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The development of rules and regulations regarding inspection, reporting, and recordkeeping.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The development of a comprehensive testing and technical assistance program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Of those sums appropriated for any fiscal year for the implementation of this subchapter, the Administrator may use not more than 5 percent to provide grants to States for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Assisting local educational agencies in performing the periodic reinspections and training activities required under title II of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2641</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Establishing and maintaining programs to accredit personnel performing asbestos inspections and response actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–519, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2989</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–368, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-18">July 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 11, 14(a)(12), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4592</ref>, 4595.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4022.</num>
<heading> Asbestos Trust Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Creation of Trust Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Asbestos Trust Fund”, consisting of such amounts as may be transferred or credited to such Trust Fund as provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers to Trust Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There are hereby transferred to the Asbestos Trust Fund amounts equivalent to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts received in the Treasury on or after <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, as repayments of loans made under <ref>section 4014 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts received as deposits from local educational agencies under <ref>section 2647(a) of title 15</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> amounts received as proceeds from any judgment recovered in any suit brought pursuant to <ref>section 4017(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monthly transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amounts transferred by paragraph (1) shall be transferred at least monthly from the general fund of the Treasury to the Asbestos Trust Fund on the basis of estimates made by the Secretary of the Treasury of the amounts referred to in such paragraph. Adjustments shall be made in the amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were more or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management of Trust Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the Asbestos Trust Fund as is not, in his judgment, required to meet current withdrawals. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States and may be acquired—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on original issue at the issue price, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of obligations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any obligation acquired by the Asbestos Trust Fund may be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest on certain proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Asbestos Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Trust Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1131(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 725</ref></heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures from Asbestos Trust Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Asbestos Trust Fund shall be available, as provided by appropriation Acts, only for purposes of carrying out the Asbestos Hazards Abatement Assistance Program under <ref>section 4014 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to borrow</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Asbestos Trust Fund, as repayable advances, $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1987, 1988, 1989, and 1990.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment of advances</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Advances made under this subsection shall be repaid, and interest on such advances shall be paid, to the general fund of the Treasury when the Secretary determines that moneys are available for such purposes in the Asbestos Trust Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Interest on advances made under this subsection shall be at a rate determined by the Secretary (as of the close of the calendar month preceding the month in which the advance is made) to be equal to the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the anticipated period during which the advance will be outstanding and shall be compounded annually.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–519, § 5</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–637, § 12</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1131(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>EXCELLENCE IN EDUCATION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 4031 to 4037.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title II, § 2303</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 324</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>MAGNET SCHOOLS ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 4051 to 4062.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title II, § 2303</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 324</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>EQUAL ACCESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4071.</num>
<heading> Denial of equal access prohibited</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction of limited open forum on basis of religious, political, philosophical, or other speech content prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any public secondary school which receives Federal financial assistance and which has a limited open forum to deny equal access or a fair opportunity to, or discriminate against, any students who wish to conduct a meeting within that limited open forum on the basis of the religious, political, philosophical, or other content of the speech at such meetings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Limited open forum” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A public secondary school has a limited open forum whenever such school grants an offering to or opportunity for one or more noncurriculum related student groups to meet on school premises during noninstructional time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fair opportunity criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Schools shall be deemed to offer a fair opportunity to students who wish to conduct a meeting within its limited open forum if such school uniformly provides that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the meeting is voluntary and student-initiated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is no sponsorship of the meeting by the school, the government, or its agents or employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> employees or agents of the school or government are present at religious meetings only in a nonparticipatory capacity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the meeting does not materially and substantially interfere with the orderly conduct of educational activities within the school; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> nonschool persons may not direct, conduct, control, or regularly attend activities of student groups.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of subchapter with respect to certain rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to authorize the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to influence the form or content of any prayer or other religious activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to require any person to participate in prayer or other religious activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to expend public funds beyond the incidental cost of providing the space for student-initiated meetings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to compel any school agent or employee to attend a school meeting if the content of the speech at the meeting is contrary to the beliefs of the agent or employee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to sanction meetings that are otherwise unlawful;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to limit the rights of groups of students which are not of a specified numerical size; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to abridge the constitutional rights of any person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal financial assistance to schools unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the availability of any other remedy under the Constitution or the laws of the United States, nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to authorize the United States to deny or withhold Federal financial assistance to any school.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of schools with respect to order, discipline, well-being, and attendance concerns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to limit the authority of the school, its agents or employees, to maintain order and discipline on school premises, to protect the well-being of students and faculty, and to assure that attendance of students at meetings is voluntary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4072.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “secondary school” means a public school which provides secondary education as determined by State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “sponsorship” includes the act of promoting, leading, or participating in a meeting. The assignment of a teacher, administrator, or other school employee to a meeting for custodial purposes does not constitute sponsorship of the meeting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “meeting” includes those activities of student groups which are permitted under a school’s limited open forum and are not directly related to the school curriculum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “noninstructional time” means time set aside by the school before actual classroom instruction begins or after actual classroom instruction ends.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4073.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this subchapter or the application thereof to any person or circumstances is judicially determined to be invalid, the provisions of the remainder of the subchapter and the application to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4074.</num>
<heading> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this subchapter shall supersede all other provisions of Federal law that are inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–377, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IX—</num>
<heading>STAR SCHOOLS PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 4081 to 4086.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 364</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3975</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>