<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 59—</num>
<heading>BARRY GOLDWATER SCHOLARSHIP AND EXCELLENCE IN EDUCATION PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4701.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Senator Barry Goldwater of the State of Arizona has served his country for 56 years as a soldier and statesman, including service in the United States Senate for a period of 30 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Senator Goldwater has a distinguished record as a Senator, including service as Chairman of the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and as Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Senator Goldwater has long maintained a special interest in the education of America’s youth, particularly in the fields of science and mathematics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> It would, therefore, be a fitting tribute to the leadership, courage, and vision of Senator Goldwater to establish in his name a scholarship program to foster and encourage excellence in science and mathematics.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1402</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Foundation” means the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation established under <ref>section 4703(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Board” means the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation established under <ref>section 4703(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “fund” means the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Fund provided for under <ref>section 4707 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “institution of higher education” means any such institution as defined in <ref>section 1001 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of Palau, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “eligible person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a permanent resident alien of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a citizen or national of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a citizen of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federal States of Micronesia, or the Republic of Palau; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any person who may be admitted to lawfully engage in occupations and establish residence as a nonimmigrant in the United States as permitted under the Compact of Free Association agreements with the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federal States of Micronesia, or the Republic of Palau.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1403</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(6)(H)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXIII, § 6302</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4703.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established, as an independent establishment of the executive branch of the United States Government, the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of Trustees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Foundation shall be subject to the supervision and direction of the Board of Trustees. The Board shall be composed of 13 members, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Two members from the Senate, one appointed by the majority leader and one appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Two members from the House of Representatives, one appointed by the majority leader and one appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Eight members, not more than four of whom shall be of the same political party, to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Education, or his designee, who shall serve ex officio as a member of the Board but shall not be eligible to serve as Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term of office of each member of the Board shall be six years, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the members first taking office shall serve as designated by the President, four for terms of two years, five for terms of four years, and four for terms of six years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a member appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the remainder of the term for which his predecessor was appointed and shall be appointed in the same manner as the original appointment for that vacancy was made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> notwithstanding the term limitation provided for under this paragraph, a member appointed under subsection (b) may continue to serve under such appointment until the successor to the member is appointed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A Member of Congress appointed to the Board under clause (1) or (2) of subsection (b) may not serve as a member of the Board for more than a total of six years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel and subsistence pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Board shall serve without pay, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1404</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(10)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1089(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1179(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1770</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4704.</num>
<heading> Barry Goldwater scholarship and excellence in education awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of scholarships, fellowships, and research internships</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Foundation may award scholarships, fellowships, and research internships to eligible persons for study in the fields of the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics. Such scholarships, fellowships, and research internships shall be awarded to persons as provided in this chapter who meet the minimum criteria established by the Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Scholarships shall be awarded to outstanding undergraduate students who intend to pursue careers in the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics, which shall be prioritized for students attending community colleges and minority-serving institutions specified in <ref>section 1067q(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Fellowships shall be awarded to outstanding graduate students who intend to pursue advanced degrees in the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Research internships shall be awarded to outstanding undergraduate students who intend to pursue careers in the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics, which shall be prioritized for students attending community colleges and minority-serving institutions specified in <ref>section 1067q(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Foundation may provide, directly or by contract, for the conduct of nationwide competition for the purpose of selecting recipients of scholarships, fellowships, and research internships awarded under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Barry Goldwater Scholars and Research Interns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Recipients of scholarships and fellowships under this chapter shall be known as “Barry Goldwater Scholars”. Recipients of research internships under this chapter shall be known as “Barry Goldwater Interns”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of honoraria to volunteers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Foundation may award honoraria to outstanding educators, teachers, and persons who have volunteered to assist in secondary schools who have made significant contributions to improve the quality of instruction in mathematics and sciences in the secondary school. To the extent the Board determines such action practicable, honoraria awarded under this subsection shall be awarded annually to persons described in the preceding sentence as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To two persons selected at large from each State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To one person selected from each county in each State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To persons affiliated with secondary schools on military reservations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To persons affiliated with the dependent overseas school system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board shall establish a schedule of honoraria to be awarded under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1405</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4009</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXIII, § 6303</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4705.</num>
<heading> Stipends</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each person awarded a scholarship or fellowship under this chapter shall receive a stipend which shall not exceed the cost to such person for tuition, fees, books, room and board, or such lesser amount as may be prescribed by the Board. Each person awarded a research internship under this chapter shall receive a stipend as may be prescribed by the Board, which shall not exceed the maximum stipend amount awarded for a scholarship or fellowship.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1406</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXIII, § 6304</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4706.</num>
<heading> Scholarship and research internship conditions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scholarship conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person awarded a scholarship under this chapter may receive payments authorized under this chapter only during such periods as the Foundation finds that the person is maintaining satisfactory proficiency pursuant to regulations of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports on scholarships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation may require reports containing such information in such form and to be filed at such times as the Foundation determines to be necessary from any person awarded a scholarship under this chapter. Such reports shall be accompanied by a certificate from an appropriate official at the institution of higher education, approved by the Foundation, stating that such person is making satisfactory progress in, and is devoting essentially full time to study or research, except as otherwise provided in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research internship conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person awarded a research internship under this chapter may receive payments authorized under this chapter only during such periods as the Foundation finds that the person is maintaining satisfactory proficiency pursuant to regulations of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports on research internships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation may require reports containing such information in such form and to be filed at such times as the Foundation determines to be necessary from any person awarded a research internship under this chapter. Such reports may be accompanied by a certificate from an appropriate official at the institution of higher education or internship employer, approved by the Foundation, stating that such person is maintaining satisfactory progress in the internship.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1407</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXIII, § 6305</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4707.</num>
<heading> Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Fund. The fund shall consist of amounts appropriated to it pursuant to <ref>section 4711 of this title</ref> and amounts credited to it under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment of fund assets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury to invest in full the amounts appropriated to the fund. Such investments may be made only in public debt securities of the United States with maturities suitable to the fund. For such purpose, such obligations may be acquired (1) on original issue at the issue price, or (2) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market place. The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of special obligations exclusively to the fund. Such special obligations shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average rate of interest, computed as to the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of such issue, borne by all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt, except that where such average rate is not a multiple of ⅛ of 1 percent, the rate of interest of such special obligations shall be the multiple of ⅛ of 1 percent next lower than such average rate. Such special obligations shall be issued only if the Secretary determines that the purchases of other interest-bearing obligations of the United States, or of obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States or original issue or at the market price, is not in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment in securities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary of the Treasury may invest any public or private funds received by the Foundation after <date date="2021-12-27">December 27, 2021</date>, in securities other than or in addition to public debt securities of the United States, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary receives a determination from the Board that such investments are necessary to enable the Foundation to carry out the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the securities in which such funds are invested are traded in established United States markets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002178">1</ref> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Board to increase the number of scholarships provided under section 4704 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002179">2</ref> of this title, or to increase the amount of the stipend authorized by section 4705 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002179">2</ref> of this title, as the Board considers appropriate and is otherwise consistent with the requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <sup>1</sup> Authority to sell obligations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any obligation acquired by the fund may be sold by the Secretary at the market price.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proceeds from certain transactions credited to fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the fund shall be credited to and form a part of the fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1408</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1089(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1054(h)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXIII, § 6306</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4708.</num>
<heading> Expenditures from fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury may pay to the Foundation from the interest and earnings of the fund such sums as the Board determines are necessary and appropriate to enable the Foundation to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits by GAO</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The activities of the Foundation under this chapter may be audited by the Government Accountability Office under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. Representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, and files and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the Foundation pertaining to such activities and necessary to facilitate the audit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1409</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4709.</num>
<heading> Executive Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment by Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be an Executive Secretary of the Foundation who shall be appointed by the Board. The Executive Secretary shall be the chief executive officer of the Foundation and shall carry out the functions of the Foundation subject to the supervision and direction of the Board. The Executive Secretary shall carry out such other functions consistent with the provisions of this chapter as the Board shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Secretary of the Foundation shall serve as a noncareer appointee of the Senior Executive Service and shall be compensated at a rate determined by the Board in accordance with <ref>section 5383 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1410</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1089(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4710.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to carry out this chapter, the Foundation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> appoint and fix the rates of basic pay of not more than three employees (in addition to the Executive Secretary appointed under section 4709 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002180">1</ref> of this title) to carry out the provisions of this chapter, without regard to the provisions in chapter 33 of title 5 governing appointment in the competitive service or the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a rate of basic pay set under this paragraph may not exceed the maximum rate provided for employees in grade GS–15 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the employee shall be entitled to the applicable locality-based comparability payment under <ref>section 5304 of title 5</ref>, subject to the applicable limitation established under subsection (g) of such section;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procure temporary and intermittent services of experts and consultants as are necessary to the extent authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, but at rates not to exceed the rate specified at the time of such service for level IV of the Executive Schedule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prescribe such regulations as it considers necessary governing the manner in which its functions shall be carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> receive money and other property donated, bequeathed, or devised, without condition or restriction other than it be used for the purposes of the Foundation, and to use, sell, or otherwise dispose of such property for the purpose of carrying out its functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> accept and use the services of voluntary and noncompensated personnel and for travel expenses, including per diem, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> enter into contracts or other arrangements, or make grants, to carry out the provisions of this chapter, and enter into such contracts or other arrangements, or make such grants, with the concurrence of two-thirds of the members of the Board, without performance or other bonds and without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> rent office space in the Washington, District of Columbia, metropolitan area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> expend not more than 5 percent of the Foundation’s annual operating budget on programs that, in addition to or in conjunction with the Foundation’s scholarship financial awards, support the development of Goldwater Scholars throughout their professional careers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> expend not more than 5 percent of the Foundation’s annual operating budget to pay the costs associated with fundraising activities, including public and private gatherings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> make other necessary expenditures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Foundation shall submit to the President and to Congress an annual report of its operations under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1411</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1179(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXIII, § 6307</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4711.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the fund $40,000,000 to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIV, § 1412</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4012</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>