<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING EDUCATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1221.</num>
<heading> Short title; applicability; definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “General Education Provisions Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of chapter</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided, this chapter applies to each applicable program of the Department of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided, this chapter does not apply to any contract made by the Department of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the following terms have the following meanings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “applicable program” means any program for which the Secretary or the Department has administrative responsibility as provided by law or by delegation of authority pursuant to law. The term includes each program for which the Secretary or the Department has administrative responsibility under the Department of Education Organization Act [<ref>20 U.S.C. 3401</ref> et seq.] or under Federal law effective after the effective date of that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “applicable statute” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Act or the title, part, section, or any other subdivision of an Act, as the case may be, that authorizes the appropriation for an applicable program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other statute that by its terms expressly controls the administration of an applicable program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Department” means the Department of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of other laws unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect the applicability of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq.], title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.], title V of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [<ref>29 U.S.C. 790</ref> et seq.], the Age Discrimination Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 6101</ref> et seq.], or other statutes prohibiting discrimination, to any applicable program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 400</ref>, formerly § 401, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–576, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-16">Oct. 16, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 164</ref>; renumbered § 400, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3912</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221–1.</num>
<heading> National policy with respect to equal educational opportunity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Recognizing that the Nation’s economic, political, and social security require a well-educated citizenry, the Congress (1) reaffirms, as a matter of high priority, the Nation’s goal of equal educational opportunity, and (2) declares it to be the policy of the United States of America that every citizen is entitled to an education to meet his or her full potential without financial barriers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 597</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221–2.</num>
<heading> National policy with respect to museums as educational institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress, recognizing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that museums serve as sources for schools in providing education for children,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that museums provide educational services of various kinds for educational agencies and institutions and institutions of higher education, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the expense of the educational services provided by museums is seldom borne by the educational agencies and institutions taking advantage of the museums’ resources,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">declares that it is the sense of the Congress that museums be considered educational institutions and that the cost of their educational services be more frequently borne by educational agencies and institutions benefiting from those services.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 597</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221–3.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FUNCTIONS OF DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1221a to 1221c.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221d.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 96–374, title X, § 1001(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1491</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–227, title IX, § 911(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-03-31">Mar. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 213</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1221e–1 to 1221e–1c.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221e–1d.</num>
<heading> Use of Council staff and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Advisory Council on Educational Research and Improvement, the Advisory Council on Education Statistics, and members of such councils may not use any staff, facilities, equipment, supplies, or franking privileges of the councils for activities unrelated to the purposes of the councils.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–498, title XIV, § 1403</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1599</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221e–2.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221e–3.</num>
<heading> General authority of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, in order to carry out functions otherwise vested in the Secretary by law or by delegation of authority pursuant to law, and subject to limitations as may be otherwise imposed by law, is authorized to make, promulgate, issue, rescind, and amend rules and regulations governing the manner of operation of, and governing the applicable programs administered by, the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 410</ref>, formerly § 408, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 559</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII</ref>, §§ 1243(b), 1244, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2353</ref>; renumbered § 410 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 222, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3914.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221e–4.</num>
<heading> Educational impact statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no regulation affecting any institution of higher education in the United States, promulgated on or after <date date="1980-10-03">October 3, 1980</date>, shall become effective unless such agency causes to be published in the Federal Register a copy of such proposed regulation together with an educational impact assessment statement which shall determine whether any information required to be transmitted under such regulation is already being gathered by or is available from any other agency or authority of the United States. Notwithstanding the exception provided under <ref>section 553(b) of title 5</ref>, such statement shall be based upon the record established under the provisions of <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, compiled during the rulemaking proceeding regarding such regulation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 411</ref>, formerly § 409, as added <ref>Pub. L. 96–374, title XIII, § 1306</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1498</ref>; renumbered § 411, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1221f to 1221h.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title V, § 5352(4)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 414</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221i.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(e) [title VII, § 708(d)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–233</ref>, 3009–312</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1221j.</num>
<heading> Television program assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Granting and contracting authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education is authorized to make grants to and contracts with public and private agencies for the production, development, or distribution (or any combination thereof) of programs designed for television systems, whether broadcast or nonbroadcast.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education shall be responsible for the administration of this section and shall also conduct surveys, research, and evaluation studies which may assist in decisions to support pilot programs for full scale production.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XV, § 1527</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2379</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>APPROPRIATIONS AND EVALUATIONS</heading>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 1—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Appropriations</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1222.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 506(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 562</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1223.</num>
<heading> Forward funding</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To the end of affording the responsible Federal, State, and local officers adequate notice of available Federal financial assistance for carrying out ongoing education activities and projects, appropriations for grants, contracts, or other payments under any applicable program are authorized to be included in the appropriations Act for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year during which such activities and projects shall be carried out.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In order to effect a transition to the timing of appropriation action authorized by subsection (a), the application of this section may result in the enactment, in a fiscal year, of separate appropriations for an applicable program (whether in the same appropriations Act or otherwise) for two consecutive fiscal years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 420</ref>, formerly § 403, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 165</ref>; renumbered § 412, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; renumbered § 411, <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 506(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 562</ref>; renumbered § 420 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 231, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3914.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1224.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 506(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 562</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1225.</num>
<heading> Availability of appropriations on academic or school-year basis; additional period for obligation of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Academic or differing fiscal year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations for any fiscal year for grants, loans, contracts, or other payments under any applicable program may, in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, be made available for obligation by the recipient on the basis of an academic or school year differing from such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Succeeding fiscal year</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, unless enacted in specific limitation of the provisions of this subsection, any funds from appropriations to carry out any programs to which this chapter is applicable during any fiscal year, which are not obligated and expended by educational agencies or institutions prior to the beginning of the fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year for which such funds were appropriated shall remain available for obligation and expenditure by such agencies and institutions during such succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any funds under any applicable program which, pursuant to paragraph (1), are available for obligation and expenditure in the year succeeding the fiscal year for which they were appropriated shall be obligated and expended in accordance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Federal statutory and regulatory provisions relating to such program which are in effect for such succeeding fiscal year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any program plan or application submitted by such educational agencies or institutions for such program for such succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of judicial proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any funds appropriated to carry out any applicable program are not obligated pursuant to a spending plan submitted in accordance with <ref>section 1341(a) of title 31</ref> and become available for obligation after the institution of a judicial proceeding seeking the release of such funds, then such funds shall be available for obligation and expenditure until the end of the fiscal year which begins after the termination of such judicial proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 421</ref>, formerly § 405, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(5)</ref>, (7), (8), <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 165</ref>; renumbered § 414, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; renumbered § 412, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 506(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (E), <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 3(12)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–112, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-09-24">Sept. 24, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1245</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2354</ref>; renumbered § 421 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 232, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3914.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1226.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1226a.</num>
<heading> Contingent extension of programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Automatic extension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorization of appropriations for, or duration of, an applicable program shall be automatically extended for one additional fiscal year unless Congress, in the regular session that ends prior to the beginning of the terminal fiscal year of such authorization or duration, has passed legislation that becomes law and extends or repeals the authorization or duration of such program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount authorized to be appropriated for the period of automatic extension under subsection (a) of an applicable program shall be the amount authorized to be appropriated for such program for the terminal fiscal year of the applicable program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acts and determinations necessary for program continuation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary is required, in the terminal fiscal year of an applicable program, to carry out certain acts or make certain determinations that are necessary for the continuation of such program, such acts or determinations shall be required to be carried out or made during the period of automatic extension under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to commissions, councils, and committees required by law to terminate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to the authorization of appropriations for a commission, council, or committee which is required by an applicable statute to terminate on a date certain.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 422</ref>, formerly § 414, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 506(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 563</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–374, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1496</ref>; renumbered § 422 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 233, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3915.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1226a–1.</num>
<heading> Payments; installments, advances or reimbursement, and adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments pursuant to grants or contracts under any applicable program may be made in installments, and in advance or by way of reimbursement, with necessary adjustments on account of overpayments or underpayments, as the Secretary may determine.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 423</ref>, formerly § 425, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 170</ref>; renumbered § 435, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; renumbered § 415, <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1231(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2342</ref>; renumbered § 423 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 261(a), <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3927.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 2—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Planning and Evaluation of Federal Education Activities</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1226b.</num>
<heading> Responsibility of States to furnish information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Biennial reports; contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each State educational agency shall submit to the Secretary a report on or before March 15 of every second year. Each such report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information with respect to the uses of Federal funds in such State in the two preceding fiscal years under any applicable program under the jurisdiction of the State educational agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information with respect to the uses of Federal funds in such State in the two preceding fiscal years under any Federal program administered by the State that provided grants or contracts to a local educational agency in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> list, with respect to each program for which information is provided, all grants made to and contracts entered into with local educational agencies and other public and private agencies and institutions within the State during each fiscal year concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> analyze the information included in the report by local educational agency and by program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include the total amount of funds available to the State under each such program for each fiscal year concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> be made readily available by the State to local educational agencies and institutions within the State and to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delinquent or incomplete reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary does not receive a report by the date required under subsection (a), or receives an incomplete report, the Secretary, not later than 30 days after such report is required to be submitted, shall take all reasonable measures to obtain the delinquent or incomplete information from the State educational agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the Secretary receives a report required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide such information to the National Center for Education Statistics, and shall make such information available, at a reasonable cost, to any individual who requests such information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional telecommunications network</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult with the Speaker and Minority Leader of the House of Representatives and the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate regarding the costs and feasibility of making the information described in subsection (a) available as part of a telecommunications network that is readily accessible to every member of Congress and other interested parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports by Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On or before August 15 of each year in which reports are submitted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate. Such report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of the content and data quality of such reports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a compilation of statistical data derived from such reports; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> information obtained by the Secretary with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> direct grants made to local educational agencies by the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contracts entered into between such agencies and the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 424</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 234</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1226c.</num>
<heading> Biennial evaluation report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1995-03-31">March 31, 1995</date>, and every two years after such date, the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate an evaluation report on the effectiveness of applicable programs in achieving such programs’ legislated intent and purposes during the two preceding fiscal years. Such report shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contain program profiles that include legislative citations, multiyear funding histories, and legislated purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> contain recent information on the progress being made toward the achievement of program objectives, including listings of program performance indicators, data from performance measurement based on the indicators, and information on the costs and benefits of the applicable programs being evaluated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> address significant program activities, such as initiatives for program improvement, regulations, and program monitoring and evaluation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> list the principal analyses and studies supporting the major conclusions in such report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> be prepared in concise summary form with necessary detailed data and appendixes, including available data to indicate the effectiveness of the programs and projects by the race, sex, disability and age of beneficiaries of such programs and projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> include the results of the program evaluations conducted in accordance with <ref>section 7981 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 425</ref>, formerly § 417, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 506(a)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 564</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1246(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2354</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–46, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-06">Aug. 6, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–374, title XIII, § 1305</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–511, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2406</ref>; renumbered § 425 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 235, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3916; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 7(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076(h)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(mm)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1226c–1.</num>
<heading> Availability of education reports, etc., to Congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any evaluation report or data or information collected in preparation of such report, which is paid for with appropriated funds, shall be made available, upon request, within 4 days to the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and of the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XV, § 1523</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1226d.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2238</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1227.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1228.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. H, title III, § 314(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1610</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1228a.</num>
<heading> Equity for students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to assist the Department in implementing the Department’s mission to ensure equal access to education and to promote educational excellence throughout the Nation, by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensuring equal opportunities to participate for all eligible students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries in any project or activity carried out under an applicable program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> promoting the ability of such students, teachers, and beneficiaries to meet high standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to develop steps to ensure equity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall require each applicant for assistance under an applicable program (other than an individual) to develop and describe in such applicant’s application the steps such applicant proposes to take to ensure equitable access to, and equitable participation in, the project or activity to be conducted with such assistance, by addressing the special needs of students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries in order to overcome barriers to equitable participation, including barriers based on gender, race, color, national origin, disability, and age.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may establish criteria and provide technical assistance for meeting the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter in any way the rights or responsibilities established under the laws cited in <ref>section 1221(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 427</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 236</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1228b.</num>
<heading> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Assessment Governing Board, the Advisory Council on Education Statistics, the National Education Goals Panel, and any other board established to analyze, address, or approve education content or student performance standards and assessments shall coordinate and interact with one another in order to ensure that each such entity does not duplicate activities to assist the States in reforming their educational systems.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 428</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 237</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3917</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(d) [title VII, § 703(c)]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1321–211</ref>, 1321–255; renumbered title I, <ref>Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1228c.</num>
<heading> Disclosure requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each educational organization, prior to enrolling a minor and prior to accepting funds for the cost of a minor’s participation in an educational program operated by such organization, shall disclose the following information in written form to the minor or the minor’s parent.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Method of solicitation and selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The method of solicitation and selection of participants in the educational program, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the origin of any mailing list used for such solicitation and selection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any recruitment through a local school official, teacher, or school personnel, including any compensation or other benefit offered to such official, teacher, or personnel for the recommendation of a minor for participation in the educational program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any open enrollment activity, including the method of outreach; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any cooperation with, or sponsorship by, a membership organization, including a description of the cooperation or sponsorship and the name of each such organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost and fees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Information regarding the cost of the educational program and information regarding the distribution of any enrollment fee, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the amount paid for, and the percentage of the total educational program cost of, each feature of the educational program, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> food;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> lodging;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> transportation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> program staffing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> textbooks, syllabi, or other scholastic educational program materials;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> speaker fees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<chapeau> administrative expenses, including expenses related to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the preparation of nonscholastic educational program materials;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the provision of financial assistance;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> mailing list rental or other recruitment activity; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> administrative salaries and consulting fees;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the identity of the organization or business providing each of the features described in clauses (i) through (vii) of subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the nature of any relationship of any board member, officer, or employee of the educational organization to any organization or business described in subparagraph (B), including the salary or other compensation paid by such organization or business to such board member, officer, or employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondiscriminatory enrollment and service policy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each educational organization shall include a verifiable statement in all enrollment or recruitment material that the educational organization does not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fail or refuse to hire, or discharge, any individual, or otherwise discriminate against any individual with respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exclude any student from participation in an educational program, discriminate against any student in providing the benefits associated with such program (including any scholarship or financial assistance, and use of any facility), or subject the student to discrimination under such program, on the basis of race, disability, or residence in a low-income area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to entitle a student to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> participation in an educational program or any benefit associated with such program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a waiver of any fee charged for such participation or benefit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> widely disseminate information about the requirements of this section to State and local school officials and parents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> require educational organizations to submit appropriate information or assurances regarding such organizations’ compliance with this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> take whatever other steps the Secretary determines are appropriate to enforce this section, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promulgating regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establishing a complaint process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> referring complaints to the relevant Federal, State, or local authorities for appropriate action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> alerting educational agencies, schools, and parents to the practices of educational organizations that violate the provisions of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> imposing civil fines (not to exceed $1,000 per violation) on educational organizations that knowingly violate this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “disability” has the same meaning given to such term by <ref>section 12102(2) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Educational organization</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), the term “educational organization” means any organization or entity that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provides an educational program for a fee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recruits students through means such as commercial media, direct mailings, school recruitment programs, school administrators, teachers or staff, or current or former participants in an educational program offered by such organization or entity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The definition in subparagraph (A) shall not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a local educational agency, State educational agency, a State department of education, or an elementary or secondary school (as defined by the terms “elementary school” and “secondary school” in <ref>section 7801 of this title</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an institution of higher education as defined by <ref>section 1001 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a local organization sponsored by an elementary or secondary school, a recreational organization, an entertainment organization, a local sports activity group, or a social club.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of subsection (a) only, such term does not include an organization or entity that provides an educational program if such organization or entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> recruits, for participation in such program, solely through a local school official; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not offer a local school official, teacher, or other school personnel compensation (other than compensation for actual expenses incurred in performing chaperon activities or for participating in separate, professionally-staffed teacher training and technical assistance seminars and workshops related to such program) or any other benefit for such recruitment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Educational program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “educational program” means a special honors program, seminar, citizenship experience, government study program, educational vacation, student exchange program, or other educational experience or honor—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is generally directed toward minors or secondary school students;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for which a tuition or enrollment fee is charged;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that is offered away from a student’s regular place of school attendance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> that includes not less than one supervised night away from home; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> that is intended to enhance a student’s regular course of study.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such term does not include a recreational program,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref> or a social or religious activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local school official</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “local school official” means the highest administrative official serving a school district, or such individual’s designee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “minor” means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “membership organization” includes any organization that maintains a membership list or collects dues or membership fees from its members.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recreational organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “recreational organization” includes any organization or entity that has as its primary function pleasure, amusement, or sports activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recreational program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “recreational program” includes any activity or service that is intended as an entertainment pastime.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 429</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 238</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3918</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(6)(C)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(mm)(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS AND CONDITIONS CONCERNING OPERATION AND ADMINISTRATION OF EDUCATION PROGRAMS: GENERAL AUTHORITY OF SECRETARY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1230.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 1<inline class="small-caps">—</inline></num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Authority</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1231.</num>
<heading> Joint funding of programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint projects; transfers of appropriations; contracts or grants; criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to enter into arrangements with other Federal agencies to jointly carry out projects of common interest, to transfer to such agencies funds appropriated under any applicable program, and to receive and use funds from such agencies, for projects of common interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds transferred or received pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be used only in accordance with the statutes authorizing the appropriation of such funds, and shall be made available by contract or grant only to recipients eligible to receive such funds under such statutes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Secretary enters into an agreement under this subsection for the administration of a project, the agency administering the project shall use such agency’s procedures to award contracts or grants and to administer such awards, unless the parties to the agreement specify the use of procedures of another agency that is a party to the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the Secretary has entered into an agreement authorized under this subsection and the Secretary and the heads of the other agencies participating in the agreement determine that joint funding is necessary to address a special need consistent with the purposes and authorized activities of each program that provides funding under the joint project, the Secretary and the heads of the other participating agencies may develop a single set of criteria for the jointly funded project and require each applicant for such project to submit a single application for review by the participating agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may develop the criteria for, and require the submission of, joint applications under two or more applicable programs under which funds are awarded on a competitive basis, and may jointly review and approve such applications separately from other applications under such programs, when the Secretary determines that such joint awards are necessary to address a special need consistent with the purposes and authorized activities of each such program. Any applicant for such a joint award shall meet the eligibility requirements of each such program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on joint funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may not construe the provisions of this section to take precedence over a limitation on joint funding contained in an applicable statute.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notice</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide notice to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate of each joint funding agreement made with other Federal agencies not later than 60 days after the making of such agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such notice shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the purpose and objectives of the joint funding arrangement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amounts and sources, by program, of the funds dedicated to such arrangement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the criteria developed to govern the award of contracts and grants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 430</ref>, formerly § 411, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 166</ref>; renumbered § 421 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III</ref>, §§ 301(a)(1), 302(a), <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>, 332; renumbered § 421A, <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 565</ref>; renumbered § 430 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 241, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3921.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1231a.</num>
<heading> Collection and dissemination of information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prepare and disseminate to State and local educational agencies and institutions information concerning applicable programs, and cooperate with other Federal officials who administer programs affecting education in disseminating information concerning such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inform the public regarding federally supported education programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collect data and information on applicable programs for the purpose of obtaining objective measurements of the effectiveness of such programs in achieving the intended purposes of such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 431</ref>, formerly § 412, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 166</ref>; renumbered § 422 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(2)(B), <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>, 332; <ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title IV, § 409(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2233</ref>; renumbered § 431, renumbered § 422, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 242, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3922; renumbered § 431, <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1062(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1231b, 1231b–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1231b–2.</num>
<heading> Review of applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons aggrieved; final State educational agency actions; hearing; ruling and reasons for ruling; rescission of final actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any applicable program under which financial assistance is provided to (or through) a State educational agency to be expended in accordance with a State plan approved by the Secretary, any applicant or recipient aggrieved by the final action of the State educational agency, and alleging a violation of State or Federal law, rules, regulations, or guidelines governing the applicable program, in (1) disapproving or failing to approve its application or program in whole or part, (2) failing to provide funds in amounts in accord with the requirements of laws and regulations, (3) ordering, in accordance with a final State audit resolution determination, the repayment of misspent or misapplied Federal funds, or (4) terminating further assistance for an approved program, may within thirty days request a hearing. Within thirty days after it receives such a request, the State educational agency shall hold a hearing on the record and shall review such final action. No later than ten days after the hearing, the State educational agency shall issue its written ruling, including reasons therefor. If it determines such final action was contrary to Federal or State law, or the rules, regulations, and guidelines governing such applicable program, it shall rescind such final action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeals to Secretary; persons aggrieved; notice; orders prescribing appropriate agency actions; finality of agency fact findings; interim orders pending appeal or review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any applicant or recipient aggrieved by the failure of a State educational agency to rescind its final action after a review under subsection (a) may appeal such action to the Secretary. An appeal under this subsection may be taken only if notice of such appeal is filed with the Secretary within twenty days after the applicant or recipient has been notified by the State educational agency of the results of its review under subsection (a). If, on such appeal, the Secretary determines the final action of the State educational agency was contrary to Federal law, or the rules, regulations, and guidelines governing the applicable program, he shall issue an order to the State educational agency prescribing appropriate action to be taken by such agency. On such appeal, findings of fact of the State educational agency, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be final. The Secretary may also issue such interim orders to State educational agencies as he may deem necessary and appropriate pending appeal or review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records; availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State educational agency shall make available at reasonable times and places to each applicant or recipient under a program to which this section applies all records of such agency pertaining to any review or appeal such applicant or recipient is conducting under this section, including records of other applicants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of assistance for noncompliance with provisions or orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any State educational agency fails or refuses to comply with any provision of this section, or with any order of the Secretary under subsection (b), the Secretary shall forthwith terminate all assistance to the State educational agency under the applicable program affected or issue such other orders as the Secretary may deem appropriate to achieve such compliance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 432</ref>, formerly § 425, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 566</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1247</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2354</ref>; renumbered § 432 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 243, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3922.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1231c.</num>
<heading> Advice, counsel, and technical assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State educational agencies, institutions of higher education</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out more effectively Federal education programs, the Secretary is authorized, upon request, to provide advice, counsel, and technical assistance to State educational agencies, institutions of higher education, and, with the approval of the appropriate State educational agency, elementary and secondary schools—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in determining benefits available to them under Federal law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in preparing applications for, and meeting requirements of, applicable programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in order to enhance the quality, increase the depth, or broaden the scope of activities under applicable programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in order to encourage simplification of applications, reports, evaluations, and other administrative procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost allocation, collection, etc., by local educational agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit local educational agencies to use organized and systematic approaches in determining cost allocation, collection, measurement, and reporting under any applicable program, if he determines (1) that the use of such approaches will not in any manner lessen the effectiveness and impact of such program in achieving purposes for which it is intended, (2) that the agency will use such procedures as will insure adequate evaluation of each of the programs involved, and (3) that such approaches are consistent with criteria prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States for the purposes of audit. For the purpose of this subsection a cost is allocable to a particular cost objective to the extent of relative benefits received by such objective.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In awarding contracts and grants for the development of curricula or instructional materials, the Secretary and the Director of the National Institute of Education shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> encourage applicants to assure that such curricula or instructional materials will be developed in a manner conducive to dissemination through continuing consultations with publishers, personnel of State and local educational agencies, teachers, administrators, community representatives, and other individuals experienced in such dissemination;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> permit applicants to include provision for reasonable consultation fees or planning costs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> insure that grants to public agencies and nonprofit private organizations and contracts with public agencies and private organizations for publication and dissemination of curricula or instructional materials, or both, are awarded competitively to such agencies and organizations which provide assurances that the curricula and instructional materials will reach the target populations for which they were developed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary’s annual report shall contain a statement of the Secretary’s activities under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 433</ref>, formerly § 414, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 167</ref>; renumbered § 424, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; renumbered § 426, <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 565</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1248</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2354</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692; renumbered § 433, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1231c–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1231d.</num>
<heading> Parental involvement and dissemination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any applicable program in which the Secretary determines that parental participation at the State or local level would increase the effectiveness of the program in achieving its purposes, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations with respect to such program setting forth criteria designed to encourage such participation. If the program for which such determination is made provides for payments to local educational agencies, applications for such payments shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> set forth such policies and procedures as will ensure that programs and projects assisted under the application have been planned and developed, and will be operated, in consultation with, and with the involvement of, parents of the children to be served by such programs and projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be submitted with assurance that such parents have had an opportunity to present their views with respect to the application; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> set forth policies and procedures for adequate dissemination of program plans and evaluations to such parents and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 434</ref>, formerly § 415, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 168</ref>; renumbered § 425, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; renumbered § 427, <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 565</ref>; renumbered § 434 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 244, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3922.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1231e.</num>
<heading> Use of funds withheld</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> At any time that the Secretary makes an allotment or reallotment to any State under any applicable program, the Secretary shall reduce such allotment or reallotment by such amount as the Secretary determines such allotment or reallotment would have been reduced, had the data on which such allotment or reallotment is based excluded all data relating to local educational agencies of the State that, on the date of the Secretary’s action, are ineligible to receive the Federal financial assistance involved because of failure to comply with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq.], title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.], <ref>section 794 of title 29</ref>, or the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 6101</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may use any funds withheld under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase the allotments or reallotments of local educational agencies within the State that are not described in subsection (a), or the allotments or reallotment of all States, in accordance with the Federal law governing the program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for grants to local educational agencies of that State in accordance with section 405 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000c–4</ref>], or for any other program administered by the Department that is designed to enhance equity in education or redress discrimination on the basis of race, color, national origin, sex, age, or disability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 435</ref>, formerly § 416, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 168</ref>; renumbered § 426, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; renumbered § 428, <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 565</ref>; renumbered § 435 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 245, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3922.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1231f.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 2—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administration: Requirements and Limitations</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1231g.</num>
<heading> Applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission and amendments of applications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, unless expressly in limitation of the provisions of this section, the Secretary is authorized to provide for the submission of applications for assistance effective for more than one fiscal year under any applicable program with whatever amendments to such applications being required as the Secretary determines essential.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uniform dates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, insofar as is practicable, establish uniform dates during the year for the submission of applications under all applicable programs and for the approval of such applications.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of common applications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, insofar as is practicable, develop and require the use of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a common application for grants to local educational agencies in applicable programs administered by State educational agencies in which the funds are distributed to such local agencies pursuant to some objective formula, and such application shall be used as the single application for as many of these programs as is practicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a common application for grants to local educational agencies in applicable programs administered by State educational agencies in which the funds are distributed to such local agencies on a competitive or discretionary basis, and such application shall be used as the single application for as many of such programs as is practicable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a common application for grants to local educational agencies in applicable programs which are directly administered by the Secretary, and such application shall be used as the single application for as many of these programs as is practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 436</ref>, formerly § 430, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1213</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2342</ref>; renumbered § 436 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 246, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3923.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Regulation” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this section, the term “regulation” means any generally applicable rule, regulation, guideline, interpretation, or other requirement that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is prescribed by the Secretary or the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has legally binding effect in connection with, or affecting, the provision of financial assistance under any applicable program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Citation of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations shall contain, immediately following each substantive provision of such regulations, citations to the particular section or sections of statutory law or other legal authority on which such provision is based.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uniform application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All regulations shall be uniformly applied and enforced throughout the 50 States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of exemption</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The exemption for public property, loans, grants and benefits in <ref>section 553(a)(2) of title 5</ref> shall apply only to regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that govern the first grant competition under a new or substantially revised program authority as determined by the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> where the Secretary determines that the requirements of this subsection will cause extreme hardship to the intended beneficiaries of the program affected by such regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule for promulgation of final regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of any Act, or any portion of any Act, affecting the administration of any applicable program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate a schedule in accordance with which the Secretary plans to promulgate final regulations that the Secretary determines are necessary to implement such Act or portion of such Act. Such schedule shall provide that all such final regulations shall be promulgated within 360 days after the date of enactment of such Act or portion of such Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmittal of final regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Concurrently with the publication of any final regulations, the Secretary shall transmit a copy of such final regulations to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 437</ref>, formerly § 421, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 169</ref>; renumbered § 431, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 509(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–142, § 7</ref>, <date date="1975-11-29">Nov. 29, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 796</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2231</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–374, title XIII, § 1302</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title V, § 533(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 453</ref>; renumbered § 437 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 247, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3923; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–511, title I, § 109(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2369</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232a.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against Federal control of education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of any applicable program shall be construed to authorize any department, agency, officer, or employee of the United States to exercise any direction, supervision, or control over the curriculum, program of instruction, administration, or personnel of any educational institution, school, or school system, or over the selection of library resources, textbooks, or other printed or published instructional materials by any educational institution or school system, or to require the assignment or transportation of students or teachers in order to overcome racial imbalance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 438</ref>, formerly § 422, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 169</ref>; renumbered § 432 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title VII, § 717(b), <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>, 369; <ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title IV, § 404(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2230</ref>; renumbered § 438, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232b.</num>
<heading> Labor standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors on all construction and minor remodeling projects assisted under any applicable program shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction and minor remodeling in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40. The Secretary of Labor shall have, with respect to the labor standards specified in this section, the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 and <ref>section 3145 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 439</ref>, formerly § 423, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–230, title IV, § 401(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 169</ref>; renumbered § 433, <ref>Pub. L. 92–318, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 326</ref>; renumbered § 439 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 261(d), <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3927.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 3—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administration of Education Programs and Projects by States and Local Educational Agencies</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1232c.</num>
<heading> State agency monitoring and enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any applicable program in which Federal funds are made available to local agencies in a State through or under the supervision of a State board or agency, the Secretary may require the State to submit a plan for monitoring compliance by local agencies with Federal requirements under such program and for enforcement by the State of such requirements. The Secretary may require such plan to provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for periodic visits by State personnel of programs administered by local agencies to determine whether such programs are being conducted in accordance with such requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for periodic audits of expenditures under such programs by auditors of the State or other auditors not under the control, direction, or supervision of the local educational agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the State investigate and resolve all complaints received by the State, or referred to the State by the Secretary, relating to the administration of such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State enforcement of Federal requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to enforce the Federal requirements under any applicable program the State may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> withhold approval, in whole or in part, of the application of a local agency for funds under the program until the State is satisfied that such requirements will be met; except that the State shall not finally disapprove such an application unless the State provides the local agency an opportunity for a hearing before an impartial hearing officer and such officer determines that there has been a substantial failure by the local agency to comply with any of such requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> suspend payments to any local agency, in whole or in part, under the program if the State has reason to believe that the local agency has failed substantially to comply with any of such requirements, except that (A) the State shall not suspend such payments until fifteen days after the State provides the local agency an opportunity to show cause why such action should not be taken and (B) no such suspension shall continue in effect longer than sixty days unless the State within such period provides the notice for a hearing required under paragraph (3) of this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> withhold payments, in whole or in part, under any such program if the State finds, after reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing before an impartial hearing officer, that the local agency has failed substantially to comply with any of such requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any withholding of payments under subsection (b)(3) of this subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002120">1</ref> shall continue until the State is satisfied that there is no longer a failure to comply substantially with any of such requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 440</ref>, formerly § 434, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1231(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2342</ref>; renumbered § 440 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 261(e), <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3927.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232d.</num>
<heading> Single State application</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of general application; approval by State supervisory authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any State which applies, contracts, or submits a plan for participation in any applicable program in which Federal funds are made available for assistance to local educational agencies through, or under the supervision of, the State educational agency of that State, such State shall submit (subject to the provisions of part D of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 7231</ref> et seq.]) to the Secretary a general application containing the assurances set forth in subsection (b). Such application may be submitted jointly for all programs covered by the application, or it may be submitted separately for each such program or for groups of programs. Each application submitted under this section must be approved by each official, agency, board, or other entity within the State which, under State law, is primarily responsible for supervision of the activities conducted under each program covered by the application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assurances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An application submitted under subsection (a) shall set forth assurances, satisfactory to the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that each program will be administered in accordance with all applicable statutes, regulations, program plans, and applications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the control of funds provided under each program and title to property acquired with program funds will be in a public agency, or in a nonprofit private agency, institution, or organization if the statute authorizing the program provides for grants to such entities, and that the public agency or nonprofit private agency, institution, or organization will administer such funds and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> that the State will adopt and use proper methods of administering each applicable program, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> monitoring of agencies, institutions, and organizations responsible for carrying out each program, and the enforcement of any obligations imposed on those agencies, institutions, and organizations under law,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing technical assistance, where necessary, to such agencies, institutions, and organizations,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> encouraging the adoption of promising or innovative educational techniques by such agencies, institutions, and organizations,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the dissemination throughout the State of information on program requirements and successful practices, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the correction of deficiencies in program operations that are identified through monitoring or evaluation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that the State will evaluate the effectiveness of covered programs in meeting their statutory objectives, at such intervals (not less often than once every three years) and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation, and that the State will cooperate in carrying out any evaluation of each program conducted by or for the Secretary or other Federal official;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that the State will use fiscal control and fund accounting procedures that will ensure proper disbursement of, and accounting for, Federal funds paid to the State under each program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> that the State will make reports to the Secretary (including reports on the results of evaluations required under paragraph (4)) as may reasonably be necessary to enable the Secretary to perform his duties under each program, and that the State will maintain such records, in accordance with the requirements of <ref>section 1232f of this title</ref>, and afford access to the records as the Secretary may find necessary to carry out his duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> that the State will provide reasonable opportunities for the participation by local agencies, representatives of the class of individuals affected by each program and other interested institutions, organizations, and individuals in the planning for and operation of each program, including the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State will consult with relevant advisory committees, local agencies, interest groups, and experienced professionals in the development of program plans required by statute;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the State will publish each proposed plan, in a manner that will ensure circulation throughout the State, at least sixty days prior to the date on which the plan is submitted to the Secretary or on which the plan becomes effective, whichever occurs earlier, with an opportunity for public comments on such plan to be accepted for at least thirty days;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the State will hold public hearings on the proposed plans if required by the Secretary by regulation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the State will provide an opportunity for interested agencies, organizations, and individuals to suggest improvements in the administration of the program and to allege that there has been a failure by any entity to comply with applicable statutes and regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> that none of the funds expended under any applicable program will be used to acquire equipment (including computer software) in any instance in which such acquisition results in a direct financial benefit to any organization representing the interests of the purchasing entity or its employees or any affiliate of such an organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective term of general application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each general application submitted under this section shall remain in effect for the duration of any program it covers. The Secretary shall not require the resubmission or amendment of that application unless required by changes in Federal or State law or by other significant changes in the circumstances affecting an assurance in that application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 441</ref>, formerly § 435, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1231(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2343</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–511, title VII, § 706(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 357</ref>; renumbered § 441 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), (3)(A), 261(f), <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3928; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1062(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(mm)(4)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232e.</num>
<heading> Single local educational agency application</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General application to State agency or board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each local educational agency which participates in an applicable program under which Federal funds are made available to such agency through a State agency or board shall submit to such agency or board a general application containing the assurances set forth in subsection (b). That application shall cover the participation by that local educational agency in all such programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assurances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The general application submitted by a local educational agency under subsection (a) shall set forth assurances—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the local educational agency will administer each program covered by the application in accordance with all applicable statutes, regulations, program plans, and applications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the control of funds provided to the local educational agency under each program, and title to property acquired with those funds, will be in a public agency and that a public agency will administer those funds and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the local educational agency will use fiscal control and fund accounting procedures that will ensure proper disbursement of, and accounting for, Federal funds paid to that agency under each program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that the local educational agency will make reports to the State agency or board and to the Secretary as may reasonably be necessary to enable the State agency or board and the Secretary to perform their duties and that the local educational agency will maintain such records, including the records required under <ref>section 1232f of this title</ref>, and provide access to those records, as the State agency or board or the Secretary deem necessary to perform their duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that the local educational agency will provide reasonable opportunities for the participation by teachers, parents, and other interested agencies, organizations, and individuals in the planning for and operation of each program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> that any application, evaluation, periodic program plan or report relating to each program will be made readily available to parents and other members of the general public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> that in the case of any project involving construction—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the project is not inconsistent with overall State plans for the construction of school facilities, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in developing plans for construction, due consideration will be given to excellence of architecture and design and to compliance with standards prescribed by the Secretary under <ref>section 794 of title 29</ref> in order to ensure that facilities constructed with the use of Federal funds are accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> that the local educational agency has adopted effective procedures for acquiring and disseminating to teachers and administrators participating in each program significant information from educational research, demonstrations, and similar projects, and for adopting, where appropriate, promising educational practices developed through such projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> that none of the funds expended under any applicable program will be used to acquire equipment (including computer software) in any instance in which such acquisition results in a direct financial benefit to any organization representing the interests of the purchasing entity or its employees or any affiliate of such an organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective term of general application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A general application submitted under this section shall remain in effect for the duration of the programs it covers. The State agencies or boards administering the programs covered by the application shall not require the submission or amendment of such application unless required by changes in Federal or State law or by other significant change in the circumstances affecting an assurance in such application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 442</ref>, formerly § 436, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1231(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2345</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–511, title VII, § 706(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2407</ref>; renumbered § 442 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), (3)(B), 261(g), <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3928.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 4—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Records; Privacy; Limitation on Withholding Federal Funds</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1232f.</num>
<heading> Records</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Records kept by recipient; full disclosure; maintenance period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each recipient of Federal funds under any applicable program through any grant, subgrant, cooperative agreement, loan, or other arrangement shall keep records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by the recipient of those funds, the total cost of the activity for which the funds are used, the share of that cost provided from other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective financial or programmatic audit. The recipient shall maintain such rec­ords for three years after the completion of the activity for which the funds are used.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit examination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access, for the purpose of audit examination, to any rec­ords maintained by a recipient that may be related, or pertinent to, grants, subgrants, cooperative agreements, loans, or other arrangements to which reference is made in subsection (a), or which may relate to the compliance of the recipient with any requirement of an applicable program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 443</ref>, formerly § 437, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1231(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2346</ref>; renumbered § 443 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 248, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3924.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232g.</num>
<heading> Family educational and privacy rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions for availability of funds to educational agencies or institutions; inspection and review of education records; specific information to be made available; procedure for access to education records; reasonableness of time for such access; hearings; written explanations by parents; definitions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution which has a policy of denying, or which effectively prevents, the parents of students who are or have been in attendance at a school of such agency or at such institution, as the case may be, the right to inspect and review the education records of their children. If any material or document in the education record of a student includes information on more than one student, the parents of one of such students shall have the right to inspect and review only such part of such material or document as relates to such student or to be informed of the specific information contained in such part of such material. Each educational agency or institution shall establish appropriate procedures for the granting of a request by parents for access to the education records of their children within a reasonable period of time, but in no case more than forty-five days after the request has been made.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> No funds under any applicable program shall be made available to any State educational agency (whether or not that agency is an educational agency or institution under this section) that has a policy of denying, or effectively prevents, the parents of students the right to inspect and review the education records maintained by the State educational agency on their children who are or have been in attendance at any school of an educational agency or institution that is subject to the provisions of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The first sentence of subparagraph (A) shall not operate to make available to students in institutions of postsecondary education the following materials:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> financial records of the parents of the student or any information contained therein;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> confidential letters and statements of recommendation, which were placed in the education records prior to <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, if such letters or statements are not used for purposes other than those for which they were specifically intended;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> if the student has signed a waiver of the student’s right of access under this subsection in accordance with subparagraph (D), confidential recommendations—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> respecting admission to any educational agency or institution,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> respecting an application for employment, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> respecting the receipt of an honor or honorary recognition.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A student or a person applying for admission may waive his right of access to confidential statements described in clause (iii) of subparagraph (C), except that such waiver shall apply to recommendations only if (i) the student is, upon request, notified of the names of all persons making confidential recommendations and (ii) such recommendations are used solely for the purpose for which they were specifically intended. Such waivers may not be required as a condition for admission to, receipt of financial aid from, or receipt of any other services or benefits from such agency or institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution unless the parents of students who are or have been in attendance at a school of such agency or at such institution are provided an opportunity for a hearing by such agency or institution, in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, to challenge the content of such student’s education records, in order to insure that the records are not inaccurate, misleading, or otherwise in violation of the privacy rights of students, and to provide an opportunity for the correction or deletion of any such inaccurate, misleading or otherwise inappropriate data contained therein and to insert into such records a written explanation of the parents respecting the content of such records.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section the term “educational agency or institution” means any public or private agency or institution which is the recipient of funds under any applicable program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section, the term “education records” means, except as may be provided otherwise in subparagraph (B), those records, files, documents, and other materials which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contain information directly related to a student; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are maintained by an educational agency or institution or by a person acting for such agency or institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “education records” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> records of instructional, supervisory, and administrative personnel and educational personnel ancillary thereto which are in the sole possession of the maker thereof and which are not accessible or revealed to any other person except a substitute;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> records maintained by a law enforcement unit of the educational agency or institution that were created by that law enforcement unit for the purpose of law enforcement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of persons who are employed by an educational agency or institution but who are not in attendance at such agency or institution, records made and maintained in the normal course of business which relate exclusively to such person in that person’s capacity as an employee and are not available for use for any other purpose; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> records on a student who is eighteen years of age or older, or is attending an institution of postsecondary education, which are made or maintained by a physician, psychiatrist, psychologist, or other recognized professional or paraprofessional acting in his professional or paraprofessional capacity, or assisting in that capacity, and which are made, maintained, or used only in connection with the provision of treatment to the student, and are not available to anyone other than persons providing such treatment, except that such records can be personally reviewed by a physician or other appropriate professional of the student’s choice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section the term “directory information” relating to a student includes the following: the student’s name, address, telephone listing, date and place of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, and the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any educational agency or institution making public directory information shall give public notice of the categories of information which it has designated as such information with respect to each student attending the institution or agency and shall allow a reasonable period of time after such notice has been given for a parent to inform the institution or agency that any or all of the information designated should not be released without the parent’s prior consent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, the term “student” includes any person with respect to whom an educational agency or institution maintains education records or personally identifiable information, but does not include a person who has not been in attendance at such agency or institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of education records; parental consent requirement; exceptions; compliance with judicial orders and subpoenas; audit and evaluation of federally-supported education programs; recordkeeping</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution which has a policy or practice of permitting the release of education records (or personally identifiable information contained therein other than directory information, as defined in paragraph (5) of subsection (a)) of students without the written consent of their parents to any individual, agency, or organization, other than to the following—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> other school officials, including teachers within the educational institution or local educational agency, who have been determined by such agency or institution to have legitimate educational interests, including the educational interests of the child for whom consent would otherwise be required;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> officials of other schools or school systems in which the student seeks or intends to enroll, upon condition that the student’s parents be notified of the transfer, receive a copy of the record if desired, and have an opportunity for a hearing to challenge the content of the record;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> authorized representatives of (I) the Comptroller General of the United States, (II) the Secretary, or (III) State educational authorities, under the conditions set forth in paragraph (3), or (ii) authorized representatives of the Attorney General for law enforcement purposes under the same conditions as apply to the Secretary under paragraph (3);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in connection with a student’s application for, or receipt of, financial aid;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> State and local officials or authorities to whom such information is specifically allowed to be reported or disclosed pursuant to State statute adopted—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> before <date date="1974-11-19">November 19, 1974</date>, if the allowed reporting or disclosure concerns the juvenile justice system and such system’s ability to effectively serve the student whose records are released, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> after <date date="1974-11-19">November 19, 1974</date>, if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the allowed reporting or disclosure concerns the juvenile justice system and such system’s ability to effectively serve, prior to adjudication, the student whose records are released; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the officials and authorities to whom such information is disclosed certify in writing to the educational agency or institution that the information will not be disclosed to any other party except as provided under State law without the prior written consent of the parent of the student.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002121">1</ref></content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> organizations conducting studies for, or on behalf of, educational agencies or institutions for the purpose of developing, validating, or administering predictive tests, administering student aid programs, and improving instruction, if such studies are conducted in such a manner as will not permit the personal identification of students and their parents by persons other than representatives of such organizations and such information will be destroyed when no longer needed for the purpose for which it is conducted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> accrediting organizations in order to carry out their accrediting functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> parents of a dependent student of such parents, as defined in <ref>section 152 of title 26</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> subject to regulations of the Secretary, in connection with an emergency, appropriate persons if the knowledge of such information is necessary to protect the health or safety of the student or other persons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the entity or persons designated in a Federal grand jury subpoena, in which case the court shall order, for good cause shown, the educational agency or institution (and any officer, director, employee, agent, or attorney for such agency or institution) on which the subpoena is served, to not disclose to any person the existence or contents of the subpoena or any information furnished to the grand jury in response to the subpoena; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the entity or persons designated in any other subpoena issued for a law enforcement purpose, in which case the court or other issuing agency may order, for good cause shown, the educational agency or institution (and any officer, director, employee, agent, or attorney for such agency or institution) on which the subpoena is served, to not disclose to any person the existence or contents of the subpoena or any information furnished in response to the subpoena;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Agriculture, or authorized representative from the Food and Nutrition Service or contractors acting on behalf of the Food and Nutrition Service, for the purposes of conducting program monitoring, evaluations, and performance measurements of State and local educational and other agencies and institutions receiving funding or providing benefits of 1 or more programs authorized under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.) or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1771</ref> et seq.) for which the results will be reported in an aggregate form that does not identify any individual, on the conditions that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any data collected under this subparagraph shall be protected in a manner that will not permit the personal identification of students and their parents by other than the authorized representatives of the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any personally identifiable data shall be destroyed when the data are no longer needed for program monitoring, evaluations, and performance measurements; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> an agency caseworker or other representative of a State or local child welfare agency, or tribal organization (as defined in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>), who has the right to access a student’s case plan, as defined and determined by the State or tribal organization, when such agency or organization is legally responsible, in accordance with State or tribal law, for the care and protection of the student, provided that the education records, or the personally identifiable information contained in such records, of the student will not be disclosed by such agency or organization, except to an individual or entity engaged in addressing the student’s education needs and authorized by such agency or organization to receive such disclosure and such disclosure is consistent with the State or tribal laws applicable to protecting the confidentiality of a student’s education records.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in subparagraph (E) of this paragraph shall prevent a State from further limiting the number or type of State or local officials who will continue to have access thereunder.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution which has a policy or practice of releasing, or providing access to, any personally identifiable information in education records other than directory information, or as is permitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection, unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is written consent from the student’s parents specifying records to be released, the reasons for such release, and to whom, and with a copy of the records to be released to the student’s parents and the student if desired by the parents, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except as provided in paragraph (1)(J), such information is furnished in compliance with judicial order, or pursuant to any lawfully issued subpoena, upon condition that parents and the students are notified of all such orders or subpoenas in advance of the compliance therewith by the educational institution or agency, except when a parent is a party to a court proceeding involving child abuse and neglect (as defined in section 3 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5101</ref> note)) or dependency matters, and the order is issued in the context of that proceeding, additional notice to the parent by the educational agency or institution is not required.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing contained in this section shall preclude authorized representatives of (A) the Comptroller General of the United States, (B) the Secretary, or (C) State educational authorities from having access to student or other records which may be necessary in connection with the audit and evaluation of Federally-supported education programs, or in connection with the enforcement of the Federal legal requirements which relate to such programs: <i>Provided</i>, That except when collection of personally identifiable information is specifically authorized by Federal law, any data collected by such officials shall be protected in a manner which will not permit the personal identification of students and their parents by other than those officials, and such personally identifiable data shall be destroyed when no longer needed for such audit, evaluation, and enforcement of Federal legal requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each educational agency or institution shall maintain a record, kept with the education records of each student, which will indicate all individuals (other than those specified in paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection), agencies, or organizations which have requested or obtained access to a student’s education records maintained by such educational agency or institution, and which will indicate specifically the legitimate interest that each such person, agency, or organization has in obtaining this information. Such record of access shall be available only to parents, to the school official and his assistants who are responsible for the custody of such records, and to persons or organizations authorized in, and under the conditions of, clauses (A) and (C) of paragraph (1) as a means of auditing the operation of the system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> With respect to this subsection, personal information shall only be transferred to a third party on the condition that such party will not permit any other party to have access to such information without the written consent of the parents of the student. If a third party outside the educational agency or institution permits access to information in violation of paragraph (2)(A), or fails to destroy information in violation of paragraph (1)(F), the educational agency or institution shall be prohibited from permitting access to information from education records to that third party for a period of not less than five years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit State and local educational officials from having access to student or other records which may be necessary in connection with the audit and evaluation of any federally or State supported education program or in connection with the enforcement of the Federal legal requirements which relate to any such program, subject to the conditions specified in the proviso in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit an institution of postsecondary education from disclosing, to an alleged victim of any crime of violence (as that term is defined in <ref>section 16 of title 18</ref>), or a nonforcible sex offense, the final results of any disciplinary proceeding conducted by such institution against the alleged perpetrator of such crime or offense with respect to such crime or offense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit an institution of postsecondary education from disclosing the final results of any disciplinary proceeding conducted by such institution against a student who is an alleged perpetrator of any crime of violence (as that term is defined in <ref>section 16 of title 18</ref>), or a nonforcible sex offense, if the institution determines as a result of that disciplinary proceeding that the student committed a violation of the institution’s rules or policies with respect to such crime or offense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this paragraph, the final results of any disciplinary proceeding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall include only the name of the student, the violation committed, and any sanction imposed by the institution on that student; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may include the name of any other student, such as a victim or witness, only with the written consent of that other student.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit an educational institution from disclosing information provided to the institution under section 14071 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002122">2</ref> of title 42 concerning registered sex offenders who are required to register under such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall take appropriate steps to notify educational institutions that disclosure of information described in subparagraph (A) is permitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surveys or data-gathering activities; regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 240 days after <date date="1994-10-20">October 20, 1994</date>, the Secretary shall adopt appropriate regulations or procedures, or identify existing regulations or procedures, which protect the rights of privacy of students and their families in connection with any surveys or data-gathering activities conducted, assisted, or authorized by the Secretary or an administrative head of an education agency. Regulations established under this subsection shall include provisions controlling the use, dissemination, and protection of such data. No survey or data-gathering activities shall be conducted by the Secretary, or an administrative head of an education agency under an applicable program, unless such activities are authorized by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Students’ rather than parents’ permission or consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, whenever a student has attained eighteen years of age, or is attending an institution of postsecondary education, the permission or consent required of and the rights accorded to the parents of the student shall thereafter only be required of and accorded to the student.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Informing parents or students of rights under this section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution unless such agency or institution effectively informs the parents of students, or the students, if they are eighteen years of age or older, or are attending an institution of postsecondary education, of the rights accorded them by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement; termination of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall take appropriate actions to enforce this section and to deal with violations of this section, in accordance with this chapter, except that action to terminate assistance may be taken only if the Secretary finds there has been a failure to comply with this section, and he has determined that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office and review board; creation; functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish or designate an office and review board within the Department for the purpose of investigating, processing, reviewing, and adjudicating violations of this section and complaints which may be filed concerning alleged violations of this section. Except for the conduct of hearings, none of the functions of the Secretary under this section shall be carried out in any of the regional offices of such Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disciplinary records; disclosure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall prohibit an educational agency or institution from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> including appropriate information in the education record of any student concerning disciplinary action taken against such student for conduct that posed a significant risk to the safety or well-being of that student, other students, or other members of the school community; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disclosing such information to teachers and school officials, including teachers and school officials in other schools, who have legitimate educational interests in the behavior of the student.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Drug and alcohol violation disclosures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this Act or the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.] shall be construed to prohibit an institution of higher education from disclosing, to a parent or legal guardian of a student, information regarding any violation of any Federal, State, or local law, or of any rule or policy of the institution, governing the use or possession of alcohol or a controlled substance, regardless of whether that information is contained in the student’s education records, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the student is under the age of 21; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the institution determines that the student has committed a disciplinary violation with respect to such use or possession.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State law regarding disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to supersede any provision of State law that prohibits an institution of higher education from making the disclosure described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation and prosecution of terrorism</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsections (a) through (i) or any provision of State law, the Attorney General (or any Federal officer or employee, in a position not lower than an Assistant Attorney General, designated by the Attorney General) may submit a written application to a court of competent jurisdiction for an ex parte order requiring an educational agency or institution to permit the Attorney General (or his designee) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collect education records in the possession of the educational agency or institution that are relevant to an authorized investigation or prosecution of an offense listed in <ref>section 2332b(g)(5)(B) of title 18</ref>, or an act of domestic or international terrorism as defined in section 2331 of that title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for official purposes related to the investigation or prosecution of an offense described in paragraph (1)(A), retain, disseminate, and use (including as evidence at trial or in other administrative or judicial proceedings) such records, consistent with such guidelines as the Attorney General, after consultation with the Secretary, shall issue to protect confidentiality.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application and approval</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An application under paragraph (1) shall certify that there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the education records are likely to contain information described in paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The court shall issue an order described in paragraph (1) if the court finds that the application for the order includes the certification described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection of educational agency or institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An educational agency or institution that, in good faith, produces education records in accordance with an order issued under this subsection shall not be liable to any person for that production.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record-keeping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsection (b)(4) does not apply to education records subject to a court order under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 444</ref>, formerly § 438, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 513(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 571</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–568, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1858</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–46, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-06">Aug. 6, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–542, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1990-11-08">Nov. 8, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2385</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–325, title XV, § 1555(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 840</ref>; renumbered § 444 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II</ref>, §§ 212(b)(1), 249, 261(h), <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>, 3924, 3928; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title IX</ref>, §§ 951, 952, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1835</ref>, 1836; <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title VI, § 1601(d)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1062(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2088</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–296, title I, § 103(d)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-13">Dec. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3192</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–278, § 2</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232h.</num>
<heading> Protection of pupil rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspection of instructional materials by parents or guardians</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All instructional materials, including teacher’s manuals, films, tapes, or other supplementary material which will be used in connection with any survey, analysis, or evaluation as part of any applicable program shall be available for inspection by the parents or guardians of the children.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limits on survey, analysis, or evaluations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No student shall be required, as part of any applicable program, to submit to a survey, analysis, or evaluation that reveals information concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> political affiliations or beliefs of the student or the student’s parent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> mental or psychological problems of the student or the student’s family;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sex behavior or attitudes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> illegal, anti-social, self-incriminating, or demeaning behavior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> critical appraisals of other individuals with whom respondents have close family relationships;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> legally recognized privileged or analogous relationships, such as those of lawyers, physicians, and ministers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> religious practices, affiliations, or beliefs of the student or student’s parent; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> income (other than that required by law to determine eligibility for participation in a program or for receiving financial assistance under such program),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">without the prior consent of the student (if the student is an adult or emancipated minor), or in the case of an unemancipated minor, without the prior written consent of the parent.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of local policies concerning student privacy, parental access to information, and administration of certain physical examinations to minors</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development and adoption of local policies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in subsections (a) and (b), a local educational agency that receives funds under any applicable program shall develop and adopt policies, in consultation with parents, regarding the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The right of a parent of a student to inspect, upon the request of the parent, a survey created by a third party before the survey is administered or distributed by a school to a student; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any applicable procedures for granting a request by a parent for reasonable access to such survey within a reasonable period of time after the request is received.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Arrangements to protect student privacy that are provided by the agency in the event of the administration or distribution of a survey to a student containing one or more of the following items (including the right of a parent of a student to inspect, upon the request of the parent, any survey containing one or more of such items):</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Political affiliations or beliefs of the student or the student’s parent.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Mental or psychological problems of the student or the student’s family.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Sex behavior or attitudes.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Illegal, anti-social, self-incriminating, or demeaning behavior.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Critical appraisals of other individuals with whom respondents have close family relationships.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Legally recognized privileged or analogous relationships, such as those of lawyers, physicians, and ministers.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Religious practices, affiliations, or beliefs of the student or the student’s parent.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> Income (other than that required by law to determine eligibility for participation in a program or for receiving financial assistance under such program).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The right of a parent of a student to inspect, upon the request of the parent, any instructional material used as part of the educational curriculum for the student; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any applicable procedures for granting a request by a parent for reasonable access to instructional material within a reasonable period of time after the request is received.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The administration of physical examinations or screenings that the school or agency may administer to a student.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The collection, disclosure, or use of personal information collected from students for the purpose of marketing or for selling that information (or otherwise providing that information to others for that purpose), including arrangements to protect student privacy that are provided by the agency in the event of such collection, disclosure, or use.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The right of a parent of a student to inspect, upon the request of the parent, any instrument used in the collection of personal information under subparagraph (E) before the instrument is administered or distributed to a student; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any applicable procedures for granting a request by a parent for reasonable access to such instrument within a reasonable period of time after the request is received.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parental notification</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of policies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The policies developed by a local educational agency under paragraph (1) shall provide for reasonable notice of the adoption or continued use of such policies directly to the parents of students enrolled in schools served by that agency. At a minimum, the agency shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide such notice at least annually, at the beginning of the school year, and within a reasonable period of time after any substantive change in such policies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> offer an opportunity for the parent (and for purposes of an activity described in subparagraph (C)(i), in the case of a student of an appropriate age, the student) to opt the student out of participation in an activity described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of specific events</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The local educational agency shall directly notify the parent of a student, at least annually at the beginning of the school year, of the specific or approximate dates during the school year when activities described in subparagraph (C) are scheduled, or expected to be scheduled.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities requiring notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The following activities require notification under this paragraph:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Activities involving the collection, disclosure, or use of personal information collected from students for the purpose of marketing or for selling that information (or otherwise providing that information to others for that purpose).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The administration of any survey containing one or more items described in clauses (i) through (viii) of paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> Any nonemergency, invasive physical examination or screening that is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> required as a condition of attendance;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> administered by the school and scheduled by the school in advance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> not necessary to protect the immediate health and safety of the student, or of other students.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing policies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A local educational agency need not develop and adopt new policies if the State educational agency or local educational agency has in place, on <date date="2002-01-08">January 8, 2002</date>, policies covering the requirements of paragraph (1). The agency shall provide reasonable notice of such existing policies to parents and guardians of students, in accordance with paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Educational products or services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Paragraph (1)(E) does not apply to the collection, disclosure, or use of personal information collected from students for the exclusive purpose of developing, evaluating, or providing educational products or services for, or to, students or educational institutions, such as the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> College or other postsecondary education recruitment, or military recruitment.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Book clubs, magazines, and programs providing access to low-cost literary products.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Curriculum and instructional materials used by elementary schools and secondary schools.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Tests and assessments used by elementary schools and secondary schools to provide cognitive, evaluative, diagnostic, clinical, aptitude, or achievement information about students (or to generate other statistically useful data for the purpose of securing such tests and assessments) and the subsequent analysis and public release of the aggregate data from such tests and assessments.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The sale by students of products or services to raise funds for school-related or education-related activities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Student recognition programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State law exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The provisions of this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not be construed to preempt applicable provisions of State law that require parental notification; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> do not apply to any physical examination or screening that is permitted or required by an applicable State law, including physical examinations or screenings that are permitted without parental notification.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General provisions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of construction</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> This section does not supersede <ref>section 1232g of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1)(D) does not apply to a survey administered to a student in accordance with the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1400</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Student rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The rights provided to parents under this section transfer to the student when the student turns 18 years old, or is an emancipated minor (under an applicable State law) at any age.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall annually inform each State educational agency and each local educational agency of the educational agency’s obligations under this section and <ref>section 1232g of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A State educational agency or local educational agency may use funds provided under part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.] to enhance parental involvement in areas affecting the in-school privacy of students.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As used in this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Instructional material</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “instructional material” means instructional content that is provided to a student, regardless of its format, including printed or representational materials, audio-visual materials, and materials in electronic or digital formats (such as materials accessible through the Internet). The term does not include academic tests or academic assessments.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Invasive physical examination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “invasive physical examination” means any medical examination that involves the exposure of private body parts, or any act during such examination that includes incision, insertion, or injection into the body, but does not include a hearing, vision, or scoliosis screening.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local educational agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “local educational agency” means an elementary school, secondary school, school district, or local board of education that is the recipient of funds under an applicable program, but does not include a postsecondary institution.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “parent” includes a legal guardian or other person standing in loco parentis (such as a grandparent or stepparent with whom the child lives, or a person who is legally responsible for the welfare of the child).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “personal information” means individually identifiable information including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a student or parent’s first and last name;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a home or other physical address (including street name and the name of the city or town);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a telephone number; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a Social Security identification number.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Student</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “student” means any elementary school or secondary school student.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “survey” includes an evaluation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Educational agencies and institutions shall give parents and students effective notice of their rights under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall take such action as the Secretary determines appropriate to enforce this section, except that action to terminate assistance provided under an applicable program shall be taken only if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there has been a failure to comply with such section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compliance with such section cannot be secured by voluntary means.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office and review board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish or designate an office and review board within the Department of Education to investigate, process, review, and adjudicate violations of the rights established under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 445</ref>, formerly § 439, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 574</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1250</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–227, title X, § 1017</ref>, <date date="1994-03-31">Mar. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 268</ref>; renumbered § 445, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1061</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2083</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(mm)(5)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232i.</num>
<heading> Limitations on withholding of Federal assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refusal to supply personal data on students or families</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 1232g(b)(1)(D) of this title</ref>, the refusal of a State or local educational agency or institution of higher education, community college, school, agency offering a preschool program, or other educational institution to provide personally identifiable data on students or their families, as a part of any applicable program, to any Federal office, agency, department, or other third party, on the grounds that it constitutes a violation of the right to privacy and confidentiality of students or their parents, shall not constitute sufficient grounds for the suspension or termination of Federal assistance. Such a refusal shall also not constitute sufficient grounds for a denial of, a refusal to consider, or a delay in the consideration of, funding for such a recipient in succeeding fiscal years. In the case of any dispute arising under this section, reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing shall be afforded the applicant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliance with nondiscrimination provisions of Federal law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The extension of Federal financial assistance to a local educational agency may not be limited, deferred, or terminated by the Secretary on the ground of noncompliance with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq.] or any other nondiscrimination provision of Federal law unless such agency is accorded the right of due process of law, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at least 30 days prior written notice of deferral to the agency, setting forth the particular program or programs which the Secretary finds to be operated in noncompliance with a specific provision of Federal law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the opportunity for a hearing on the record before a duly appointed administrative law judge within a 60-day period (unless such period is extended by mutual consent of the Secretary and such agency) from the commencement of any deferral;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the conclusion of such hearing and the rendering of a decision on the merits by the administrative law judge within a period not to exceed 90 days from the commencement of such hearing, unless the judge finds by a decision that such hearing cannot be concluded or such decision cannot be rendered within such period, in which case such judge may extend such period for not to exceed 60 additional days;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the limitation of any deferral of Federal financial assistance which may be imposed by the Secretary to a period not to exceed 15 days after the rendering of such decision unless there has been an express finding on such record that such agency has failed to comply with any such nondiscrimination provision of Federal law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> procedures, which shall be established by the Secretary, to ensure the availability of sufficient funds, without regard to any fiscal year limitations, to comply with the decision of such judge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with imposition of quotas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for the Secretary to defer or limit any Federal financial assistance on the basis of any failure to comply with the imposition of quotas (or any other numerical requirements which have the effect of imposing quotas) on the student admission practices of an institution of higher education or community college receiving Federal financial assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 446</ref>, formerly § 440, as added <ref>Pub. L. 93–380, title V, § 515(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 574</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title IV</ref>, §§ 407, 408, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2232</ref>, 2233; renumbered § 446 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(b)(1)</ref>, (3)(C), <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1232j.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on federally sponsored testing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law and except as provided in subsection (b), no funds provided to the Department of Education or to an applicable program, may be used to pilot test, field test, implement, administer or distribute in any way any federally sponsored national test in reading, mathematics, or any other subject that is not specifically and explicitly provided for in authorizing legislation enacted into law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to the Third International Mathematics and Science Study or other international comparative assessments developed under the authority of <ref>section 9543(a)(6) of this title</ref> and administered to only a representative sample of pupils in the United States and in foreign nations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 447</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title III, § 305(a)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–374; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1062(4)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2088</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–279, title IV, § 404(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ENFORCEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1234.</num>
<heading> Office of Administrative Law Judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Department of Education an Office of Administrative Law Judges (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Office”) which shall conduct—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> recovery of funds hearings pursuant to <ref>section 1234a of this title</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> withholding hearings pursuant to <ref>section 1234d of this title</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> cease and desist hearings pursuant to <ref>section 1234e of this title</ref>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> other proceedings designated by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The administrative law judges (hereinafter “judges”) of the Office shall be appointed by the Secretary in accordance with <ref>section 3105 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment requirements; chief judge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The judges shall be officers or employees of the Department. The judges shall meet the requirements imposed for administrative law judges pursuant to <ref>section 3105 of title 5</ref>. In choosing among equally qualified candidates for such positions the Secretary shall give favorable consideration to the candidates’ experience in State or local educational agencies and their knowledge of the workings of Federal education programs in such agencies. The Secretary shall designate one of the judges of the Office to be the chief judge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment of judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of conducting hearings described in subsection (a), the chief judge shall assign a judge to each case or class of cases. A judge shall be disqualified in any case in which the judge has a substantial interest, has been of counsel, is or has been a material witness, or is so related to or connected with any party or the party’s attorney as to make it improper for the judge to be assigned to the case.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review and evidentiary functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The judge shall review and may require that evidence be taken on the sufficiency of the preliminary departmental determination as set forth in <ref>section 1234a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conduct of proceedings; costs and fees of parties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The proceedings of the Office shall be conducted according to such rules as the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation in conformance with the rules relating to hearings in title 5, sections 554, 556, and 557.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of title 5, section 504, relating to costs and fees of parties, shall apply to the proceedings before the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discovery; scope, time, etc.; issue and enforcement of subpoenas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In order to secure a fair, expeditious, and economical resolution of cases and where the judge determines that the discovered information is likely to elicit relevant information with respect to an issue in the case, is not sought primarily for the purposes of delay or harassment, and would serve the ends of justice, the judge may order a party to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> produce relevant documents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> answer written interrogatories that inquire into relevant matters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> have depositions taken.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The judge shall set a time limit of 90 days on the discovery period. The judge may extend this period for good cause shown. At the request of any party, the judge may establish a specific schedule for the conduct of discovery.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In order to carry out the provisions of subsections (f)(1) and (g)(1), the judge is authorized to issue subpoenas and apply to the appropriate court of the United States for enforcement of a subpoena. The court may enforce the subpoena as if it pertained to a proceeding before that court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mediation of disputes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a process for the voluntary mediation of disputes pending before the Office. The mediator shall be agreed to by all parties involved in mediation and shall be independent of the parties to the dispute. In the mediation of disputes the Secretary shall consider mitigating circumstances and proportion of harm pursuant to <ref>section 1234b of this title</ref>. In accordance with rule 408 of the Federal Rules of Evidence, evidence of conduct or statements made in compromise negotiations shall not be admissible in proceedings before the Office. Mediation shall be limited to 120 days, except that the mediator may grant extensions of such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Professional personnel; employment, assignment, or transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall employ, assign, or transfer sufficient professional personnel, including judges of the Office, to ensure that all matters brought before the Office may be dealt with in a timely manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 451</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2346</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234a.</num>
<heading> Recovery of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preliminary departmental decision; grounds of determination; notice requirements; prima facie case; amount of funds recoverable</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary determines that a recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement under an applicable program must return funds because the recipient has made an expenditure of funds that is not allowable under that grant or cooperative agreement, or has otherwise failed to discharge its obligation to account properly for funds under the grant or cooperative agreement, the Secretary shall give the recipient written notice of a preliminary departmental decision and notify the recipient of its right to have that decision reviewed by the Office and of its right to request mediation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In a preliminary departmental decision, the Secretary shall have the burden of establishing a prima facie case for the recovery of funds, including an analysis reflecting the value of the program services actually obtained in a determination of harm to the Federal interest. The facts to serve as the basis of the preliminary departmental decision may come from an audit report, an investigative report, a monitoring report, or other evidence. The amount of funds to be recovered shall be determined on the basis of <ref>section 1234b of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purpose of paragraph (2), failure by a recipient to maintain records required by law, or to allow the Secretary access to such records, shall constitute a prima facie case.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of preliminary departmental decision; form and contents of application for review; inadequate preliminary decisions; duties of recipient to subrecipients after preliminary decision; burden of proof</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A recipient that has received written notice of a preliminary departmental decision and that desires to have such decision reviewed by the Office shall submit to the Office an application for review not later than 60 days after receipt of notice of the preliminary departmental decision. The application shall be in the form and contain the information specified by the Office. As expeditiously as possible, the Office shall return to the Secretary for such action as the Secretary considers appropriate any preliminary departmental decision which the Office determines does not meet the requirements of subsection (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In cases where the preliminary departmental decision requests a recovery of funds from a State recipient, that State recipient may not recover funds from an affected local educational agency unless that State recipient has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transmitted a copy of the preliminary departmental decision to any affected subrecipient within 10 days of the date that the State recipient in a State administered program received such written notice; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consulted with each affected subrecipient to determine whether the State recipient should submit an application for review under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In any proceeding before the Office under this section, the burden shall be upon the recipient to demonstrate that it should not be required to return the amount of funds for which recovery is sought in the preliminary departmental decision under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A hearing shall be set 90 days after receipt of a request for review of a preliminary departmental decision by the Office, except that such 90-day requirement may be waived at the discretion of the judge for good cause.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of findings of fact in preliminary decision; conclusiveness; remand; new or modified findings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon review of a decision of the Office by the Secretary, the findings of fact by the Office, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive. However, the Secretary, for good cause shown, may remand the case to the Office to take further evidence, and the Office may thereupon make new or modified findings of fact and may modify its previous action. Such new or modified findings of fact shall likewise be conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> During the conduct of such review, there shall not be any ex parte contact between the Secretary and individuals representing the Department or the recipient.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for filing petition for review of preliminary decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Parties to the proceeding shall have 30 days to file a petition for review of a decision of the administrative law judges with the Office of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stay of collection or other adverse action by Secretary against recipient</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a recipient submits a timely application for review of a preliminary departmental decision, the Secretary shall take no collection action until the decision of the Office upholding the preliminary Department decision in whole or in part becomes final agency action under subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a recipient files a timely petition for judicial review under <ref>section 1234g of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall take no collection action until judicial review is completed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The filing of an application for review under paragraph (1) or a petition for judicial review under paragraph (2) shall not affect the authority of the Secretary to take any other adverse action under this subchapter against the recipient.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preliminary decision as final agency action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A decision of the Office regarding the review of a preliminary departmental decision shall become final agency action 60 days after the recipient receives written notice of the decision unless the Secretary either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> modifies or sets aside the decision, in whole or in part, in which case the decision of the Secretary shall become final agency action when the recipient receives written notice of the Secretary’s action, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> remands the decision to the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of decisions as final agency actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall publish decisions that have become final agency action under subsection (g) in the Federal Register or in another appropriate publication within 60 days.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection amounts and procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of a preliminary departmental decision under subsection (a) for which review has not been requested in accordance with subsection (b), and the amount sustained by a decision of the Office or the Secretary which becomes final agency action under subsection (g), may be collected by the Secretary in accordance with chapter 37 of title 31.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compromise of preliminary departmental decisions; preconditions; notice requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may, subject to the notice requirements of paragraph (2), compromise any preliminary departmental decision under this section which does not exceed the amount agreed to be returned by more than $200,000, if the Secretary determines that (A) the collection of any or all or the amount thereof would not be practical or in the public interest, and (B) the practice which resulted in the preliminary departmental decision has been corrected and will not recur.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not less than 45 days prior to the exercise of the authority to compromise a preliminary departmental decision pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of intention to do so. The notice shall provide interested persons an opportunity to comment on any proposed action under this subsection through the submission of written data, views, or arguments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation period respecting return of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No recipient under an applicable program shall be liable to return funds which were expended in a manner not authorized by law more than 5 years before the recipient received written notice of a preliminary departmental decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foregoing of interest during period of administrative review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No interest shall be charged arising from a claim during the administrative review of the preliminary departmental decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 452</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2347</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 250(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3926</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234b.</num>
<heading> Measure of recovery</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount returned proportionate to extent of harm violation caused to an identifiable Federal interest; reduction; determination of identifiable Federal interest</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A recipient determined to have made an unallowable expenditure, or to have otherwise failed to discharge its responsibility to account properly for funds, shall be required to return funds in an amount that is proportionate to the extent of the harm its violation caused to an identifiable Federal interest associated with the program under which the recipient received the award. Such amount shall be reduced in whole or in part by an amount that is proportionate to the extent the mitigating circumstances caused the violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purpose of paragraph (1), an identifiable Federal interest includes, but is not limited to, serving only eligible beneficiaries; providing only authorized services or benefits; complying with expenditure requirements and conditions (such as set-aside, excess cost, maintenance of effort, comparability, supplement-not-supplant, and matching requirements); preserving the integrity of planning, application, recordkeeping, and reporting requirements; and maintaining accountability for the use of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction or waiver of amount based on mitigating circumstances; burden of proof; determination of mitigating circumstances; weight, etc., of written request for guidance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When a State or local educational agency is determined to have made an unallowable expenditure, or to have otherwise failed to discharge its responsibility to account properly for funds, and mitigating circumstances exist, as described in paragraph (2), the judge shall reduce such amount by an amount that is proportionate to the extent the mitigating circumstances caused the violation. Furthermore, the judge is authorized to determine that no recovery is justified when mitigating circumstances warrant. The burden of demonstrating the existence of mitigating circumstances shall be upon the State or local educational agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of paragraph (1), mitigating circumstances exist only when it would be unjust to compel the recovery of funds because the State or local educational agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> actually and reasonably relied upon erroneous written guidance provided by the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> made an expenditure or engaged in a practice after—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the State or local educational agency submitted to the Secretary, in good faith, a written request for guidance with respect to the expenditure or practice at issue, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a Department official did not respond within 90 days of receipt by the Department of such request; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> actually and reasonably relied upon a judicial decree issued to the recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A written request for guidance as described in paragraph (2) sent by certified mail (return receipt requested) shall be conclusive proof of receipt by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the Secretary responds to a written request for guidance described in paragraph (2)(B) more than 90 days after its receipt, the State or local educational agency that submitted the request shall comply with the guidance received at the earliest practicable time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> In order to demonstrate the existence of the mitigating circumstances described in paragraph (2)(B), the State or local educational agency shall demonstrate that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the written request for guidance accurately described the proposed expenditure or practice and included the facts necessary for a determination of its legality; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the written request for guidance contained a certification by the chief legal officer of the State educational agency that such officer had examined the proposed expenditure or practice and believed the proposed expenditure or practice was permissible under then applicable State and Federal law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the State or local educational agency reasonably believed that the proposed expenditure or practice was permissible under then applicable State and Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall disseminate to State educational agencies responses to written requests for guidance, described in paragraph (5), that reflect significant interpretations of applicable law or policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of written requests for guidance on periodic basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall periodically review the written requests for guidance submitted under this section to determine the need for new or supplementary regulatory or other guidance under applicable programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 453</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2349</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234c.</num>
<heading> Remedies for existing violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever the Secretary has reason to believe that any recipient of funds under any applicable program is failing to comply substantially with any requirement of law applicable to such funds, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> withhold further payments under that program, as authorized by <ref>section 1234d of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issue a complaint to compel compliance through a cease and desist order of the Office, as authorized by <ref>section 1234e of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enter into a compliance agreement with a recipient to bring it into compliance, as authorized by <ref>section 1234f of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> take any other action authorized by law with respect to the recipient.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any action, or failure to take action, by the Secretary under this section shall not preclude the Secretary from seeking a recovery of funds under <ref>section 1234a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 454</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2349</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234d.</num>
<heading> Withholding</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary authority over further payments under applicable program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with <ref>section 1234c of this title</ref>, the Secretary may withhold from a recipient, in whole or in part, further payments (including payments for administrative costs) under an applicable program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Before withholding payments, the Secretary shall notify the recipient, in writing, of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the intent to withhold payments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the factual and legal basis for the Secretary’s belief that the recipient has failed to comply substantially with a requirement of law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an opportunity for a hearing to be held on a date at least 30 days after the notification has been sent to the recipient.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The hearing shall be held before the Office and shall be conducted in accordance with the rules prescribed pursuant to subsections (f) and (g) of <ref>section 1234 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of payments, authorities, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pending the outcome of any hearing under this section, the Secretary may suspend payments to a recipient, suspend the authority of the recipient to obligate Federal funds, or both, after such recipient has been given reasonable notice and an opportunity to show cause why future payments or authority to obligate Federal funds should not be suspended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings of fact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon review of a decision of the Office by the Secretary, the findings of fact by the Office, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive. However, the Secretary, for good cause shown, may remand the case to the Office to take further evidence, and the Office may thereupon make new or modified findings of fact and may modify its previous action. Such new or modified findings of fact shall likewise be conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final agency action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The decision of the Office in any hearing under this section shall become final agency action 60 days after the recipient receives written notice of the decision unless the Secretary either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> modifies or sets aside the decision, in whole or in part, in which case the decision of the Secretary shall become final agency action when the recipient receives written notice of the Secretary’s action; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> remands the decision of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 455</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2350</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234e.</num>
<heading> Cease and desist orders</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance and contents of complaint</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with <ref>section 1234c of this title</ref>, the Secretary may issue to a recipient under an applicable program a complaint which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes the factual and legal basis for the Secretary’s belief that the recipient is failing to comply substantially with a requirement of law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> contains a notice of a hearing to be held before the Office on a date at least 30 days after the service of the complaint.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appearance contesting order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The recipient upon which a complaint has been served shall have the right to appear before the Office on the date specified and to show cause why an order should not be entered by the Office requiring the recipient to cease and desist from the violation of law charged in the complaint.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report; issuance of cease and desist order</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The testimony in any hearing held under this section shall be reduced to writing and filed with the Office. If upon that hearing the Office is of the opinion that the recipient is in violation of any requirement of law as charged in the complaint, the Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make a report in writing stating its findings of fact; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> issue to the recipient an order requiring the recipient to cease and desist from the practice, policy, or procedure which resulted in the violation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report and order as final agency action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report and order of the Office under this section shall become the final agency action when the recipient receives the report and order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement of final order</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may enforce a final order of the Office under this section which becomes final agency action by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> withholding from the recipient any portion of the amount payable to it, including the amount payable for administrative costs, under the applicable program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> certifying the facts to the Attorney General who shall cause an appropriate proceeding to be brought for the enforcement of the order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 456</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2351</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234f.</num>
<heading> Compliance agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary authority; purposes of agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with <ref>section 1234c of this title</ref>, the Secretary may enter into a compliance agreement with a recipient under an applicable program. The purpose of any compliance agreement under this section shall be to bring the recipient into full compliance with the applicable requirements of law as soon as feasible and not to excuse or remedy past violations of such requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures applicable</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Before entering into a compliance agreement with a recipient, the Secretary shall hold a hearing at which the recipient, affected students and parents or their representatives, and other interested parties are invited to participate. The recipient shall have the burden of persuading the Secretary that full compliance with the applicable requirements of law is not feasible until a future date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Secretary determines, on the basis of all the evidence presented, that full compliance is genuinely not feasible until a future date, the Secretary shall make written findings to that effect and shall publish those findings, along with the substance of any compliance agreement, in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A compliance agreement under this section shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an expiration date not later than 3 years from the date of the written findings under subsection (b)(2), by which the recipient shall be in full compliance with the applicable requirements of law, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> those terms and conditions with which the recipient must comply until it is in full compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure of recipient to comply with terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a recipient fails to comply with the terms and conditions of a compliance agreement under this section, the Secretary may consider that compliance agreement to be no longer in effect, and the Secretary may take any action authorized by law with respect to the recipient.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 457</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234g.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recipients entitled to review; stay of action by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any recipient of funds under an applicable program that would be adversely affected by a final agency action under section 1234a, 1234d, or 1234e of this title, and any State entitled to receive funds under a program described in <ref>section 1232d(a) of this title</ref> whose application has been disapproved by the Secretary, shall be entitled to judicial review of such action in accordance with the provisions of this section. The Secretary may not take any action on the basis of a final agency action until judicial review is completed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petition for review; filing of record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A recipient that desires judicial review of an action described in subsection (a) shall, within 60 days of that action, file with the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which that recipient is located, a petition for review of such action. A copy of the petition shall be transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Secretary. The Secretary shall file in the court the record of the proceedings on which the action was based, as provided in <ref>section 2112 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings of fact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The findings of fact by the Office, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive; but the court, for good cause shown, may remand the case to the Office to take further evidence, and the Office may make new or modified findings of fact and may modify its previous action, and shall certify to the court the record of the further proceedings. Such new or modified findings of fact shall likewise be conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of review; review by Supreme Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The court shall have jurisdiction to affirm the action of the Office or the Secretary or to set it aside, in whole or in part. The judgment of the court shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon certiorari or certification as provided in <ref>section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 458</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 356</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 212(b)(3)(D)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3913</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234h.</num>
<heading> Use of recovered funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment to recipient; factors considered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary recovers funds paid to a recipient under a grant or cooperative agreement made under an applicable program because the recipient made an expenditure of funds that was not allowable, or otherwise failed to discharge its responsibility to account properly for funds, the Secretary may consider those funds to be additional funds available for that program and may arrange to repay to the recipient affected by that action an amount not to exceed 75 percent of the recovered funds if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the practices or procedures of the recipient that resulted in the violation of law have been corrected, and that the recipient is in all other respects in compliance with the requirements of that program, provided that the recipient was notified of any noncompliance with such requirements and given a reasonable period of time to remedy such noncompliance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the recipient has submitted to the Secretary a plan for the use of those funds pursuant to the requirements of that program and, to the extent possible, for the benefit of the population that was affected by the failure to comply or by the misuse of funds that resulted in the recovery; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the use of those funds in accordance with that plan would serve to achieve the purposes of the program under which the funds were originally paid.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions of repayment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any payments by the Secretary under this section shall be subject to such other terms and conditions as the Secretary considers necessary to accomplish the purposes of the affected programs, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the submission of periodic reports on the use of funds provided under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consultation by the recipient with students, parents, or representatives of the population that will benefit from the payments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the funds made available under this section shall remain available for expenditure for a period of time deemed reasonable by the Secretary, but in no case to exceed more than three fiscal years following the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the fiscal year in which final agency action under <ref>section 1234a(e) of this title</ref> is taken; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if such recipient files a petition for judicial review, the fiscal year in which final judicial action under <ref>section 1234g of this title</ref> is taken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register of notice of intent to enter into repayment arrangement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At least 30 days prior to entering into an arrangement under this section, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of intent to enter into such an arrangement and the terms and conditions under which payments will be made. Interested persons shall have an opportunity for at least 30 days to submit comments to the Secretary regarding the proposed arrangement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 459</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 356</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 250(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3927</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1234i.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “recipient” means a recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement under an applicable program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “applicable program” excludes programs authorized by the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.] and assistance programs provided under the Act of <date date="1950-09-30">September 30, 1950</date> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002123">1</ref> (Public Law 874, 81st Congress), and the Act of <date date="1950-09-23">September 23, 1950</date> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002123">1</ref> (Public Law 815, 81st Congress).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 460</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>READY TO LEARN TELEVISION</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1235 to 1235g.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1011(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1986</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>