<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 75—</num>
<heading>EARLY LEARNING OPPORTUNITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9401.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase the availability of voluntary programs, services, and activities that support early childhood development, increase parent effectiveness, and promote the learning readiness of young children so that young children enter school ready to learn;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support parents, child care providers, and caregivers who want to incorporate early learning activities into the daily lives of young children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to remove barriers to the provision of an accessible system of early childhood learning programs in communities throughout the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to increase the availability and affordability of professional development activities and compensation for caregivers and child care providers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to facilitate the development of community-based systems of collaborative service delivery models characterized by resource sharing, linkages between appropriate supports, and local planning for services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 802]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–80.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9402.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Caregiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “caregiver” means an individual, including a relative, neighbor, or family friend, who regularly or frequently provides care, with or without compensation, for a child for whom the individual is not the parent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child care provider</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “child care provider” means a provider of non-residential child care services (including center-based, family-based, and in-home child care services) for compensation who or that is legally operating under State law, and complies with applicable State and local requirements for the provision of child care services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Early learning</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “early learning”, used with respect to a program or activity, means learning designed to facilitate the development of cognitive, language, motor, and social-emotional skills for, and to promote learning readiness in, young children.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Early learning program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “early learning program” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a program of services or activities that helps parents, caregivers, and child care providers incorporate early learning into the daily lives of young children; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a program that directly provides early learning to young children.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local Council</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Local Council” means a Local Council established or designated under <ref>section 9413(a) of this title</ref> that serves one or more localities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Locality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “locality” means a city, county, borough, township, or area served by another general purpose unit of local government, an Indian tribe, a Regional Corporation, or a Native Hawaiian entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “parent” means a biological parent, an adoptive parent, a stepparent, a foster parent, or a legal guardian of, or a person standing in loco parentis to, a child.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Poverty line</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “poverty line” means the poverty line (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget, and revised annually in accordance with <ref>section 9902(2) of title 42</ref>) applicable to a family of the size involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Regional Corporation” means an entity listed in <ref>section 619(4)(B) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “training” means instruction in early learning that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is required for certification under State and local laws, regulations, and policies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is required to receive a nationally or State recognized credential or its equivalent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is received in a postsecondary education program focused on early learning or early childhood development in which the individual is enrolled; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is provided, certified, or sponsored by an organization that is recognized for its expertise in promoting early learning or early childhood development.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Young child</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “young child” means any child from birth to the age of mandatory school attendance in the State where the child resides.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 803]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–81.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9403.</num>
<heading> Prohibitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation not required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person, including a parent, shall be required to participate in any program of early childhood education, early learning, parent education, or developmental screening pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of parents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect the rights of parents otherwise established in Federal, State, or local law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Particular methods or settings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No entity that receives funds under this chapter shall be required to provide services under this chapter through a particular instructional method or in a particular instructional setting to comply with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonduplication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No funds provided under this chapter shall be used to carry out an activity funded under another provision of law providing for Federal child care or early learning programs, unless an expansion of such activity is identified in the local needs assessment and performance goals under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 804]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–82.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9404.</num>
<heading> Authorization and appropriation of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Health and Human Services to carry out this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $750,000,000 for fiscal year 2001;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $1,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2002;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $1,500,000,000 for fiscal year 2003; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2004 and 2005.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 805]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–82.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9405.</num>
<heading> Coordination of Federal programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the Secretary of Education shall develop mechanisms to resolve administrative and programmatic conflicts between Federal programs that would be a barrier to parents, caregivers, service providers, or children related to the coordination of services and funding for early learning programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of equipment and supplies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a collaborative activity funded under this chapter and another provision of law providing for Federal child care or early learning programs, the use of equipment and nonconsumable supplies purchased with funds made available under this chapter or such provision shall not be restricted to children enrolled or otherwise participating in the program carried out under this chapter or such provision, during a period in which the activity is predominately funded under this chapter or such provision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 806]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–82.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9406.</num>
<heading> Program authorized</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From amounts appropriated under <ref>section 9404 of this title</ref> the Secretary shall award grants to States to enable the States to award grants to Local Councils to pay the Federal share of the cost of carrying out early learning programs in the locality served by the Local Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal share of the cost described in subsections (a) and (e) shall be 85 percent for the first and second years of the grant, 80 percent for the third and fourth years of the grant, and 75 percent for the fifth and subsequent years of the grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The non-Federal share of the cost described in subsections (a) and (e) may be contributed in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including facilities, equipment, or services, which may be provided from State or local public sources, or through donations from private entities. For the purposes of this paragraph the term “facilities” includes the use of facilities, but the term “equipment” means donated equipment and not the use of equipment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall not award a grant under this chapter to any State unless the Secretary first determines that the total expenditures by the State and its political subdivisions to support early learning programs (other than funds used to pay the non-Federal share under subsection (b)(2)) for the fiscal year for which the determination is made is equal to or greater than such expenditures for the preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplement not supplant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts received under this chapter shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, and local public funds expended to promote early learning.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If funds appropriated to carry out this chapter are less than $150,000,000 for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall award grants for the fiscal year directly to Local Councils, on a competitive basis, to pay the Federal share of the cost of carrying out early learning programs in the locality served by the Local Council. In carrying out the preceding sentence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subsection (c), subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 9409 of this title</ref>, and paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of <ref>section 9410(a) of this title</ref> shall not apply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> State responsibilities described in <ref>section 9410(d) of this title</ref> shall be carried out by the Local Council with regard to the locality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall provide such technical assistance and monitoring as necessary to ensure that the use of the funds by Local Councils and the distribution of the funds to Local Councils are consistent with this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall assume the responsibilities of the Lead State Agency under this chapter, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 807]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–82.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9407.</num>
<heading> Uses of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to <ref>section 9409 of this title</ref>, grant funds under this chapter shall be used to pay for developing, operating, or enhancing voluntary early learning programs that are likely to produce sustained gains in early learning.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to <ref>section 9409 of this title</ref>, Lead State Agencies and Local Councils shall ensure that funds made available under this chapter to the agencies and Local Councils are used for three or more of the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Helping parents, caregivers, child care providers, and educators increase their capacity to facilitate the development of cognitive, language comprehension, expressive language, social-emotional, and motor skills, and promote learning readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Promoting effective parenting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Enhancing early childhood literacy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Developing linkages among early learning programs within a community and between early learning programs and health care services for young children.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Increasing access to early learning opportunities for young children with special needs, including developmental delays, by facilitating coordination with other programs serving such young children.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Increasing access to existing early learning programs by expanding the days or times that the young children are served, by expanding the number of young children served, or by improving the affordability of the programs for low-income families.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Improving the quality of early learning programs through professional development and training activities, increased compensation, and recruitment and retention incentives, for early learning providers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Removing ancillary barriers to early learning, including transportation difficulties and absence of programs during nontraditional work times.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Lead State Agency designated under <ref>section 9409(c) of this title</ref> and Local Councils receiving a grant under this chapter shall ensure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that Local Councils described in <ref>section 9413 of this title</ref> work with local educational agencies to identify cognitive, social, emotional, and motor developmental abilities which are necessary to support children’s readiness for school;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the programs, services, and activities assisted under this chapter will represent developmentally appropriate steps toward the acquisition of those abilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the programs, services, and activities assisted under this chapter collectively provide benefits for children cared for in their own homes as well as children placed in the care of others.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sliding scale payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">States and Local Councils receiving assistance under this chapter shall ensure that programs, services, and activities assisted under this chapter which customarily require a payment for such programs, services, or activities, adjust the cost of such programs, services, and activities provided to the individual or the individual’s child based on the individual’s ability to pay.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 808]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–83.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9408.</num>
<heading> Reservations and allotments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation for Indian tribes, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall reserve 1 percent of the total amount appropriated under <ref>section 9404 of this title</ref> for each fiscal year, to be allotted to Indian tribes, Regional Corporations, and Native Hawaiian entities, of which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 0.5 percent shall be available to Indian tribes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 0.5 percent shall be available to Regional Corporations and Native Hawaiian entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allotments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">From the funds appropriated under this chapter for each fiscal year that are not reserved under subsection (a), the Secretary shall allot to each State the sum of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an amount that bears the same ratio to 50 percent of such funds as the number of children 4 years of age and younger in the State bears to the number of such children in all States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an amount that bears the same ratio to 50 percent of such funds as the number of children 4 years of age and younger living in families with incomes below the poverty line in the State bears to the number of such children in all States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum allotment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No State shall receive an allotment under subsection (b) for a fiscal year in an amount that is less than .40 percent of the total amount appropriated for the fiscal year under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any portion of the allotment to a State that is not expended for activities under this chapter in the fiscal year for which the allotment is made shall remain available to the State for two additional years, after which any unexpended funds shall be returned to the Secretary. The Secretary shall use the returned funds to carry out a discretionary grant program for research-based early learning demonstration projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make allotments under this chapter on the basis of the most recent data available to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 809]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–84.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9409.</num>
<heading> Grant administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal administrative costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may use not more than 3 percent of the amount appropriated under <ref>section 9404 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year to pay for the administrative costs of carrying out this chapter, including the monitoring and evaluation of State and local efforts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State administrative costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State that receives a grant under this chapter may use—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not more than 2 percent of the funds made available through the grant to carry out activities designed to coordinate early learning programs on the State level, including programs funded or operated by the State educational agency, health, children and family, and human service agencies, and any State-level collaboration or coordination council involving early learning and education, such as the entities funded under <ref>section 9835(a)(2)(B)(vi) of title 42</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not more than 2 percent of the funds made available through the grant for the administrative costs of carrying out the grant program and the costs of reporting State and local efforts to the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not more than 3 percent of the funds made available through the grant for training, technical assistance, and wage incentives provided by the State to Local Councils.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead State Agency</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive an allotment under this chapter, the Governor of a State shall appoint, after consultation with the leadership of the State legislature, a Lead State Agency to carry out the functions described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead State Agency</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Lead State Agency described in paragraph (1) shall allocate funds to Local Councils as described in <ref>section 9411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of agency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In addition to allocating funds pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Lead State Agency shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> advise and assist Local Councils in the performance of their duties under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> develop and submit the State application;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> evaluate and approve applications submitted by Local Councils under <ref>section 9412 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> ensure collaboration with respect to assistance provided under this chapter between the State agency responsible for education and the State agency responsible for children and family services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> prepare and submit to the Secretary, an annual report on the activities carried out in the State under this chapter, which shall include a statement describing how all funds received under this chapter are expended and documentation of the effects that resources under this chapter have had on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> parental capacity to improve learning readiness in their young children;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> early childhood literacy;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> linkages among early learning programs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> linkages between early learning programs and health care services for young children;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> access to early learning activities for young children with special needs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> access to existing early learning programs through expansion of the days or times that children are served;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> access to existing early learning programs through expansion of the number of young children served;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VIII)</num>
<content> access to and affordability of existing early learning programs for low-income families;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IX)</num>
<content> the quality of early learning programs resulting from professional development, and recruitment and retention incentives for caregivers; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(X)</num>
<content> removal of ancillary barriers to early learning, including transportation difficulties and absence of programs during nontraditional work times; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> ensure that training and research is made available to Local Councils and that such training and research reflects the latest available brain development and early childhood development research related to early learning.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 810]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–85; <ref>Pub. L. 110–134, § 29(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-12">Dec. 12, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9410.</num>
<heading> State requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for a grant under this chapter, a State shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that funds received by the State under this chapter shall be subject to appropriation by the State legislature, consistent with the terms and conditions required under State law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designate a Lead State Agency under <ref>section 9409(c) of this title</ref> to administer and monitor the grant and ensure State-level coordination of early learning programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure that funds made available under this chapter are distributed on a competitive basis throughout the State to Local Councils serving rural, urban, and suburban areas of the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> assist the Secretary in developing mechanisms to ensure that Local Councils receiving funds under this chapter comply with the requirements of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State preference</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In awarding grants to Local Councils under this chapter, the State, to the maximum extent possible, shall ensure that a broad variety of early learning programs that provide a continuity of services across the age spectrum assisted under this chapter are funded under this chapter, and shall give preference to supporting—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a Local Council that meets criteria, that are specified by the State and approved by the Secretary, for qualifying as serving an area of greatest need for early learning programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a Local Council that demonstrates, in the application submitted under <ref>section 9412 of this title</ref>, the Local Council’s potential to increase collaboration as a means of maximizing use of resources provided under this chapter with other resources available for early learning programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local preference</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In awarding grants under this chapter, Local Councils shall give preference to supporting—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> projects that demonstrate their potential to collaborate as a means of maximizing use of resources provided under this chapter with other resources available for early learning programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> programs that provide a continuity of services for young children across the age spectrum, individually, or through community-based networks or cooperative agreements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> programs that help parents and other caregivers promote early learning with their young children.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance goals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Based on information and data received from Local Councils, and information and data available through State resources, the State shall biennially assess the needs and available resources related to the provision of early learning programs within the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance goals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Based on the analysis of information described in paragraph (1), the State shall establish measurable performance goals to be achieved through activities assisted under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State shall award grants to Local Councils only for purposes that are consistent with the performance goals established under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State shall report to the Secretary annually regarding the State’s progress toward achieving the performance goals established in paragraph (2) and any necessary modifications to those goals, including the rationale for the modifications.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Improvement plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary determines, based on the State report submitted under paragraph (4), that the State is not making progress toward achieving the performance goals described in paragraph (2), then the State shall submit a performance improvement plan to the Secretary, and demonstrate reasonable progress in implementing such plan, in order to remain eligible for funding under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 811]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–86.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9411.</num>
<heading> Local allocations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Lead State Agency shall allocate to Local Councils in the State not less than 93 percent of the funds provided to the State under this chapter for a fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Lead State Agency shall allocate funds provided under this chapter on the basis of the population of the locality served by the Local Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 812]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–88.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9412.</num>
<heading> Local applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be eligible to receive assistance under this chapter, the Local Council shall submit an application to the Lead State Agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Lead State Agency may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each application submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include a statement ensuring that the local government entity, Indian tribe, Regional Corporation, or Native Hawaiian entity has established or designated a Local Council under <ref>section 9413 of this title</ref>, and the Local Council has developed a local plan for carrying out early learning programs under this chapter that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a needs and resources assessment concerning early learning services and a statement describing how early learning programs will be funded consistent with the assessment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement of how the Local Council will ensure that early learning programs will meet the performance goals reported by the Lead State Agency under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of how the Local Council will form collaboratives among local youth, social service, and educational providers to maximize resources and concentrate efforts on areas of greatest need.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 813]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–88.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9413.</num>
<heading> Local administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local Council</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive funds under this chapter, a local government entity, Indian tribe, Regional Corporation, or Native Hawaiian entity, as appropriate, shall establish or designate a Local Council, which shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> representatives of local agencies directly affected by early learning programs assisted under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> parents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other individuals concerned with early learning issues in the locality, such as representative entities providing elementary education, child care resource and referral services, early learning opportunities, child care, and health services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other key community leaders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designating existing entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a local government entity, Indian tribe, Regional Corporation, or Native Hawaiian entity has, before <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, a Local Council or a regional entity that is comparable to the Local Council described in paragraph (1), the entity, tribe, or corporation may designate the council or entity as a Local Council under this chapter, and shall be considered to have established a Local Council in compliance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Local Council shall be responsible for preparing and submitting the application described in <ref>section 9412 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 3 percent of the funds received by a Local Council under this chapter shall be used to pay for the administrative costs of the Local Council in carrying out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal agent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Local Council may designate any entity, with a demonstrated capacity for administering grants, that is affected by, or concerned with, early learning issues, including the State, to serve as fiscal agent for the administration of grant funds received by the Local Council under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 814]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–88.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>