<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 48—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3401.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> education is fundamental to the development of individual citizens and the progress of the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is a continuing need to ensure equal access for all Americans to educational opportunities of a high quality, and such educational opportunities should not be denied because of race, creed, color, national origin, or sex;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> parents have the primary responsibility for the education of their children, and States, localities, and private institutions have the primary responsibility for supporting that parental role;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in our Federal system, the primary public responsibility for education is reserved respectively to the States and the local school systems and other instrumentalities of the States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the American people benefit from a diversity of educational settings, including public and private schools, libraries, museums and other institutions, the workplace, the community, and the home;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the importance of education is increasing as new technologies and alternative approaches to traditional education are considered, as society becomes more complex, and as equal opportunities in education and employment are promoted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> there is a need for improvement in the management and coordination of Federal education programs to support more effectively State, local, and private institutions, students, and parents in carrying out their educational responsibilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the dispersion of education programs across a large number of Federal agencies has led to fragmented, duplicative, and often inconsistent Federal policies relating to education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Presidential and public consideration of issues relating to Federal education programs is hindered by the present organizational position of education programs in the executive branch of the Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> there is no single, full-time, Federal education official directly accountable to the President, the Congress, and the people.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3402.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress declares that the establishment of a Department of Education is in the public interest, will promote the general welfare of the United States, will help ensure that education issues receive proper treatment at the Federal level, and will enable the Federal Government to coordinate its education activities more effectively. Therefore, the purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to strengthen the Federal commitment to ensuring access to equal educational opportunity for every individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to supplement and complement the efforts of States, the local school systems and other instrumentalities of the States, the private sector, public and private educational institutions, public and private nonprofit educational research institutions, community-based organizations, parents, and students to improve the quality of education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to encourage the increased involvement of the public, parents, and students in Federal education programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to promote improvements in the quality and usefulness of education through federally supported research, evaluation, and sharing of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to improve the coordination of Federal education programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to improve the management and efficiency of Federal education activities, especially with respect to the process, procedures, and administrative structures for the dispersal of Federal funds, as well as the reduction of unnecessary and duplicative burdens and constraints, including unnecessary paperwork, on the recipients of Federal funds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to increase the accountability of Federal education programs to the President, the Congress, and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3403.</num>
<heading> Relationship with States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of local governments and educational institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the intention of the Congress in the establishment of the Department to protect the rights of State and local governments and public and private educational institutions in the areas of educational policies and administration of programs and to strengthen and improve the control of such governments and institutions over their own educational programs and policies. The establishment of the Department of Education shall not increase the authority of the Federal Government over education or diminish the responsibility for education which is reserved to the States and the local school systems and other instrumentalities of the States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Curriculum, administration, and personnel; library resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of a program administered by the Secretary or by any other officer of the Department shall be construed to authorize the Secretary or any such officer to exercise any direction, supervision, or control over the curriculum, program of instruction, administration, or personnel of any educational institution, school, or school system, over any accrediting agency or association, or over the selection or content of library resources, textbooks, or other instructional materials by any educational institution or school system, except to the extent authorized by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding under pre-existing programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall not, during the period within eight months after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, take any action to withhold, suspend, or terminate funds under any program transferred by this chapter by reason of the failure of any State to comply with any applicable law requiring the administration of such a program through a single organizational unit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3404.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, unless otherwise provided or indicated by the context—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Department” means the Department of Education or any component thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Deputy Secretary” means the Deputy Secretary of Education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “function” includes any duty, obligation, power, authority, responsibility, right, privilege, activity, or program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the terms “private” and “private educational” refer to independent, nonpublic, and private institutions of elementary, secondary, and postsecondary education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “office” includes any office, institute, council, unit, organizational entity, or component thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 112(a)(3)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1454.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ESTABLISHMENT OF THE DEPARTMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3411.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Department; appointment of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established an executive department to be known as the Department of Education. The Department shall be administered, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, under the supervision and direction of a Secretary of Education. The Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 671</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3412.</num>
<heading> Principal officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deputy Secretary of Education</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department a Deputy Secretary of Education who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. During the absence or disability of the Secretary, or in the event of a vacancy in the office of the Secretary, the Deputy Secretary shall act as Secretary. The Secretary shall designate the order in which other officials of the Department shall act for and perform the functions of the Secretary during the absence or disability of both the Secretary and Deputy Secretary or in the event of vacancies in both of those offices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Deputy Secretary shall have responsibility for the conduct of intergovernmental relations of the Department, including assuring (i) that the Department carries out its functions in a manner which supplements and complements the education policies, programs, and procedures of the States and the local school systems and other instrumentalities of the States, and (ii) that appropriate officials of the Department consult with individuals responsible for making policy relating to education in the States and the local school systems and other instrumentalities of the States concerning differences over education policies, programs, and procedures and concerning the impact of the rules and regulations of the Department on the States and the local school systems and other instrumentalities of the States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Local education authorities may inform the Deputy Secretary of any rules or regulations of the Department which are in conflict with another rule or regulation issued by any other Federal department or agency or with any other office of the Department. If the Deputy Secretary determines, after consultation with the appropriate Federal department or agency, that such a conflict does exist, the Deputy Secretary shall report such conflict or conflicts to the appropriate Federal department or agency together with recommendations for the correction of the conflict.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistant Secretaries and General Counsel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be in the Department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Assistant Secretary for Elementary and Secondary Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Assistant Secretary for Postsecond­ary Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an Assistant Secretary for Special Education and Rehabilitative Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a General Counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each of the Assistant Secretaries and the General Counsel shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department, a Special Assistant for Gender Equity who shall be appointed by the Secretary. The Special Assistant shall promote, coordinate, and evaluate gender equity programs, including the dissemination of information, technical assistance, and coordination of research activities. The Special Assistant shall advise the Secretary and Deputy Secretary on all matters relating to gender equity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department a Director of the Institute of Education Sciences who shall be appointed in accordance with section 114(a) of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 9514(a)</ref>] and perform the duties described in that Act [<ref>20 U.S.C. 9501</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspector General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Inspector General appointed in accordance with chapter 4 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Under Secretary of Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There may be in the Department an Under Secretary of Education who shall perform such functions as the Secretary may prescribe. The Under Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There shall be in the Department four additional officers who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Notwithstanding the previous sentence, the appointments of individuals to serve as the Assistant Secretary for Management shall not be subject to the advice and consent of the Senate. The officers appointed under this subsection shall perform such functions as the Secretary shall prescribe, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> congressional relations functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> public information functions, including the provision, through the use of the latest technologies, of useful information about education and related opportunities to students, parents, and communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> functions related to monitoring parental and public participation in programs where such participation is required by law, and encouraging the involvement of parents, students, and the public in the development and implementation of departmental programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> management and budget functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> planning, evaluation, and policy development functions, including development of policies to promote the efficient and coordinated administration of the Department and its programs and to encourage improvements in education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> functions related to encouraging and promoting the study of foreign languages and the study of cultures of other countries at the elementary, secondary, and postsecondary levels.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statements of functions of nominees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the President submits the name of an individual to the Senate for confirmation as an officer of the Department under this section, the President shall state the particular functions of the Department such individual will exercise upon taking office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supervision by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each officer of the Department established under this section shall report directly to the Secretary and shall, in addition to any functions vested in or required to be delegated to such officer, perform such additional functions as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of literacy related functions by Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education, in addition to performing such functions as the Secretary may prescribe, shall have responsibility for coordination of all literacy related programs and policy initiatives in the Department. The Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education shall assist in coordinating the related activities and programs of other Federal departments and agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liaison for Community and Junior Colleges</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department a Liaison for Community and Junior Colleges, who shall be an officer of the Department appointed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall appoint, not later than 6 months after <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, as the Liaison for Community and Junior Colleges a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has attained an associate degree from a community or junior college; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has been employed in a community or junior college setting for not less than 5 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Liaison for Community and Junior Colleges shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> serve as principal advisor to the Secretary on matters affecting community and junior colleges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide guidance to programs within the Department dealing with functions affecting community and junior colleges; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> work with the Federal Interagency Committee on Education to improve coordination of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the outreach programs in the numerous Federal departments and agencies that administer education and job training programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> collaborative business education partnerships; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> education programs located in, and regarding, rural areas.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 112(a)(3)(B)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1454; <ref>Pub. L. 102–73, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1991-07-25">July 25, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 334</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–103, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1991-08-17">Aug. 17, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–325, title XV, § 1553(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 838</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–227, title IX, § 913</ref>, <date date="1994-03-31">Mar. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1072(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–279, title IV, § 402(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. H, title III, § 307(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(40)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3413.</num>
<heading> Office for Civil Rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; administration; delegation of functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office for Civil Rights, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights appointed under <ref>section 3412(b) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 3472 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall delegate to the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights all functions, other than administrative and support functions, transferred to the Secretary under <ref>section 3441(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance and enforcement reports; copies submitted to Secretary</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights shall make an annual report to the Secretary, the President, and the Congress summarizing the compliance and enforcement activities of the Office for Civil Rights and identifying significant civil rights or compliance problems as to which such Office has made a recommendation for corrective action and as to which, in the judgment of the Assistant Secretary, adequate progress is not being made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the report required by paragraph (1) shall be transmitted to the Secretary, the President, and the Congress by the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights without further clearance or approval. The Assistant Secretary shall provide copies of the report required by paragraph (1) to the Secretary sufficiently in advance of its submission to the President and the Congress to provide a reasonable opportunity for comments of the Secretary to be appended to the report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Assistant Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to the authority otherwise provided under this section, the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights, in carrying out the provisions of this section, is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to collect or coordinate the collection of data necessary to ensure compliance with civil rights laws within the jurisdiction of the Office for Civil Rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees, including staff attorneys, as may be necessary to carry out the functions of such Office, subject to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to enter into contracts and other arrangements for audits, studies, analyses, and other services with public agencies and with private organizations and persons, and to make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the compliance and enforcement functions of such Office; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, to obtain services as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> at a rate not to exceed the equivalent daily rate payable for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3414.</num>
<heading> Office of Elementary and Secondary Education; inclusion of Office of Migrant Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office of Elementary and Secondary Education, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Elementary and Secondary Education appointed under <ref>section 3412(b) of this title</ref>. The Assistant Secretary shall administer such functions affecting elementary and secondary education, both public and private, as the Secretary shall delegate. There shall be within the Office of Elementary and Secondary Education and directly under the supervision of the Assistant Secretary for Elementary and Secondary Education, an Office of Migrant Education, which shall be responsible for the administration of programs established by part C of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 6391</ref> et seq.] and by subpart 5 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1070d–2</ref>].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–511, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 391(h)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4023</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3415.</num>
<heading> Office of Postsecondary Education</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There shall be in the Department an Office of Postsecondary Education, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education appointed under <ref>section 3412(b) of this title</ref>. The Assistant Secretary shall administer such functions affecting postsecondary education, both public and private, as the Secretary shall delegate, and shall serve as the principal adviser to the Secretary on matters affecting postsecondary education.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education shall appoint a Deputy Assistant Secretary for International and Foreign Language Education to perform such functions affecting postsecondary, international, and foreign language education as the Secretary may prescribe. The Deputy Assistant Secretary for International and Foreign Language Education shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be an individual with extensive background and experience in international and foreign language education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have responsibility for encouraging and promoting the study of foreign languages and the study of the cultures of other countries at the elementary, secondary, and postsecondary levels in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coordinate with related international and foreign language education programs of other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–315, title IX, § 935</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3416.</num>
<heading> Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education appointed under <ref>section 3412(b) of this title</ref>. The Assistant Secretary shall administer such functions affecting career, technical, and adult education as the Secretary shall delegate, and shall serve as principal adviser to the Secretary on matters affecting career, technical, and adult education. The Secretary, through the Assistant Secretary, shall also provide a unified approach to rural education and rural family education through the coordination of programs within the Department and shall work with the Federal Interagency Committee on Education to coordinate related activities and programs of other Federal departments and agencies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. H, title III, § 307(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3417.</num>
<heading> Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Special Education and Rehabilitative Services appointed under <ref>section 3412(b) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 3472 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall delegate to the Assistant Secretary all functions, other than administrative and support functions, transferred to the Secretary under sections 3441(a)(1) of this title (with respect to the bureau for the education and training of the handicapped), 3441(a)(2)(H) of this title, and 3441(a)(4) of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 674</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3418.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 720</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3419.</num>
<heading> Institute of Education Sciences</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Education the Institute of Education Sciences, which shall be administered in accordance with the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 9501</ref> et seq.] by the Director appointed under section 114(a) of that Act [<ref>20 U.S.C. 9514(a)</ref>].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 208</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–279, title IV, § 402(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3420.</num>
<heading> Office of English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement for Limited English Proficient Students</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office of English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement for Limited English Proficient Students, to be administered by a Director of English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement for Limited English Proficient Students, who shall be appointed by the Secretary. The Director shall coordinate the administration of bilingual education programs by the Department and shall consult with the Secretary concerning policy decisions affecting bilingual education and minority languages affairs. The Director shall report directly to the Secretary, and shall perform such additional functions as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 209</ref>, formerly § 210, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 675</ref>; renumbered § 209, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1072(b)</ref>, (c)(2)(A), (d), <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2089</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3421.</num>
<heading> Office of General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office of General Counsel, to be administered by the General Counsel appointed under <ref>section 3412(b) of this title</ref>. The General Counsel shall provide legal assistance to the Secretary concerning the programs and policies of the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 210</ref>, formerly § 211, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 675</ref>; renumbered § 210, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3422.</num>
<heading> Office of Inspector General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office of Inspector General, established in accordance with chapter 4 of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 211</ref>, formerly § 212, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 675</ref>; renumbered § 211, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(41)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3423.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–392, title VI, § 602(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-09-25">Sept. 25, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 840</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3423a.</num>
<heading> Office of Correctional Education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> education is important to, and makes a significant contribution to, the readjustment of incarcerated individuals to society; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is a growing need for immediate action by the Federal Government to assist State and local educational programs for criminal offenders in correctional institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter to encourage and support educational programs for criminal offenders in correctional institutions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education shall establish within the Department of Education an Office of Correctional Education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, through the Office of Correctional Education established under subsection (c) of this section, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate all correctional education programs within the Department of Education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide technical support to State and local educational agencies and schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Affairs on correctional education programs and curricula;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide an annual report to the Congress on the progress of the Office of Correctional Education and the status of correctional education in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> cooperate with other Federal agencies carrying out correctional education programs to ensure coordination of such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consult with, and provide outreach to, State directors of correctional education and correctional educators; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> collect from States a sample of information on the number of individuals who complete a vocational education sequence, earn a high school degree or general equivalency diploma, or earn a postsecondary degree while incarcerated and the correlation with job placement, job retention, and recidivism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “criminal offender” means any individual who is charged with or convicted of any criminal offense, including a youth offender or a juvenile offender;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “correctional institution” means any—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prison,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> jail,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> reformatory,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> work farm,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> detention center, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> halfway house, community-based rehabilitation center, or any other similar institution designed for the confinement or rehabilitation of criminal offenders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “State educational agency” means the State board of education or other agency or officer primarily responsible for the State supervision of public elementary and secondary schools, or, if there is no such officer or agency, an officer or agency designated by the Governor or by State law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 212</ref>, formerly § 214, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–392, title VI, § 602(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-09-25">Sept. 25, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 840</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title II, § 20408(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1827</ref>; renumbered § 212, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3423b.</num>
<heading> Office of Non-Public Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department an Office of Non-Public Education to ensure the maximum potential participation of non-public school students in all Federal educational programs for which such students are eligible.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 214</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3423c.</num>
<heading> Office of Indian Education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Indian Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be an Office of Indian Education (referred to in this section as “the Office”) in the Department of Education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall be under the direction of the Director, who shall be appointed by the Secretary and who shall report directly to the Assistant Secretary for Elementary and Secondary Education.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be responsible for administering part A of title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be involved in, and be primarily responsible for, the development of all policies affecting Indian children and adults under programs administered by the Office of Elementary and Secondary Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordinate the development of policy and practice for all programs in the Department relating to Indian persons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assist the Assistant Secretary of the Office of Educational Research and Improvement in identifying research priorities related to the education of Indian persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian preference in employment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall give a preference to Indian persons in all personnel actions in the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such preference shall be implemented in the same fashion as the preference given to any veteran under <ref>section 45 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 215</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 372(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3977</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(v)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3423d.</num>
<heading> Office of English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement for Limited English Proficient Students</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be, in the Department, an Office of English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement for Limited English Proficient Students through which the Secretary shall carry out functions relating to bilingual education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall be headed by a Director of English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement for Limited English Proficient Students, appointed by the Secretary, to whom the Secretary shall delegate all delegable functions relating to bilingual education. The Director shall also be assigned responsibility for recommending improvements and providing technical assistance to other Federal programs serving language-minority and limited-English-proficient students and their families and for assisting the Assistant Secretary of the Office of Educational Research and Improvement in identifying research priorities which reflect the needs of language-minority and limited-English language proficient students.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall be organized as the Director determines to be appropriate in order to carry out such functions and responsibilities effectively.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that limited-English-proficient and language-minority students are included in ways that are valid, reliable, and fair under all standards and assessment development conducted or funded by the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 216</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 372(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3978</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1072(b)</ref>, (c)(2)(B), (d), <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2089</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3424.</num>
<heading> Federal Interagency Committee on Education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and function</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a Federal Interagency Committee on Education (hereafter referred to in this section as the “Committee”). The Committee shall assist the Secretary in providing a mechanism to assure that the procedures and actions of the Department and other Federal departments and agencies are fully coordinated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of Federal programs, policies and practices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee shall study and make recommendations for assuring effective coordination of Federal programs, policies, and administrative practices affecting education, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consistent administration and development of policies and practices among Federal agencies in the conduct of related programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> full and effective communication among Federal agencies to avoid unnecessary duplication of activities and repetitive collection of data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> full and effective cooperation with the Secretary on such studies and analyses as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordination of related programs to assure that recipients of Federal assistance are efficiently and responsively served; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> full and effective involvement and participation of students and parents in Federal education programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee shall be composed of the Secretary, who shall chair the Committee, and senior policy making officials from those Federal agencies, commissions, and boards that the President may find appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of additional persons to attend meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and the Executive Director of the Domestic Policy Staff may each designate a staff member to attend meetings of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal vocational education and training programs study; report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee shall conduct a study concerning the progress, effectiveness, and accomplishments of Federal vocational education and training programs, and the need for improved coordination between all federally funded vocational education and training programs. The Committee shall report the findings of such study to the Secretary and the Congress within two years of <date date="1979-10-17">October 17, 1979</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required meetings; establishment of subcommittees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee shall meet at least twice each year. The Secretary may establish subcommittees of the Committee to facilitate coordination in important areas of Federal activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary and the head of each agency represented on the Committee under subsection (c) shall furnish necessary assistance to the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 217</ref>, formerly § 214, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 676</ref>; renumbered § 215, <ref>Pub. L. 101–392, title VI, § 602(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-09-25">Sept. 25, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 840</ref>; renumbered § 217, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 372(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3977</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3425.</num>
<heading> Office of Educational Technology</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department of Education an Office of Educational Technology (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”), to be administered by the Director of Educational Technology. The Director of Educational Technology shall report directly to the Secretary and shall perform such additional functions as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Educational Technology (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”), through the Office, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in support of the overall national technology policy and in consultation with other Federal departments or agencies which the Director determines appropriate, provide leadership to the Nation in the use of technology to promote achievement of the National Education Goals and to increase opportunities for all students to achieve State content and challenging State student performance standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review all programs and training functions administered by the Department and recommend policies in order to promote increased use of technology and technology planning throughout all such programs and functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> review all relevant programs supported by the Department to ensure that such programs are coordinated with and support the national long-range technology plan developed pursuant to section 5862(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002147">1</ref> of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> perform such additional functions as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Officers and employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director is authorized to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Office, subject to the provisions of title 5 (governing appointments in the competitive service), and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title (relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experts and consultants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may obtain the services of experts and consultants in accordance with <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 218</ref>, formerly § 216, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–227, title II, § 233(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-03-31">Mar. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 154</ref>; renumbered § 218, <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1072(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3426.</num>
<heading> Liaison for Proprietary Institutions of Higher Education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be in the Department a Liaison for Proprietary Institutions of Higher Education, who shall be an officer of the Department appointed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall appoint, not later than 6 months after <date date="1998-10-07">October 7, 1998</date>, a Liaison for Proprietary Institutions of Higher Education who shall be a person who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has attained a certificate or degree from a proprietary institution of higher education; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has been employed in a proprietary institution setting for not less than 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Liaison for Proprietary Institutions of Higher Education shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the principal advisor to the Secretary on matters affecting proprietary institutions of higher education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide guidance to programs within the Department that involve functions affecting proprietary institutions of higher education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> work with the Federal Interagency Committee on Education to improve the coordination of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the outreach programs in the numerous Federal departments and agencies that administer education and job training programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> collaborative business and education partnerships; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> education programs located in, and involving, rural areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 219</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title IX, § 961</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3427.</num>
<heading> Coordinator for the outlying areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall designate an office of the Department to coordinate the activities of the Department as they relate to the outlying areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2002-01-08">January 8, 2002</date>, the head of the office designated under subsection (a) shall appoint a coordinator for the outlying areas, who shall be a person with substantial experience in the operation of Federal programs in the outlying areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The coordinator for the outlying areas shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the principal advisor to the Department on Federal matters affecting the outlying areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> evaluate, on a periodic basis, the needs of education programs in the outlying areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assist with the coordination of programs that serve the outlying areas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide guidance to programs within the Department that serve the outlying areas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outlying areas defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “outlying areas” includes Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas Islands, but does not include the freely associated states of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title II, § 220</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1072(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2088</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>TRANSFERS OF AGENCIES AND FUNCTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3441.</num>
<heading> Transfers from Department of Health, Education, and Welfare</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions transferred to Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are transferred to the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all functions of the Assistant Secretary for Education and of the Commissioner of Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, and all functions of the Office of such Assistant Secretary and of the Education Division of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare and of any officer or component of such Office or Division;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the General Education Provisions Act [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1221</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Education Amendments of 1978;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref>7 U.S.C. 321–328</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the National Defense Education Act of 1958;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the International Education Act of 1966;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1400</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> part B of title V of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2929</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the Vocational Education Act of 1963;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> the Career Education Incentive Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> laws relating to the relationship between (i) Gallaudet College, Howard University, the American Printing House for the Blind, and the National Technical Institute for the Deaf, and (ii) the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> the Model Secondary School for the Deaf Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> subpart A[C] of part IV of title III of the Communications Act of 1934 [<ref>47 U.S.C. 395</ref> et seq.] with respect to the telecommunications demonstration program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content><ref>section 550 of title 40</ref> with respect to donations of surplus property for educational purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Education Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare with respect to or being administered by the Office for Civil Rights which relate to functions transferred by this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [<ref>29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.], except that the provisions of this subparagraph shall not be construed to transfer to the Secretary the functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under sections 222 and 1615 of the Social Security Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 422</ref> and 1382d];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all functions with respect to or being administered by the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare through the Commissioner of Rehabilitation Services under the Act of <date date="1936-06-20">June 20, 1936</date>, commonly referred to as the Randolph-Sheppard Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 107</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> all functions of the Commissioner of Rehabilitation and the Director of the National Institute of Handicapped Research of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [<ref>29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> all functions of the Advisory Council on Education Statistics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> all functions of the Federal Education Data Acquisition Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offices, etc., transferred to Department</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are transferred to the Department—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all offices in the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Education or in the Education Division of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all offices in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare established under the provisions of law listed in subparagraphs (A) through (Q) of subsection (a)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> all offices in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare established under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [<ref>29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Advisory Council on Education Statistics;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Federal Education Data Acquisition Council; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any advisory committee of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare giving advice or making recommendations that primarily concern education functions transferred by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative functions transferred to Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are transferred to the Secretary all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Assistant Secretary for Education, or the Commissioner of Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, as the case may be, with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Education Division of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Education, including the National Center for Education Statistics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any advisory committee in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare giving advice and making recommendations principally concerning education functions transferred by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation of functions relating to Project Head Start</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in the provisions of this section or in the provisions of this chapter shall authorize the transfer of functions under part A of title V of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2928</ref> et seq.], relating to Project Head Start, from the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–476, title IX, § 901(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1142</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(e) [title VII, § 709(b)(2)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–233</ref>, 3009–313.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3442.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 720</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3443.</num>
<heading> Transfers from Department of Labor</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions relating to programs for the education of migrant and seasonal farmworkers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of section 601 of this Act, there shall be transferred to the Secretary, at such time on or after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, as the Secretary certifies that there has been established in the Department a single component responsible for the administration and the coordination of programs relating to the education of migrants, all functions of the Secretary of Labor or the Department of Labor relating to such education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to conduct functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to conduct the functions transferred by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 302</ref>, formerly § 303, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 680</ref>; renumbered § 302, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(16)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–421.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3444.</num>
<heading> Transfer of programs from National Science Foundation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Science education; exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There are transferred to the Secretary all programs relating to science education of the National Science Foundation or the Director of the National Science Foundation established prior to <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, pursuant to the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1861</ref> et seq.], except the programs or parts of programs, as determined after review by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Director of the National Science Foundation, which relate to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> scientific career development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the continuing education of scientific personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increasing the participation of women, minorities, and the handicapped in careers in science;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the conduct of basic and applied research and development applied to science learning at all educational levels and the dissemination of results concerning such research and development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> informing the general public of the nature of science and technology and of attendant values and public policy issues.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (1), no mission oriented research functions or programs of the National Science Foundation or any other Federal agency shall be transferred by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary; consultation and advice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to conduct the programs transferred by subsection (a). In conducting such programs the Secretary shall consult, as appropriate, with the Director of the National Science Foundation, and shall establish advisory mechanisms designed to assure that scientists and engineers are fully involved in the development, implementation, and review of science education programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The annual report to be transmitted by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 3486 of this title</ref> shall include a description of arrangements, developed by the Secretary in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation, for coordinated planning and operation of science education programs, including measures to facilitate the implementations of successful innovations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation of certain Foundation authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section is intended to repeal or limit the authority of the National Science Foundation or the Director of the National Science Foundation to initiate and conduct programs under the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 1861</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 303</ref>, formerly § 304, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 680</ref>; renumbered § 303, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3445.</num>
<heading> Transfers from Department of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Secretary all functions of the Attorney General and of the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration with regard to the student loan and grant programs known as the law enforcement education program and the law enforcement intern program authorized by subsections (b), (c), and (f) of section 406 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002148">1</ref> of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 304</ref>, formerly § 305, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 680</ref>; renumbered § 304, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3446.</num>
<heading> Transfers from Department of Housing and Urban Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Secretary all functions relating to college housing loans of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and of the Department of Housing and Urban Development under title IV of the Housing Act of 1950 [<ref>12 U.S.C. 1749</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 305</ref>, formerly § 306, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 681</ref>; renumbered § 305, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3447.</num>
<heading> Effect of transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The transfer of a function or office from an officer or agency to the Secretary or to the Department includes any aspects of such function or office vested in a subordinate of such officer or in a component of such agency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 306</ref>, formerly § 307, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 681</ref>; renumbered § 306, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISIONS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Personnel Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3461.</num>
<heading> Officers and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Secretary and the Department. Except as otherwise provided by law, such officers and employees shall be appointed in accordance with the civil service laws and their compensation fixed in accordance with title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of General Schedule; termination of authority; exemption from limitations on executive positions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> At the request of the Secretary, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, under <ref>section 5108 of title 5</ref>, provide for the establishment in each of the grade levels GS–16, GS–17, and GS–18 of a number of positions in the Department equal to the number of positions in that grade level which were used primarily for the performance of functions and offices transferred under this chapter and which were assigned and filled on the day before <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–279, title IV, § 403(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1985</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Appointments to positions provided for under this subsection may be made without regard to the provisions of <ref>section 3324 of title 5</ref>, if the individual appointed in such position is an individual who is transferred in connection with the transfer of functions and offices under this chapter and, on the day preceding <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, holds a position and has duties comparable to those of the position to which appointed hereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The authority under this subsection with respect to any position shall terminate when the person first appointed to fill such position ceases to hold such position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For purposes of section 414(a)(3)(A) of the Civil Service Reform Act of 1978, an individual appointed under this subsection shall be deemed to occupy the same position as the individual occupied on the day preceding <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–498, title XIV, § 1401(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1597</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senior Executive Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall establish positions within the Senior Executive Service for 15 limited-term appointees. The Secretary shall appoint individuals to such positions as provided by <ref>section 3394 of title 5</ref>. Such positions shall expire on the later of three years after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, or three years after the initial appointment to each position. Positions in effect under this subsection shall be taken into account in applying the limitations on positions prescribed under section 3134(e) and section 5108 of such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian preference laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prevent the application of any Indian preference law in effect on the day before <date date="1979-10-17">October 17, 1979</date>, to any function or office transferred by this chapter and subject to any such law on the day before <date date="1979-10-17">October 17, 1979</date>. Any function or office transferred by this chapter and subject to any such law shall continue to be subject to any such law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 681</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–498, title XIV, § 1401(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–279, title IV, § 403(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3462.</num>
<heading> Experts and consultants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may as provided in appropriation Acts obtain the services of experts and consultants in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> and may compensate such experts and consultants at rates not to exceed the daily rate prescribed for GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may use not more than 1 percent of the funds appropriated for any education program that awards such funds on a competitive basis to pay the expenses and fees of non-Federal experts necessary to review applications and proposals for such funds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of paragraph (1) shall not apply to any education program under which funds are authorized to be appropriated to pay the fees and expenses of non-Federal experts to review applications and proposals for such funds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–227, title IX, § 981</ref>, <date date="1994-03-31">Mar. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3463.</num>
<heading> Personnel reduction and annual limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Work-years limitation; allocations; adjustments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, there shall be included in each appropriation Act containing appropriations for the administration of the Department for any fiscal year beginning after <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date> (other than an appropriation Act containing only supplemental appropriations for the Department), an annual limitation on the total number of work-years for the personnel of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the allocation of the work-years available under paragraph (1) among the organizational units and components of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the President transmits any reorganization plan under chapter 9 of title 5 which would result in the transfer of functions or offices to the Secretary or the Department, the message transmitting the plan shall include any adjustments which may be necessary in a work-year limitation established under paragraph (1) to reflect changes in the work-years required as a result of such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Full-time equivalent personnel reductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the end of the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, the number of full-time equivalent personnel positions available for performing functions transferred to the Secretary or the Department by this chapter shall be reduced by 500.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel computations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Computations required to be made for purposes of this section shall be made on the basis of all personnel employed by the Department, including experts and consultants employed under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> and all other part-time and full-time personnel employed to perform functions of the Secretary or the Department, except personnel employed under special programs for students and disadvantaged youth (including temporary summer employment).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, by rule, establish a method for computing work-years for personnel of the Department as described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on effects of reorganization on employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, as soon as practicable, but not later than one year after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, prepare and transmit to the Congress a report on the effects on employees of the reorganization under this chapter, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an identification of any position within the Department or elsewhere in the executive branch, which it considers unnecessary due to consolidation of functions under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement of the number of employees entitled to pay savings by reason of the organization under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a statement of the number of employees who are voluntarily or involuntarily separated by reason of such reorganization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an estimate of the personnel costs associated with such reorganization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the effects of such reorganization on labor management relations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> such legislative and administrative recommendations for improvements in personnel management within the Department as the Director considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1041(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 714</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Administrative Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3471.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Force and effect of actions by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out any function transferred by this chapter, the Secretary, or any officer or employee of the Department, may exercise any authority available by law (including appropriation Acts) with respect to such function to the official or agency from which such function is transferred, and the actions of the Secretary in exercising such authority shall have the same force and effect as when exercised by such official or agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The director of any office continued in the Department the director of which was required, prior to <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, to report to the Commissioner of Education or the Assistant Secretary for Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, shall report to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to delegate reporting requirements vested in the Secretary by paragraph (1) to any officer or employee of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 683</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3472.</num>
<heading> Delegation of functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the Secretary may delegate any function to such officers and employees of the Department as the Secretary may designate, and may authorize such successive redelegations of such functions within the Department as may be necessary or appropriate. No delegation of functions by the Secretary under this section or under any other provision of this chapter shall relieve the Secretary of responsibility for the administration of such functions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 684</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3473.</num>
<heading> Reorganization of Department</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization; limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized, subject to the requirements of <ref>section 3412(f) of this title</ref>, to allocate or reallocate functions among the officers of the Department, and to establish, consolidate, alter, or discontinue such organizational entities within the Department as may be necessary or appropriate, but the authority of the Secretary under this subsection does not extend to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any office, bureau, unit, or other entity transferred to the Department and established by statute or any function vested by statute in such an entity or officer of such an entity, except as provided in subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the abolition of organizational entities established by this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the alteration of the delegation of functions to any specific organizational entity required by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alteration, consolidation, or discontinuance of statutory and organizational entities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, consolidate, alter, or discontinue any of the following statutory entities, or reallocate any functions vested by statute in the following statutory entities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Office of English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement for Limited English Proficient Students;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Teacher Corps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Community College Unit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the National Center for Education Statistics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the National Institute of Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Office of Environmental Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Office of Consumers’ Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Office of Indian Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Office of Career Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the Office of Non-Public Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the bureau for the education and training for the handicapped; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> the administrative units for guidance and counseling programs, the veterans’ cost of instruction program, and the program for the gifted and talented children.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may alter, consolidate, or discontinue any organizational entity continued within the Department and described in paragraph (1) of this subsection or reallocate any function vested by statute in such an entity, upon the expiration of a period of ninety days after the receipt by the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives of notice given by the Secretary containing a full and complete statement of the action proposed to be taken pursuant to this subsection and the facts and circumstances relied upon in support of such proposed action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 684</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–496, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1980-12-04">Dec. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(e) [title VII, § 709(c)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–233</ref>, 3009–313; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1072(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2089</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3474.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to prescribe such rules and regulations as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate to administer and manage the functions of the Secretary or the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 685</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3930</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3475.</num>
<heading> Contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, the Secretary is authorized to make, enter into, and perform such contracts, grants, leases, cooperative agreements, or other similar transactions with Federal or other public agencies (including State and local governments) and private organizations and persons, and to make such payments, by way of advance or reimbursement, as the Secretary may determine necessary or appropriate to carry out functions of the Secretary or the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, no authority to enter into contracts or to make payments under this subchapter shall be effective except to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance under appropriation Acts. This subsection shall not apply with respect to the authority granted under <ref>section 3481 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3476.</num>
<heading> Regional and field offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish, alter, discontinue, or maintain such regional or other field offices as the Secretary may find necessary or appropriate to perform functions of the Secretary or the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 416</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3477.</num>
<heading> Acquisition and maintenance of property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized properties; establishment of necessary facilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to acquire (by purchase, lease, condemnation, or otherwise), construct, improve, repair, operate, and maintain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> schools and related facilities (but only to the extent that operation of schools and related facilities by the Department is authorized by this chapter);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> laboratories;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> research and testing sites and facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> quarters and related accommodations for employees and dependents of employees of the Department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> personal property (including patents), or any interest therein,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">as may be necessary; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide by contract or otherwise for the establishment of eating facilities and other necessary facilities for the health and welfare of employees of the Department at its installations, and purchase and maintain equipment therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Day care center facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority available to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under <ref>section 2564 of this title</ref>, shall also be available to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special purpose facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority granted by subsection (a) of this section shall be available only with respect to facilities of a special purpose nature that cannot readily be reassigned from similar Federal activities and are not otherwise available for assignment to the Department by the Administrator of General Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 417</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3478.</num>
<heading> Facilities at remote locations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized services, supplies and facilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to provide, construct, or maintain for employees and their dependents stationed at remote locations as necessary and when not otherwise available at such remote locations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> emergency medical services and supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> food and other subsistence supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> dining facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> audiovisual equipment, accessories, and supplies for recreation and training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> reimbursement for food, clothing, medicine, and other supplies furnished by such employees in emergencies for the temporary relief of distressed persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> living and working quarters and facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> transportation for dependents of employees of the Department to the nearest appropriate educational facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The furnishing of medical treatment under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) and the furnishing of services and supplies under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (a) shall be at prices reflecting reasonable value as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriation credits and refunds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Proceeds from reimbursements under this section may be credited to the appropriation of funds that bear or will bear all or part of the cost of such work or services or used to refund excess sums when necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 418</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3479.</num>
<heading> Use of facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal, State, local and foreign government facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With their consent, the Secretary may, with or without reimbursement, use the research, equipment, services, and facilities of any agency or instrumentality of the United States, of any State or political subdivision thereof, or of any foreign government, in carrying out any function of the Secretary or the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public and private permittees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to permit public and private agencies, corporations, associations, organizations, or individuals to use any real property, or any facilities, structures, or other improvements thereon, under the custody and control of the Secretary for Department purposes. The Secretary shall permit the use of such property, facilities, structures, or improvements under such terms and rates and for such period as may be in the public interest, except that the periods of such uses may not exceed five years. The Secretary may require permittees under this section to recondition and maintain, at their own expense, the real property, facilities, structures, and improvements used by such permittees to a standard satisfactory to the Secretary. This subsection shall not apply to excess property as defined in <ref>section 102(3) of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriation credits and refunds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Proceeds from reimbursements under this section may be credited to the appropriation of funds that bear or will bear all or part of the cost of such equipment or facilities provided or to refund excess sums when necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interests in real property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any interest in real property acquired pursuant to this chapter shall be acquired in the name of the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 419</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 720</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3480.</num>
<heading> Copyrights and patents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to acquire any of the following described rights if the property acquired thereby is for use by or for, or useful to, the Department:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> copyrights, patents, and applications for patents, designs, processes, and manufacturing data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> licenses under copyrights, patents, and applications for patents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> releases, before suit is brought, for past infringement of patents or copyrights.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 420</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 687</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3481.</num>
<heading> Gifts and bequests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to accept, hold, administer, and utilize gifts, bequests and devises of property, both real and personal, and to accept donations of services, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Department. Gifts, bequests, and devises of money and proceeds from sales of other property received as gifts, bequests, or devises shall be deposited in the Treasury and shall be available for disbursement upon the order of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3930</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3482.</num>
<heading> Technical advice</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized, upon request, to provide advice, counsel, and technical assistance to applicants or potential applicants for grants and contracts and other interested persons with respect to any functions of the Secretary or the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consolidation of applications for grants and contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may permit the consolidation of applications for grants or contracts with respect to two or more functions of the Secretary or the Department, but such consolidation shall not alter the statutory criteria for approval of applications for funding with respect to such functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 422</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 687</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3483.</num>
<heading> Working capital fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; administrative services included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, is authorized to establish for the Department a working capital fund, to be available without fiscal year limitation, for expenses necessary for the maintenance and operation of such common administrative services as the Secretary shall find to be desirable in the interests of economy and efficiency, including such services as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a central supply service for stationery and other supplies and equipment for which adequate stocks may be maintained to meet in whole or in part the requirements of the Department and its components;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> central messenger, mail, telephone, and other communications services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> office space, central services for document reproduction, and for graphics and visual aids; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a central library service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capital; reimbursement of funds; credit; miscellaneous receipts; transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The capital of the fund shall consist of any appropriations made for the purpose of providing working capital and the fair and reasonable value of such stocks of supplies, equipment, and other assets and inventories on order as the Secretary may transfer to the fund, less the related liabilities and unpaid obligations. Such funds shall be reimbursed in advance from available funds of agencies and offices in the Department, or from other sources, for supplies and services at rates that will approximate the expense of operation, including the accrual of annual leave and the depreciation of equipment. The fund shall also be credited with receipts from sale or exchange of property and receipts in payment for loss or damage to property owned by the fund. There shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts any surplus of the fund (all assets, liabilities, and prior losses considered) above the amounts transferred or appropriated to establish and maintain such fund. There shall be transferred to the fund the stocks of supplies, equipment, other assets, liabilities, and unpaid obligations relating to the services which the Secretary determines, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, will be performed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 423</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 687</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3483a.</num>
<heading> Department of Education Nonrecurring Expenses Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Department of Education Nonrecurring Expenses Fund” (the Fund): <i>Provided</i>, That unobligated balances of expired discretionary funds appropriated for this or any succeeding fiscal year from the General Fund of the Treasury to the Department of Education by this or any other Act may be transferred (not later than the end of the fifth fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such funds are available for the purposes for which appropriated) into the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available until expended, and in addition to such other funds as may be available for such purposes, for information and business technology system modernization and facilities infrastructure improvements necessary for the operation of the Department, subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts in the Fund may be obligated only after the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate are notified at least 30 days in advance of the specific information and business technology system modernization project or facility infrastructure improvement obligations planned for such amounts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. H, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3484.</num>
<heading> Funds transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, when authorized in an appropriation Act in any fiscal year, transfer funds from one appropriation to another within the Department, except that no appropriation for any fiscal year shall be either increased or decreased pursuant to this section by more than 5 percent and no such transfer shall result in increasing any such appropriation above the amount authorized to be appropriated therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 424</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3485.</num>
<heading> Seal of Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall cause a seal of office to be made for the Department of such design as the Secretary shall approve. Judicial notice shall be taken of such seal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 425</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3486.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after the close of each fiscal year, make a single, comprehensive report to the President for transmission to the Congress on the activities of the Department during such fiscal year. The report shall include a statement of goals, priorities, and plans for the Department together with an assessment of the progress made toward—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the attainment of such goals, priorities, and plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the more effective and efficient management of the Department and the coordination of its functions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the reduction of excessive or burdensome regulation and of unnecessary duplication and fragmentation in Federal education programs,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">accompanied where necessary by recommendations for proposed legislation for the achievement of such objectives.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estimate on non-Federal personnel employed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall also include an estimate of the extent of the non-Federal personnel employed pursuant to contracts entered into by the Department under <ref>section 3475 of this title</ref> or under any other authority (including any subcontract thereunder), the number of such contracts and subcontracts pursuant to which non-Federal personnel are employed, and the total cost of those contracts and subcontracts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 426</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3487.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3488.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to any limitation on appropriations applicable with respect to any function or office transferred to the Secretary or the Department, there are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 1980 and each succeeding fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter and to enable the Secretary to administer and manage the Department. Funds appropriated in accordance with this section shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 427</ref>, formerly § 428, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 689</ref>; renumbered § 427, <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3489.</num>
<heading> General extension of authorizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the limitations contained in subtitle A of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal years 1982, 1983, and 1984 such sums as may be necessary to carry out each of the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1950-09-30">September 30, 1950</date> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002149">1</ref> (Public Law 874, 81st Congress);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Act of <date date="1950-09-23">September 23, 1950</date> <sup>1</sup> (Public Law 815, 81st Congress);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the General Education Provisions Act [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1221</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Indian Education Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> titles XI [<ref>25 U.S.C. 2000</ref> et seq.], XIV [<ref>20 U.S.C. 921</ref> et seq.], and XV of the Education Amendments of 1978 and part H of title XIII of the Education Amendments of 1980;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Adult Education Act; <sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> section 342 of the Education Amendments of 1976 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 2532</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Asbestos School Hazards Detection and Control Act [<ref>20 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Joint Resolution of <date date="1972-10-19">October 19, 1972</date> (<ref>86 Stat. 907</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Vocational Education Act of 1963; <sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> title IV of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000c</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the Navajo Community College Act and the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 [<ref>25 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> part C of title IX of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965,<sup>1</sup> relating to Women’s Educational Equity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title V, § 528</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–211, § 20</ref>, <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1418</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(e) [title VII, § 709(a)(2)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–233</ref>, 3009–312; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title IX, § 901(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1828</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–315, title IX, § 941(k)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3490.</num>
<heading> Potential financial interests or impaired objectivity of covered individuals or entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of integrity and ethical values within Department of Education</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 60 days after <date date="2007-12-26">December 26, 2007</date>, the Secretary of Education shall implement procedures—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assess whether a covered individual or entity has a potential financial interest in, or impaired objectivity towards, a product or service purchased with, or guaranteed or insured by, funds administered by the Department of Education or a contracted entity of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to disclose the existence of any such potential financial interest or impaired objectivity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by Inspector General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Within 60 days after the implementation of the procedures described in subsection (a), the Inspector General of the Department of Education shall report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate on the adequacy of such procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Within 1 year, the Inspector General shall conduct at least 1 review to ensure that such procedures are properly implemented and are effective to uncover and disclose the existence of potential financial interests or impaired objectivity described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Inspector General shall report to such Committees any recommendations for modifications to such procedures that the Inspector General determines are necessary to uncover and disclose the existence of such potential financial interests or impaired objectivity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “covered individual or entity” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an officer or professional employee of the Department of Education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a contractor or subcontractor of the Department, or an individual hired by the contracted entity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a member of a peer review panel of the Department; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a consultant or advisor to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. G, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2198</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>TRANSITIONAL, SAVINGS, AND CONFORMING PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3501.</num>
<heading> Transfer and allocation of appropriations and personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel and appropriations in connection with functions and offices transferred by this chapter; use of unexpended funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balance of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with the functions and offices, or portions thereof transferred by this chapter, subject to <ref>section 1531 of title 31</ref>, shall be transferred to the Secretary for appropriate allocation. Unexpended funds transferred pursuant to this subsection shall be used only for the purposes for which the funds were originally authorized and appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Positions specified to carry out functions or offices transferred by this chapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Positions expressly specified by statute or reorganization plan to carry out functions or offices transferred by this chapter, personnel occupying those positions on the effective date of this chapter, and personnel authorized to receive compensation in such positions at the rate prescribed for offices and positions at level IV or V of the Executive Schedule (<ref>5 U.S.C. 5315–531</ref>6) on <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, shall be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 3503 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 689</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3502.</num>
<heading> Effect on personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-separation or non-reduction in grade or compensation of full-time personnel and part-time personnel holding permanent positions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the transfer pursuant to this subchapter of full-time personnel (except special Government employees) and part-time personnel holding permanent positions shall not cause any such employee to be separated or reduced in grade or compensation for one year after the date of transfer to the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Positions compensated in accordance with Executive Schedule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who, on the day preceding <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, held a position compensated in accordance with the Executive Schedule prescribed in chapter 53 of title 5 and who, without a break in service, is appointed in the Department to a position having duties comparable to the duties performed immediately preceding such appointment shall continue to be compensated in such new position at not less than the rate provided for such previous position, for the duration of the service of such person in such new position.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3503.</num>
<heading> Agency terminations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific terminations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, the following entities shall terminate:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Education Division of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, including the Office of Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Bureau of Occupational and Adult Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Positions authorized to be compensated at rate prescribed for level IV or V of the Executive Schedule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each position which was expressly authorized by law, or the incumbent of which was authorized to receive compensation at the rate prescribed for level IV or V of the Executive Schedule (<ref>5 U.S.C. 5315–531</ref>6), in an office terminated pursuant to this chapter shall also terminate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 720</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3504.</num>
<heading> Incidental transfers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of Director of Office of Management and Budget; termination of affairs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, at such time or times as the Director shall provide, is authorized and directed to make such determinations as may be necessary with regard to the functions, offices, or portions thereof transferred by this chapter, and to make such additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions, offices, or portions thereof, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter. The Director shall provide for the termination of the affairs of all entities terminated by this chapter and for such further measures and dispositions as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of positions within Senior Executive Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget is authorized, at such time as the Director of the Office of Management and Budget provides, to make such determinations as may be necessary with regard to the transfer of positions within the Senior Executive Service in connection with functions and offices transferred by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3505.</num>
<heading> Savings provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orders, determinations, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses, and privileges—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, any Federal department or agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of functions which are transferred under this chapter to the Secretary or the Department, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which are in effect on <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with the law by the President, the Secretary, or other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proceedings and applications; transfer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The provisions of this chapter shall not affect any proceedings, including notices of proposed rulemaking, or any application for any license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending on <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, before any department, agency, commission, or component thereof, functions of which are transferred by this chapter; but such proceedings and applications, to the extent that they relate to functions so transferred, shall be continued. Orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this chapter had not been enacted; and orders issued in any such proceedings shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by the Secretary, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this chapter had not been enacted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to promulgate regulations providing for the orderly transfer of proceedings continued under paragraph (1) to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (e)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provisions of this chapter shall not affect suits commenced prior to <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in all such suits, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and effect as if this chapter had not been enacted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liabilities incurred</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against any officer in the official capacity of such individual as an officer of any department or agency, functions of which are transferred by this chapter, shall abate by reason of the enactment of this chapter. No cause of action by or against any department or agency, functions of which are transferred by this chapter, or by or against any officer thereof in the official capacity of such officer shall abate by reason of the enactment of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, before <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, any department or agency, or officer thereof in the official capacity of such officer, is a party to a suit, and under this chapter any function of such department, agency, or officer is transferred to the Secretary or any other official of the Department, then such suit shall be continued with the Secretary or other appropriate official of the Department substituted or added as a party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Orders and actions of the Secretary in the exercise of functions transferred under this chapter shall be subject to judicial review to the same extent and in the same manner as if such orders and actions had been by the agency or office, or part thereof, exercising such functions immediately preceding their transfer. Any statutory requirements relating to notice, hearings, action upon the record, or administrative review that apply to any function transferred by this chapter shall apply to the exercise of such function by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3506.</num>
<heading> Separability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, neither the remainder of this chapter nor the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances shall be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3507.</num>
<heading> Existing references to transferor officials or bodies deemed references to transferee officials or bodies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to any function transferred by this chapter and exercised on or after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, reference in any other Federal law to any department, commission, or agency or any officer or office the functions of which are so transferred shall be deemed to refer to the Secretary, other official, or component of the Department to which this chapter transfers such functions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3508.</num>
<heading> Department of Health and Human Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redesignation of Department of Health, Education, and Welfare</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Health, Education, and Welfare is hereby redesignated the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare or any other official of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare is hereby redesignated the Secretary or official, as appropriate, of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reference to Department, Secretary, etc., of Health, Education, and Welfare deemed reference to Department, Secretary, etc., of Health and Human Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any reference to the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, or any other official of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare in any law, rule, regulation, certificate, directive, instruction, or other official paper in force on <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, shall be deemed to refer and apply to the Department of Health and Human Services or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, respectively, except to the extent such reference is to a function or office transferred to the Secretary or the Department under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3509.</num>
<heading> Coordination of programs for handicapped</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall identify, assess, coordinate, and eliminate conflict, duplication, and inconsistencies among programs significantly affecting handicapped individuals carried out by or under the Department of Health and Human Services, shall promote efficiency among such programs, and shall seek to coordinate, to the maximum extent feasible, such programs with programs significantly affecting handicapped individuals carried out by or under the Department of Education.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 510</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3510.</num>
<heading> Transitional provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With the consent of the appropriate department or agency head concerned, the Secretary is authorized to utilize the services of such officers, employees, and other personnel of the departments and agencies from which functions or offices have been transferred to the Secretary or the Department, and funds appropriated to such functions or offices for such period of time as may reasonably be needed to facilitate the orderly implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>