<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 45—</num>
<heading>CAREER EDUCATION AND CAREER DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>CAREER EDUCATION AND DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2501.</num>
<heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter to provide Federal assistance to States to enable them to plan for the development of career education and career development programs and activities for individuals of all ages, and to plan for the improvement of existing programs and activities, in the areas of awareness, exploration, planning, and decisionmaking of individuals served with regard to career opportunities and career development throughout the lifetimes of such individuals, through—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> planning for the development of information on the needs for career education and career development for all individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> planning for the promotion of a national dialogue on career education and career development designed to encourage each State and local educational agency to determine and adopt the approach best suited to the needs of the individuals served by each such agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> planning for the assessment of the status of career education and career development programs and practices, including a reassessment of the stereotyping of career opportunities by race or by sex;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> planning for the demonstration of the best of the current career education and career development programs and practices by planning to develop and test exemplary programs and practices using various theories, concepts, and approaches with respect to career education and through planning for a nationwide system of regional career education centers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> planning for the training and retraining of persons for conducting career education and career development programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> developing State and local plans for implementing programs designed to ensure that every person has the opportunity to gain the knowledge and skills necessary for gainful or maximum employment and for full participation in our society according to his or her ability.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 331</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2502.</num>
<heading> Funding requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of this subchapter $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1978. The provisions of section 1226a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002144">1</ref> of this title shall not apply to the authorization made by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of amounts appropriated; allotments to States, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> From the sums appropriated under this subchapter, the Secretary of Education shall reserve an amount not to exceed $2,000,000, for the purpose of carrying out <ref>section 2505 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> From the remainder of the sums appropriated under this subchapter, the Secretary of Education shall reserve such amount, not to exceed 1 per centum thereof, as he may determine necessary and shall allot such amount among the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, according to their relative need for assistance under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Of the remainder of the sums appropriated, the Secretary of Education shall allot to each State $100,000, and of the remainder of the sums appropriated the Secretary of Education shall allot to each State an amount which bears the same ratio to such sums for such year as the population of the State bears to the population of all States, for purposes of carrying out <ref>section 2501 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal share of funds allotted to States under this subchapter shall not exceed 80 per centum of the total cost of the planning undertaken pursuant to this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 332</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–207, § 16</ref>, <date date="1977-12-13">Dec. 13, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2503.</num>
<heading> Administration by Office of Career Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this subchapter shall be carried out by the Secretary of Education through the Office of Career Education established pursuant to <ref>section 2612a(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 333</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2504.</num>
<heading> Prerequisites for State participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any State desiring to receive the amount for which it is eligible for any fiscal year pursuant to this subchapter shall agree to submit to the Secretary of Education by <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>, a report on any planning undertaken pursuant to this subchapter. Such report shall be in such form as the State may desire, and may include planning proposals for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> extending career education and career development programs and services to all individuals in the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> extending the concept of the education process beyond the school into the area of employment and community affairs, and relating the subject matter curriculums of schools to the needs of individuals to function in society;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the implementation of new concepts in career education and career development and for the replication of concepts which have demonstrated success;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the development of training programs, including inservice training programs, for teachers, counselors, other educators, and administrators;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> fostering cooperative arrangements with such community groups and agencies as the public employment services, vocational rehabilitation service, community mental health agencies, education opportunity centers, and other community resources concerned with vocational development guidance and counseling, in order to avoid unnecessary duplication in the provision of services in the community or area to be served; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> inventories of State, local, and private resources available for the development of career education and career development programs and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 334</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2505.</num>
<heading> Grants or contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information gathering; analysis of career trends and options; publication of periodic reports and reference works; conduct of seminars, workshops, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Education shall provide, either directly or by grant or contract, for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the gathering, cataloging, storing, analyzing, and disseminating information related to the availability of, and preparation for, careers in the United States, including information concerning current career options, future career trends, and career education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the ongoing analysis of career trends and options in the United States, using information from both the public and private sectors, including such sources as the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the Department of Commerce, the United States International Trade Commission, economic analysts, labor unions, and private industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the publication of periodic reports and reference works using analysis prepared pursuant to this section and containing exemplary materials from the career education field, including research findings, results, and techniques from successful projects and programs, and highlights of ongoing analyses of career trends in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the conduct of seminars, workshops, and career information sessions for the purpose of disseminating to teachers, guidance counselors, other career educators, administrators, other education personnel, and the general public information compiled and analyzed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, and to the extent practicable, the Secretary of Education shall (1) make use of existing offices, centers, clearinghouses, and research capabilities, (2) coordinate among the offices, centers, clearinghouses, and research capabilities in carrying out his career information responsibilities, and (3) use the career information capabilities of the Department of Education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 335</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(2), title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 678, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2506.</num>
<heading> Functions of National Advisory Council for Career Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Advisory Council for Career Education established pursuant to <ref>section 2612a(g) of this title</ref> shall, in addition to its duties under that section, advise the Secretary of Education with respect to the implementation of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 336</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>GUIDANCE AND COUNSELING ACTIVITIES AND PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2531.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> guidance and counseling activities are an essential component to assure success in achieving the goals of many education programs: <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002145">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> lack of coordination among guidance and counseling activities supported jointly or separately by Federal programs and by State and local programs has resulted in an underutilization of resources available for such activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increased and improved preparation of education professionals is needed in guidance and counseling, including administration of guidance and counseling programs at the State and local levels, with special emphasis on inservice training which takes educational professionals into the workplaces of business and industry, the professions, and other occupational pursuits, and that increased and improved use of individuals employed in such pursuits are needed for effective guidance and counseling programs, including (A) bringing persons employed in such pursuits into schools, and (B) bringing students into such workplaces for observation of, and participation in, such pursuits, in order to acquaint the students with the nature of the work.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 341</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2532.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal years 1978 through 1983</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $20,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1978 through 1983, to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations; allotments to States, etc.; reallotments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 for fiscal year 1977, for purposes of grants to States made by the Secretary of Education for programs, projects, and leadership activities designed to expand and strengthen counseling and guidance services in elementary and secondary schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No sums are authorized to be appropriated under section 401(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002146">1</ref> of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 for fiscal year 1977, for the purpose of making grants under part B (Libraries and Learning Resources) of title IV of such Act, for such fiscal year which represent the amount authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Education shall allot the amounts appropriated under this subsection among Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands according to their respective needs for assistance under this subsection. In addition, he shall allot from such amounts to (i) the Secretary of the Interior the amounts necessary for the programs, projects, and activities authorized by this subsection for children and teachers in elementary and secondary schools operated for Indian children by the Department of the Interior; and (ii) the Secretary of Defense the amounts necessary for the programs, projects, and activities authorized by this subsection for children and teachers in the overseas dependents schools of the Department of Defense. The terms upon which payment for such purposes shall be made to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Defense shall be determined pursuant to such criteria as the Secretary of Education determines will best carry out the purposes of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> From the amounts appropriated to carry out this subsection, the Secretary of Education shall allot to each State from such amounts an amount which bears the same ratio to such amounts as the number of children aged five to seventeen, inclusive, in the State bears to the number of such children in all the States. For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term “State” shall not include Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. The number of children aged five to seventeen, inclusive, in a State and in all the States shall be determined by the Secretary of Education on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data available to him.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The amount of any State’s allotment under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B) to carry out this subsection which the Secretary of Education determines will not be required to carry out this subsection shall be available for reallotment from time to time, on such dates as the Secretary of Education may fix, to other States in proportion to the original allotments to such States under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B) but with such proportionate amount for any of such other States being reduced to the extent it exceeds the sum the Secretary of Education estimates such State needs and will be able to use. The total of such reductions shall be similarly reallotted among the States whose proportionate amounts were not so reduced. Any amounts reallotted to a State under this subparagraph from funds appropriated under this subsection shall be deemed a part of its allotment under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 342</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–561, title XIII, § 1351</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2533.</num>
<heading> Administration by unit in Department of Education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Education shall establish or designate an administrative unit within the Department of Education for purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carrying out provisions of this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> providing information regarding guidance and counseling as a profession, guidance and counseling activities of the Federal Government, and, to the extent practicable, activities of State and local programs of guidance and counseling; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> advising the Secretary of Education on coordinating guidance and counseling activities included in all programs which he is authorized to carry out, and, to the extent he deems practicable, how such activities may be coordinated with other programs of the Federal Government and State and local guidance and counseling programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation of amount for implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education may reserve an amount not to exceed 5 per centum of the sums appropriated under this subchapter to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–43, § 1(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1977-06-15">June 15, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(2), title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 678, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2534.</num>
<heading> Contracts and grants to States, educational agencies, etc.</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education is authorized, on a competitive basis, to enter into contracts and make grants to State and local educational agencies, to institutions of higher education, and to private nonprofit organizations to assist them in conducting institutes, work shops, and seminars designed to improve the professional guidance qualifications of teachers and counselors in State and local educational agencies and nonpublic elementary and secondary school systems, including opportunities for teachers and guidance counselors in such agencies and systems to obtain experience in business and industry, the professions, and other occupational pursuits, and including, for the purpose of such improvement, such programs, services, or activities which bring individuals with experience in such pursuits into schools as counselors or advisors for students, and which bring students into the workplaces of such pursuits to acquaint students with the nature of the work and to provide training for supervisory and technical personnel in such agencies and systems having responsibilities for guidance and counseling, and to improve supervisory services in the field of guidance and counseling.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of programs of guidance and counseling</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education is authorized to make grants to States to assist them in carrying out programs to coordinate new and existing programs of guidance and counseling in the States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 344</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 2561 to 2563.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2564.</num>
<heading> Departmental day care center facilities; establishment; fees and charges; equipment and operation by appropriated funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services is authorized by contract or otherwise to establish, equip, and operate day care center facilities for the purpose of serving children who are members of households of employees of the Department of Health and Human Services. The Secretary is authorized to establish or provide for the establishment of appropriate fees and charges to be chargeable against the Department employees or others who are beneficiaries of services provided by such facilities to pay for the cost of their operation and to accept money, equipment, or other property donated for use in connection with the facilities. No appropriated funds may be used for the equipping or operation of any centers provided under this authority. The prohibition made by the preceding sentence shall not preclude the provision of appropriate donated space nor the purchase of the initial equipment for the centers, except that the cost of such equipment shall be reimbursed over the expected life of such equipment, not to exceed 10 years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title V, § 524</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2565.</num>
<heading> Wayne Morse Chair of Law and Politics</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Education (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to provide financial assistance in accordance with the provisions of this section to assist in establishing the Wayne Morse Chair of Law and Politics at the University of Oregon, of Eugene, Oregon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal share; application for financial assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the Federal share of the cost of establishing the Wayne Morse Chair of Law and Politics shall not exceed 50 per centum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No financial assistance under this section may be made except upon an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information, as the Secretary may reasonably require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums, not to exceed $500,000, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Funds appropriated pursuant to this section shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–482, title V, § 525</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2566.</num>
<heading> Hubert H. Humphrey Institute of Public Affairs; grants for development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In recognition of the public service of Senator Hubert H. Humphrey, the Secretary of Education (hereafter in sections 2566 to 2569 of this title referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to make grants in accordance with the provisions of sections 2566 to 2569 of this title to assist in the development of the Hubert H. Humphrey Institute of Public Affairs, located at the University of Minnesota, Minneapolis-Saint Paul.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–270, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-04-27">Apr. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2567.</num>
<heading> Everett McKinley Dirksen Congressional Leadership Research Center; grants for development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In recognition of the public service of Senator Everett McKinley Dirksen, the Secretary is authorized to make grants in accordance with the provisions of sections 2566 to 2569 of this title to assist in the development of the Everett McKinley Dirksen Congressional Leadership Research Center, located in Pekin, Illinois.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–270, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-04-27">Apr. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2568.</num>
<heading> Payments to Humphrey Institute and Dirksen Center; procedures applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No payment may be made under sections 2566 to 2569 of this title except upon an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–270, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-04-27">Apr. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2569.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for Humphrey Institute and Dirksen Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount for Institute</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums, not to exceed $5,000,000, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of <ref>section 2566 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount for Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums, not to exceed $2,500,000, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of <ref>section 2567 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated pursuant to sections 2566 to 2569 of this title shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–270, § 4(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1978-04-27">Apr. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>