<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 80—</num>
<heading>STATE FISCAL STABILIZATION FUND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10001.</num>
<heading> Allocations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Outlying areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From the amount appropriated to carry out this chapter, the Secretary of Education shall first allocate up to one-half of 1 percent to the outlying areas on the basis of their respective needs, as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, for activities consistent with this chapter under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and oversight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, in addition, reserve up to $14,000,000 for administration and oversight of this chapter, including for program evaluation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation for additional programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After reserving funds under subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary shall reserve $5,000,000,000 for grants under sections 10006 and 10007 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State allocations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After carrying out subsections (a), (b), and (c), the Secretary shall allocate the remaining funds made available to carry out this chapter to the States as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 61 percent on the basis of their relative population of individuals aged 5 through 24.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 39 percent on the basis of their relative total population.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From funds allocated under subsection (d), the Secretary shall make grants to the Governor of each State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reallocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Governor shall return to the Secretary any funds received under subsection (e) that the Governor does not award as subgrants or otherwise commit within two years of receiving such funds, and the Secretary shall reallocate such funds to the remaining States in accordance with subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14001</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10002.</num>
<heading> State uses of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Education fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each fiscal year, the Governor shall use 81.8 percent of the State’s allocation under <ref>section 10001(d) of this title</ref> for the support of elementary, secondary, and postsecondary education and, as applicable, early childhood education programs and services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restoring State support for education</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Governor shall first use the funds described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> to provide the amount of funds, through the State’s primary elementary and secondary education funding formulae, that is needed—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to restore, in each of fiscal years 2009, 2010, and 2011, the level of State support provided through such formulae to the greater of the fiscal year 2008 or fiscal year 2009 level; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> where applicable, to allow existing State formulae increases to support elementary and secondary education for fiscal years 2010 and 2011 to be implemented and allow funding for phasing in State equity and adequacy adjustments, if such increases were enacted pursuant to State law prior to <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide, in each of fiscal years 2009, 2010, and 2011, the amount of funds to public institutions of higher education in the State that is needed to restore State support for such institutions (excluding tuition and fees paid by students) to the greater of the fiscal year 2008 or fiscal year 2009 level.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Shortfall</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Governor determines that the amount of funds available under paragraph (1) is insufficient to support, in each of fiscal years 2009, 2010, and 2011, public elementary, secondary, and higher education at the levels described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A), the Governor shall allocate those funds between those clauses in proportion to the relative shortfall in State support for the education sectors described in those clauses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fiscal year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “fiscal year” shall have the meaning given such term under State law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subgrants to improve basic programs operated by local educational agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After carrying out paragraph (2), the Governor shall use any funds remaining under paragraph (1) to provide local educational agencies in the State with subgrants based on their relative shares of funding under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311</ref> et seq.) for the most recent year for which data are available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other government services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Governor shall use 18.2 percent of the State’s allocation under <ref>section 10001(d) of this title</ref> for public safety and other government services, which may include assistance for elementary and secondary education and public institutions of higher education, and for modernization, renovation, or repair of public school facilities and institutions of higher education facilities, including modernization, renovation, and repairs that are consistent with a recognized green building rating system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability to all institutions of higher education</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A Governor shall not consider the type or mission of an institution of higher education, and shall consider any institution for funding for modernization, renovation, and repairs within the State that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> qualifies as an institution of higher education, as defined in subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002258">1</ref> 10013(3) of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> continues to be eligible to participate in the programs under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref>20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall allow a local educational agency to engage in school modernization, renovation, or repair that is inconsistent with State law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14002</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. F, title V, § 523(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10003.</num>
<heading> Uses of funds by local educational agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A local educational agency that receives funds under this chapter may use the funds for any activity authorized by the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6301</ref> et seq.) (“ESEA”), the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1400</ref> et seq.) (“IDEA”), the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 9201</ref> et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002259">1</ref> or the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2301</ref> et seq.) (“the Perkins Act”) or for modernization, renovation, or repair of public school facilities, including modernization, renovation, and repairs that are consistent with a recognized green building rating system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A local educational agency may not use funds received under this chapter for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> payment of maintenance costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> stadiums or other facilities primarily used for athletic contests or exhibitions or other events for which admission is charged to the general public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> purchase or upgrade of vehicles; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> improvement of stand-alone facilities whose purpose is not the education of children, including central office administration or operations or logistical support facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall allow a local educational agency to engage in school modernization, renovation, or repair that is inconsistent with State law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14003</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 281</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. F, title V, § 523(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10004.</num>
<heading> Uses of funds by institutions of higher education</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A public institution of higher education that receives funds under this chapter shall use the funds for education and general expenditures, and in such a way as to mitigate the need to raise tuition and fees for in-State students, or for modernization, renovation, or repair of institution of higher education facilities that are primarily used for instruction, research, or student housing, including modernization, renovation, and repairs that are consistent with a recognized green building rating system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An institution of higher education may not use funds received under this chapter to increase its endowment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional prohibition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No funds awarded under this chapter may be used for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the maintenance of systems, equipment, or facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> modernization, renovation, or repair of stadiums or other facilities primarily used for athletic contests or exhibitions or other events for which admission is charged to the general public; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> modernization, renovation, or repair of facilities—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> used for sectarian instruction or religious worship; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in which a substantial portion of the functions of the facilities are subsumed in a religious mission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14004</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10005.</num>
<heading> State applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Governor of a State desiring to receive an allocation under <ref>section 10001(d) of this title</ref> shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In such application, the Governor shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> include the assurances described in subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide baseline data that demonstrates the State’s current status in each of the areas described in such assurances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> describe how the State intends to use its allocation, including whether the State will use such allocation to meet maintenance of effort requirements under the ESEA and IDEA and, in such cases, what amount will be used to meet such requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incentive grant application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Governor of a State seeking a grant under <ref>section 10006 of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> submit an application for consideration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describe the status of the State’s progress in each of the areas described in subsection (d), and the strategies the State is employing to help ensure that students in the subgroups described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v)(II) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002260">1</ref> of the ESEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)(II)</ref>) who have not met the State’s proficiency targets continue making progress toward meeting the State’s student academic achievement standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> describe the achievement and graduation rates (as described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(vi) <sup>1</sup> of the ESEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(vi)</ref>) and as clarified in section 200.19(b)(1) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations) of public elementary and secondary school students in the State, and the strategies the State is employing to help ensure that all subgroups of students identified in section 1111(b)(2) of the ESEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)</ref>) in the State continue making progress toward meeting the State’s student academic achievement standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> describe how the State would use its grant funding to improve student academic achievement in the State, including how it will allocate the funds to give priority to high-need local educational agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> include a plan for evaluating the State’s progress in closing achievement gaps.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assurances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An application under subsection (b) shall include the following assurances:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elementary and secondary education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The State will, in each of fiscal years 2009, 2010, and 2011, maintain State support for elementary and secondary education at least at the level of such support in fiscal year 2006.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The State will, in each of fiscal years 2009, 2010, and 2011, maintain State support for public institutions of higher education (not including support for capital projects or for research and development or tuition and fees paid by students) at least at the level of such support in fiscal year 2006.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Achieving equity in teacher distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State will take actions to improve teacher effectiveness and comply with section 1111(b)(8)(C) <sup>1</sup> of the ESEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(8)(C)</ref>) in order to address inequities in the distribution of highly qualified teachers between high- and low-poverty schools, and to ensure that low-income and minority children are not taught at higher rates than other children by inexperienced, unqualified, or out-of-field teachers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Improving collection and use of data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State will establish a longitudinal data system that includes the elements described in <ref>section 9871(e)(2)(D) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards and assessments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The State—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will enhance the quality of the academic assessments it administers pursuant to section 1111(b)(3) of the ESEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(3)</ref>) through activities such as those described in section 6112(a) <sup>1</sup> of such Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 7301a(a)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will comply with the requirements of paragraphs (3)(C)(ix) and (6) of section 1111(b) <sup>1</sup> of the ESEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311(b)</ref>) and section 612(a)(16) of the IDEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1412(a)(16)</ref>) related to the inclusion of children with disabilities and limited English proficient students in State assessments, the development of valid and reliable assessments for those students, and the provision of accommodations that enable their participation in State assessments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> will take steps to improve State academic content standards and student academic achievement standards consistent with <ref>section 9871(e)(1)(A)(ii) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supporting struggling schools</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State will ensure compliance with the requirements of section 1116(b)(7)(C)(iv) <sup>1</sup> and section 1116(b)(8)(B) <sup>1</sup> of the ESEA with respect to schools identified under such sections.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Improving early childhood care and education</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The State will take actions to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> increase the number and percentage of low-income and disadvantaged children in each age group of infants, toddlers, and pre-schoolers who are enrolled in high-quality early learning programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> design and implement an integrated system of high-quality early learning programs and services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> ensure that any use of assessments conforms with the recommendations of the National Research Council’s reports on early childhood.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14005</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. F, title V, § 523(d)</ref>–(f), <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–10, div. B, title VIII, § 1832(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-04-15">Apr. 15, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 164</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10006.</num>
<heading> State incentive grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reservation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">From the total amount reserved under <ref>section 10001(c) of this title</ref> that is not used for <ref>section 10007 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may reserve up to 1 percent for technical assistance to States to assist them in meeting the objectives of paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) of <ref>section 10005(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remainder</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the remaining funds, the Secretary shall, in fiscal year 2010, make grants to States that have made significant progress in meeting the objectives of paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) of <ref>section 10005(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis for grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall determine which States receive grants under this section, and the amount of those grants, on the basis of information provided in State applications under <ref>section 10005 of this title</ref> and such other criteria as the Secretary determines appropriate, which may include a State’s need for assistance to help meet the objective of paragraphs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002261">1</ref> (2), (3), (4), (5), or (6) of <ref>section 10005(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subgrants to local educational agencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State receiving a grant under this section shall use at least 50 percent of the grant to provide local educational agencies in the State with subgrants based on their relative shares of funding under part A of title I of the ESEA (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311</ref> et seq.) for the most recent year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) does not apply to grants made by the Secretary to consortia of States to develop academic assessments that are aligned with academic standards, or to a State or States for improving early childhood care and education except that such a State may use its grant funds to make subgrants to public or private agencies and organizations for activities consistent with the purposes of the grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14006</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–117, div. D, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–10, div. B, title VIII, § 1832(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-04-15">Apr. 15, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. F, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10007.</num>
<heading> Innovation Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For the purposes of this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a local educational agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a partnership between a nonprofit organization and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one or more local educational agencies; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a consortium of schools.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program established</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">From the total amount reserved under <ref>section 10001(c) of this title</ref>, the Secretary may reserve up to $650,000,000 to establish an Innovation Fund, which shall consist of academic achievement awards that recognize eligible entities that meet the requirements described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of awards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall make awards to eligible entities in order to identify, document, and bring to scale innovative best practices based on demonstrated success, to allow such eligible entities to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expand their work and serve as models for best practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> work in partnership with the private sector and the philanthropic community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for such an award, an eligible entity shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have significantly closed the achievement gaps between groups of students described in section 6311(b)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002262">1</ref> of this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have demonstrated success in significantly increasing student academic achievement for all groups of students described in such section;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have made significant improvement in other areas, such as graduation rates or increased recruitment and placement of high-quality teachers and school leaders, as demonstrated with meaningful data; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> demonstrate that it has established one or more partnerships with the private sector, which may include philanthropic organizations, and that the private sector will provide matching funds in order to help bring results to scale.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of an eligible entity that includes a nonprofit organization, the eligible entity shall be considered to have met the eligibility requirements of paragraphs (1)(A) or (1)(B) and (2) of subsection (b) if the nonprofit organization has a record of significantly improving student achievement, attainment, or retention and shall be considered to have met the requirements of subsection (b)(3) if it demonstrates that it will meet the requirement relating to private-sector matching.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subgrants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of an eligible entity that is a partnership described in subsection (a)(1)(B), the partner serving as the fiscal agent may make subgrants to one or more of the other entities in the partnership.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14007</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–117, div. D, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10008.</num>
<heading> State reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each year of the program under this chapter, a State receiving funds under this chapter shall submit a report to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, that describes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the uses of funds provided under this chapter within the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> how the State distributed the funds it received under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of jobs that the Governor estimates were saved or created with funds the State received under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> tax increases that the Governor estimates were averted because of the availability of funds from this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the State’s progress in reducing inequities in the distribution of highly qualified teachers, in implementing a State longitudinal data system, and in developing and implementing valid and reliable assessments for limited English proficient students and children with disabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the tuition and fee increases for in-State students imposed by public institutions of higher education in the State during the period of availability of funds under this chapter, and a description of any actions taken by the State to limit those increases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the extent to which public institutions of higher education maintained, increased, or decreased enrollment of in-State students, including students eligible for Pell Grants or other need-based financial assistance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a description of each modernization, renovation and repair project funded, which shall include the amounts awarded and project costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14008</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10009.</num>
<heading> Evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct evaluations of the programs under sections 10006 and 10007 of this title which shall include, but not be limited to, the criteria used for the awards made, the States selected for awards, award amounts, how each State used the award received, and the impact of this funding on the progress made toward closing achievement gaps.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14009</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10010.</num>
<heading> Secretary’s report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and of the Senate, not less than 6 months following the submission of State reports, that evaluates the information provided in the State reports under <ref>section 10008 of this title</ref> and the information required by <ref>section 10005(b)(3) of this title</ref> including State-by-State information.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14010</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10011.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on provision of certain assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No recipient of funds under this chapter shall use such funds to provide financial assistance to students to attend private elementary or secondary schools, unless such funds are used to provide special education and related services to children with disabilities, as authorized by the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1400</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14011</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. F, title V, § 523(g)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10012.</num>
<heading> Fiscal relief</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of relieving fiscal burdens on States and local educational agencies that have experienced a precipitous decline in financial resources, the Secretary of Education may waive or modify any requirement of this chapter relating to maintaining fiscal effort.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A waiver or modification under this section shall be for any of fiscal year 2009, fiscal year 2010, or fiscal year 2011, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall not grant a waiver or modification under this section unless the Secretary determines that the State receiving such waiver or modification will not provide for elementary, secondary, and public higher education, for the fiscal year under consideration, a smaller percentage of the total revenues available to the State than the percentage provided for such purpose in the preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon prior approval from the Secretary, a State or local educational agency that receives funds under this chapter may treat any portion of such funds that is used for elementary, secondary, or postsecondary education as non-Federal funds for the purpose of any requirement to maintain fiscal effort under any other program, including part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.), administered by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent level of effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding (d),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002263">1</ref> the level of effort required by a State or local educational agency for the following fiscal year shall not be reduced.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14012</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. F, title V, § 523(h)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10013.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, as used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “elementary education” and “secondary education” have the meaning given such terms under State law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “high-need local educational agency” means a local educational agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that serves not fewer than 10,000 children from families with incomes below the poverty line; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for which not less than 20 percent of the children served by the agency are from families with incomes below the poverty line;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 1001 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any other term used that is defined in section 7801 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002264">1</ref> of this title shall have the meaning given the term in such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIV, § 14013</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>