<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>PAYMENTS TO MENTALLY INCOMPETENT PERSONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 601.</num>
<heading> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This chapter applies to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> members of a uniformed service who are on active duty (other than for training) or who are on a retired list of that service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> members of the Fleet Reserve or Fleet Marine Corps Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 602.</num>
<heading> Payments: designation of person to receive amounts due</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Active duty pay and allowances, amounts due for accrued or accumulated leave, or retired or retainer pay, that are otherwise payable to a member to whom this chapter applies and who is mentally incapable of managing his affairs, may be paid for that member’s use or benefit to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a legal committee, guardian, or other representative that has been appointed by a court of competent jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an individual to whom the member has granted authority to manage such funds pursuant to a valid and legally executed durable power of attorney; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any person designated by the Secretary concerned, or by any officer to whom he delegates his authority under this section, without the appointment in judicial proceedings of a committee, guardian, or other legal representative.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An individual may not be designated under subsection (a)(3) to receive payments unless a board consisting of at least three qualified medical officers or physicians, one of whom is specially qualified in the treatment of mental disorders, determines that the member is mentally incapable of managing the member’s affairs. Any such board shall be appointed from available medical officers or physicians under his jurisdiction by the head of whichever of the following is providing medical treatment for the member, or by a person designated by that head—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Department of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Department of the Navy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Department of the Air Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Department of Health and Human Services; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the hospitalization or medical care of the member is not provided by the United States, the board shall be appointed by the Secretary of the department having jurisdiction of the member.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A payment made to a person who is authorized to receive payments under this section discharges the obligation of the United States as to the amount paid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A person serving in a legal, medical, fiduciary, or other capacity, may not demand or accept a fee, commission, or other charge for any service performed under this chapter, unless a court of competent jurisdiction orders payment of such fee, commission, or other charge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A person who is designated under subsection (a)(3) to receive payments under this section shall furnish satisfactory assurance that the amounts received by him will be applied to the use and benefit of the incompetent member, and, where the payments may reasonably be expected to be more than $25,000, shall provide a suitable bond to be paid for out of amounts due the incompetent member.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 483</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(17)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1604</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VI, § 645</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 603.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary concerned and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prescribe regulations necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1604</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 604.</num>
<heading> Determination of Secretary final</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The determination as to the person authorized to receive a payment under <ref>section 602 of this title</ref> is final and is not subject to review by an official of the United States or a court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 66</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>