<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>PROHIBITIONS AND PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 801.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VI, § 6001(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3362</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 802.</num>
<heading> Forfeiture of pay during absence from duty due to disease from intemperate use of alcohol or drugs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, on active duty who is absent from the member’s regular duties for a continuous period of more than one day because of disease that is directly caused by and immediately follows the member’s intemperate use of alcoholic liquor or habit-forming drugs is not entitled to pay for the period of that absence. However, a member whose pay is forfeited for more than one month is entitled to $5 for personal expenses for each full month that the member’s pay is forfeited. Determinations of periods and causes of absence under this section shall be made as prescribed by the Secretary concerned, and are final.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 803.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers of the Army, Air Force, or Space Force: forfeiture of pay when dropped from rolls</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A commissioned officer of the Army, the Air Force, or the Space Force who is dropped from the rolls under <ref>section 1161(b) of title 10</ref> for absence without authority for three months forfeits all pay due or to become due.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 486</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(i)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 804.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XI, § 1122(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 463</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 805.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 683(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 665</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>