<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>ALLOTMENTS AND ASSIGNMENTS OF PAY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 701.</num>
<heading> Members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force; contract surgeons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned, a commissioned officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force may transfer or assign the officer’s pay account, when due and payable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A contract surgeon, or contract dental surgeon, of the Army, Navy, or Air Force, on duty in Alaska, Hawaii, the Philippine Islands, or Puerto Rico, may transfer or assign the person’s pay account, when due and payable, under the regulations prescribed under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An enlisted member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force may not assign the member’s pay, and if the member does so, the assignment is void.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force and a contract surgeon of the Army, Navy, or Air Force may make allotments from the pay of the member or surgeon for the purpose of supporting relatives or for any other purpose that the Secretary considers proper. Such allotments may include a maximum of six allotments considered to be discretionary under such regulations. For a member or former member entitled to retired or retainer pay, a maximum of six discretionary allotments authorized during active military service may be continued into retired status, and new discretionary allotments may be authorized so long as the total number of discretionary allotments does not exceed six.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If an allotment made under subsection (d) is paid to the allottee before the disbursing officer receives a notice of discontinuance from the officer required by regulation to furnish the notice, the amount of the allotment shall be credited to the disbursing officer. If an allotment is erroneously paid because the officer required by regulation to so report failed to report the death of the allotter or any other fact that makes the allotment not payable, the amount of the payment not recovered from the allottee shall, if practicable, be collected by the Secretary concerned from the officer who failed to make the report.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 67</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 683(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VI, § 651(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2582</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(h)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 702.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 683(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 665</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 703.</num>
<heading> Allotments: members of Coast Guard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Coast Guard may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, make allotments from their pay and allowances.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 704.</num>
<heading> Allotments: officers of Public Health Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commissioned officers of the Public Health Service who are on active duty may, under regulations prescribed by the President, make allotments from their pay.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 705.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 683(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 665</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 706.</num>
<heading> Allotments: commissioned officers of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Commerce, commissioned officers of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration may make allotments or assignments of their pay.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 49(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(18)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 707.</num>
<heading> Allotments: members of the National Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, may allow a member of the National Guard who is not on active duty to make allotments from his pay under sections 204 and 206 of this title for the payment of premiums under a group life insurance program sponsored by the military department of the State in which such member holds his National Guard membership or by the National Guard association of such State if the State or association concerned has agreed in writing to reimburse the United States for all costs incurred by the United States in providing for such allotments. The amount of such costs and procedures for reimbursements shall be determined by the Secretary of Defense and his determination shall be conclusive. All amounts of reimbursements for such costs received by the United States from a State or an association shall be credited to the appropriations or funds against which charges have been made for such costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The United States is not liable for loss or damage suffered by a person as a result of an error made by an officer or employee of the United States in carrying out the allotment program under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–289, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-24">May 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 172</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(19)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>