<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 19—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1001.</num>
<heading> Regulations relating to pay and allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A Secretary of a military department may not prescribe a regulation under this title or any other law, relating to the pay and allowances of members of an armed force under that department, unless it has been approved under procedures prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Regulations of the Secretary concerned relating to pay and allowances matters, similar to those covered by subsection (a), for members of the Coast Guard, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Public Health Service, shall, as far as practicable, conform to regulations approved under that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Commerce, or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, may obtain from the Comptroller General an advisory opinion with respect to a proposed regulation especially affecting a department under that Secretary’s jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 489</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718</ref>, §§ 49(a)(1), 69, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1121</ref>, 1123; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(22)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1002.</num>
<heading> Additional training or duty without pay: Reserves and members of National Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of the National Guard, or of a reserve component of a uniformed service, may, with his consent, be given additional training or other duty as provided by law, without pay, as may be authorized by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member who performs training or other duty without pay under subsection (a) may, in the discretion of the Secretary concerned, be authorized the travel and transportation allowances prescribed by <ref>section 452 of this title</ref> for travel performed to and from that training or duty, and, during the performance of that training or duty, be furnished with subsistence and quarters in kind or commutation thereof at a rate to be fixed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a military technician (dual status), as described in <ref>section 10216 of title 10</ref>, is performing active duty without pay while on leave from technician employment, as authorized by <ref>section 6323(d) of title 5</ref>, the Secretary concerned may authorize the payment of a per diem allowance to the military technician in lieu of commutation for subsistence and quarters under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not authorize compensation for work or study performed by a member of a reserve component in connection with correspondence courses of an armed force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to a member who is entitled to basic pay under chapter 3 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 489</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 672(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(f)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(h)(7)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1003.</num>
<heading> Assimilation of pay and allowances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chapters 3 and 5 and sections 402 through 403b, 405, 414, 452, and 453 of this title apply equally to persons who are not serving as members of a uniformed service but whose pay or allowances, or both, are assimilated under law or a regulation prescribed under law, to the pay or allowances, or both, of commissioned officers, warrant officers, or enlisted members of any grade, rank, or rating in any uniformed service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 490</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(f)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(h)(8)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1004.</num>
<heading> Computation of pay and allowances for month or part of month</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of a uniformed service who is entitled to pay and allowances under this title for a continuous period of less than one month is entitled to his pay and allowances for each day of that period at the rate of <sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>30</sub> of the monthly amount of his pay and allowances. The thirty-first day of a calendar month may not be excluded from a computation under this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 490</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1005.</num>
<heading> Army, Air Force, and Space Force: prompt payments required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Army, the Air Force, and the Space Force shall be paid at such times that arrears will at no time be more than two months, unless circumstances make further arrears unavoidable.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 490</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(k)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1006.</num>
<heading> Advance payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a member of a uniformed service may be paid in advance—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not more than three months’ pay of such member upon such member’s change of permanent station; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of an allotment made from such member’s pay to a dependent if such member is assigned or scheduled for assignment to sea duty or other duty with a unit or command deployed or to be deployed outside the United States and the allotment is made by such member not more than sixty days before the scheduled date of the assignment of such member to such duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a member of a uniformed service who is on duty at a distant station where the pay and emoluments to which he is entitled cannot be disbursed regularly, may be paid in advance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, an advance of pay to a member of a uniformed service who is on duty outside the United States, or other place designated by the Secretary of Defense, of not more than two months’ basic pay may be made to a member if the member or the dependents of the member are ordered evacuated by competent authority. An advance of pay under this subsection is not subject to the conditions under which advances of pay may be made under subsection (a) or (b). An advance may be made on the basis of the evacuation of a member’s dependents only if all dependents of members of the uniformed services are ordered evacuated from the place where the member’s dependents are located. In the case of a member with dependents, the payment may be made directly to dependents previously designated by the member. The Secretary concerned or his designee may waive any right of recovery of not more than one month’s basic pay advanced under this subsection if he finds that recovery of the advance would be against equity and good conscience or against the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If a person to whom an advance of pay is made under subsection (a), (b), or (c) dies or is separated from his uniformed service, before liquidation of that advance, the amount remaining unliquidated at the time of his death or separation shall be credited to the account of the disbursing officer concerned. However, the unliquidated amount remains a debt of that person or his estate to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As far as practicable, regulations for the administration of subsections (a)–(d) shall be uniform for all of the uniformed services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an obligation for an advance of pay made pursuant to this section shall be recorded as an obligation only in the fiscal year in which the entitlement of the member to the pay accrues.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Current appropriations available for advance payments under this section may be transferred to the prior fiscal year appropriation available for the same purpose in the amount of any unliquidated advance payments that remain at the end of such prior fiscal year. Such unliquidated advance payments shall then be credited to the current appropriation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, an advance of pay of not more than three months’ pay may be made to an officer of the Coast Guard who is ordered to sea duty or to or from shore duty beyond the seas. In addition, the Commandant of the Coast Guard may direct such advances as he considers necessary and proper to members of the Coast Guard stationed at distant stations where the pay and emoluments to which they are entitled cannot be paid regularly.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, the dislocation allowance authorized by <ref>section 452(c)(2) of this title</ref> for a member of a uniformed service whose dependents are covered by <ref>section 452(b)(11) of this title</ref> may be paid in advance of the evacuation of the dependents and to the dependents designated by the member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary concerned may, when the last day of the pay period falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday, authorize the payment of pay and allowances to members of uniformed service under his jurisdiction on the preceding workday but not more than three days before the last day of that pay period. If a member dies after he has received an advance payment under this subsection, but before the last day of the pay period for which the payment is made, no part of the amount so advance is recoverable by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, not more than one month’s pay may be paid in advance to a member of the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship program upon reporting for a period of active duty required by <ref>section 2121(c) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, not more than one month’s pay may be paid in advance to a member of the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps who is ordered to field training or a practice required under <ref>section 2109 of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 490</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–26, § 1(6)</ref>, <date date="1965-05-22">May 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–193</ref>, <date date="1965-09-21">Sept. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 70</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 3(1)</ref>, (9), <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>, 1315; <ref>Pub. L. 96–76, title III, § 313(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–215, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-03-25">Mar. 25, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–343, § 8</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(23)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title I, § 131(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(j)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1303(b)(12)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1679</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VI, § 652</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(f)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(h)(9)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1007.</num>
<heading> Deductions from pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The pay of an officer of an armed force may be withheld, under <ref>section 5512 of title 5</ref>, only for an indebtedness to the United States admitted by the officer or shown by the judgment of a court, or upon a special order issued in the discretion of the Secretary of Defense (or the Secretary of Homeland Security, in the case of an officer of the Coast Guard when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy), or upon the denial of relief of an officer pursuant to <ref>section 3527 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An amount due to the United States from an enlisted member of the Army, the Air Force, or the Space Force for articles sold to the member on credit under section 4621(a)(1) or 9621(a)(1) of title 10, as the case may be, shall be deducted from the next pay due the member after the sale is reported.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, an amount that a member of the uniformed services is administratively determined to owe the United States or any of its instrumentalities may be deducted from the member’s pay in monthly installments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> After the deduction of pay forfeited by the sentence of a court-martial, if any, or otherwise authorized by law to be withheld, the deductions authorized by this section may not reduce the pay actually received by a member of the uniformed services for any month to less than one-third of the member’s pay for that month.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the indebtedness of a member of the uniformed services to the United States is due to the overpayment of pay or allowances to the member through no fault of the member, the amount of the overpayment shall be recovered in monthly installments. The amount deducted from the pay of the member for a month to recover the overpayment amount may not exceed 15 percent of the member’s pay for that month unless the member requests or consents to collection of the overpayment at an accelerated rate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In all cases described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall provide a reasonable opportunity for the member to request a delay in the imposition of the repayment requirement to recover the indebtedness. Before beginning collection efforts, the Secretary concerned shall consider the reasons provided by the member for the requested delay, including the financial ability of the member to repay the indebtedness, and the hardship that immediate collection would impose on the member and the member’s dependents.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In accordance with clause (ii), if the indebtedness of a member of the uniformed services to the United States occurs, through no fault of the member, as a result of the overpayment of pay or allowances to the member or upon the settlement of the member’s accounts, the Secretary concerned may not recover the indebtedness from the member, including a retired or former member, using deductions from the pay of the member, deductions from retired or separation pay, or any other collection method unless recovery of the indebtedness commences before the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the indebtedness was incurred.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Clause (i) applies with respect to indebtedness incurred on or after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than January 1 of each of 2017 through 2027, the Director of the Defense Finance and Accounting Service shall review all cases occurring during the 10-year period prior to the date of the review of indebtedness of a member of the uniformed services, including a retired or former member, to the United States in which—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the recovery of the indebtedness commenced after the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the indebtedness was incurred; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Director did not otherwise notify the member of such indebtedness during such 10-year period.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Director shall submit to the congressional defense committees and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate each review conducted under clause (i), including the amounts owed to the United States by the members included in such review.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If a member of the uniformed services, through no fault of the member, incurs a wound, injury, or illness while in the line of duty in a combat operation or combat zone designated by the President or the Secretary of Defense, any overpayment of pay or allowances made to the member while the member recovers from the wound, injury, or illness may not be deducted from the member’s pay until—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the member is notified of the overpayment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the later of the following occurs:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the completion of the tour of duty of the member in the combat operation or combat zone.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of the reassignment of the member from a military treatment facility or other medical unit outside of the theater of operations.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the member, after receiving notification of the overpayment, requests or consents to initiation at an earlier date of the collection of the overpayment of the pay or allowances.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (c), an amount due the United States from an enlisted member of the Army, the Air Force, or the Space Force may be deducted from the member’s pay on final statement, or from the member’s savings on his clothing allowance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The amount of any damage, or cost of repairs, to arms or equipment caused by the abuse or negligence of a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, as the case may be, who had the care of, or was using, the property when it was damaged, shall be deducted from his pay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> If, upon final settlement of the accounts of an officer of the Army, the Air Force, or the Space Force charged with the issue of an article of military supply, there is a deficiency of that article, or if an article of military supply with whose issue an officer is charged is damaged, the value of the lost article or the amount of the damage shall be charged against the officer and deducted from the officer’s monthly pay, unless the officer shows to the satisfaction of the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, by one or more affidavits setting forth the circumstances, that the officer was not at fault.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> An amount due the United States from an officer of the Army, the Air Force, or the Space Force for rations bought on credit, and for articles bought on credit under section 4621(a)(1) or 9621(a)(1) of title 10, shall be deducted from the next pay due that officer after the sale is reported.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon request by a service relief society and subject to paragraph (2), an amount owed by a member of the uniformed services to the relief society may be deducted from the pay on final statement of such member and paid to that relief society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An amount may not be deducted under paragraph (1) from the pay of a member unless the Secretary concerned makes a determination of the amount owed in accordance with the regulations prescribed under subsection (c). Any amount determined to be owed to a service relief society under this paragraph shall be considered an amount that the member is administratively determined to owe the United States under subsection (c) and shall be collectible in accordance with such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretaries concerned shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “service relief society” means the Army Emergency Relief, the Air Force Aid Society, the Navy Relief Society, or the Coast Guard Mutual Assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be deducted each month from the pay of each enlisted member, warrant officer, and limited duty officer of the armed forces on active duty an amount (determined under paragraph (3)) not to exceed $1.00.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts deducted under paragraph (1) shall be deposited in the Armed Forces Retirement Home Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense or, in the case of the Coast Guard, the Commandant, after consultation with the Chief Operating Officer of the Armed Forces Retirement Home, shall determine from time to time the amount to be deducted under paragraph (1) from the pay of enlisted members, warrant officers, and limited duty officers on the basis of the financial needs of the Armed Forces Retirement Home. The amount to be deducted may be fixed at different amounts on the basis of grade or length of service, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> This subsection does not apply to an enlisted member, warrant officer, or limited duty officer of a reserve component.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 491</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718</ref>, §§ 71, 72, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1124</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 5(3)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIII, § 1305</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 684</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VI, § 633(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 343(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1533(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1054(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 371(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 913(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1009(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1006(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 674</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title VI, § 661(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2370</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 205(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VI, § 671(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2173</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(k)(2)</ref>, title XIV, § 1412(c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3829</ref>, 4031.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1008.</num>
<heading> Presidential recommendations concerning adjustments and changes in pay and allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall direct an annual review of the adequacy of the pays and allowances authorized by this title for members of the uniformed services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever the President considers it appropriate, but in no event later than <date date="1967-01-01">January 1, 1967</date>, and not less than once each four years thereafter, he shall direct a complete review of the principles and concepts of the compensation system for members of the uniformed services. Upon completion of such review he shall submit a detailed report to Congress summarizing the results of such review together with any recommendations he may have proposing changes in the statutory salary system and other elements of the compensation structure provided members of the uniformed services.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–132, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-08-21">Aug. 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 546</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VI, § 642(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1009.</num>
<heading> Adjustments of monthly basic pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Annual Adjustment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective on January 1 of each year, the rates of basic pay for members of the uniformed services under <ref>section 203(a) of this title</ref> shall be increased under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effectiveness of Adjustment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An adjustment under this section shall have the force and effect of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Equal Percentage Increase for All Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An adjustment made under this section in a year shall provide all eligible members with an increase in the monthly basic pay that is the percentage (rounded to the nearest one-tenth of one percent) by which the ECI for the base quarter of the year before the preceding year exceeds the ECI for the base quarter of the second year before the preceding calendar year (if at all).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), but subject to subsection (d), the percentage of the adjustment taking effect under this section during each of fiscal years 2004, 2005, and 2006, shall be one-half of one percentage point higher than the percentage that would otherwise be applicable under such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “ECI” means the Employment Cost Index (wages and salaries, private industry workers) published quarterly by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “base quarter” for any year is the three-month period ending on September 30 of such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of Member’s Total Compensation While Performing Certain Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The total daily equivalent amount of the elements of compensation described in paragraph (3), together with other pay and allowances under this title, to be paid to a member of the uniformed services who is temporarily assigned to duty away from the member’s permanent duty station or to duty under field conditions at the member’s permanent duty station shall not be less, for any day during the assignment period, than the total amount, for the day immediately preceding the date of the assignment, of the elements of compensation and other pay and allowances of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to an element of compensation or other pay or allowance of a member during an assignment described in such paragraph to the extent that the element of compensation or other pay or allowance is reduced or terminated due to circumstances unrelated to the assignment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The elements of compensation referred to in this subsection mean—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the monthly basic pay authorized members of the uniformed services by <ref>section 203(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the basic allowance for subsistence authorized members of the uniformed services by <ref>section 402 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the basic allowance for housing authorized members of the uniformed services by <ref>section 403 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presidential Determination of Need for Alternative Pay Adjustment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If, because of national emergency or serious economic conditions affecting the general welfare, the President considers the pay adjustment which would otherwise be required by this section in any year to be inappropriate, the President shall prepare and transmit to Congress before September 1 of the preceding year a plan for such alternative pay adjustments as the President considers appropriate, together with the reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In evaluating an economic condition affecting the general welfare under this subsection, the President shall consider pertinent economic measures including the Indexes of Leading Economic Indicators, the Gross Domestic Product, the unemployment rate, the budget deficit, the Consumer Price Index, the Producer Price Index, the Employment Cost Index, and the Implicit Price Deflator for Personal Consumption Expenditures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President shall include in the plan submitted to Congress under paragraph (1) an assessment of the impact that the alternative pay adjustments proposed in the plan would have on the Government’s ability to recruit and retain well-qualified persons for the uniformed services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–419, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-09-19">Sept. 19, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1152</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–361, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 925</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–342, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(24)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (2), (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VI, § 642(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 368</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 604(a)(1), 605, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1783</ref>, 1784; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1010.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: promotions; effective date for pay and allowances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer of a uniformed service who is promoted to a grade above second lieutenant or ensign is entitled to the pay and allowances of the grade to which promoted on the effective date of the promotion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title IV, § 403(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2905</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2401</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1011.</num>
<heading> Mess operation: reimbursement of expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall, by regulation, establish rates for meals sold at messes to officers, civilians, and enlisted members. Such rates shall be established at a level sufficient to provide reimbursement of operating expenses and food costs to the appropriations concerned, but members of the uniformed services and civilians in a travel status receiving a per diem allowance in lieu of subsistence shall be charged at a rate of not less than $2.50 per day. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if the Secretary determines that it is in the best interest of the United States, the Secretary may reduce a rate for meals established under this subsection by the amount of that rate attributable to operating expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, payment for meals at the rates established under this section may be made in cash or, in the case of enlisted members or civilian employees, by deduction from pay. Members of organized nonprofit youth groups sponsored at either the national or local level, when extended the privilege of visiting a military installation or when residing at a military installation pursuant to an agreement in effect on <date date="1986-06-30">June 30, 1986</date>, and permitted to eat in the general mess by the commanding officer of the installation, shall pay the commuted ration cost of such meal or meals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Spouses and dependent children of enlisted members in pay grades E–1, E–2, E–3, and E–4 may not be charged for meals sold at messes in excess of a level sufficient to cover food costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish rates for meals sold at Coast Guard dining facilities, provide for reimbursement of operating expenses and food costs to the appropriations concerned, and reduce the rates for such meals when the Secretary determines that it is in the best interest of the United States to do so.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2906</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VIII, § 810(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 681</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title VI, § 655</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3891</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1012.</num>
<heading> Disbursement and accounting: pay of enlisted members of the National Guard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated for the pay, under subsections (a), (b), and (d) of section 206, section 301(f), section 402(e), and <ref>section 1002 of this title</ref>, of enlisted members of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States for attending regular periods of duty and instruction shall be disbursed and accounted for by the Secretary of Defense. All such disbursements shall be made for 3-month periods for units of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, and on pay rolls prepared and authenticated as prescribed in those regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(i)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1061</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1303(b)(13)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VI, § 602(c)(2)</ref>, title IX, § 913(c)(1), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 357</ref>, 411; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(b)(5)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–292.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1013.</num>
<heading> Payment of compensation for victims of terrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any benefit or payment pursuant to <ref>section 559 of this title</ref>, or section 1032 or 1095a or chapter 110 of title 10, shall be paid out of funds available to the Secretary concerned for military personnel.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–399, title VIII, § 801(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 888</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1233(g)(4)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(h)(6)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1014.</num>
<heading> Payment date for pay and allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Amounts of basic pay, basic allowance for housing, basic allowance for subsistence, and other payments of military compensation (other than travel and transportation allowances and separation allowances) shall be paid on the first day of the month beginning after the month during which the right to such compensation accrues.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) does not preclude one payment in midmonth for any element of compensation and does not affect any authority to make advance payments of pay and allowances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> With respect to a member of the uniformed services who has elected to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan under <ref>section 211 of this title</ref>, subsection (a) does not preclude the payment of an amount equal to one-half of the monthly deposit to the Thrift Savings Fund otherwise to be made by the member in participating in the Plan, which amount may be deposited in the Thrift Savings Fund at midmonth.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title IX, § 9103(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–118, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title IX, § 9103(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–118, § 1013; renumbered § 1014, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 8(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 285</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VI, § 603(d)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1782</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1015.</num>
<heading> Recordation of installment payment obligations for incentive pays and similar benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of any pay, allowance, bonus, or other benefit described in subsection (b) that is paid to a member of the uniformed services on an installment basis, each installment payment shall be charged to appropriations that are available for obligation at the time such payment is payable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Pay and Benefits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) applies to any incentive pay, special pay, or bonus, or similar periodic payment of pay or allowances, or of educational benefits or stipends, that is paid to a member of the uniformed services under this title or title 10.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VI, § 662(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 859</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>