<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Payments for unused accrued leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term “discharge” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of an enlisted member, separation or release from active duty under honorable conditions, termination of an enlistment in conjunction with the commencement of a successive enlistment (without regard to the date of the expiration of the term of the enlistment being terminated), or appointment as an officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an officer, separation or release from active duty under honorable conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of either an officer or an enlisted member, death while on active duty unless the decedent was put to death as lawful punishment for a crime or a military offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of an officer or an enlisted member of a reserve component who is not serving on active duty, separation or release from the reserve component under honorable conditions, or death; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in the case of an enlisted member of a reserve component who is not serving on active duty, termination of enlistment in conjunction with the commencement of a successive enlistment, or appointment as an officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, who has accrued leave to the member’s credit at the time of the member’s discharge, is entitled to be paid in cash or by a check on the Treasurer of the United States for such leave on the basis of the basic pay to which the member was entitled on the date of discharge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Payment may not be made under this subsection to a member who is discharged for the purpose of accepting an appointment or a warrant in any uniformed service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Payment may not be made to a member for any leave he elects to have carried over to a new enlistment in any uniformed service on the day after the date of his discharge; but payment may be made to a member for any leave he elects not to carry over to a new enlistment. However, the number of days of leave for which payment is made may not exceed sixty, less the number of days for which payment was previously made under this section after <date date="1976-02-09">February 9, 1976</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A member to whom a payment may not be made under this subsection, or a member who reverts from officer to enlisted status, carries the accrued leave standing to his credit from the one status to the other within any uniformed service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The limitation in the second sentence of paragraph (3) and in subsection (f) shall not apply with respect to leave accrued—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by a member of a reserve component while serving on active duty in support of a contingency operation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by a member of the armed forces in the Retired Reserve while serving on active duty in support of a contingency operation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> by a retired member of the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, or Regular Space Force or a member of the Fleet Reserve or Fleet Marine Corps Reserve while the member is serving on active duty in support of a contingency operation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> by a member of a reserve component while serving on active duty, full-time National Guard duty, or active duty for training for a period of more than 30 days but not in excess of 365 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An enlisted member of the armed forces who would lose accumulated leave in excess of 90 days of leave under <ref>section 701(e) of title 10</ref> may elect to be paid in cash or by a check on the Treasurer of the United States for any leave in excess so accumulated for up to 30 days of such leave. A member may make an election under this paragraph only once.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Unused accrued leave for which payment is made under subsection (b) is not considered as service for any purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Payments for unused accrued leave under subsections (b) and (g), in the case of a member who dies while on active duty or in the case of a member or former member who dies after retirement or discharge and before he receives that payment, shall be made in accordance with <ref>section 2771 of title 10</ref>. In the case of a member who dies while on active duty, payment for unused accrued leave under subsections (b) and (g) shall be based upon the unused accrued leave the member carried forward into the leave year during which he died plus the unused leave that accrued to him during that leave year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The limitations in the second sentence of subsection (b)(3), subsection (f), and the second sentence of subsection (g) shall not apply with respect to a payment made under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration who is discharged under other than honorable conditions forfeits all accrued leave to his credit at the time of his discharge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may require that a member of a uniformed service who is discharged before completing six months of active duty because of a failure to serve satisfactorily (as determined by the Secretary concerned) forfeit all accrued leave to his credit at the time of his discharge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The number of days upon which payment under subsection (b) or (g) is based may not exceed sixty, less the number of days for which payment has been previously made under such subsections after <date date="1976-02-09">February 9, 1976</date>. For the purposes of this subsection, the number of days upon which payment may be based shall be determined without regard to any break in service or change in status in the uniformed services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> An officer of the Regular Corps of the Public Health Service, or an officer of the Reserve Corps <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002017">1</ref> of the Public Health Service on active duty, who is credited with accumulated and accrued annual leave on the date of his separation, retirement, or release from active duty, shall, if his application for that leave is approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, be paid for that leave in a lump-sum on the basis of his basic pay, subsistence allowance, and allowance for quarters whether or not he is receiving that allowance on that date. However, the number of days upon which the lump-sum payment is based is subject to subsection (f). A lump-sum payment may not be made under this subsection to an officer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whose appointment expires or is terminated and who, without a break in active service, accepts a new appointment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> who is retired for age in time of war and is continued on, or recalled to, active duty without a break in active service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> who is transferred to another department or agency of the United States under circumstances in which, by any other law, his leave may be transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In this subsection, the term “accumulated annual leave” means unused accrued annual leave carried forward from one leave year into the next leave year, and the term “accrued annual leave” means the annual leave accruing to an officer during one leave year.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Payment shall be made for all leave accumulated under <ref>section 701(f) of title 10</ref> as soon as possible after the name of the person concerned is removed from a missing status, as defined in <ref>section 551(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–151</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1965-08-28">Aug. 28, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718</ref>, §§ 49(a)(1), 65, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1121</ref>, 1123; <ref>Pub. L. 92–596, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–361, title III, § 304(a)</ref>–(g), <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 925</ref>, 926; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(14)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2938</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VI, § 682</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 8(e)(6)</ref>, (9), <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 286</ref>, 287; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VI, § 637</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 368</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 671</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VI, § 651(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 551(d)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 516(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(h)(3)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1955</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(g)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), (3)(A), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3827</ref>, 3828; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 631(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2631</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Absences due to sickness, wounds, and certain other causes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, who is absent because of sickness or wounds, or who is directed by the Secretary concerned, or the Secretary’s designated representative, to be absent from duty to await orders pending disability retirement proceedings for a period that is longer than the leave authorized by <ref>section 701 of title 10</ref>, is entitled to the pay and allowances to which the member would be entitled if the member were not so absent. A member who is absent with leave for any other reason for not longer than the leave authorized by that section is entitled to the same pay and allowances to which the member would be entitled if the member were not on leave, and to any additional allowances otherwise provided by law for members on leave.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (a) and <ref>section 701(g) of title 10</ref>, a member who is authorized by the Secretary concerned, or the Secretary’s designated representative, to be absent for a period that is longer than the leave authorized by <ref>section 701 of title 10</ref> is not entitled to pay or allowances during the part of the member’s absence that is more than the number of days’ leave authorized by that section. Nothing in this subsection may be construed to deprive a member, detailed or assigned by the Secretary concerned as a full-time student at a civilian institution to pursue a program of education that is substantially the same as a program of education offered to civilians, of pay or allowances to which such member is entitled.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 49(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(15)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 506(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(g)(1)(B)</ref>, (3)(B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3827</ref>, 3828; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 631(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 552(c)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Absence without leave or over leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, who is absent without leave or over leave, forfeits all pay and allowances for the period of that absence, unless it is excused as unavoidable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard when it is operating as service in the Department of the Navy, the Secretary of Defense may determine to pay the pay and allowances described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not delegate the authority to make a determination under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after determining to pay any pay or allowance under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report regarding such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A commissioned officer of the Regular Corps of the Public Health Service, or an officer of the Reserve Corps <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">1</ref> of the Public Health Service on active duty, who is absent without leave, forfeits all pay and allowances for the period of that absence, unless it is excused as unavoidable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 49(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 516(15)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(g)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3827</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 289</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Cadets and midshipmen: chapter does not apply to</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter does not apply to cadets at the United States Military Academy, the United States Air Force Academy, the Coast Guard Academy, midshipmen at the United States Naval Academy, or cadets or midshipmen serving elsewhere in the armed forces.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>