<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 8—</num>
<heading>TRAVEL AND TRANSPORTATION ALLOWANCES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>TRAVEL AND TRANSPORTATION AUTHORITIES—NEW LAW</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 451.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions Relating to Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subchapter and subchapter II:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “administering Secretary” or “administering Secretaries” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, with respect to the armed forces (including the Coast Guard when it is operating as a service in the Navy).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security, with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce, with respect to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services, with respect to the Public Health Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “authorized traveler” means a person who is authorized travel and transportation allowances when performing official travel ordered or authorized by the administering Secretary. Such term includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A member of the uniformed services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A family member of a member of the uniformed services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A person acting as an escort or attendant for a member or family member who is traveling on official travel or is traveling with the remains of a deceased member or as an escort or attendant for dependents of a member for necessary travel performed not later than one year after the member is unable to accompany the dependents who are incapable of traveling alone.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A person who participates in a military funeral honors detail.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps cadet or midshipman.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> An applicant or rejected applicant for enlistment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Any person whose employment or service is considered directly related to a Government official activity or function under regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> Any other person not covered by subparagraphs (A) through (G) who is determined by the administering Secretary pursuant to regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref> as warranting the provision of travel benefits for purposes of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Transportation of survivors to attend burial services or transfer of deceased members after death overseas as provided in <ref>section 453(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Transportation of designated individuals incident to the hospitalization of members as provided in <ref>section 452(b)(12) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Transportation of designated individuals incident to the repatriation of members as provided in <ref>section 452(b)(13) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Transportation of non-medical attendants as provided in <ref>section 452(b)(14) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Transportation of designated individuals to attend Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program events as provided in <ref>section 452(b)(15) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Transportation of a person with regard to a single event when the administering Secretary determines that the travel is necessary to ensure fairness and equity, respond to emergency or humanitarian circumstances, or serve the best interests of the Government.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Transportation of a dependent child of a member of the uniformed services to the United States to obtain formal secondary, undergraduate, graduate, or vocational education, if the permanent duty assignment location of the member is outside the continental United States (other than in Alaska or Hawaii).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> Transportation of a dependent child of a member of the uniformed services within the United States to obtain formal secondary, undergraduate, graduate, or vocational education, if the permanent duty assignment location of the member is in Alaska or Hawaii and the school is located in a State outside of the permanent duty assignment location.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> Transportation of a dependent to a location where a member of the uniformed services is on permanent duty aboard a ship that is overhauling, inactivating, or under construction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “family member”, with respect to a member of the uniformed services, means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A dependent, as defined in <ref>section 401(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A child, as defined in <ref>section 401(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A parent, as defined in <ref>section 401(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A sibling of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A former spouse of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions Relating to Travel and Transportation Allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subchapter and subchapter II:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “official travel” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Military duty or official business performed by an authorized traveler away from a duty assignment location or other authorized location.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Travel performed by an authorized traveler ordered to relocate from a permanent duty station to another permanent duty station.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Travel performed by an authorized traveler ordered to the first permanent duty station, or separated or retired from uniformed service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Local travel in or around the temporary duty or permanent duty station.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Other travel as authorized or ordered by the administering Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “actual and necessary expenses” means expenses incurred in fact by an authorized traveler as a reasonable consequence of official travel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “travel allowances” means the daily lodging, meals, and other related expenses, including relocation expenses, incurred by an authorized traveler while on official travel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “transportation allowances” means the costs of temporarily or permanently moving an authorized traveler, the personal property of an authorized traveler, or a combination thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “transportation-, lodging-, or meals-in-kind” means transportation, lodging, or meals provided by the Government without cost to an authorized traveler.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “miscellaneous expenses” means authorized expenses incurred in addition to authorized allowances during the performance of official travel by an authorized traveler.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “personal property”, with respect to transportation allowances, includes baggage, furniture, and other household items, clothing, privately owned vehicles, house trailers, mobile homes, and any other personal items that would not otherwise be prohibited by any other provision of law or regulation prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “relocation allowances” means the costs associated with relocating a member of the uniformed services and the member’s dependents between an old and new temporary or permanent duty assignment location or other authorized location. Such costs include pet quarantine expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “dislocation allowances” means the costs associated with relocation of the household of a member of the uniformed services and the member’s dependents in relation to a change in the member’s permanent duty assignment location ordered for the convenience of the Government or incident to an evacuation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “permanent duty assignment location” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the official station of a member of the uniformed services; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the residence of a dependent of a member of the uniformed services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> As used in subparagraph (A)(ii), the residence of a dependent who is a student not living with the member while at school is the permanent duty assignment location of the dependent student.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1453</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VI, § 621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI, § 603(b)</ref>, (c)(2), (d)(2), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1766</ref>, 1767; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(h)(6)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2629</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 452.</num>
<heading> Allowable travel and transportation: general authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise prohibited by law, a member of the uniformed services or other authorized traveler may be provided transportation-, lodging-, or meals-in-kind, or actual and necessary expenses of travel and transportation, for, or in connection with, official travel under circumstances as specified in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specific Circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority under subsection (a) includes travel under or in connection with, but not limited to, the following circumstances, to the extent specified in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Temporary duty that requires travel between a permanent duty assignment location and another authorized temporary duty location, and travel in or around the temporary duty location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Permanent change of station that requires travel between an old and new temporary or permanent duty assignment location or other authorized location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Temporary duty or assignment relocation related to consecutive overseas tours or in-place-consecutive overseas tours.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Recruiting duties for the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Assignment or detail to another Government department or agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Rest and recuperative leave.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Convalescent leave.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Reenlistment leave.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Reserve component inactive-duty training performed outside the normal commuting distance of the member’s permanent residence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Ready Reserve muster duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Unusual, extraordinary, hardship, or emergency circumstances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Presence of family members at a military medical facility incident to the illness or injury of members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Presence of family members at the repatriation of members held captive.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Presence of non-medical attendants for very seriously or seriously wounded, ill, or injured members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Attendance at Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program events.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Missing status, as determined by the Secretary concerned under chapter 10 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> Attendance at or participation in international sports competitions described under <ref>section 717 of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Travel by a dependent child to the United States to obtain formal secondary, undergraduate, graduate, or vocational education, if the permanent duty assignment location of the member of the uniformed services is outside the continental United States (other than in Alaska or Hawaii).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Travel by a dependent child within the United States to obtain formal secondary, undergraduate, graduate, or vocational education, if the permanent duty assignment location of the member of the uniformed services is in Alaska or Hawaii and the school is located in a State outside of the permanent duty assignment location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (i), travel by a dependent to a location where a member of the uniformed services is on permanent duty aboard a ship that is overhauling, inactivating, or under construction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> Presence of family members at the funeral and memorial services of members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> Permanent change of assignment to or from a naval vessel undergoing nuclear refueling or defueling and any concurrent complex overhaul, even if such assignment is within the same area as the current assignment of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> Current assignment to a naval vessel entering or exiting nuclear refueling or defueling and any concurrent complex overhaul.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters Included</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Travel and transportation allowances which may be provided under subsection (a) include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Allowances for transportation (including fares and tolls, without regard to distance travelled), lodging, and meals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Dislocation or relocation allowances paid in connection with a change in a member’s temporary or permanent duty assignment location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A partial dislocation allowance paid to a member ordered to occupy or vacate housing provided by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Passport and visa fees required for foreign travel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Other related miscellaneous expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mode of Providing Travel and Transportation Allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any authorized travel and transportation may be provided—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as an actual expense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as an authorized allowance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in-kind; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> using a combination of the authorities under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel and Transportation Allowances When Travel Orders Are Modified, etc</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An authorized traveler whose travel and transportation order or authorization is canceled, revoked, or modified may be allowed actual and necessary expenses or travel and transportation allowances in connection with travel performed pursuant to such order or authorization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An authorized traveler may be allowed advance payments for authorized travel and transportation allowances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Unauthorized Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any unauthorized travel or transportation expense is not the responsibility of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The administering Secretary may not provide payment under this section for an expense for which payment may be provided from any other appropriate Government or non-Government entity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dependent Transportation Incident to Ship Construction, Inactivation, and Overhauling</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority under subsection (a) for travel in connection with circumstances described in subsection (b)(20) shall be subject to the following terms and conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The member of the uniformed services must be permanently assigned to the ship for 31 or more consecutive days to be eligible for allowances, and the transportation allowances accrue on the 31st day and every 60 days thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Transportation in kind, reimbursement for personally procured transportation, or a monetary allowance for mileage in place of the cost of transportation may be provided, in lieu of the member’s entitlement to transportation, for the member’s dependents from the location that was the home port of the ship before commencement of overhaul or inactivation to the port of overhaul or inactivation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The total reimbursement for transportation for the member’s dependents may not exceed the cost of one Government-procured commercial round-trip travel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel for Inactive-duty Training and Muster Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If a member of the uniformed services travels more than 50 miles from the member’s permanent residence (as established under paragraph (2)) for training described in paragraph (9) of subsection (b) or duty described in paragraph (10) of that subsection, the member shall be provided, in the form of actual expenses, in-kind, or a combination thereof—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> actual and necessary expenses of travel and transportation for, or in connection with, such travel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meals, incidentals, and expenses related to such travel, to the same extent specified in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref> for a member on official travel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the permanent residence of a member—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be established not later than 30 days after the date on which the permanent duty assignment of the member begins; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not be re-established until after the member receives subsequent orders for a permanent change of assignment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of a member whose permanent residence changes after the date described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2) and before the member receives orders described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph, the Secretary concerned may provide the member expenses described in paragraph (1) or such other reimbursement as the Secretary determines appropriate if the member travels more than 50 miles from the new permanent residence of the member for training described in paragraph (9) of subsection (b) or duty described in paragraph (10) of such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1455</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VI, § 607(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1425</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VI, § 605</ref>, title XII, § 1299N, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3672</ref>, 4016; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 603(c)(1), (d)(1), 623, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1766</ref>, 1767, 1772; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 621</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VI, § 623(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1933</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 453.</num>
<heading> Allowable travel and transportation: specific authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to any other authority for the provision of travel and transportation allowances, the administering Secretaries may provide travel and transportation allowances under this subchapter in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Absence From Temporary Duty Location</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An authorized traveler may be paid travel and transportation allowances, or reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses of travel, incurred at a temporary duty location during an authorized absence from that location.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Movement of Personal Property</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member of a uniformed service may be allowed moving expenses and transportation allowances for self and dependents associated with the movement of personal property and household goods, including such expenses when associated with a self-move.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority in paragraph (1) includes the movement and temporary and non-temporary storage of personal property, household goods, and privately owned vehicles in connection with the temporary or permanent move between authorized locations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For movement of household goods, the administering Secretaries shall prescribe weight allowances in regulations under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref>. The prescribed weight allowances may not exceed 18,000 pounds (including household goods in temporary storage, but excluding packing and crating), except that the administering Secretary may, on a case-by-case basis, authorize additional weight allowances as necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The administering Secretary may prescribe the terms, rates, and conditions that authorize a member of the uniformed services to ship or store privately owned vehicles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> No carrier, port agent, warehouseman, freight forwarder, or other person involved in the transportation of property may have any lien on, or hold, impound, or otherwise interfere with, the movement of baggage and household goods being transported under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unusual or Emergency Circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An authorized traveler may be provided travel and transportation allowances under this section for unusual, extraordinary, hardship, or emergency circumstances, including circumstances warranting evacuation from a permanent duty assignment location.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Particular Separation Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The administering Secretary may provide travel-in-kind and transportation-in-kind for the following persons in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member who is retired, or is placed on the temporary disability retired list, under chapter 61 of title 10.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A member who is retired with pay under any other law or who, immediately following at least eight years of continuous active duty with no single break therein of more than 90 days, is discharged with separation pay or is involuntarily released from active duty with separation pay or readjustment pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member who is discharged under <ref>section 1173 of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attendance at Memorial Ceremonies and Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A family member or member of the uniformed services who attends a deceased member’s repatriation, burial, or memorial ceremony or service may be provided travel and transportation allowances to the extent provided in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement of Qualifying Spouse Relicensing Costs and Business Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> From amounts otherwise made available for a fiscal year to provide travel and transportation allowances under this chapter, the Secretary concerned may reimburse a member of the uniformed services for qualified relicensing costs and qualified business costs of the spouse of the member when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the member relocates to a new jurisdiction or geographic area as the result of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assignment to a duty station;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a reassignment, either as a result of a permanent change of station or permanent change of assignment, between duty stations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a transfer from a regular component of a uniformed service into the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve of a uniformed service, if the member is authorized a final move from the last duty station to the new jurisdiction or geographic area; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> placement on the temporary disability retired list under chapter 61 of title 10; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the movement of the member’s dependents is authorized at the expense of the United States under this section as part of the relocation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Reimbursement provided to a member under this subsection for qualified relicensing costs may not exceed $1,000 in connection with each relocation described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Reimbursement provided to a member under this subsection for qualified business costs may not exceed $1,000 in connection with each relocation described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No reimbursement may be provided under this subsection for qualified relicensing costs or qualified business costs paid or incurred after <date date="2029-12-31">December 31, 2029</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “qualified relicensing costs” means costs, including exam, continuing education courses, business license, permit, and registration fees, incurred by the spouse of a member if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the spouse was licensed or certified in a profession, or owned a business, during the member’s previous duty assignment and requires a new professional license or certification, or business license or permit, to engage in that profession in a new jurisdiction because of the member’s relocation described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the costs were incurred or paid to secure or maintain the professional license or certification, or business license or permit, from the new jurisdiction in connection with such relocation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “qualified business costs” means costs, including moving services for equipment, equipment removal, new equipment purchases, information technology expenses, and inspection fees, incurred by the spouse of a member if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the spouse owned a business during the member’s previous duty assignment and the costs result from a the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref> member’s relocation described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the costs were incurred or paid to move such business to a new location in connection with such relocation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for Transportation of Pets Arising From Certain Permanent Changes of Stations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may reimburse a member for any cost related to the relocation of a pet that arises from a permanent change of station of such member within the continental United States. Such reimbursement may not exceed $550 for each such permanent change of station.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may reimburse a member for any cost related to the relocation of a pet that arises from a permanent change of station of such member to or from a duty station located outside the continental United States. Such reimbursement may not exceed $4,000 for each such permanent change of station.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Attendance at Professional Military Education Institution or Training Classes.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the military department concerned may authorize temporary duty status, and travel and transportation allowances payable to a member in such status, for a member under the jurisdiction of such Secretary who is reassigned—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> between duty stations located within the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a period of not more than one year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for the purpose of participating in professional military education or training classes,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with orders to return to the duty station where the member maintains primary residence and the dependents of such member reside.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of the military department concerned assigns permanent duty status to a member described in paragraph (1), such member shall be eligible for travel and transportation allowances including the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Transportation, including mileage at the same rate paid for a permanent change of station.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Per diem while traveling between the permanent duty station and professional military education institution or training site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Per diem paid in the same manner and amount as temporary lodging expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Per diem equal to the amount of the basic allowance for housing under <ref>section 403 of this title</ref> paid to a member—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the grade of such member;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> without dependents;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> who resides in the military housing area in which the professional military education institution or training site is located.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Movement of household goods in an amount determined under applicable regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1457</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VI, § 621(c)(1)</ref>, (h), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 783</ref>, 784; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 522(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VI, § 622(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3676</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 622(a), 623–625, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2625–2627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VI, § 635</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VI, § 624</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1934</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 454.</num>
<heading> Travel and transportation: pilot programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pilot Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as otherwise prohibited by law, the Secretary of Defense may conduct pilot programs to evaluate alternative travel and transportation programs, policies, and processes for Department of Defense authorized travelers. Any such pilot program shall be designed to enhance cost savings or other efficiencies that accrue to the Government and be conducted so as to evaluate one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Alternative methods for performing and reimbursing travel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Means for limiting the need for travel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Means for reducing the environmental impact of travel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than three pilot programs may be carried out under subsection (a) at any one time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The duration of a pilot program may not exceed four years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority to carry out a pilot program is subject to the availability of appropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days before the commencement of a pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the pilot program. The report on a pilot program under this paragraph shall set forth a description of the pilot program, including the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The purpose of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The duration of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The cost savings or other efficiencies anticipated to accrue to the Government under the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 60 days after the completion of a pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the pilot program. The report on a pilot program under this paragraph shall set forth the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of results of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Secretary considers appropriate in light of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Defense Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “congressional defense committees” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 101(a)(16) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1458</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 455.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for travel: may not be used for attendance at certain meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations of the Department of Defense that are available for travel may not, without the approval of the Secretary concerned or his designee, be used for expenses incident to attendance of a member of an armed force under that department at a meeting of a technical, scientific, professional, or similar organization.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 476</ref>, § 412; renumbered § 455, <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 456.</num>
<heading> Managed travel program refunds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credit of Refunds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may credit refunds attributable to Department of Defense managed travel programs as a direct result of official travel to such operation and maintenance or research, development, test, and evaluation accounts of the Department as designated by the Secretary that are available for obligation for the fiscal year in which the refund or amount is collected.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Refunds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Refunds credited under subsection (a) may only be used for official travel or operations and efficiency improvements for improved financial management of official travel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Managed travel program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “managed travel program” includes air, rental car, train, bus, dining, lodging, and travel management, but does not include rebates or refunds attributable to the use of the Government travel card, the Government Purchase Card, or Government travel arranged by Government Contracted Travel Management Centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Refund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “refund” includes miscellaneous receipts credited to the Department identified as a refund, rebate, repayment, or other similar amounts collected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1424</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 461.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other travel and transportation authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An authorized traveler may not be paid travel and transportation allowances or receive travel-in-kind and transportation-in-kind, or a combination thereof, under both subchapter I and subchapter III for official travel performed under a single or related travel and transportation order or authorization by the administering Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 462.</num>
<heading> Travel and transportation allowances paid to members that are unauthorized or in excess of authorized amounts: requirement for repayment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), a member of the uniformed services or other person who is paid travel and transportation allowances under subchapter I shall repay to the United States any amount of such payment that is determined to be unauthorized or in excess of the applicable authorized amount.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref> shall specify procedures for determining the circumstances under which an exception to repayment otherwise required by subsection (a) may be granted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Bankruptcy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An obligation to repay the United States under this section is, for all purposes, a debt owed the United States. A discharge in bankruptcy under title 11 does not discharge a person from such debt if the discharge order is entered less than five years after the date on which the debt was incurred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 463.</num>
<heading> Programs of compliance; electronic processing of travel claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs of Compliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The administering Secretaries shall provide for compliance with the requirements of this chapter through programs of compliance established and maintained for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The programs of compliance under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> minimize the provision of benefits under this chapter based on inaccurate claims, unauthorized claims, overstated or inflated claims, and multiple claims for the same benefits through the electronic verification of travel claims on a near-time basis and such other means as the administering Secretaries may establish for purposes of the programs of compliance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that benefits provided under this chapter do not exceed reasonable or actual and necessary expenses of travel claimed or reasonable allowances based on commercial travel rates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Electronic Processing of Travel Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> By not later than the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012, any travel claim under this chapter shall be processed electronically.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The administering Secretary, or the Secretary’s designee, may waive the requirement in paragraph (1) with respect to a particular claim in the interests of the department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The electronic processing of claims under this subsection shall be subject to the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under <ref>section 464 of this title</ref> which shall apply uniformly to all members of the uniformed services and, to the extent practicable, to all other authorized travelers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 464.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter and subchapter I shall be administered under terms, rates, conditions, and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the other administering Secretaries for members of the uniformed services. Such regulations shall be uniform for the Department of Defense and shall apply as uniformly as practicable to the uniformed services under the jurisdiction of the other administering Secretaries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>[SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>REPEALED]</heading>
<section>
<num>[§§ 471 to 474b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1767</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 475.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 405]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 475a to 490.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1767</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 491.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 431]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 492 to 494.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1767</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 495.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 435]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>