<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 409—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40901.</num>
<heading> Science, Space, and Technology Education Trust Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is appropriated, by transfer from funds appropriated in the Department of Housing and Urban Development—Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1989 (<ref>Public Law 100–404</ref>, <ref>102 Stat. 1014</ref>), for “Construction of facilities”, the sum of $15,000,000 to the “Science, Space, and Technology Education Trust Fund”, which is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States. The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest these funds in the United States Treasury special issue securities, and interest shall be credited to the Trust Fund on a quarterly basis. Such interest shall be available for the purpose of making grants for programs directed at improving science, space, and technology education in the United States. The Administrator, after consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation, shall review applications made for such grants and determine the distribution of available funds on a competitive basis. Grants shall be made available to any awardee only to the extent that the awardee provides matching funds from non-Federal sources to carry out the program for which grants from this Trust Fund are made. Of the funds made available by this Trust Fund, $250,000 shall be disbursed each calendar quarter to the Challenger Center for Space Science Education. The Administrator shall submit to Congress an annual report on the grants made pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40902.</num>
<heading> National Aeronautics and Space Administration Endeavor Teacher Fellowship Trust Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the Treasury of the United States, in tribute to the dedicated crew of the Space Shuttle Challenger, a trust fund to be known as the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Endeavor Teacher Fellowship Trust Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Trust Fund”). The Trust Fund shall consist of amounts which may from time to time, at the discretion of the Administrator, be transferred from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Gifts and Donations Trust Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investment of Trust Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall direct the Secretary of the Treasury to invest and reinvest funds in the Trust Fund in public debt securities with maturities suitable for the needs of the Trust Fund, and bearing interest at rates determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturities. Interest earned shall be credited to the Trust Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Income accruing from the Trust Fund principal shall be used to create the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Endeavor Teacher Fellowship Program, to the extent provided in advance in appropriation Acts. The Administrator is authorized to use such funds to award fellowships to selected United States nationals who are undergraduate students pursuing a course of study leading to certified teaching degrees in elementary education or in secondary education in mathematics, science, or technology disciplines. Awards shall be made pursuant to standards established for the fellowship program by the Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The interest accruing from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Endeavor Teacher Fellowship Trust Fund principal shall be available in fiscal year 2012 for the purpose of the Endeavor Science Teacher Certificate Program.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–55, div. B, title III</ref>, <date date="2011-11-18">Nov. 18, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40903.</num>
<heading> Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research—merit grant competition requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Eligible State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “eligible State” means a State designated by the Administrator as eligible to compete in the National Science Foundation’s Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Making use of the existing infrastructure established in eligible States by the National Science Foundation, the Administrator shall conduct a merit grant competition among the eligible States in areas of research important to the mission of the Administration. With respect to a grant application by an eligible State, the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the application’s merit and relevance to the mission of the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the potential for the grant to serve as a catalyst to enhance the ability of researchers in the State to become more competitive for regular Administration funding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the potential for the grant to improve the environment for science, mathematics, and engineering education in the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the need to ensure the maximum distribution of grants among eligible States, consistent with merit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supplemental Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall endeavor, where appropriate, to supplement grants made under subsection (b) with such grants for fellowships, traineeships, equipment, or instrumentation as are available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information in Annual Budget Submission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In order to ensure that research expertise and talent throughout the Nation is developed and engaged in Administration research and education activities, the Administration shall, as part of its annual budget submission, detail additional steps that can be taken to further integrate the participating eligible States in both existing and new or emerging Administration research programs and center activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10851(e)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40904.</num>
<heading> Microgravity research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure the capacity to support ground-based research leading to space-based basic and applied scientific research in a variety of disciplines with potential direct national benefits and applications that can be advanced significantly from the uniqueness of microgravity and the space environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carry out, to the maximum extent practicable, basic, applied, and commercial International Space Station research in fields such as molecular crystal growth, animal research, basic fluid physics, combustion research, cellular biotechnology, low-temperature physics, and cellular research at a level that will sustain the existing United States scientific expertise and research capability in microgravity research.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40905.</num>
<heading> Program to expand distance learning in rural underserved areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall develop or expand programs to extend science and space educational outreach to rural communities and schools through video conferencing, interpretive exhibits, teacher education, classroom presentations, and student field trips.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priorities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall give priority to existing programs, including Challenger Learning Centers—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that utilize community-based partnerships in the field;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that build and maintain video conference and exhibit capacity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that travel directly to rural communities and serve low-income populations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> with a special emphasis on increasing the number of women and minorities in the science and engineering professions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40906.</num>
<heading> Equal access to the Administration’s education programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall strive to ensure equal access for minority and economically disadvantaged students to the Administration’s education programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Every 2 years, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate describing the efforts by the Administrator to ensure equal access for minority and economically disadvantaged students under this section and the results of such efforts. As part of the report, the Administrator shall provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> data on minority participation in the Administration’s education programs, at a minimum in the categories of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> elementary and secondary education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> undergraduate education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> graduate education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the total value of grants the Administration made to Historically Black Colleges and Universities and to Hispanic Serving Institutions through education programs during the period covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish the Dr. Mae C. Jemison Grant Program to work with Minority Serving Institutions to bring more women of color into the field of space and aeronautics.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40907.</num>
<heading> Museums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may provide grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, museums and planetariums to enable them to enhance programs related to space exploration, aeronautics, space science, Earth science, or microgravity.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40908.</num>
<heading> Continuation of certain education programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From amounts appropriated to the Administration for education programs, the Administrator shall ensure the continuation of the Space Grant Program, the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research, and, consistent with the results of the review under section 614 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2005 (<ref>Public Law 109–155</ref>, <ref>119 Stat. 2933</ref>), the Administration Explorer School program, to motivate and develop the next generation of explorers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40909.</num>
<heading> Compliance with title IX of Education Amendments of 1972</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To comply with title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.), the Administrator shall conduct compliance reviews of at least 2 grantees annually.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>