<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 203—</num>
<heading>RESPONSIBILITIES AND VISION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20301.</num>
<heading> General responsibilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall ensure that the Administration carries out a balanced set of programs that shall include, at a minimum, programs in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> human space flight, in accordance with <ref>section 20302 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> aeronautics research and development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> scientific research, which shall include, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> robotic missions to study the Moon and other planets and their moons, and to deepen understanding of astronomy, astrophysics, and other areas of science that can be productively studied from space;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Earth science research and research on the Sun-Earth connection through the development and operation of research satellites and other means;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> support of university research in space science, Earth science, and microgravity science; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> research on microgravity, including research that is not directly related to human exploration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation and Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the programs of the Administration, the Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consult and coordinate to the extent appropriate with other relevant Federal agencies, including through the National Science and Technology Council;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> work closely with the private sector, including by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encouraging the work of entrepreneurs who are seeking to develop new means to launch satellites, crew, or cargo;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contracting with the private sector for crew and cargo services, including to the International Space Station, to the extent practicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> using commercially available products (including software) and services to the extent practicable to support all Administration activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> encouraging commercial use and development of space to the greatest extent practicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> involve other nations to the extent appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20302.</num>
<heading> Vision for space exploration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish a program to develop a sustained human presence in cis-lunar space or on the Moon, including a robust precursor program, to promote exploration, science, commerce, and United States preeminence in space, and as a stepping-stone to future exploration of Mars and other destinations. The Administrator is further authorized to develop and conduct appropriate international collaborations in pursuit of these goals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Future Exploration of Mars</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall manage human space flight programs, including the Space Launch System and Orion, to enable humans to explore Mars and other destinations by defining a series of sustainable steps and conducting mission planning, research, and technology development on a timetable that is technically and fiscally possible, consistent with section 70504.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Orion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Orion” means the multipurpose crew vehicle described under section 303 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 18323</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space launch system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Space Launch System” means has the meaning <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref> given the term in section 3 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 18302</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 33</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20303.</num>
<heading> Contribution to innovation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation in Interagency Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administration shall be a full participant in any interagency effort to promote innovation and economic competitiveness through near-term and long-term basic scientific research and development and the promotion of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, consistent with the Administration’s mission, including authorized activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Historic Foundation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In order to carry out the participation described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall build on the historic role of the Administration in stimulating excellence in the advancement of physical science and engineering disciplines and in providing opportunities and incentives for the pursuit of academic studies in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Balanced Science Program and Robust Authorization Levels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The balanced science program authorized by section 101(d) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2005 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 16611(d)</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> shall be an element of the contribution by the Administration to the interagency programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall submit to Congress and the President an annual report describing the activities conducted pursuant to this section, including a description of the goals and the objective metrics upon which funding decisions were made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include, with regard to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education programs, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of each program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The amount spent on each program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The number of students or teachers served by each program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20304.</num>
<heading> Basic research enhancement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Basic Research</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “basic research” has the meaning given the term in Office of Management and Budget Circular No. A–11.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Commerce shall, to the extent practicable, coordinate basic research activities related to physical sciences, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20305.</num>
<heading> National Academies decadal surveys</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall enter into agreements on a periodic basis with the National Academies for independent assessments, also known as decadal surveys, to take stock of the status and opportunities for Earth and space science discipline fields and Aeronautics research and to recommend priorities for research and programmatic areas over the next decade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Independent Cost Estimates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The agreements described in subsection (a) shall include independent estimates of the life cycle costs and technical readiness of missions assessed in the decadal surveys whenever possible.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reexamination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall request that each National Academies decadal survey committee identify any conditions or events, such as significant cost growth or scientific or technological advances, that would warrant the Administration asking the National Academies to reexamine the priorities that the decadal survey had established.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>