<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 701—</num>
<heading>USE OF SPACE LAUNCH SYSTEM OR ALTERNATIVES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70101.</num>
<heading> Recovery of fair value of placing Department of Defense payloads in orbit with space launch system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, or any interagency agreement, the Administrator shall charge such prices as are necessary to recover the fair value of placing Department of Defense payloads into orbit by means of the space launch system.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 117(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70102.</num>
<heading> Space launch system use policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Space Launch System may be used for the following circumstances:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Payloads and missions that contribute to extending human presence beyond low-Earth orbit and substantially benefit from the unique capabilities of the Space Launch System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Other payloads and missions that substantially benefit from the unique capabilities of the Space Launch System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> On a space available basis, Federal Government or educational payloads that are consistent with NASA’s mission for exploration beyond low-Earth orbit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Compelling circumstances, as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements With Foreign Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may plan, negotiate, or implement agreements with foreign entities for the launch of payloads for international collaborative efforts relating to science and technology using the Space Launch System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compelling Circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the date the Administrator makes a determination under subsection (a)(4), the Administrator shall transmit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives written notification of the Administrator’s intent to select the Space Launch System for a specific mission under that subsection, including justification for the determination.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 117(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70103.</num>
<heading> Commercial payloads on space launch system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Launch vehicle</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “launch vehicle” means any vehicle constructed for the purpose of operating in, or placing a payload in, outer space.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payload</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “payload” means an object which a person undertakes to place in outer space by means of a launch vehicle, and includes subcomponents of the launch vehicle specifically designed or adapted for that object.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Commercial payloads may not be accepted for launch as primary payloads on the space launch system unless the Administrator determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the payload requires the unique capabilities of the space launch system; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> launching of the payload on the space launch system is important for either national security or foreign policy purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3428</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 117(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70104.</num>
<heading> Definition of Space Launch System</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “Space Launch System” means the Space Launch System authorized under section 302 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 18322</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 117(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>