<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 501—</num>
<heading>SPACE COMMERCE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial provider</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “commercial provider” means any person providing space transportation services or other space-related activities, primary control of which is held by persons other than Federal, State, local, and foreign governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payload</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “payload” means anything that a person undertakes to transport to, from, or within outer space, or in suborbital trajectory, by means of a space transportation vehicle, but does not include the space transportation vehicle itself except for its components which are specifically designed or adapted for that payload.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space-related activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space-related activities” includes research and development, manufacturing, processing, service, and other associated and support activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space transportation services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space transportation services” means the preparation of a space transportation vehicle and its payloads for transportation to, from, or within outer space, or in suborbital trajectory, and the conduct of transporting a payload to, from, or within outer space, or in suborbital trajectory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space transportation vehicle</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space transportation vehicle” means any vehicle constructed for the purpose of operating in, or transporting a payload to, from, or within, outer space, or in suborbital trajectory, and includes any component of such vehicle not specifically designed or adapted for a payload.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” means each of the several States of the Union, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states commercial provider</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “United States commercial provider” means a commercial provider, organized under the laws of the United States or of a State, that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> more than 50 percent owned by United States nationals; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a subsidiary of a foreign company and the Secretary of Transportation finds that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> such subsidiary has in the past evidenced a substantial commitment to the United States market through—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> investments in the United States in long-term research, development, and manufacturing (including the manufacture of major components and subassemblies); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> significant contributions to employment in the United States; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the country or countries in which such foreign company is incorporated or organized, and, if appropriate, in which it principally conducts its business, affords reciprocal treatment to companies described in subparagraph (A) comparable to that afforded to such foreign company’s subsidiary in the United States, as evidenced by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> providing comparable opportunities for companies described in subparagraph (A) to participate in Government-sponsored research and development similar to that authorized under this chapter;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> providing no barriers, to companies described in subparagraph (A) with respect to local investment opportunities, that are not provided to foreign companies in the United States; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> providing adequate and effective protection for the intellectual property rights of companies described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PROMOTION OF COMMERCIAL SPACE OPPORTUNITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50111.</num>
<heading> Commercialization of Space Station</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Congress declares that a priority goal of constructing the International Space Station is the economic development of Earth orbital space. Congress further declares that free and competitive markets create the most efficient conditions for promoting economic development, and should therefore govern the economic development of Earth orbital space. Congress further declares that the use of free market principles in operating, servicing, allocating the use of, and adding capabilities to the Space Station, and the resulting fullest possible engagement of commercial providers and participation of commercial users, will reduce Space Station operational costs for all partners and the Federal Government’s share of the United States burden to fund operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of United States Commercially Provided Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In order to stimulate commercial use of space, help maximize the utility and productivity of the International Space Station, and enable a commercial means of providing crew transfer and crew rescue services for the International Space Station, the Administration shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make use of United States commercially provided International Space Station crew transfer and crew rescue services to the maximum extent practicable, if those commercial services have demonstrated the capability to meet Administration-specified ascent, entry, and International Space Station proximity operations safety requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> limit, to the maximum extent practicable, the use of the Crew Exploration Vehicle to missions carrying astronauts beyond low Earth orbit once commercial crew transfer and crew rescue services that meet safety requirements become operational;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> facilitate, to the maximum extent practicable, the transfer of Administration-developed technologies to potential United States commercial crew transfer and rescue service providers, consistent with United States law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> issue a notice of intent, not later than 180 days after <date date="2008-10-15">October 15, 2008</date>, to enter into a funded, competitively awarded Space Act Agreement with 2 or more commercial entities for a Phase 1 Commercial Orbital Transportation Services crewed vehicle demonstration program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional intent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the intent of Congress that funding for the program described in paragraph (1)(D) shall not come at the expense of full funding of the amounts authorized under section 101(3)(A) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2008 (<ref>Public Law 110–422</ref>, <ref>122 Stat. 4783</ref>), and for future fiscal years, for Orion Crew Exploration Vehicle development, Ares I Crew Launch Vehicle development, or International Space Station cargo delivery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional technologies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administration shall make International Space Station-compatible docking adaptors and other relevant technologies available to the commercial crew providers selected to service the International Space Station.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crew transfer and crew rescue services contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a commercial provider demonstrates the capability to provide International Space Station crew transfer and crew rescue services and to satisfy Administration ascent, entry, and International Space Station proximity operations safety requirements, the Administration shall enter into an International Space Station crew transfer and crew rescue services contract with that commercial provider for a portion of the Administration’s anticipated International Space Station crew transfer and crew rescue requirements from the time the commercial provider commences operations under contract with the Administration through calendar year 2016, with an option to extend the period of performance through calendar year 2020.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">ISS Transition Plan.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator, in coordination with the ISS management entity (as defined in section 2 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Transition Authorization Act of 2017), ISS partners, the scientific user community, and the commercial space sector, shall develop a plan to transition in a step-wise approach from the current regime that relies heavily on NASA sponsorship to a regime where NASA could be one of many customers of a low-Earth orbit non-governmental human space flight enterprise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2017-12-01">December 1, 2017</date>, and biennially thereafter until 2028, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the progress in achieving the Administration’s deep space human exploration objectives on ISS and prospects for accomplishing future mission requirements, space exploration objectives, and other research objectives on future commercially supplied low-Earth orbit platforms or migration of those objectives to cis-lunar space;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the steps NASA is taking and will take, including demonstrations that could be conducted on the ISS, to stimulate and facilitate commercial demand and supply of products and services in low-Earth orbit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an identification of barriers preventing the commercialization of low-Earth orbit, including issues relating to policy, regulations, commercial intellectual property, data, and confidentiality, that could inhibit the use of the ISS as a commercial incubator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the criteria for defining the ISS as a research success;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the criteria used to determine whether the ISS is meeting the objective under section 301(b)(2) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Transition Authorization Act of 2017;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an assessment of whether the criteria under subparagraphs (D) and (E) are consistent with the research areas defined in, and recommendations and schedules under, the current National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine Decadal Survey on Biological and Physical Sciences in Space;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any necessary contributions that ISS extension would make to enabling execution of the human exploration roadmap under section 432 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Transition Authorization Act of 2017;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the cost estimates for operating the ISS to achieve the criteria required under subparagraphs (D) and (E) and the contributions identified under subparagraph (G);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the cost estimates for extending operations of the ISS to 2024, 2028, and 2030;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> an evaluation of the feasible and preferred service life of the ISS beyond the period described in section 503 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 18353</ref>), through at least 2030, as a unique scientific, commercial, and space exploration-related facility, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a general discussion of international partner capabilities and prospects for extending the partnership;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the cost associated with extending the service life;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an assessment on the technical limiting factors of the service life of the ISS, including a list of critical components and their expected service life and availability; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> such other information as may be necessary to fully describe the justification for and feasibility of extending the service life of the ISS, including the potential scientific or technological benefits to the Federal Government, public, or to academic or commercial entities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> an identification of the necessary actions and an estimate of the costs to deorbit the ISS once it has reached the end of its service life;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> the impact on deep space exploration capabilities, including a crewed mission to Mars in the 2030s, if the preferred service life of the ISS is extended beyond 2024 and NASA maintains a flat budget profile; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<chapeau> an evaluation of the functions, roles, and responsibilities for management and operation of the ISS and a determination of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> those functions, roles, and responsibilities the Federal Government should retain during the lifecycle of the ISS;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> those functions, roles, and responsibilities that could be transferred to the commercial space sector;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the metrics that would indicate the commercial space sector’s readiness and ability to assume the functions, roles, and responsibilities described in clause (ii); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any necessary changes to any agreements or other documents and the law to enable the activities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Demonstrations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If additional Government crew, power, and transportation resources are available after meeting the Administration’s requirements for ISS activities defined in the human exploration roadmap and related research, demonstrations identified under paragraph (2) may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> test the capabilities needed to meet future mission requirements, space exploration objectives, and other research objectives described in paragraph (2)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> demonstrate or test capabilities, including commercial modules or deep space habitats, Environmental Control and Life Support Systems, orbital satellite assembly, exploration space suits, a node that enables a wide variety of activity, including multiple commercial modules and airlocks, additional docking or berthing ports for commercial crew and cargo, opportunities for the commercial space sector to cost share for transportation and other services on the ISS, other commercial activities, or services obtained through alternate acquisition approaches.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title III, § 303(c)</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10815(e)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50112.</num>
<heading> Promotion of United States Global Positioning System standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to support and sustain the Global Positioning System in a manner that will most effectively contribute to the national security, public safety, scientific, and economic interests of the United States, Congress encourages the President to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure the operation of the Global Positioning System on a continuous worldwide basis free of direct user fees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> enter into international agreements that promote cooperation with foreign governments and international organizations to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish the Global Positioning System and its augmentations as an acceptable international standard; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> eliminate any foreign barriers to applications of the Global Positioning System worldwide; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> provide clear direction and adequate resources to the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information so that on an international basis the Assistant Secretary can—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> achieve and sustain efficient management of the electromagnetic spectrum used by the Global Positioning System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> protect that spectrum from disruption and interference.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50113.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of space science data</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Space Science Data</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “space science data” includes scientific data concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the elemental and mineralogical resources of the moon, asteroids, planets and their moons, and comets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> microgravity acceleration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> solar storm monitoring.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition From Commercial Providers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall, to the extent possible and while satisfying the scientific or educational requirements of the Administration, and where appropriate, of other Federal agencies and scientific researchers, acquire, where cost effective, space science data from a commercial provider.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Space Science Data as Commercial Product or Commercial Service Under Acquisition Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Acquisitions of space science data by the Administrator shall be carried out in accordance with applicable acquisition laws and regulations (including applicable provisions of chapters 201 through 285, 341 through 343, and 363 of title 10). For purposes of such law and regulations, space science data shall be considered to be a commercial product or commercial service. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude the United States from acquiring, through contracts with commercial providers, sufficient rights in data to meet the needs of the scientific and educational community or the needs of other government activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Federal Government from requiring compliance with applicable safety standards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not authorize the Administration to provide financial assistance for the development of commercial systems for the collection of space science data.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(g)(10)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702</ref>(<i>l</i>)(10), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50114.</num>
<heading> Administration of commercial space centers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall administer the Commercial Space Center program in a coordinated manner from Administration headquarters in Washington, D.C.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50115.</num>
<heading> Sources of Earth science data</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall, to the extent possible and while satisfying the scientific or educational requirements of the Administration, and where appropriate, of other Federal agencies and scientific researchers, acquire, where cost-effective, space-based and airborne Earth remote sensing data, services, distribution, and applications from a commercial provider.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as Commercial Product or Commercial Service Under Acquisition Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Acquisitions by the Administrator of the data, services, distribution, and applications referred to in subsection (a) shall be carried out in accordance with applicable acquisition laws and regulations (including applicable provisions of chapters 201 through 285, 341 through 343, and 363 of title 10). For purposes of such law and regulations, such data, services, distribution, and applications shall be considered to be a commercial product or commercial service. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude the United States from acquiring, through contracts with commercial providers, sufficient rights in data to meet the needs of the scientific and educational community or the needs of other government activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Federal Government from requiring compliance with applicable safety standards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration and Execution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall be carried out as part of the Commercial Remote Sensing Program at the Stennis Space Center.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(g)(10)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702</ref>(<i>l</i>)(10), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50116.</num>
<heading> Commercial technology transfer program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall execute a commercial technology transfer program with the goal of facilitating the exchange of services, products, and intellectual property between the Administration and the private sector. This program shall place at least as much emphasis on encouraging the transfer of Administration technology to the private sector (“spinning out”) as on encouraging use of private sector technology by the Administration. This program shall be maintained in a manner that provides clear benefits for the Administration, the domestic economy, and the research community, while protecting national security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Structure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the program described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall provide program participants with at least 45 days notice of any proposed changes to the structure of the Administration’s technology transfer and commercialization organizations that is in effect as of <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title VIII, § 829</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 66</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL ACQUISITION OF SPACE TRANSPORTATION SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50131.</num>
<heading> Requirement to procure commercial space transportation services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this section or in section 70102, the Federal Government shall acquire space transportation services from United States commercial providers whenever such services are required in the course of its activities. To the maximum extent practicable, the Federal Government shall plan missions to accommodate the space transportation services capabilities of United States commercial providers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Government shall not be required to acquire space transportation services under subsection (a) if, on a case-by-case basis, the Administrator or, in the case of a national security issue, the Secretary of the Air Force, determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a payload requires the unique capabilities of the space shuttle;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cost effective space transportation services that meet specific mission requirements would not be reasonably available from United States commercial providers when required;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the use of space transportation services from United States commercial providers poses an unacceptable risk of loss of a unique scientific opportunity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the use of space transportation services from United States commercial providers is inconsistent with national security objectives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the use of space transportation services from United States commercial providers is inconsistent with international agreements for international collaborative efforts relating to science and technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> it is more cost effective to transport a payload in conjunction with a test or demonstration of a space transportation vehicle owned by the Federal Government; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a payload can make use of the available cargo space on a space shuttle mission as a secondary payload, and such payload is consistent with the requirements of research, development, demonstration, scientific, commercial, and educational programs authorized by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements With Foreign Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall prevent the Administrator from planning or negotiating agreements with foreign entities for the launch of Federal Government payloads for international collaborative efforts relating to science and technology.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delayed Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) shall not apply to space transportation services and space transportation vehicles acquired or owned by the Federal Government before <date date="1998-10-28">October 28, 1998</date>, or with respect to which a contract for such acquisition or ownership has been entered into before <date date="1998-10-28">October 28, 1998</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Historical Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not be construed to prohibit the Federal Government from acquiring, owning, or maintaining space transportation vehicles solely for historical display purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 117(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50132.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of commercial space transportation services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Commercial Space Transportation Services as Commercial Service Under Acquisition Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Acquisitions of space transportation services by the Federal Government shall be carried out in accordance with applicable acquisition laws and regulations (including applicable provisions of chapters 201 through 285, 341 through 343, and 363 of title 10). For purposes of such law and regulations, space transportation services shall be considered to be a commercial service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Federal Government from requiring compliance with applicable safety standards.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3400</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(g)(10)(C)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702</ref>(<i>l</i>)(10), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 50133.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–10, title IV, § 416(c)</ref>, <date date="2017-03-21">Mar. 21, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 35</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50134.</num>
<heading> Use of excess intercontinental ballistic missiles</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Federal Government shall not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> convert any missile described in subsection (c) to a space transportation vehicle configuration; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfer ownership of any such missile to another person, except as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorized Federal Uses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A missile described in subsection (c) may be converted for use as a space transportation vehicle by the Federal Government if, except as provided in paragraph (2) and at least 30 days before such conversion, the agency seeking to use the missile as a space transportation vehicle transmits to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, a certification that the use of such missile—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> would result in cost savings to the Federal Government when compared to the cost of acquiring space transportation services from United States commercial providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meets all mission requirements of the agency, including performance, schedule, and risk requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is consistent with international obligations of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is approved by the Secretary of Defense or the designee of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception to requirement that certification be transmitted 30 days before conversion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement under paragraph (1) that the certification described in that paragraph must be transmitted at least 30 days before conversion of the missile shall not apply if the Secretary of Defense determines that compliance with that requirement would be inconsistent with meeting immediate national security requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Missiles Referred to</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The missiles referred to in this section are missiles owned by the United States that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> were formerly used by the Department of Defense for national defense purposes as intercontinental ballistic missiles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have been declared excess to United States national defense needs and are in compliance with international obligations of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3400</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>