<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 603—</num>
<heading>REMOTE SENSING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 60301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Geospatial information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “geospatial information” means knowledge of the nature and distribution of physical and cultural features on the landscape based on analysis of data from airborne or spaceborne platforms or other types and sources of data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">High resolution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “high resolution” means resolution better than five meters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Institution of higher education</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60302.</num>
<heading> General responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop a sustained relationship with the United States commercial remote sensing industry and, consistent with applicable policies and law, to the maximum practicable, rely on their services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in conjunction with United States industry and universities, research, develop, and demonstrate prototype Earth science applications to enhance Federal, State, local, and tribal governments’ use of government and commercial remote sensing data, technologies, and other sources of geospatial information for improved decision support to address their needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60303.</num>
<heading> Pilot projects to encourage public sector applications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish a program of grants for competitively awarded pilot projects to explore the integrated use of sources of remote sensing and other geospatial information to address State, local, regional, and tribal agency needs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preferred Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In awarding grants under this section, the Administrator shall give preference to projects that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make use of commercial data sets, including high resolution commercial satellite imagery and derived satellite data products, existing public data sets where commercial data sets are not available or applicable, or the fusion of such data sets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> integrate multiple sources of geospatial information, such as geographic information system data, satellite-provided positioning data, and remotely sensed data, in innovative ways;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include funds or in-kind contributions from non-Federal sources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> involve the participation of commercial entities that process raw or lightly processed data, often merging that data with other geospatial information, to create data products that have significant value added to the original data; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> taken together demonstrate as diverse a set of public sector applications as possible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall seek opportunities to assist—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the development of commercial applications potentially available from the remote sensing industry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> State, local, regional, and tribal agencies in applying remote sensing and other geospatial information technologies for growth management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assistance for a pilot project under subsection (a) shall be provided for a period not to exceed 3 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each recipient of a grant under subsection (a) shall transmit a report to the Administrator on the results of the pilot project within 180 days of the completion of that project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Workshop</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each recipient of a grant under subsection (a) shall, not later than 180 days after the completion of the pilot project, conduct at least one workshop for potential users to disseminate the lessons learned from the pilot project as widely as feasible.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall issue regulations establishing application, selection, and implementation procedures for pilot projects, and guidelines for reports and workshops required by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60304.</num>
<heading> Program evaluation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advisory Committee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish an advisory committee, consisting of individuals with appropriate expertise in State, local, regional, and tribal agencies, the university research community, and the remote sensing and other geospatial information industries, to monitor the program established under <ref>section 60303 of this title</ref>. The advisory committee shall consult with the Federal Geographic Data Committee and other appropriate industry representatives and organizations. Notwithstanding <ref>section 1013 of title 5</ref>, the advisory committee established under this subsection shall remain in effect until the termination of the program under <ref>section 60303 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effectiveness Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>, the Administrator shall transmit to Congress an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program established under <ref>section 60303 of this title</ref> in exploring and promoting the integrated use of sources of remote sensing and other geospatial information to address State, local, regional, and tribal agency needs. Such evaluation shall have been conducted by an independent entity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3424</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(326)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60305.</num>
<heading> Data availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that the results of each of the pilot projects completed under <ref>section 60303 of this title</ref> shall be retrievable through an electronic, internet-accessible database.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3424</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60306.</num>
<heading> Education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish an educational outreach program to increase awareness at institutions of higher education and State, local, regional, and tribal agencies of the potential applications of remote sensing and other geospatial information and awareness of the need for geospatial workforce development.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3424</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>