<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 303—</num>
<heading>CONTRACTING AND PROCUREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 30301.</num>
<heading> Guaranteed customer base</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No amount appropriated to the Administration may be used to fund grants, contracts, or other agreements with an expected duration of more than one year, when a primary effect of the grant, contract, or agreement is to provide a guaranteed customer base for or establish an anchor tenancy in new commercial space hardware or services unless an appropriations Act specifies the new commercial space hardware or services to be developed or used, or the grant, contract, or agreement is otherwise identified in such Act.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3363</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30302.</num>
<heading> Quality assurance personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Administration Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person providing articles to the Administration under a contract entered into after <date date="1991-12-09">December 9, 1991</date>, may not exclude Administration quality assurance personnel from work sites except as provided in a contract provision that has been submitted to Congress as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administration shall not enter into any contract which permits the exclusion of Administration quality assurance personnel from work sites unless the Administrator has submitted a copy of the provision permitting such exclusion to Congress at least 60 days before entering into the contract.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3363</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30303.</num>
<heading> Tracking and data relay satellite services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administration is authorized, when so provided in an appropriation Act, to enter into and to maintain a contract for tracking and data relay satellite services. Such services shall be furnished to the Administration in accordance with applicable authorization and appropriations Acts. The Government shall incur no costs under such contract prior to the furnishing of such services except that the contract may provide for the payment for contingent liability of the Government which may accrue in the event the Government should decide for its convenience to terminate the contract before the end of the period of the contract. Facilities which may be required in the performance of the contract may be constructed on Government-owned lands if there is included in the contract a provision under which the Government may acquire title to the facilities, under terms and conditions agreed upon in the contract, upon termination of the contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall in January of each year report to the Committee on Science and Technology and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate the projected aggregate contingent liability of the Government under termination provisions of any contract authorized in this section through the next fiscal year. The authority of the Administration to enter into and to maintain the contract authorized hereunder shall remain in effect unless repealed by legislation enacted by Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3363</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30304.</num>
<heading> Award of contracts to small businesses and disadvantaged individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall annually establish a goal of at least 8 percent of the total value of prime and subcontracts awarded in support of authorized programs, including the space station by the time operational status is obtained, which funds will be made available to small business concerns or other organizations owned or controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals (within the meaning of paragraphs (5) and (6) of section 8(a) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(a)</ref>)), including Historically Black Colleges and Universities that are part B institutions (as defined in section 322(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1061(2)</ref>)), Hispanic-serving institutions (as defined in section 502(a)(5) of that Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)(5)</ref>)), Tribal Colleges or Universities (as defined in section 316(b)(3) of that Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)(3)</ref>)), Alaska Native-serving institutions (as defined in section 317(b)(2) of that Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)(2)</ref>)), Native Hawaiian-serving institutions (as defined in section 317(b)(4) of that Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)(4)</ref>)), and minority educational institutions (as defined by the Secretary of Education pursuant to the General Education Provisions Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1221</ref> et seq.)).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3364</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30305.</num>
<heading> Outreach program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administration shall competitively select an organization to partner with Administration centers, aerospace contractors, and academic institutions to carry out a program to help promote the competitiveness of small, minority-owned, and women-owned businesses in communities across the United States through enhanced insight into the technologies of the Administration’s space and aeronautics programs. The program shall support the mission of the Administration’s Innovative Partnerships Program with its emphasis on joint partnerships with industry, academia, government agencies, and national laboratories.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Structure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the program described in subsection (a), the organization shall support the mission of the Administration’s Innovative Partnerships Program by undertaking the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Facilitating enhanced insight</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Facilitating the enhanced insight of the private sector into the Administration’s technologies in order to increase the competitiveness of the private sector in producing viable commercial products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Creating network</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Creating a network of academic institutions, aerospace contractors, and Administration centers that will commit to donating appropriate technical assistance to small businesses, giving preference to socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, and HUBZone small business concerns. This paragraph shall not apply to any contracting actions entered into or taken by the Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Creating network of economic development organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Creating a network of economic development organizations to increase the awareness and enhance the effectiveness of the program nationwide.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than one year after <date date="2008-10-15">October 15, 2008</date>, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate describing the efforts and accomplishments of the program established under subsection (a) in support of the Administration’s Innovative Partnerships Program. As part of the report, the Administrator shall provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> data on the number of small businesses receiving assistance, jobs created and retained, and volunteer hours donated by the Administration, contractors, and academic institutions nationwide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an estimate of the total dollar value of the economic impact made by small businesses that received technical assistance through the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an accounting of the use of funds appropriated for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3364</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30306.</num>
<heading> Small business contracting</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In consultation with the Small Business Administration, the Administrator shall develop a plan to maximize the number and amount of contracts awarded to small business concerns (within the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>)) and to meet established contracting goals for such concerns.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish as a priority meeting the contracting goals developed in conjunction with the Small Business Administration to maximize the amount of prime contracts, as measured in dollars, awarded in each fiscal year by the Administration to small business concerns (within the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>)).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30307.</num>
<heading> Requirement for independent cost analysis</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “implementation” means all activity in the life cycle of a project after preliminary design, independent assessment of the preliminary design, and approval to proceed into implementation, including critical design, development, certification, launch, operations, disposal of assets, and, for technology programs, development, testing, analysis, and communication of the results.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before any funds may be obligated for implementation of a project that is projected to cost more than $250,000,000 in total project costs, the Administrator shall conduct and consider an independent life-cycle cost analysis of the project and shall report the results to Congress. In developing cost accounting and reporting standards for carrying out this section, the Administrator shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with other laws, solicit the advice of experts outside of the Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30308.</num>
<heading> Cost effectiveness calculations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial provider</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “commercial provider” means any person providing space transportation services or other space-related activities, the primary control of which is held by persons other than a Federal, State, local, or foreign government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise required by law, in calculating the cost effectiveness of the cost of the Administration engaging in an activity as compared to a commercial provider, the Administrator shall compare the cost of the Administration engaging in the activity using full cost accounting principles with the price the commercial provider will charge for such activity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30309.</num>
<heading> Use of abandoned and underutilized buildings, grounds, and facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Depressed Communities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “depressed communities” means rural and urban communities that are relatively depressed, in terms of age of housing, extent of poverty, growth of per capita income, extent of unemployment, job lag, or surplus labor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In any case in which the Administrator considers the purchase, lease, or expansion of a facility to meet requirements of the Administration, the Administrator shall consider whether those requirements could be met by the use of one of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Abandoned or underutilized buildings, grounds, and facilities in depressed communities that can be converted to Administration usage at a reasonable cost, as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any military installation that is closed or being closed, or any facility at such an installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Any other facility or part of a facility that the Administrator determines to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> owned or leased by the United States for the use of another agency of the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> considered by the head of the agency involved to be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> excess to the needs of that agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> underutilized by that agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30310.</num>
<heading> Exception to alternative fuel procurement requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Section 526(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 17142(a)</ref>) does not prohibit the Administration from entering into a contract to purchase a generally available fuel that is not an alternative or synthetic fuel or predominantly produced from a nonconventional petroleum source, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the contract does not specifically require the contractor to provide an alternative or synthetic fuel or fuel from a nonconventional petroleum source;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the purpose of the contract is not to obtain an alternative or synthetic fuel or fuel from a nonconventional petroleum source; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the contract does not provide incentives for a refinery upgrade or expansion to allow a refinery to use or increase its use of fuel from a nonconventional petroleum source.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>