<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 509—</num>
<heading>COMMERCIAL SPACE LAUNCH ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50901.</num>
<heading> Findings and purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the peaceful uses of outer space continue to be of great value and to offer benefits to all mankind;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> private applications of space technology have achieved a significant level of commercial and economic activity and offer the potential for growth in the future, particularly in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> new and innovative equipment and services are being sought, produced, and offered by entrepreneurs in telecommunications, information services, microgravity research, human space flight, and remote sensing technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the private sector in the United States has the capability of developing and providing private launching, reentry, and associated services that would complement the launching, reentry, and associated capabilities of the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the development of commercial launch vehicles, reentry vehicles, and associated services would enable the United States to retain its competitive position internationally, contributing to the national interest and economic well-being of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> providing launch services and reentry services by the private sector is consistent with the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States and would be facilitated by stable, minimal, and appropriate regulatory guidelines that are fairly and expeditiously applied;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the United States should encourage private sector launches, reentries, and associated services and, only to the extent necessary, regulate those launches, reentries, and services to ensure compliance with international obligations of the United States and to protect the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> space transportation, including the establishment and operation of launch sites, reentry sites, and complementary facilities, the providing of launch services and reentry services, the establishment of support facilities, and the providing of support services, is an important element of the transportation system of the United States, and in connection with the commerce of the United States there is a need to develop a strong space transportation infrastructure with significant private sector involvement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the participation of State governments in encouraging and facilitating private sector involvement in space-related activity, particularly through the establishment of a space transportation-related infrastructure, including launch sites, reentry sites, complementary facilities, and launch site and reentry site support facilities, is in the national interest and is of significant public benefit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the goal of safely opening space to the American people and their private commercial, scientific, and cultural enterprises should guide Federal space investments, policies, and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> private industry has begun to develop commercial launch vehicles capable of carrying human beings into space and greater private investment in these efforts will stimulate the Nation’s commercial space transportation industry as a whole;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> space transportation is inherently risky, and the future of the commercial human space flight industry will depend on its ability to continually improve its safety performance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> a critical area of responsibility for the Department of Transportation is to regulate the operations and safety of the emerging commercial human space flight industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the public interest is served by creating a clear legal, regulatory, and safety regime for commercial human space flight; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> the regulatory standards governing human space flight must evolve as the industry matures so that regulations neither stifle technology development nor expose crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants to avoidable risks as the public comes to expect greater safety for crew, government astronauts, and space flight participants from the industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to promote economic growth and entrepreneurial activity through use of the space environment for peaceful purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to encourage the United States private sector to provide launch vehicles, reentry vehicles, and associated services by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> simplifying and expediting the issuance and transfer of commercial licenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitating and encouraging the use of Government-developed space technology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promoting the continuous improvement of the safety of launch vehicles designed to carry humans, including through the issuance of regulations, to the extent permitted by this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide that the Secretary of Transportation is to oversee and coordinate the conduct of commercial launch and reentry operations, issue permits and commercial licenses and transfer commercial licenses authorizing those operations, and protect the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to facilitate the strengthening and expansion of the United States space transportation infrastructure, including the enhancement of United States launch sites and launch-site support facilities, and development of reentry sites, with Government, State, and private sector involvement, to support the full range of United States space-related activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1330</ref>, <ref>§ 70101 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2846</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3974</ref>; renumbered § 70101 then <ref>§ 50901 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(A), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 112(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50902.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “citizen of the United States” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual who is a citizen of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an entity organized or existing under the laws of the United States or a State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an entity organized or existing under the laws of a foreign country if the controlling interest (as defined by the Secretary of Transportation) is held by an individual or entity described in subclause (A) or (B) of this clause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “crew” means any employee of a licensee or transferee, or of a contractor or subcontractor of a licensee or transferee, who performs activities in the course of that employment directly relating to the launch, reentry, or other operation of or in a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle that carries human beings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “executive agency” has the same meaning given that term in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “government astronaut” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is designated by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration under section 20113(n);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is carried within a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle in the course of his or her employment, which may include performance of activities directly relating to the launch, reentry, or other operation of the launch vehicle or reentry vehicle; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> is either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an employee of the United States Government, including the uniformed services, engaged in the performance of a Federal function under authority of law or an Executive act; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an international partner astronaut.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “international partner astronaut” means an individual designated under Article 11 of the International Space Station Intergovernmental Agreement, by a partner to that agreement other than the United States, as qualified to serve as an International Space Station crew member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “International Space Station Intergovernmental Agreement” means the Agreement Concerning Cooperation on the International Space Station, signed at Washington <date date="1998-01-29">January 29, 1998</date> (TIAS 12927).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> “launch” means to place or try to place a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle and any payload or human being from Earth—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in a suborbital trajectory;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in Earth orbit in outer space; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> otherwise in outer space,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">including activities involved in the preparation of a launch vehicle or payload for launch, when those activities take place at a launch site in the United States.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “launch property” means an item built for, or used in, the launch preparation or launch of a launch vehicle.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> “launch services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> activities involved in the preparation of a launch vehicle, payload, crew (including crew training), government astronaut, or space flight participant for launch; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the conduct of a launch.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “launch site” means the location on Earth from which a launch takes place (as defined in a license the Secretary issues or transfers under this chapter) and necessary facilities at that location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> “launch vehicle” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a vehicle built to operate in, or place a payload or human beings in, outer space; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a suborbital rocket.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “obtrusive space advertising” means advertising in outer space that is capable of being recognized by a human being on the surface of the Earth without the aid of a telescope or other technological device.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> “payload” means an object that a person undertakes to place in outer space by means of a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle, including components of the vehicle specifically designed or adapted for that object.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> except in section 50904(c), “permit” means an experimental permit issued under section 50906.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> “person” means an individual and an entity organized or existing under the laws of a State or country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> “reenter” and “reentry” mean to return or attempt to return, purposefully, a reentry vehicle and its payload or human beings, if any, from Earth orbit or from outer space to Earth.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<chapeau> “reentry services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> activities involved in the preparation of a reentry vehicle and payload, crew (including crew training), government astronaut, or space flight participant, if any, for reentry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the conduct of a reentry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> “reentry site” means the location on Earth to which a reentry vehicle is intended to return (as defined in a license the Secretary issues or transfers under this chapter).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> “reentry vehicle” means a vehicle designed to return from Earth orbit or outer space to Earth, or a reusable launch vehicle designed to return from Earth orbit or outer space to Earth, substantially intact.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> “space flight participant” means an individual, who is not crew or a government astronaut, carried within a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<chapeau> “space support vehicle flight” means a flight in the air that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not a launch or reentry; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is conducted by a space support vehicle.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<chapeau> “space support vehicle” means a vehicle that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a launch vehicle;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a reentry vehicle; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a component of a launch or reentry vehicle.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> unless and until regulations take effect under section 50922(c)(2), “suborbital rocket” means a vehicle, rocket-propelled in whole or in part, intended for flight on a suborbital trajectory, and the thrust of which is greater than its lift for the majority of the rocket-powered portion of its ascent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> “suborbital trajectory” means the intentional flight path of a launch vehicle, reentry vehicle, or any portion thereof, whose vacuum instantaneous impact point does not leave the surface of the Earth.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<chapeau> “third party” means a person except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States Government or the Government’s contractors or subcontractors involved in launch services or reentry services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a licensee or transferee under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a licensee’s or transferee’s contractors, subcontractors, or customers involved in launch services or reentry services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the customer’s contractors or subcontractors involved in launch services or reentry services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<content> “United States” means the States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1331</ref>, <ref>§ 70102 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(92)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2846</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–391, title III, § 322(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3975</ref>; renumbered § 70102 then <ref>§ 50902 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(B), (5)(A), (B), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 112(c)</ref>, (e)–(j), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 712</ref>, 713; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50903.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Facilitating Commercial Launches and Reentries</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> encourage, facilitate, and promote commercial space launches and reentries by the private sector, including those involving space flight participants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> take actions to facilitate private sector involvement in commercial space transportation activity, and to promote public-private partnerships involving the United States Government, State governments, and the private sector to build, expand, modernize, or operate a space launch and reentry infrastructure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the responsibilities under subsection (b), the Secretary shall encourage, facilitate, and promote the continuous improvement of the safety of launch vehicles designed to carry humans, and the Secretary may, consistent with this chapter, promulgate regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive Agency Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When necessary, the head of an executive agency shall assist the Secretary in carrying out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1332</ref>, <ref>§ 70103 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2847</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3976</ref>; renumbered § 70103 then <ref>§ 50903 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(C), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50904.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on launches, operations, and reentries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A license issued or transferred under this chapter, or a permit, is required for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for a person to launch a launch vehicle or to operate a launch site or reentry site, or to reenter a reentry vehicle, in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for a citizen of the United States (as defined in section 50902(1)(A) or (B) of this title) to launch a launch vehicle or to operate a launch site or reentry site, or to reenter a reentry vehicle, outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for a citizen of the United States (as defined in <ref>section 50902(1)(C) of this title</ref>) to launch a launch vehicle or to operate a launch site or reentry site, or to reenter a reentry vehicle, outside the United States and outside the territory of a foreign country unless there is an agreement between the United States Government and the government of the foreign country providing that the government of the foreign country has jurisdiction over the launch or operation or reentry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for a citizen of the United States (as defined in <ref>section 50902(1)(C) of this title</ref>) to launch a launch vehicle or to operate a launch site or reentry site, or to reenter a reentry vehicle, in the territory of a foreign country if there is an agreement between the United States Government and the government of the foreign country providing that the United States Government has jurisdiction over the launch or operation or reentry.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding this subsection, a permit shall not authorize a person to operate a launch site or reentry site.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance With Payload Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The holder of a license or permit under this chapter may launch or reenter a payload only if the payload complies with all requirements of the laws of the United States related to launching or reentering a payload.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preventing Launches and Reentries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish whether all required licenses, authorizations, and permits required for a payload have been obtained. If no license, authorization, or permit is required, the Secretary may prevent the launch or reentry if the Secretary decides the launch or reentry would jeopardize the public health and safety, safety of property, or national security or foreign policy interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single License or Permit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that only 1 license or permit is required from the Department of Transportation to conduct activities involving crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants, including launch and reentry, for which a license or permit is required under this chapter. The Secretary shall ensure that all Department of Transportation regulations relevant to the licensed or permitted activity are satisfied.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1332</ref>, <ref>§ 70104 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2847</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(3)</ref>–(5), <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3976</ref>; renumbered § 70104 then <ref>§ 50904 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(D), (5)(C)–(E), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 112(k)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 713</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50905.</num>
<heading> License applications and requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person may apply to the Secretary of Transportation for a license or transfer of a license under this chapter in the form and way the Secretary prescribes. Consistent with the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States, the Secretary, not later than 180 days after accepting an application in accordance with criteria established pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(D),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> shall issue or transfer a license if the Secretary decides in writing that the applicant complies, and will continue to comply, with this chapter and regulations prescribed under this chapter. The Secretary shall inform the applicant of any pending issue and action required to resolve the issue if the Secretary has not made a decision not later than 120 days after accepting an application in accordance with criteria established pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(D).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> The Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a written notice not later than 30 days after any occurrence when the Secretary has not taken action on a license application within the deadline established by this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary may establish procedures for safety approvals of launch vehicles, reentry vehicles, safety systems, processes, services, or personnel (including approval procedures for the purpose of protecting the health and safety of crew, government astronauts, and space flight participants, to the extent permitted by subsections (b) and (c)) that may be used in conducting licensed commercial space launch or reentry activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this subsection, all requirements of the laws of the United States applicable to the launch of a launch vehicle or the operation of a launch site or a reentry site, or the reentry of a reentry vehicle, are requirements for a license or permit under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may prescribe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any term necessary to ensure compliance with this chapter, including on-site verification that a launch, operation, or reentry complies with representations stated in the application;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any additional requirement necessary to protect the public health and safety, safety of property, national security interests, and foreign policy interests of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> by regulation that a requirement of a law of the United States not be a requirement for a license or permit if the Secretary, after consulting with the head of the appropriate executive agency, decides that the requirement is not necessary to protect the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> additional license requirements, for a launch vehicle carrying a human being for compensation or hire, necessary to protect the health and safety of crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants, only if such requirements are imposed pursuant to final regulations issued in accordance with subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> regulations establishing criteria for accepting or rejecting an application for a license or permit under this chapter within 60 days after receipt of such application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive a requirement, including the requirement to obtain a license, for an individual applicant if the Secretary decides that the waiver is in the public interest and will not jeopardize the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States. The Secretary may not grant a waiver under this paragraph that would permit the launch or reentry of a launch vehicle or a reentry vehicle without a license or permit if a human being will be on board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The holder of a license or a permit under this chapter may launch or reenter crew only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the crew has received training and has satisfied medical or other standards specified in the license or permit in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the holder of the license or permit has informed any individual serving as crew in writing, prior to executing any contract or other arrangement to employ that individual (or, in the case of an individual already employed as of the date of enactment of the Commercial Space Launch Amendments Act of 2004, as early as possible, but in any event prior to any launch in which the individual will participate as crew), that the United States Government has not certified the launch vehicle as safe for carrying crew or space flight participants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the holder of the license or permit and crew have complied with all requirements of the laws of the United States that apply to crew.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The holder of a license or a permit under this chapter may launch or reenter a space flight participant only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary, the holder of the license or permit has informed the space flight participant in writing about the risks of the launch and reentry, including the safety record of the launch or reentry vehicle type, and the Secretary has informed the space flight participant in writing of any relevant information related to risk or probable loss during each phase of flight gathered by the Secretary in making the determination required by section 50914(a)(2) and (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the holder of the license or permit has informed any space flight participant in writing, prior to receiving any compensation from that space flight participant or (in the case of a space flight participant not providing compensation) otherwise concluding any agreement to fly that space flight participant, that the United States Government has not certified the launch vehicle as safe for carrying crew or space flight participants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary, the space flight participant has provided written informed consent to participate in the launch and reentry and written certification of compliance with any regulations promulgated under paragraph (6)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the holder of the license or permit has complied with any regulations promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (6).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary may issue regulations requiring space flight participants to undergo an appropriate physical examination prior to a launch or reentry under this chapter. This subparagraph shall cease to be in effect three years after the date of enactment of the Commercial Space Launch Amendments Act of 2004.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may issue additional regulations setting reasonable requirements for space flight participants, including medical and training requirements. Such regulations shall not be effective before the expiration of 3 years after the date of enactment of the Commercial Space Launch Amendments Act of 2004.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Safety Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may issue regulations governing the design or operation of a launch vehicle to protect the health and safety of crew, government astronauts, and space flight participants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Regulations issued under this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describe how such regulations would be applied when the Secretary is determining whether to issue a license under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> apply only to launches in which a vehicle will be carrying a human being for compensation or hire;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> be limited to restricting or prohibiting design features or operating practices that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have resulted in a serious or fatal injury (as defined in 49 CFR 830, as in effect on <date date="2004-11-10">November 10, 2004</date>) to crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants during a licensed or permitted commercial human space flight; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> contributed to an unplanned event or series of events during a licensed or permitted commercial human space flight that posed a high risk of causing a serious or fatal injury (as defined in 49 CFR 830, as in effect on <date date="2004-11-10">November 10, 2004</date>) to crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> be issued with a description of the instance or instances when the design feature or operating practice being restricted or prohibited contributed to a result or event described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Facilitation of standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall continue to work with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, or its successor organization, to facilitate the development of voluntary industry consensus standards based on recommended best practices to improve the safety of crew, government astronauts, and space flight participants as the commercial space sector continues to mature.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Communication and transparency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to discuss potential regulatory approaches, potential performance standards, or any other topic related to this subsection with the commercial space industry, including observations, findings, and recommendations from the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, or its successor organization, prior to the issuance of a notice of proposed rulemaking. Such discussions shall not be construed to permit the Secretary to promulgate industry regulations except as otherwise provided in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Interim voluntary industry consensus standards reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2016-12-31">December 31, 2016</date>, and every 30 months thereafter until <date date="2021-12-31">December 31, 2021</date>, the Secretary, in consultation and coordination with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, or its successor organization, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the progress of the commercial space transportation industry in developing voluntary industry consensus standards that promote best practices to improve industry safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report shall include, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any voluntary industry consensus standards that have been accepted by the industry at large;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the identification of areas that have the potential to become voluntary industry consensus standards that are currently under consideration by the industry at large;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an assessment from the Secretary on the general progress of the industry in adopting voluntary industry consensus standards;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any lessons learned about voluntary industry consensus standards, best practices, and commercial space launch operations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any lessons learned associated with the development, potential application, and acceptance of voluntary industry consensus standards, best practices, and commercial space launch operations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> recommendations, findings, or observations from the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, or its successor organization, on the progress of the industry in developing voluntary industry consensus standards that promote best practices to improve industry safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the SPACE Act of 2015, the Secretary, in consultation and coordination with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, or its successor organization, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report specifying key industry metrics that might indicate readiness of the commercial space sector and the Department of Transportation to transition to a safety framework that may include regulations under paragraph (9) that considers space flight participant, government astronaut, and crew safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than March 31 of each of 2018 and 2022, the Secretary, in consultation and coordination with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, or its successor organization, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that identifies the activities, described in this subsection and subsection (d) most appropriate for a new safety framework that may include regulatory action, if any, and a proposed transition plan for such safety framework.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Independent review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2022-12-31">December 31, 2022</date>, an independent systems engineering and technical assistance organization or standards development organization contracted by the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives an assessment of the readiness of the commercial space industry and the Federal Government to transition to a safety framework that may include regulations. As part of the review, the contracted organization shall evaluate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the progress of the commercial space industry in adopting voluntary industry consensus standards as reported by the Secretary in the interim assessments included in the reports under paragraph (5);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the progress of the commercial space industry toward meeting the key industry metrics identified by the report under paragraph (6), including the knowledge and operational experience obtained by the commercial space industry while providing services for compensation or hire; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether the areas identified in the reports under paragraph (5) are appropriate for regulatory action, or further development of voluntary industry consensus standards, considering the progress evaluated in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Learning period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Beginning on <date date="2028-01-01">January 1, 2028</date>, the Secretary may propose regulations under this subsection without regard to subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (2). The development of any such regulations shall take into consideration the evolving standards of the commercial space flight industry as identified in the reports published under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to issue requirements or regulations to protect the public health and safety, safety of property, national security interests, and foreign policy interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures and Timetables</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish procedures and timetables that expedite review of a license or permit application and reduce the regulatory burden for an applicant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1333</ref>, <ref>§ 70105 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(6)</ref>–(15), <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3976–3979</ref>; renumbered § 70105 then <ref>§ 50905 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(E), (5)(F), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title VIII, § 827</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 133</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–55, title I, § 102(e)</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I</ref>, §§ 111, 112(<i>l</i>), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 709</ref>, 713; <ref>Pub. L. 118–15, div. B, title II, § 2202(k)</ref>, <date date="2023-09-30">Sept. 30, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–34, title I, § 102(k)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-26">Dec. 26, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 1114</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–41, title I, § 102(k)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-08">Mar. 8, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 22</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LVII, § 5702(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50906.</num>
<heading> Experimental permits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A person may apply to the Secretary of Transportation for an experimental permit under this section in the form and manner the Secretary prescribes. Consistent with the protection of the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States, the Secretary, not later than 120 days after receiving an application pursuant to this section, shall issue a permit if the Secretary decides in writing that the applicant complies, and will continue to comply, with this chapter and regulations prescribed under this chapter. The Secretary shall inform the applicant of any pending issue and action required to resolve the issue if the Secretary has not made a decision not later than 90 days after receiving an application. The Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a written notice not later than 15 days after any occurrence when the Secretary has failed to act on a permit within the deadline established by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may establish procedures for safety approvals of launch vehicles, reentry vehicles, safety systems, processes, services, or personnel that may be used in conducting commercial space launch or reentry activities pursuant to a permit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In order to encourage the development of a commercial space flight industry, the Secretary may when issuing permits use the authority granted under section 50905(b)(2)(C).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may issue a permit only for reusable suborbital rockets or reusable launch vehicles that will be launched into a suborbital trajectory or reentered under that permit solely for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> research and development to test design concepts, equipment, or operating techniques;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> showing compliance with requirements as part of the process for obtaining a license under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> crew training for a launch or reentry using the design of the rocket or vehicle for which the permit would be issued.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> Permits issued under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> authorize an unlimited number of launches and reentries for a particular suborbital rocket or suborbital rocket design, or for a particular reusable launch vehicle or reusable launch vehicle design, for the uses described in subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specify the type of modifications that may be made to the suborbital rocket or launch vehicle without changing the design to an extent that would invalidate the permit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Permits shall not be transferable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Secretary may issue a permit under this section notwithstanding any license issued under this chapter. The issuance of a license under this chapter may not invalidate a permit issued under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> No person may operate a reusable suborbital rocket or reusable launch vehicle under a permit for carrying any property or human being for compensation or hire.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of sections 50907, 50908, 50909, 50910, 50912, 50914, 50917, 50918, 50919, and 50923 of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a permit shall be considered a license;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the holder of a permit shall be considered a licensee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a vehicle operating under a permit shall be considered to be licensed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the issuance of a permit shall be considered licensing.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection shall not be construed to allow the transfer of a permit.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(16)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3979</ref>, <ref>§ 70105a of title 49</ref>; renumbered § 70105a then <ref>§ 50906 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(F), (5)(G), (H), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50907.</num>
<heading> Monitoring activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A licensee under this chapter must allow the Secretary of Transportation to place an officer or employee of the United States Government or another individual as an observer at a launch site or reentry site the licensee uses, at a production facility or assembly site a contractor of the licensee uses to produce or assemble a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle, at a site not owned or operated by the Federal Government or a foreign government used for crew, government astronaut, or space flight participant training, or at a site at which a payload is integrated with a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle. The observer will monitor the activity of the licensee or contractor at the time and to the extent the Secretary considers reasonable to ensure compliance with the license or to carry out the duties of the Secretary under sections 50904(c), 50905, and 50906 of this title. A licensee must cooperate with an observer carrying out this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent provided in advance in an appropriation law, the Secretary may make a contract with a person to carry out subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1334</ref>, <ref>§ 70106 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(17)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3980</ref>; renumbered § 70106 then <ref>§ 50907 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(G), (5)(I), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 112(m)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 713</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50908.</num>
<heading> Effective periods, and modifications, suspensions, and revocations, of licenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Periods of Licenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall specify the period for which a license issued or transferred under this chapter is in effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modifications</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> On the initiative of the Secretary or on application of the licensee, the Secretary may modify a license issued or transferred under this chapter if the Secretary decides the modification will comply with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall modify a license issued or transferred under this chapter whenever a modification is needed for the license to be in conformity with a regulation that was issued pursuant to section 50905(c) after the issuance of the license. This paragraph shall not apply to permits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Suspensions and Revocations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may suspend or revoke a license if the Secretary decides that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the licensee has not complied substantially with a requirement of this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the suspension or revocation is necessary to protect the public health and safety, the safety of property, or a national security or foreign policy interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Suspensions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may suspend a license when a previous launch or reentry under the license has resulted in a serious or fatal injury (as defined in 49 CFR 830, as in effect on <date date="2004-11-10">November 10, 2004</date>) to any human being and the Secretary has determined that continued operations under the license are likely to cause additional serious or fatal injury (as defined in 49 CFR 830, as in effect on <date date="2004-11-10">November 10, 2004</date>) to any human being.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any suspension imposed under this subsection shall be for as brief a period as possible and, in any event, shall cease when the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has determined that the licensee has taken sufficient steps to reduce the likelihood of a recurrence of the serious or fatal injury; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has modified the license pursuant to subsection (b) to sufficiently reduce the likelihood of a recurrence of the serious or fatal injury.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection shall not apply to permits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Periods of Modifications, Suspensions, and Revocations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless the Secretary specifies otherwise, a modification, suspension, or revocation under this section takes effect immediately and remains in effect during a review under <ref>section 50912 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall notify the licensee in writing of the decision of the Secretary under this section and any action the Secretary takes or proposes to take based on the decision.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1334</ref>, <ref>§ 70107 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(18)</ref>, (19), <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3980</ref>; renumbered § 70107 then <ref>§ 50908 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(H), (5)(J), (K), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 112(n)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 713</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50909.</num>
<heading> Prohibition, suspension, and end of launches, operation of launch sites and reentry sites, and reentries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation may prohibit, suspend, or end immediately the launch of a launch vehicle or the operation of a launch site or reentry site, or reentry of a reentry vehicle, licensed under this chapter if the Secretary decides the launch or operation or reentry is detrimental to the public health and safety, the safety of property, or a national security or foreign policy interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Periods of Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An order under this section takes effect immediately and remains in effect during a review under <ref>section 50912 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1334</ref>, <ref>§ 70108 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2848</ref>; renumbered § 70108 then <ref>§ 50909 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(I), (5)(L), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50910.</num>
<heading> Preemption of scheduled launches or reentries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With the cooperation of the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Secretary of Transportation shall act to ensure that a launch or reentry of a payload is not preempted from access to a United States Government launch site, reentry site, or launch property, except for imperative national need, when a launch date commitment or reentry date commitment from the Government has been obtained for a launch or reentry licensed under this chapter. A licensee or transferee preempted from access to a launch site, reentry site, or launch property does not have to pay the Government any amount for launch services, or services related to a reentry, attributable only to the scheduled launch or reentry prevented by the preemption.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Imperative National Need Decisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Defense or the Administrator shall decide when an imperative national need requires preemption under subsection (a) of this section. That decision may not be delegated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In cooperation with the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Defense or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall submit to Congress not later than 7 days after a decision to preempt under subsection (a) of this section, a report that includes an explanation of the circumstances justifying the decision and a schedule for ensuring the prompt launching or reentry of a preempted payload.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1335</ref>, <ref>§ 70109 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2849</ref>; renumbered § 70109 then <ref>§ 50910 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(J), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50911.</num>
<heading> Space advertising</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Licensing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter or any other provision of law, the Secretary may not, for the launch of a payload containing any material to be used for the purposes of obtrusive space advertising—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue or transfer a license under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> waive the license requirements of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Launching</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No holder of a license under this chapter may launch a payload containing any material to be used for purposes of obtrusive space advertising.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial Space Advertising</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall apply to nonobtrusive commercial space advertising, including advertising on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> commercial space transportation vehicles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> space infrastructure payloads;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> space launch facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> launch support facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–391, title III, § 322(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1598</ref>, <ref>§ 70109a of title 49</ref>; renumbered § 70109a then <ref>§ 50911 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(K), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50912.</num>
<heading> Administrative hearings and judicial review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Hearings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall provide an opportunity for a hearing on the record to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an applicant under this chapter, for a decision of the Secretary under section 50905(a) or 50906 of this title to issue or transfer a license with terms or deny the issuance or transfer of a license;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an owner or operator of a payload under this chapter, for a decision of the Secretary under <ref>section 50904(c) of this title</ref> to prevent the launch or reentry of the payload; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a licensee under this chapter, for a decision of the Secretary under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 50908(b) or (c) of this title to modify, suspend, or revoke a license; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 50909(a) of this title</ref> to prohibit, suspend, or end a launch or operation of a launch site or reentry site, or reentry of a reentry vehicle, licensed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A final action of the Secretary under this chapter is subject to judicial review as provided in chapter 7 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1335</ref>, <ref>§ 70110 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(20)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3981</ref>; renumbered § 70110 then <ref>§ 50912 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(L), (5)(M)–(P), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50913.</num>
<heading> Acquiring United States Government property and services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements and Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Transportation shall facilitate and encourage the acquisition by the private sector and State governments of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> launch or reentry property of the United States Government that is excess or otherwise is not needed for public use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> launch services and reentry services, including utilities, of the Government otherwise not needed for public use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In acting under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary shall consider the commercial availability on reasonable terms of substantially equivalent launch property or launch services or reentry services from a domestic source, whether such source is located on or off a Federal range.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Price</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, “direct costs” means the actual costs that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> can be associated unambiguously with a commercial launch or reentry effort; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Government would not incur if there were no commercial launch or reentry effort.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In consultation with the Secretary, the head of the executive agency providing the property or service under subsection (a) of this section shall establish the price for the property or service. The price for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acquiring launch property by sale or transaction instead of sale is the fair market value;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acquiring launch property (except by sale or transaction instead of sale) is an amount equal to the direct costs, including specific wear and tear and property damage, the Government incurred because of acquisition of the property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> launch services or reentry services is an amount equal to the direct costs, including the basic pay of Government civilian and contractor personnel, the Government incurred because of acquisition of the services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure the establishment of uniform guidelines for, and consistent implementation of, this section by all Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection by Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may collect a payment under this section with the consent of the head of the executive agency establishing the price. Amounts collected under this subsection shall be deposited in the Treasury. Amounts (except for excess launch property) shall be credited to the appropriation from which the cost of providing the property or services was paid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection by Other Governmental Heads</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government may collect a payment for an activity involved in producing a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle, or the payload of either, for launch or reentry if the activity was agreed to by the owner or manufacturer of the launch vehicle, reentry vehicle, or payload.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1335</ref>, <ref>§ 70111 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2849</ref>; renumbered § 70111 then <ref>§ 50913 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(M), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50914.</num>
<heading> Liability insurance and financial responsibility requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When a launch or reentry license is issued or transferred under this chapter, the licensee or transferee shall obtain liability insurance or demonstrate financial responsibility in amounts to compensate for the maximum probable loss from claims by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a third party for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from an activity carried out under the license; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United States Government against a person for damage or loss to Government property resulting from an activity carried out under the license.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the amounts required under paragraph (1)(A) and (B) of this subsection, after consulting with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Secretary of the Air Force, and the heads of other appropriate executive agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For the total claims related to one launch or reentry, a licensee or transferee is not required to obtain insurance or demonstrate financial responsibility of more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> $500,000,000 under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $100,000,000 under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the maximum liability insurance available on the world market at reasonable cost if the amount is less than the applicable amount in clause (A)(i) or (ii) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> An insurance policy or demonstration of financial responsibility under this subsection shall protect the following, to the extent of their potential liability for involvement in launch services or reentry services, at no cost to the Government:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> executive agencies and personnel, contractors, and subcontractors of the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contractors, subcontractors, and customers of the licensee or transferee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> contractors and subcontractors of the customer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> space flight participants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (E) of paragraph (4) ceases to be effective <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reciprocal Waiver of Claims</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A launch or reentry license issued or transferred under this chapter shall contain a provision requiring the licensee or transferee to make a reciprocal waiver of claims with applicable parties involved in launch services or reentry services under which each party to the waiver agrees to be responsible for personal injury to, death of, or property damage or loss sustained by it or its own employees resulting from an activity carried out under the applicable license.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In this paragraph, the term “applicable parties” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contractors, subcontractors, and customers of the licensee or transferee;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> contractors and subcontractors of the customers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> space flight participants.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Clause (iii) of subparagraph (B) ceases to be effective <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation shall make, for the Government, executive agencies of the Government involved in launch services or reentry services, and contractors and subcontractors involved in launch services or reentry services, a reciprocal waiver of claims with the licensee or transferee, contractors, subcontractors, crew, space flight participants, and customers of the licensee or transferee, and contractors and subcontractors of the customers, involved in launch services or reentry services under which each party to the waiver agrees to be responsible for property damage or loss it sustains, or for personal injury to, death of, or property damage or loss sustained by its own employees or by space flight participants, resulting from an activity carried out under the applicable license. The waiver applies only to the extent that claims are more than the amount of insurance or demonstration of financial responsibility required under subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section. After consulting with the Administrator and the Secretary of the Air Force, the Secretary of Transportation may waive, for the Government and a department, agency, and instrumentality of the Government, the right to recover damages for damage or loss to Government property to the extent insurance is not available because of a policy exclusion the Secretary of Transportation decides is usual for the type of insurance involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Maximum Probable Losses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the maximum probable losses under subsection (a)(1)(A) and (B) of this section associated with an activity under a license not later than 90 days after a licensee or transferee requires a determination and submits all information the Secretary requires. The Secretary shall amend the determination as warranted by new information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than November 15 of each year, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives a report on current determinations made under subsection (c) of this section related to all issued licenses and the reasons for the determinations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than May 15 of each year, the Secretary of Transportation shall review the amounts specified in subsection (a)(3)(A) of this section and submit a report to Congress that contains proposed adjustments in the amounts to conform with changed liability expectations and availability of insurance on the world market. The proposed adjustment takes effect 30 days after a report is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Launches or Reentries Involving Government Facilities and Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish requirements consistent with this chapter for proof of financial responsibility and other assurances necessary to protect the Government and its executive agencies and personnel from liability, death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss as a result of a launch or operation of a launch site or reentry site or a reentry involving a facility or personnel of the Government. The Secretary may not relieve the Government of liability under this subsection for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from the willful misconduct of the Government or its agents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection and Crediting Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government shall collect a payment owed for damage or loss to Government property under its jurisdiction or control resulting from an activity carried out under a launch or reentry license issued or transferred under this chapter. The payment shall be credited to the current applicable appropriation, fund, or account of the department, agency, or instrumentality.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any claim by a third party or space flight participant for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from an activity carried out under the license shall be the exclusive jurisdiction of the Federal courts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1336</ref>, <ref>§ 70112 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(74)</ref>, (93), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3396</ref>, 3398; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2850</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(21)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3981</ref>; renumbered § 70112 then <ref>§ 50914 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(N), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I</ref>, §§ 103(a)(1), 106, 107, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 706</ref>, 707; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LVII, § 5702(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50915.</num>
<heading> Paying claims exceeding liability insurance and financial responsibility requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent provided in advance in an appropriation law or to the extent additional legislative authority is enacted providing for paying claims in a compensation plan submitted under subsection (d) of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall provide for the payment by the United States Government of a successful claim (including reasonable litigation or settlement expenses) of a third party against a person described in paragraph (3)(A) resulting from an activity carried out under the license issued or transferred under this chapter for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from an activity carried out under the license. However, claims may be paid under this section only to the extent the total amount of successful claims related to one launch or reentry—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is more than the amount of insurance or demonstration of financial responsibility required under <ref>section 50914(a)(1)(A) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not more than $1,500,000,000 (plus additional amounts necessary to reflect inflation occurring after <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>) above that insurance or financial responsibility amount.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not provide for paying a part of a claim for which death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss results from willful misconduct by the licensee or transferee. To the extent insurance required under <ref>section 50914(a)(1)(A) of this title</ref> is not available to cover a successful third party liability claim because of an insurance policy exclusion the Secretary decides is usual for the type of insurance involved, the Secretary may provide for paying the excluded claims without regard to the limitation contained in section 50914(a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A person described in this subparagraph is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a licensee or transferee under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a contractor, subcontractor, or customer of the licensee or transferee;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a contractor or subcontractor of a customer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a space flight participant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Clause (iv) of subparagraph (A) ceases to be effective <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice, Participation, and Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before a payment under subsection (a) of this section is made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notice must be given to the Government of a claim, or a civil action related to the claim, against a party described in subsection (a)(1) of this section for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Government must be given an opportunity to participate or assist in the defense of the claim or action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary must approve any part of a settlement to be paid out of appropriations of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withholding Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may withhold a payment under subsection (a) of this section if the Secretary certifies that the amount is not reasonable. However, the Secretary shall deem to be reasonable the amount of a claim finally decided by a court of competent jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Surveys, Reports, and Compensation Plans</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If as a result of an activity carried out under a license issued or transferred under this chapter the total of claims related to one launch or reentry is likely to be more than the amount of required insurance or demonstration of financial responsibility, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> survey the causes and extent of damage; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit expeditiously to Congress a report on the results of the survey.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 90 days after a court determination indicates that the liability for the total of claims related to one launch or reentry may be more than the required amount of insurance or demonstration of financial responsibility, the President, on the recommendation of the Secretary, shall submit to Congress a compensation plan that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> outlines the total dollar value of the claims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recommends sources of amounts to pay for the claims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> includes legislative language required to carry out the plan if additional legislative authority is required; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for a single event or incident, may not be for more than $1,500,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A compensation plan submitted to Congress under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have an identification number; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be submitted to the Senate and the House of Representatives on the same day and when the Senate and House are in session.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Resolutions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, “resolution”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a joint resolution of Congress the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress approves the compensation plan numbered _____ submitted to the Congress on _____ __, 20__.”, with the blank spaces being filled appropriately; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include a resolution that includes more than one compensation plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Senate shall consider under this subsection a compensation plan requiring additional appropriations or legislative authority not later than 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date on which the plan is submitted to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A resolution introduced in the Senate shall be referred immediately to a committee by the President of the Senate. All resolutions related to the same plan shall be referred to the same committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the committee of the Senate to which a resolution has been referred does not report the resolution within 20 calendar days after it is referred, a motion is in order to discharge the committee from further consideration of the resolution or to discharge the committee from further consideration of the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A motion to discharge may be made only by an individual favoring the resolution and is highly privileged (except that the motion may not be made after the committee has reported a resolution on the plan). Debate on the motion is limited to one hour, to be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the resolution. An amendment to the motion is not in order. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to is not in order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If the motion to discharge is agreed to or disagreed to, the motion may not be renewed and another motion to discharge the committee from another resolution on the same plan may not be made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> After a committee of the Senate reports, or is discharged from further consideration of, a resolution, a motion to proceed to the consideration of the resolution is in order at any time, even though a similar previous motion has been disagreed to. The motion is highly privileged and is not debatable. An amendment to the motion is not in order. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to is not in order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Debate on the resolution referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph is limited to not more than 10 hours, to be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the resolution. A motion further to limit debate is not debatable. An amendment to, or motion to recommit, the resolution is not in order. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the resolution is agreed to or disagreed to is not in order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The following shall be decided in the Senate without debate:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a motion to postpone related to the discharge from committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a motion to postpone consideration of a resolution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an appeal from a decision of the chair related to the application of the rules of the Senate to the procedures related to a resolution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies to a license issued or transferred under this chapter for which the Secretary receives a complete and valid application not later than <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>. This section does not apply to permits.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1338</ref>, <ref>§ 70113 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(94)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2850</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–74, title IV, § 433</ref>, <date date="1999-10-20">Oct. 20, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1097</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–377, § 1(a)(1) [title IV, § 429]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1441</ref>, 1441A–56; <ref>Pub. L. 106–405</ref>, §§ 5(b), 6(a), <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–428, § 1</ref>, <date date="2004-11-30">Nov. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2432</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(22)</ref>, (23), <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–125, § 1</ref>, <date date="2009-12-28">Dec. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3486</ref>; renumbered § 70113 then <ref>§ 50915 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(O), (5)(Q), (R), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–273, § 3</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, § 8</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 7</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I</ref>, §§ 102(d), 103(a)(2), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LVII, § 5702(3)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50916.</num>
<heading> Disclosing information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation, an officer or employee of the United States Government, or a person making a contract with the Secretary under <ref>section 50907(b) of this title</ref> may disclose information under this chapter that qualifies for an exemption under <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> or is designated as confidential by the person or head of the executive agency providing the information only if the Secretary decides withholding the information is contrary to the public or national interest.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1340</ref>, <ref>§ 70114 of title 49</ref>; renumbered § 70114 then <ref>§ 50916 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(P), (5)(S), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50917.</num>
<heading> Enforcement and penalty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person may not violate this chapter, a regulation prescribed under this chapter, or any term of a license issued or transferred under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct investigations and inquiries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> administer oaths;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take affidavits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> under lawful process—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> enter at a reasonable time a launch site, reentry site, production facility, assembly site of a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle, crew or space flight participant training site, or site at which a payload is integrated with a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle to inspect an object to which this chapter applies or a record or report the Secretary requires be made or kept under this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> seize the object, record, or report when there is probable cause to believe the object, record, or report was used, is being used, or likely will be used in violation of this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may delegate a duty or power under this chapter related to enforcement to an officer or employee of another executive agency with the consent of the head of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After notice and an opportunity for a hearing on the record, a person the Secretary finds to have violated subsection (a) of this section is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $100,000. A separate violation occurs for each day the violation continues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In conducting a hearing under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subpena witnesses and records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enforce a subpena in an appropriate district court of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall impose the civil penalty by written notice. The Secretary may compromise or remit a penalty imposed, or that may be imposed, under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall recover a civil penalty not paid after the penalty is final or after a court enters a final judgment for the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1341</ref>, <ref>§ 70115 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2850</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(24)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3981</ref>; renumbered § 70115 then <ref>§ 50917 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(Q), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50918.</num>
<heading> Consultation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters Affecting National Security</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall consult with the Secretary of Defense on a matter under this chapter affecting national security. The Secretary of Defense shall identify and notify the Secretary of Transportation of a national security interest relevant to an activity under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters Affecting Foreign Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation shall consult with the Secretary of State on a matter under this chapter affecting foreign policy. The Secretary of State shall identify and notify the Secretary of Transportation of a foreign policy interest or obligation relevant to an activity under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Matters</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation shall consult with the head of another executive agency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide consistent application of licensing requirements under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to ensure fair treatment for all license applicants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> when appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1341</ref>, <ref>§ 70116 of title 49</ref>; renumbered § 70116 then <ref>§ 50918 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(R), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50919.</num>
<heading> Relationship to other executive agencies, laws, and international obligations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in this chapter, a person is not required to obtain from an executive agency a license, approval, waiver, or exemption to launch a launch vehicle or operate a launch site or reentry site, or to reenter a reentry vehicle.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Communications Commission and Secretary of Commerce</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This chapter does not affect the authority of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Federal Communications Commission under the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref>47 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Commerce under chapter 601 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">States and Political Subdivisions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A State or political subdivision of a State—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not adopt or have in effect a law, regulation, standard, or order inconsistent with this chapter; but</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may adopt or have in effect a law, regulation, standard, or order consistent with this chapter that is in addition to or more stringent than a requirement of, or regulation prescribed under, this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Transportation is encouraged to consult with a State to simplify and expedite the approval of a space launch or reentry activity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign Countries</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out this chapter consistent with an obligation the United States Government assumes in a treaty, convention, or agreement in force between the Government and the government of a foreign country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consider applicable laws and requirements of a foreign country when carrying out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Launch Not an Export; Reentry Not an Import</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A launch vehicle, reentry vehicle, or payload that is launched or reentered is not, because of the launch or reentry, an export or import, respectively, for purposes of a law controlling exports or imports, except that payloads launched pursuant to foreign trade zone procedures as provided for under the Foreign Trade Zones Act (<ref>19 U.S.C. 81a–81u</ref>) shall be considered exports with regard to customs entry.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This chapter does not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a launch, reentry, operation of a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle, operation of a launch site or reentry site, or other space activity the Government carries out for the Government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> planning or policies related to the launch, reentry, operation, or activity under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following activities are not space activities the Government carries out for the Government under paragraph (1):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A government astronaut being carried within a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A government astronaut performing activities directly relating to the launch, reentry, or other operation of the launch vehicle or reentry vehicle under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1342</ref>, <ref>§ 70117 of title 49</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(95)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2850</ref>; renumbered § 70117 then <ref>§ 50919 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(S), (5)(T), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 112</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 713</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50920.</num>
<heading> User fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation may collect a user fee for a regulatory or other service conducted under this chapter only if specifically authorized by this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1342</ref>, <ref>§ 70118 of title 49</ref>; renumbered § 70118 then <ref>§ 50920 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(T), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50921.</num>
<heading> Office of Commercial Space Transportation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation for the activities of the Office of the Associate Administrator for Commercial Space Transportation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $11,941,000 for fiscal year 2005;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $12,299,000 for fiscal year 2006;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $12,668,000 for fiscal year 2007;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $13,048,000 for fiscal year 2008; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $13,440,000 for fiscal year 2009.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1343</ref>, <ref>§ 70119 of title 49</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2851</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–405, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–360, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1680</ref>; renumbered § 70119 then <ref>§ 50921 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(U), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50922.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation, within 9 months after the date of the enactment of this section, shall issue regulations to carry out this chapter that include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> guidelines for industry and State governments to obtain sufficient insurance coverage for potential damages to third parties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procedures for requesting and obtaining licenses to launch a commercial launch vehicle;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> procedures for requesting and obtaining operator licenses for launch;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> procedures for requesting and obtaining launch site operator licenses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> procedures for the application of government indemnification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reentry</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Transportation, within 6 months after the date of the enactment of this section, shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to carry out this chapter that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> procedures for requesting and obtaining licenses to reenter a reentry vehicle;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procedures for requesting and obtaining operator licenses for reentry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> procedures for requesting and obtaining reentry site operator licenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amendments</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of the Commercial Space Launch Amendments Act of 2004, the Secretary shall publish proposed regulations to carry out that Act, including regulations relating to crew, space flight participants, and permits for launch or reentry of reusable suborbital rockets. Not later than 18 months after such date of enactment, the Secretary shall issue final regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Starting 3 years after the date of enactment of the Commercial Space Launch Amendments Act of 2004, the Secretary may issue final regulations changing the definition of suborbital rocket under this chapter. No such regulation may take effect until 180 days after the Secretary has submitted the regulation to the Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary may issue regulations under this paragraph only if the Secretary has determined that the definition in section 50902 does not describe, or will not continue to describe, all appropriate vehicles and only those vehicles. In making that determination, the Secretary shall take into account the evolving nature of the commercial space launch industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Licenses for the launch or reentry of launch vehicles or reentry vehicles with human beings on board and permits may be issued by the Secretary prior to the issuance of the regulations described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of the Commercial Space Launch Amendments Act of 2004, the Secretary shall issue guidelines or advisory circulars to guide the implementation of that Act until regulations are issued.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), no licenses for the launch or reentry of launch vehicles or reentry vehicles with human beings on board or permits may be issued starting three years after the date of enactment of the Commercial Space Launch Amendments Act of 2004 unless the final regulations described in subsection (c) have been issued.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2850</ref>, <ref>§ 70120 of title 49</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–492, § 2(c)(25)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3981</ref>; renumbered § 70120 then <ref>§ 50922 of title 51</ref> and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(V), (5)(U), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440–3442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50923.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall submit to Congress an annual report to accompany the President’s budget request that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes all activities undertaken under this chapter, including a description of the process for the application for and approval of licenses under this chapter and recommendations for legislation that may further commercial launches and reentries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reviews the performance of the regulatory activities and the effectiveness of the Office of Commercial Space Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2851</ref>, <ref>§ 70121 of title 49</ref>; renumbered § 70121 then <ref>§ 50923 of title 51</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2)</ref>, (3)(W), <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>