<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 407—</num>
<heading>ENVIRONMENTALLY FRIENDLY AIRCRAFT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40701.</num>
<heading> Research and development initiative</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator may establish an initiative with the objective of developing, and demonstrating in a relevant environment, technologies to enable the following commercial aircraft performance characteristics:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Noise levels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Noise levels on takeoff and on airport approach and landing that do not exceed ambient noise levels in the absence of flight operations in the vicinity of airports from which such commercial aircraft would normally operate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Energy consumption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Twenty-five percent reduction in the energy required for medium- to long-range flights, compared to aircraft in commercial service as of <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emissions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nitrogen oxides on take-off and landing that are significantly reduced, without adversely affecting hydrocarbons and smoke, relative to aircraft in commercial service as of <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40702.</num>
<heading> Additional research and development initiative</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish an initiative involving the Administration, universities, industry, and other research organizations as appropriate, of research, development, and demonstration, in a relevant environment, of technologies to enable the following commercial aircraft performance characteristics:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Noise levels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Noise levels on takeoff and on airport approach and landing that do not exceed ambient noise levels in the absence of flight operations in the vicinity of airports from which such commercial aircraft would normally operate, without increasing energy consumption or nitrogen oxide emissions compared to aircraft in commercial service as of <date date="2008-10-15">October 15, 2008</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Greenhouse gas emissions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Significant reductions in greenhouse gas emissions compared to aircraft in commercial services as of <date date="2008-10-15">October 15, 2008</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40703.</num>
<heading> Research alignment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to pursuing the research and development initiative described in <ref>section 40702 of this title</ref>, the Administrator shall, to the maximum extent practicable within available funding, align the fundamental aeronautics research program to address high priority technology challenges of the National Academies’ Decadal Survey of Civil Aeronautics, and shall work to increase the degree of involvement of external organizations, and especially of universities, in the fundamental aeronautics research program.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40704.</num>
<heading> Research program on perceived impact of sonic booms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish a cooperative research program with industry, including the conduct of flight demonstrations in a relevant environment, to collect data on the perceived impact of sonic booms. The data could enable the promulgation of appropriate standards for overland commercial supersonic flight operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall ensure that sonic boom research is coordinated as appropriate with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, and as appropriate make use of the expertise of the Partnership for Air Transportation Noise and Emissions Reduction Center of Excellence sponsored by the Administration and the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>