<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 311—</num>
<heading>SAFETY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 31101.</num>
<heading> Aerospace Safety Advisory Panel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established an Aerospace Safety Advisory Panel consisting of a maximum of 9 members who shall be appointed by the Administrator for terms of 6 years each. Not more than 4 such members shall be chosen from among the officers and employees of the Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading>
<content>One member shall be designated by the Panel as its Chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Panel shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review safety studies and operations plans referred to it, including evaluating the Administration’s compliance with the return-to-flight and continue-to-fly recommendations of the Columbia Accident Investigation Board, and make reports thereon;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> advise the Administrator and Congress with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the hazards of proposed or existing facilities and proposed operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the adequacy of proposed or existing safety standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> management and culture related to safety; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> perform such other duties as the Administrator may request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compensation and Expenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Compensation.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal officers and employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the Panel who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall receive no compensation for the member’s services as such.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members appointed from outside the federal government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the Panel appointed from outside the Federal Government shall receive compensation, at a rate not to exceed the per diem rate equivalent to the maximum rate payable under <ref>section 5376 of title 5</ref>, for each day the member is engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Panel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the Panel shall be allowed necessary travel expenses (or in the alternative, mileage for use of a privately owned vehicle and a per diem in lieu of subsistence not to exceed the rate and amount prescribed in sections 5702 and 5704 of title 5), and other necessary expenses incurred by the member in the performance of duties vested in the Panel, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, the Standardized Government Travel Regulations, or <ref>section 5731 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Panel shall submit an annual report to the Administrator and to Congress. In the first annual report submitted after <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>, the Panel shall include an evaluation of the Administration’s management and culture related to safety. Each annual report shall include an evaluation of the Administration’s compliance with the recommendations of the Columbia Accident Investigation Board through retirement of the space shuttle.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31102.</num>
<heading> Drug and alcohol testing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Controlled Substance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “controlled substance” means any substance under section 102(6) of the Controlled Substances Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 802(6)</ref>) specified by the Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Testing Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employees of administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish a program applicable to employees of the Administration whose duties include responsibility for safety-sensitive, security, or national security functions. Such program shall provide for preemployment, reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing for use, in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation, of alcohol or a controlled substance. The Administrator may also prescribe regulations, as the Administrator considers appropriate in the interest of safety, security, and national security, for the conduct of periodic recurring testing of such employees for such use in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employees of contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall, in the interest of safety, security, and national security, prescribe regulations. Such regulations shall establish a program that requires Administration contractors to conduct preemployment, reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing of contractor employees responsible for safety-sensitive, security, or national security functions (as determined by the Administrator) for use, in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation, of alcohol or a controlled substance. The Administrator may also prescribe regulations, as the Administrator considers appropriate in the interest of safety, security, and national security, for the conduct of periodic recurring testing of such employees for such use in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Suspension, disqualification, or dismissal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In prescribing regulations under the programs required by this subsection, the Administrator shall require, as the Administrator considers appropriate, the suspension, disqualification, or dismissal of any employee to which paragraph (1) or (2) applies, in accordance with the provisions of this section, in any instance where a test conducted and confirmed under this section indicates that such employee has used, in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation, alcohol or a controlled substance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Service.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition unless program of rehabilitation completed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No individual who is determined by the Administrator under this section to have used, in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation, alcohol or a controlled substance after <date date="1991-12-09">December 9, 1991</date>, shall serve as an Administration employee with responsibility for safety-sensitive, security, or national security functions (as determined by the Administrator), or as an Administration contractor employee with such responsibility, unless such individual has completed a program of rehabilitation described in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unconditional prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any such individual determined by the Administrator under this section to have used, in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation, alcohol or a controlled substance after <date date="1991-12-09">December 9, 1991</date>, shall not be permitted to perform the duties that the individual performed prior to the date of the determination, if the individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engaged in such use while on duty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prior to such use had undertaken or completed a rehabilitation program described in subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> following such determination refuses to undertake such a rehabilitation program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> following such determination fails to complete such a rehabilitation program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Program for Rehabilitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations and availability of program for contractor employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall prescribe regulations setting forth requirements for rehabilitation programs which at a minimum provide for the identification and opportunity for treatment of employees referred to in subsection (b) in need of assistance in resolving problems with the use, in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation, of alcohol or a controlled substance. Each contractor is encouraged to make such a program available to all of its employees in addition to those employees referred to in subsection (b)(2). The Administrator shall determine the circumstances under which such employees shall be required to participate in such a program. Nothing in this subsection shall preclude any Administration contractor from establishing a program under this subsection in cooperation with any other such contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and maintenance of program for administration employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish and maintain a rehabilitation program which at a minimum provides for the identification and opportunity for treatment of those employees of the Administration whose duties include responsibility for safety-sensitive, security, or national security functions who are in need of assistance in resolving problems with the use of alcohol or controlled substances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures for Testing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In establishing the programs required under subsection (b), the Administrator shall develop requirements which shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote, to the maximum extent practicable, individual privacy in the collection of specimen samples;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to laboratories and testing procedures for controlled substances, incorporate the Department of Health and Human Services scientific and technical guidelines dated <date date="1988-04-11">April 11, 1988</date>, and any subsequent amendments thereto, including mandatory guidelines which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish comprehensive standards for all aspects of laboratory controlled substances testing and laboratory procedures to be applied in carrying out this section, including standards which require the use of the best available technology for ensuring the full reliability and accuracy of controlled substances tests and strict procedures governing the chain of custody of specimen samples collected for controlled substances testing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish the minimum list of controlled substances for which individuals may be tested; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establish appropriate standards and procedures for periodic review of laboratories and criteria for certification and revocation of certification of laboratories to perform controlled substances testing in carrying out this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> require that all laboratories involved in the controlled substances testing of any individual under this section shall have the capability and facility, at such laboratory, of performing screening and confirmation tests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide that all tests which indicate the use, in violation of applicable law or Federal regulation, of alcohol or a controlled substance by any individual shall be confirmed by a scientifically recognized method of testing capable of providing quantitative data regarding alcohol or a controlled substance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide that each specimen sample be subdivided, secured, and labelled in the presence of the tested individual and that a portion thereof be retained in a secure manner to prevent the possibility of tampering, so that in the event the individual’s confirmation test results are positive the individual has an opportunity to have the retained portion assayed by a confirmation test done independently at a second certified laboratory if the individual requests the independent test within 3 days after being advised of the results of the initial confirmation test;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> ensure appropriate safeguards for testing to detect and quantify alcohol in breath and body fluid samples, including urine and blood, through the development of regulations as may be necessary and in consultation with the Department of Health and Human Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide for the confidentiality of test results and medical information of employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> ensure that employees are selected for tests by nondiscriminatory and impartial methods, so that no employee is harassed by being treated differently from other employees in similar circumstances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Effect on Other Laws and Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consistency with federal regulation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No State or local government shall adopt or have in effect any law, rule, regulation, ordinance, standard, or order that is inconsistent with the regulations promulgated under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuance of regulations issued before <date date="1991-12-09">december 9, 1991</date></inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict the discretion of the Administrator to continue in force, amend, or further supplement any regulations issued before <date date="1991-12-09">December 9, 1991</date>, that govern the use of alcohol and controlled substances by Administration employees with responsibility for safety-sensitive, security, and national security functions (as determined by the Administrator), or by Administration contractor employees with such responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>