<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 507—</num>
<heading>OFFICE OF SPACE COMMERCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50701.</num>
<heading> Definition of Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “Office” means the Office of Space Commerce established in <ref>section 50702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3408</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 720</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50702.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established within the Department of Commerce an Office of Space Commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be a senior executive and shall be compensated at a level in the Senior Executive Service under <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref> as determined by the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions of Office</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Office shall be the principal unit for the coordination of space-related issues, programs, and initiatives within the Department of Commerce, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to foster the conditions for the economic growth and technological advancement of the United States space commerce industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to coordinate space commerce policy issues and actions within the Department of Commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to represent the Department of Commerce in the development of United States policies and in negotiations with foreign countries to promote United States space commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to promote the advancement of United States geospatial technologies related to space commerce, in cooperation with relevant interagency working groups; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide support to Federal Government organizations working on Space-Based Positioning Navigation, and Timing policy, including the National Coordination Office for Space-Based Position,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> Navigation, and Timing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of Director</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The primary responsibilities of the Director in carrying out the functions of the Office shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promoting commercial provider investment in space activities by collecting, analyzing, and disseminating information on space markets, and conducting workshops and seminars to increase awareness of commercial space opportunities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assisting United States commercial providers in the efforts of those providers to conduct business with the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> acting as an industry advocate within the executive branch of the Federal Government to ensure that the Federal Government meets the space-related requirements of the Federal Government, to the fullest extent feasible, using commercially available space goods and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensuring that the United States Government does not compete with United States commercial providers in the provision of space hardware and services otherwise available from United States commercial providers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> promoting the export of space-related goods and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> representing the Department of Commerce in the development of United States policies and in negotiations with foreign countries to ensure free and fair trade internationally in the area of space commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> seeking the removal of legal, policy, and institutional impediments to space commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3408</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title III</ref>, §§ 301(c), 302, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 720</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50703.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall submit an annual report on the activities of the Office, including planned programs and expenditures, to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>