<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 401—</num>
<heading>AERONAUTICS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40101.</num>
<heading> Definition of institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term by section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3378</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40102.</num>
<heading> Governmental interest in aeronautics research and development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress reaffirms the national commitment to aeronautics research made in chapter 201 of this title. Aeronautics research and development remains a core mission of the Administration. The Administration is the lead agency for civil aeronautics research. Further, the government of the United States shall promote aeronautics research and development that will expand the capacity, ensure the safety, and increase the efficiency of the Nation’s air transportation system, promote the security of the Nation, protect the environment, and retain the leadership of the United States in global aviation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40103.</num>
<heading> Cooperation with other agencies on aeronautics activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall coordinate, as appropriate, the Administration’s aeronautics activities with relevant programs in the Department of Transportation, the Department of Defense, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of Homeland Security, including the activities of the Next Generation Air Transportation System Joint Planning and Development Office established under section 709 of the Vision 100—Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act (<ref>Public Law 108–176</ref>, <ref>49 U.S.C. 40101</ref> note).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40104.</num>
<heading> Cooperation among Mission Directorates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Research and development activities performed by the Aeronautics Research Mission Directorate with the primary objective of assisting in the development of a flight project in another Mission Directorate shall be funded by the Mission Directorate seeking assistance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>HIGH PRIORITY AERONAUTICS RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40111.</num>
<heading> Fundamental research program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In order to ensure that the Nation maintains needed capabilities in fundamental areas of aeronautics research, the Administrator shall establish a program of long-term fundamental research in aeronautical sciences and technologies that is not tied to specific development projects.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall conduct the program under this section, in part by awarding grants to institutions of higher education. The Administrator shall encourage the participation of institutions of higher education located in States that participate in the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research. All grants to institutions of higher education under this section shall be awarded through merit review.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40112.</num>
<heading> Research and technology programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supersonic Transport Research and Development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish an initiative with the objective of developing and demonstrating, in a relevant environment, airframe and propulsion technologies to enable efficient, economical overland flight of supersonic civil transport aircraft with no significant impact on the environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Research and Development Initiative on Reduction of Greenhouse Gas and Noise Emissions From Aircraft.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall establish an initiative to research, develop, and demonstrate new technologies and concepts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from aviation, including carbon dioxide, nitrogen oxides, other greenhouse gases, water vapor, black carbon and sulfate aerosols, and increased cloudiness due to contrail formation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to reduce aviation noise emissions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to enable associated aircraft performance characteristics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Goals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The goals of the initiative required by paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to ensure United States leadership in research and technology innovation leading to substantial reductions in aviation noise and greenhouse gas emissions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to enhance and expand basic research, and the translation of basic research into applications, that may lead to transformational advances in reducing aviation noise and greenhouse gas emissions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to accelerate research and development that contributes to maturing new technologies for reducing aircraft noise and greenhouse gas emissions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to obtain and disseminate associated testing and performance data that facilitates the incorporation of new technologies into commercial aircraft development as soon as practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The objectives of the initiative established under paragraph (1) and the goals described in paragraph (2) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as soon as practicable, a reduction of greenhouse gas emissions from new aircraft by at least 50 percent, as compared to the highest-performing aircraft technologies in service as of <date date="2021-12-31">December 31, 2021</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> noise levels from aircraft throughout all phases of flight that do not exceed ambient noise levels in the absence of flight operations in the vicinity of the flight route;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> net-zero greenhouse gas emissions from aircraft by 2050; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> demonstration of new technologies developed pursuant to such initiative on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> regional aircraft intended to enter into service by 2030; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> single-aisle aircraft designed to accommodate more than 125 passengers intended to enter into service by 2040.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rotorcraft and Other Runway-Independent Air Vehicles</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish a rotorcraft and other runway-independent air vehicles initiative with the objective of developing and demonstrating improved safety, noise, and environmental impact in a relevant environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hypersonics Research</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish a hypersonics research program with the objective of exploring the science and technology of hypersonic flight using air-breathing propulsion concepts, through a mix of theoretical work, basic and applied research, and development of flight research demonstration vehicles. The program may also include the transition to the hypersonic range of Mach 3 to Mach 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revolutionary Aeronautical Concepts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish a research program which covers a unique range of subsonic, fixed wing vehicles and propulsion concepts. This research is intended to push technology barriers beyond current subsonic technology. Propulsion concepts include advanced materials, morphing engines, hybrid engines, and fuel cells.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Fuel Cell-Powered Aircraft Research.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish a fuel cell-powered aircraft research program whose objective shall be to develop and test concepts to enable a hydrogen fuel cell-powered aircraft that would have no hydrocarbon or nitrogen oxide emissions into the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approach</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish a program of competitively awarded grants available to teams of researchers that may include the participation of individuals from universities, industry, and government for the conduct of this research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Mars Aircraft Research.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish a Mars Aircraft project whose objective shall be to develop and test concepts for an uncrewed aircraft that could operate for sustained periods in the atmosphere of Mars.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approach</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may establish a program of competitively awarded grants available to teams of researchers that may include the participation of individuals from universities, industry, and government for the conduct of this research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3379</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10833(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1749</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40113.</num>
<heading> Airspace systems research</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Airspace Systems Research program shall pursue research and development to enable revolutionary improvements to and modernization of the National Airspace System, as well as to enable the introduction of new systems for vehicles that can take advantage of an improved, modern air transportation system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>, the Administrator shall align the projects of the Airspace Systems Research program so that they directly support the objectives of the Joint Planning and Development Office’s Next Generation Air Transportation System Integrated Plan.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40114.</num>
<heading> Aviation safety and security research</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Aviation Safety and Security Research program shall pursue research and development activities that directly address the safety and security needs of the National Airspace System and the aircraft that fly in it. The program shall develop prevention, intervention, and mitigation technologies aimed at causal, contributory, or circumstantial factors of aviation accidents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>, the Administrator shall align the projects of the Aviation Safety and Security Research program so that they directly support the objectives of the Joint Planning and Development Office’s Next Generation Air Transportation System Integrated Plan.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40115.</num>
<heading> Aviation weather research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator may carry out a program of collaborative research with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration on convective weather events, with the goal of significantly improving the reliability of 2-hour to 6-hour aviation weather forecasts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40116.</num>
<heading> University-based Centers for Research on Aviation Training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall award grants to institutions of higher education (or consortia thereof) to establish one or more Centers for Research on Aviation Training under cooperative agreements with appropriate Administration Centers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purpose of the Centers for Research on Aviation Training shall be to investigate the impact of new technologies and procedures, particularly those related to the aircraft flight deck and to the air traffic management functions, on training requirements for pilots and air traffic controllers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An institution of higher education (or a consortium of such institutions) seeking funding under this section shall submit an application to the Administrator at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require, including, at a minimum, a 5-year research plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Award Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An award made by the Administrator under this section shall be for a period of 5 years and may be renewed on the basis of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> satisfactory performance in meeting the goals of the research plan proposed in the application submitted under subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other requirements as specified by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SCHOLARSHIPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40131.</num>
<heading> Aeronautics scholarships</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall establish a program of scholarships for full-time graduate students who are United States citizens and are enrolled in, or have been accepted by and have indicated their intention to enroll in, accredited Masters degree programs in aeronautical engineering or equivalent programs at institutions of higher education. Each such scholarship shall cover the costs of room, board, tuition, and fees, and may be provided for a maximum of 2 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>, the Administrator shall publish regulations governing the scholarship program under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Training Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Students who have been awarded a scholarship under this section shall have the opportunity for paid employment at one of the Administration Centers engaged in aeronautics research and development during the summer prior to the first year of the student’s Masters program, and between the first and second year, if applicable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>DATA REQUESTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40141.</num>
<heading> Aviation data requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall make available upon request satellite imagery and aerial photography of remote terrain that the Administration owns at the time of the request to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration or the Director of the Five Star Medallion Program, to assist and train pilots in navigating challenging topographical features of such terrain.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3382</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>