<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 709—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL SPACE STATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 70901.</num>
<heading> Peaceful uses of space station</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No civil space station authorized under section 103(a)(1) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1991 (<ref>Public Law 101–611</ref>, <ref>104 Stat. 3190</ref>) may be used to carry or place in orbit any nuclear weapon or any other weapon of mass destruction, to install any such weapon on any celestial body, or to station any such weapon in space in any other manner. This civil space station may be used only for peaceful purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70902.</num>
<heading> Allocation of International Space Station research budget</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall allocate at least 15 percent of the funds budgeted for International Space Station research to ground-based, free-flyer, and International Space Station life and microgravity science research that is not directly related to supporting the human exploration program, consistent with <ref>section 40904 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70903.</num>
<heading> International Space Station research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out a program of microgravity research consistent with <ref>section 40904 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consider the need for a life sciences centrifuge and any associated holding facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70904.</num>
<heading> International Space Station completion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the policy of the United States to achieve diverse and growing utilization of, and benefits from, the International Space Station.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements, Capabilities, and Configuration Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Administrator shall ensure that the International Space Station will—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be assembled and operated in a manner that fulfills international partner agreements, as long as the Administrator determines that the shuttle can safely enable the United States to do so;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be used for a diverse range of microgravity research, including fundamental, applied, and commercial research, consistent with <ref>section 40904 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have an ability to support a crew size of at least 6 persons, unless the Administrator transmits to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate not later than 60 days after <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>, a report explaining why such a requirement should not be met, the impact of not meeting the requirement on the International Space Station research agenda and operations and international partner agreements, and what additional funding or other steps would be required to have an ability to support a crew size of at least 6 persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> support Crew Exploration Vehicle docking and automated docking of cargo vehicles or modules launched by either heavy-lift or commercially-developed launch vehicles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> support any diagnostic human research, on-orbit characterization of molecular crystal growth, cellular research, and other research that the Administration believes is necessary to conduct, but for which the Administration lacks the capacity to return the materials that need to be analyzed to Earth; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> be operated at an appropriate risk level.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contingencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall ensure that the International Space Station can have available, if needed, sufficient logistics and on-orbit capabilities to support any potential period during which the space shuttle or its follow-on crew and cargo systems are unavailable, and can have available, if needed, sufficient surge delivery capability or prepositioning of spares and other supplies needed to accommodate any such hiatus.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before making any change in the International Space Station assembly sequence in effect on <date date="2005-12-30">December 30, 2005</date>, the Administrator shall transmit to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a plan to carry out the policy described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70905.</num>
<heading> National laboratory designation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of United States Segment of the International Space Station</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section the term “United States segment of the International Space Station” means those elements of the International Space Station manufactured—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the United States by other nations in exchange for funds or launch services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To further the policy described in <ref>section 70501(a) of this title</ref>, the United States segment of the International Space Station is hereby designated a national laboratory.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Management.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Partnerships</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall seek to increase the utilization of the International Space Station by other Federal entities and the private sector through partnerships, cost-sharing agreements, and other arrangements that would supplement Administration funding of the International Space Station.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator may enter into a contract with a nongovernmental entity to operate the International Space Station national laboratory, subject to all applicable Federal laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70906.</num>
<heading> International Space Station National Laboratory Advisory Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than one year after <date date="2008-10-15">October 15, 2008</date>, the Administrator shall establish under chapter 10 of title 5 a committee to be known as the “International Space Station National Laboratory Advisory Committee” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Committee”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Committee shall be composed of individuals representing organizations that have formal agreements with the Administration to utilize the United States portion of the International Space Station, including allocations within partner elements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall appoint a chair from among the members of the Committee, who shall serve for a 2-year term.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties of the Committee.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Committee shall monitor, assess, and make recommendations regarding effective utilization of the International Space Station as a national laboratory and platform for research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Committee shall submit to the Administrator, on an annual basis or more frequently as considered necessary by a majority of the members of the Committee, a report containing the assessments and recommendations required by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Committee shall exist for the life of the International Space Station.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(327)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4342</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 70907.</num>
<heading> Maintaining use through at least 2030</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator shall take all necessary steps to ensure that the International Space Station remains a viable and productive facility capable of potential United States utilization through at least <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">NASA Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In furtherance of the policy under subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that the International Space Station, as a designated national laboratory—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> remains viable as an element of overall exploration and partnership strategies and approaches;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is considered for use by all NASA mission directorates, as appropriate, for technically appropriate scientific data gathering or technology risk reduction demonstrations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> remains an effective, functional vehicle providing research and test bed capabilities for the United States through at least <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title I, § 114(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10815(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>