<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 513—</num>
<heading>SPACE RESOURCE COMMERCIAL EXPLORATION AND UTILIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 51301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Asteroid resource</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “asteroid resource” means a space resource found on or within a single asteroid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Space resource.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space resource” means an abiotic resource in situ in outer space.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space resource” includes water and minerals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states citizen</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “United States citizen” has the meaning given the term “citizen of the United States” in section 50902.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51302.</num>
<heading> Commercial exploration and commercial recovery</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President, acting through appropriate Federal agencies, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> facilitate commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources by United States citizens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> discourage government barriers to the development in the United States of economically viable, safe, and stable industries for commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources in manners consistent with the international obligations of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote the right of United States citizens to engage in commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources free from harmful interference, in accordance with the international obligations of the United States and subject to authorization and continuing supervision by the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the President shall submit to Congress a report on commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources by United States citizens that specifies—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the authorities necessary to meet the international obligations of the United States, including authorization and continuing supervision by the Federal Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recommendations for the allocation of responsibilities among Federal agencies for the activities described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 51303.</num>
<heading> Asteroid resource and space resource rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A United States citizen engaged in commercial recovery of an asteroid resource or a space resource under this chapter shall be entitled to any asteroid resource or space resource obtained, including to possess, own, transport, use, and sell the asteroid resource or space resource obtained in accordance with applicable law, including the international obligations of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–90, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>