<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 503—</num>
<heading>COMMERCIAL REUSABLE IN-SPACE TRANSPORTATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial provider</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “commercial provider” means any person or entity providing commercial reusable in-orbit space transportation services or systems, primary control of which is held by persons other than the Federal Government, a State or local government, or a foreign government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In-space transportation services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “in-space transportation services” means operations and activities involved in the direct transportation or attempted transportation of a payload or object from one orbit to another by means of an in-space transportation vehicle.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In-space transportation system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “in-space transportation system” means the space and ground elements, including in-space transportation vehicles and support space systems, and ground administration and control facilities and associated equipment, necessary for the provision of in-space transportation services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In-space transportation vehicle</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “in-space transportation vehicle” means a vehicle designed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to be based and operated in space;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to transport various payloads or objects from one orbit to another orbit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to be reusable and refueled in space.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states commercial provider</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “United States commercial provider” means any commercial provider organized under the laws of the United States that is more than 50 percent owned by United States nationals.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3401</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50302.</num>
<heading> Loan guarantees for production of commercial reusable in-space transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Make Loan Guarantees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may guarantee loans made to eligible United States commercial providers for purposes of producing commercial reusable in-space transportation services or systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible United States Commercial Providers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe requirements for the eligibility of United States commercial providers for loan guarantees under this section. Such requirements shall ensure that eligible providers are financially capable of undertaking a loan guaranteed under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Loans Guaranteed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not guarantee a loan for a United States commercial provider under this section unless the Secretary determines that credit would not otherwise be reasonably available at the time of the guarantee for the commercial reusable in-space transportation service or system to be produced utilizing the proceeds of the loan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Credit Subsidy.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall collect from each United States commercial provider receiving a loan guarantee under this section an amount equal to the amount, as determined by the Secretary, to cover the cost, as defined in section 502(5) of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 661a(5)</ref>), of the loan guarantee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic disbursements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a loan guarantee in which proceeds of the loan are disbursed over time, the Secretary shall collect the amount required under this subsection on a pro rata basis, as determined by the Secretary, at the time of each disbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Other Terms and Conditions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on subordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A loan guaranteed under this section may not be subordinated to another debt contracted by the United States commercial provider concerned, or to any other claims against such provider.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction on income</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A loan guaranteed under this section may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide income which is excluded from gross income for purposes of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide significant collateral or security, as determined by the Secretary, for other obligations the income from which is so excluded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of guarantee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The guarantee of a loan under this section shall be conclusive evidence of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> That the guarantee has been properly obtained.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> That the loan qualifies for the guarantee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> That, but for fraud or material misrepresentation by the holder of the loan, the guarantee is valid, legal, and enforceable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other terms and conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may establish any other terms and conditions for a guarantee of a loan under this section as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the financial interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Enforcement of Rights.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General may take any action the Attorney General considers appropriate to enforce any right accruing to the United States under a loan guarantee under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forbearance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General may, with the approval of the parties concerned, forbear from enforcing any right of the United States under a loan guaranteed under this section for the benefit of a United States commercial provider if such forbearance will not result in any cost, as defined in section 502(5) of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 661a(5)</ref>), to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Utilization of property</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to the terms of a loan guaranteed under this section, upon the default of a United States commercial provider under the loan, the Secretary may, at the election of the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assume control of the physical asset financed by the loan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> complete, recondition, reconstruct, renovate, repair, maintain, operate, or sell the physical asset.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Credit Instruments.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to issue instruments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate, issue credit instruments to United States commercial providers of in-space transportation services or systems, with the aggregate cost (as determined under the provisions of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.)) of such instruments not to exceed $1,500,000,000, but only to the extent that new budget authority to cover such costs is provided in subsequent appropriations Acts or authority is otherwise provided in subsequent appropriations Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credit subsidy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall provide a credit subsidy for any credit instrument issued under this subsection in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The eligibility of a United States commercial provider of in-space transportation services or systems for a credit instrument under this subsection is in addition to any eligibility of such provider for a loan guarantee under other provisions of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>